Hey, what's going on? And spilled burn
is time for the Thursday afternoon,
just before Friday, Monday
morning podcast and Jess jacket.
Yay.
Do you,
how was your week going?
Is it going well? I am in
gloomy, rainy, Vancouver,
British Columbia home with the BC lions,
the Vancouver Canucks and
no fucking Westminster dog
show know there's someplace
out here at Westminster.
And I learned today that they
do have a big dog show up here,
but I don't think they
are one in the same.
I can't remember if Westminster
takes place in Beverly Hills
or in New York City,
but all I know is that you have to be
a particular level white person to be
invited. I learned that because
I thought I was white enough,
you know, and they were
like, uh Oh no, you are not.
And uh,
my dream of attending it was over.
Um, I just think it's funny. I like dogs.
And then it's just funny when they
get them all like, you know, oh,
shampooed up and they're prancing around,
you know,
and I don't know,
there's always like that thought of
what if the owner false just adds to the
tension, you know? Um, anyways,
I'm up here in Vancouver.
I'm having a great time. Uh, this
past weekend I went to a wedding,
uh, awesome wedding, tremendous wedding.
Two people that should be getting married.
They totally had the connection.
Is there anything worse unless
you just really into shine Freud.
Um, when you go to a wedding and you
just see two people and you're like,
this fucking thing is not going to last
the weekend I've been to two of those
and one of them,
the marriage lasted two years maybe.
And then the other one, as far as
I know, they're still together. Um,
the first weird wedding that I went to,
I think the bride was having second
thoughts because the groom was standing up
there forever
and then she just showed a,
walked down the hall, walked
on down the hall, right.
Walk down the aisle was there dad
and did not have that look that,
you know,
somebody usually has on their wedding day.
Um,
and then when she went up to the altar
the whole time they were doing the vows,
she was laughing uncontrollably.
Um, which, you know,
sometimes it's just a form
of nervousness, but, uh,
they didn't even kiss. And as they walked
out, they went ahead and kiss. But uh,
as far as I know, they're still
together. And then another one was, uh,
someone I was in business with when I
first got in to New York City and I went
to this person's wedding and
I remember we went out there
and,
uh,
the mother-in-law we got there like
what was traffic when we got there right
before the wedding was going to start,
it was in the backyard of these
rich people's, uh, state, right?
This guy married into money and he wasn't
rich, so I think they didn't like him.
So she was,
we pulled up,
she was outside walking the dog
dressed the way you would walk a dog.
Like she wasn't really even ready.
It was like sort of this nonverbal protest
of what was going on in there and uh,
that seemed weird. I
was like, wow. You know,
the inlaws usually never liked the
fucking person that daughter's marrying.
They never think that he's good enough.
Right. So it didn't really, you know,
it wasn't much of a red flag. But
then I just remembered when, uh,
the groom apps to where they
got married, he went to, uh,
give a toast as to why he loved
his wife and it was fucking brutal.
He was like, uh, she, cause
she gave some big toast to him.
So then he goes, okay, uh, and
Dan to you, my lovely wife, you,
uh, you, you, you make me laugh. Uh,
where the background like lighter your
life reason you get up in the morning,
like trying to help him out.
It was one of those things where everyone
was smiling like this is going to be
great. And then it just became like,
everyone just started looking down,
going to wrap it up,
wrap it up, wrap it up.
And that one lasted like two years
and it was such a fucked up marriage.
I remember him telling me
that they just had this big fight
and they were both kind of exhausted
and one of them was just kind of like,
what are we doing?
And the other one who was his psych,
yeah,
do you like not want to do this anymore?
And the other one was like,
no. And then the other one was like,
really? Because I don't either.
And then they started laughing like a
bad fucking movie and they had a really
amiable divorce.
And I think he was cool.
He didn't try to take any of her fucking
money and they just went their separate
ways. Having said that,
this wedding that I went to,
I always have that in the back of my
head because as much as I like to do
standup, I don't literally like to be
living in a bit when I'm at a wedding,
you know? Um, I don't know.
I just saw them interacting right
before the wedding and you know,
it's super stressful if you've ever gotten
married and they just seem chill and
relaxed. So it was
like, oh good, good. Um,
what was funny about this wedding
was there was also another bulb,
ginger at the wedding with a red beard,
like my doppelganger.
And um,
I went there and I had a drink and then
I had another drink and then I was just
like, Eh, you know, that's
good. I'm going to stop there.
And I started drinking water.
Now on the other hand,
the other guy was acting
like me last year.
Well before I took four months off for
drinking and this fucking guy got fucking
loaded, right? So I saw it was kind of
swaying in the breeze and I'm like, Ugh,
you know, Ben there, I'm not going to
judge. He's having a good time, whatever.
Right? So the fucking guy, next
thing I know, I'm looking outside
and this guy,
like this wedding was so perfect,
was in this really cool restaurant and
slash bar and so up front was the bar and
they had these ceiling to floor windows
and the evil version of me at some point
staggered outside and I
just felt everybody looking
and they looked and he just
fucking puked in the street in front of
like a third of the wedding was up at
the bar,
like a giant puddle of fucking puke.
So all his friends rush outside and
their fucking suits to help about,
and somebody brought a chair out.
Oh,
they sit the guy down and
I'm not laughing at the guy,
I'm just laughing cause I've been
there. I mean, not in a fucking,
not have at all wedding that I was
just that looking at me. But you know,
we've all had our moments.
I remember one time I was somewhere
down the Cape Fucking Cape Cod joke,
best fucking potato chips.
Um,
I somehow passed out on a bluff that
was headed down towards the ocean.
I was just like the middle of the day
and
uh, I forget where my buddy
was. He was the one driving,
he was somewhere else.
It came home,
something happen with the car.
Um,
and we were just passed out on like
the fucking, this, it was a bluff.
Why I just like saying that word.
I've never used it properly.
And all of a sudden I was laying there,
the son felt good and everything.
I was passed out and like
it felt like a day later,
all of a sudden they just here and
out there. That is where the Nina,
the Pinta and it fit that in his Santa
Maria came in back in 14 fucking blah,
blah, blah, blah, blah. And then I
had this little kid's voice go, Mommy,
why is that guy sleeping there?
And there was like some sort
of fucking tore going on
and a,
I vaguely remember changing a tire and
I didn't put the Jack Underneath the
frame and it went and like
writing through the floorboard.
So there you go. All right.
I'm not judging this guy,
but it was funny as fucking hell.
So this fucking guy fucking just,
you know, Great Lakes Yak, you know,
puke all over the streets.
If somebody brings a chair out and they
sit him down and he's sitting at hanging
his head like,
you know,
Jordan was sitting when he had the flu
and they put the towel over his head.
He was sitting like that
minus the towel over his head.
So then they start calling like an Uber
or Lyft and these cars keep pulling up
and they pull up to this bald dude with
the red beard sitting with his head
hanging down in a giant puddle of puke.
And everybody would just pull out
and be like, yeah, it's fucking,
guy's not getting my car. They
would drive away. And, uh,
it just became this thing like,
do you got to move them down the street?
You got to get them away from the puke.
And Anyway,
somebody finally came along
and took him home. But, uh,
he was definitely the highlight
of the evening. So, uh, I want to,
I don't know who that guy was, but
I want to thank him for the, uh,
the free entertainment. So anyways,
let's get back on track here.
I'm up here in our Vancouver and uh,
as I mentioned before,
I don't know if I mentioned,
uh,
I was talking to a number of people
up here that listen to this podcast,
that fly helicopters and one
of them had access to the, uh,
Cabri g two. I hope I'm saying that
right cabaret or is it Cabrini?
I think it's Cabri g two,
which is basically like the Robinson
r 22 that I fly at. But it has,
you know, any safety issues that the
Robinson may or may not have, you know,
that it does have,
I'm just not trying to shit on it because
I fly it all the time and I do like
that helicopter.
These people took it to the next level.
It's like the next iPhone, except
it didn't try to like, you know,
capture your fucking face.
Um, it was new and improved,
so I wanted to try this thing out and um,
these people had access to it.
So I was going to rent a car today
and his drive about an hour outside of
Vancouver. Um, but then I got a text from
the guy who was going to fly with today.
There's a guy here, he's a big fan of
yours. He's got a fucking, he's got a 66,
we'll pick you up right at
the heliport downtown. I was
like, fuck it, let's do it.
So I show up, this dude named
Chris, I want to thank him.
Great guy picked me up to tell me all
the way out there. And I was telling him,
he goes, so how did you get into
one of the fly? Uh, the Cabri g two?
And I was like, well, you know, I read all
about, you know, the low, Geez, you know,
situations, the mass bumping.
I got a little freaked out.
Vietnam helicopter pilots.
I just kind of feel like it's a bit of
a safety issue and they just sort of
taught pilots how to fly out
of it rather than fix it.
But what the fuck do I know?
I only have 160 hours. Right?
But that was just my gut feeling.
So I want to check this thing out,
see what the deals with this thing.
So we land at the airport and as we land,
one of those Cabri g twos is coming in.
And I immediately loved it.
I loved the shape of it.
And when it landed,
seeing this little two seater with the
fully articulated main rotor system was
like, I mean that's, that's
been the dream. Um, you know,
cause with the our 22 you've got to
lead with the, a collective with,
with those things, you can just push the
stick forward, which, uh, it's still,
whenever I something like that, when the
guy just goes, okay, no, sit forward.
I always have to make the joke that, you
know, I usually don't hear that, you know,
flying a Robinson. So anyways, um,
the thing lands and as it lands,
I see this guy getting out who looks
just like the dude that I saw on the
youtube video and it's like that the guy
who uploaded the video video that did
the whole,
the whole thing from nose to tail
review of it, he goes, yeah, that's him.
And it was so surreal because I didn't
know I was going to meet this guy.
It was like literally the guy that was
the reason that I wanted to fly it.
I ended up not only going to his place,
I ended up getting a fly with them. Uh,
it's BC helicopters and the guy's name
is Misha Gilb and he was incredible
pilot.
He did an auto rotation at the end that
was just was unreal for those of you who
fly Robinson's, there's no
watching your rpms going too high,
too low.
It's just he just put the collective down
and steer it and he landed this thing
like, like, like a fucking
daisy. It was incredible. And um,
so anyways,
he,
he was filming the entire time
that we will outline and um,
I was flying horribly.
I could barely even,
I couldn't even hold a hover in the thing
because the main road had turned the
exact opposite way. And as much as I
told myself, ignore your muscle memory,
just, Oh, you know, correct.
Whichever way the nose is going.
And it was also super sensitive. It felt
like the sports suspension on a car,
like a sports car,
you know?
MMM.
Where it was so hypersensitive that I just
kept over correcting. And then it was,
it took me back to when
I had like under 10 hours
flying and was just the first time trying
to hold a hover. But, uh, of course,
by the end I got way
better than where I was at,
but by then his GoPro had ran out.
So you can guys can have a fun time
laughing at me flying this thing like a
fucking salmon going up seats upstream.
It was pretty bad in the beginning, but,
um, I really, really loved
it and I got to fly up.
Yeah.
You know, I mean it was definitely
a cloudy day and everything,
but I thought it was kind of cool that
it was raining out and all that just to
fly in something different and um,
got to go all along the,
uh,
the whole skyline of Vancouver,
all the way up to where all these rich
people live and shit. And then, uh,
we flew back and on the way
back we flew up this river bed,
which I hope he keeps that footage. That's
one of the coolest things I ever did.
MMM.
I felt like I was on like
the discovery channel.
Like I should have been chasing a bunch
of gazelles or something or watching
hippos, you know, fighting alligators
to something out on the Serengeti.
It was amazing. And, um, we ended
up landing off airport up there.
We landed off airport and uh,
just some farmer's yard.
And that's when I was just like,
I had it. The thing was all over
the place when I was flying. Um,
but anyways, just want to thank
everybody at BC helicopters eyes.
I had such a great time and I
will definitely be back. And uh,
for those of you who do fly,
if you get a chance to check out one of
those Cabri g two is a pretty fucking
amazing. Um, and uh, and that's it.
And then I got two more shows tonight
at the Queen Elizabeth Theater here and
um,
and then I immediately go back to go hang
with the family because that's the new
me, right? I fly in the day of the Gig
and then I do the Gig the next day.
And then I immediately leave
cause uh, I got my, you know,
my lovely wife and my daughter,
I gotta I gotta get home too.
So fun.
Now if I only leave for like two days,
I don't have that much guilt where you
feel like an absent absentee father,
you know. Um, so anyways, um,
what time do we got here? Just 15
minutes and I should probably do this.
Read here. Okay. Me On
ds. Everybody. All right,
you heard me talk about me on these and
you know that I am a big believer in
their product.
They're the perfect balance of comfortable
fit every month they have new and
exciting prints and they arrive
at your door in a fun bag.
That now when I was a kid that
was a term for titties. Hey look,
a little fun bags on that broad.
Um, so I guess they ride it.
Brian and Avon Bag,
uh,
me undies uses a lady me undies uses Lens
Zig micro modal modal in their Cabrini
Cabri and their underwear.
It's sustainably sourced naturally soft
fiber that starts with beechwood trees.
The underwear is made out of trees and
ends with the most amazing fabric you've
ever experienced. The results have
been downright dreaming. Well,
thank God I wouldn't want to pet my ball
bag gets stabbed with this split up me
undies is so sure you'll
love their underwear.
They offer a 100% satisfaction guarantee.
If you don't love your first pair of you
get a full refund, that's a no brainer.
Get 20% off a pair of the most comfortable
undies that you will ever put on.
Fuck.
Can I get to a sentence?
They get your 20% off your first pair
of free shipping and 100% satisfaction
guarantee. Go to be on
these.com/burr. That's me,
undies.com/burr. All right, let's take a
second to talk about the fuck and Oscars.
Um, congratulations to everyone who
was nominated and everybody who won,
but in particular to people, one, I
don't know if you were paying attention,
but two people that
won an Oscar on Monday.
Also do a voice on the wonderful cartoon.
F is for family.
Allison Janney who did the voice
of our misses plasta where, uh,
she won an Oscar for
the Tonya Harding movie.
And then Sam Rockwell who does
the voice of a Frank's number six,
even though he does, he's not
even aware that he's this nemesis.
Vic Reynolds one for three billboards.
Um, so that's pretty cool. You know,
I think that upped the ante of our show.
The status anyways
too. I know, I'm throwing
that in. Who Does your show?
Who Do you do your show with?
O two Oscar winners. Allison
Janney and Sam Rockwell. Right.
Laura dern, Justin Long. Dave Kouchner.
I'm hearing I can go on forever.
Um, by the way, I'm really loving
the, I don't want to jinx it,
but this season three, I know
I'm teasing it early, but, uh,
we've been laughing our asses
off in the, uh, the edit room.
But I got to tell you yesterday I came
in landed and I was really tired because
uh, I did a show the night before to, uh,
for Hsas show down at the Improv and
I had a beer or two after
at the end of the, um,
at the end of the show and he
didn't get home til like, you know,
one in the morning or something like that.
And then my daughter,
my daughter gets up at like a quarter
to six, six o'clock. It's hilarious.
Yeah,
it just come downstairs. He can't,
you know, in that this point,
like the reason why I drink so little
now is now I don't know what happened.
Like if I have like, like one beer
or two beers, like the next day,
you know,
my daughter wakes me up and
it's just like, I feel it some
waking up just not like hung over,
but it just feeling like less energized
and you know,
she's talking all this jibberish out
there and I just opened the door and the
second I opened the door she just goes,
hi.
I don't know if I told you is like
high as her words for everything.
High means high, high means I want
that. Or if she wants attention,
she does like this frantic
like hi. Hi. Hi. Hi.
Like if she sees two people
talking and she wants to be,
it's a really like her being like, hey,
hey, hey, hey, little help over here. Um,
I want to get out of this
fucking chair. So, um, anyways,
so I didn't get a lot of sleep and then
I had to go to the airport and then I
flew up. And whenever you
fly in the plane this way,
it's always like everybody wants to sleep
except for that one person who has the
window open and then I can't fall asleep.
So I get to the hotel and I'm like,
all right,
I'm just going to lay down
here for like a half an hour.
And I had south park on speaking of,
you know,
animated shows, just total next
level. Absolutely fucking hilarious.
And I was watching this episode where
Cartman had stolen a bunch of votes
and, uh, I still,
I fell asleep and I woke
up a little later on.
I opened my eyes and
South Park was still on.
I didn't realize that they
had a marathon going on,
like they did like three or four
episodes in a row. Long story short,
my pickup for the seven o'clock show is
at six 20 and I am asleep and all of a
sudden the phone rings super loud in my
room and I opened my eyes is pitch black
in the room and I was like,
oh fuck.
And I was trying to find
my way out and I couldn't,
I literally opened the door that
went into a closet and then verse,
he called me and I saw it was six 30.
Okay.
And
I literally just threw my clothes on,
didn't even iron my shirt,
got to the venue,
sipped a little stroke Coty and went
out on stage. Had a great set though,
but I was like really? A,
it was weird. I was like,
I wasn't tired cause I slept for like
three hours. So I felt refreshed,
but I also felt like I
just woke up. So, um,
I dunno if the first 10 minutes the show
felt like an outer body experience, but,
uh,
I've never slept like,
like that close up until like almost like
missing a show or something like that.
But, uh, fortunately, uh, you
know, it went well. I don't
know. I kind of went nowhere,
you know, I almost missed my show, but I
didn't. And then the show went well, like,
did I really need to fucking tell you
all of that? Was there a reason for that?
I apologize that this recording sucks.
I bought at an external
mic for my iPhone that, uh,
Kevin shake the hilarious Kevin Shay
who came on my show. That's right.
It came on the Monday morning podcast,
promoted his special and told
me all about this. Mike going,
I love this fucking microphone.
I'm gonna have to talk to him about it
cause I ordered it off the Internet there
, the inner web. And, uh, it
was only 20 bucks. I'm like,
how the fuck is the microphone that
only cost $20 is going to be good.
And guess what? It isn't. It fucking
sucks. So I must be using it wrong.
Cause Kevin Shades is smart guy so he's
got to teach me how to use the fucking
thing cause it sounds worse than if I just
hold the phone up like I am right now.
If that makes any sense.
Yeah.
But anyways, I, oh my God,
I have to tell you this fucking stupid
tee shirt that I saw and there was like
some corporation up here, you know,
selling clothes. One of those.
Okay,
well I'm one of those
fucking close the place.
And on the mannequins they have all
these fucking political tee shirts about
equal pay for women.
And it says like enough is enough and
something about a quality and all that.
And it's just like I just can't like
these fucking assholes. It's like you
were, the guy's not fucking paying people.
Like why am I getting a fucking leg? My
voice cracking it. What the fuck are you,
how do you get off selling
those fucking shirts?
I don't understand why these
feminist groups don't go
in there and be like, okay,
you're selling enough
is enough. T shirts, uh,
why you sell and let's look into your
fucking history of paying people.
Yeah.
That's like this new, this new fucking
thing. What it is, is that a new thing?
This is what people always do when a
movement happens and they get freaked out
by what they eventually do is they
join it and once they join it,
they have like a level of control or they
could just act like they fucking agree
with it. So then like you don't, nobody's
looking at you like you're a problem.
You basically, you just sort
of send it down the line
like, no problem. Here, look,
we have a,
I'm not this enough t shirts.
Um, I actually have an uh, an
enough is enough thing, uh,
enough is enough as far as just
going after what guys do to women.
How about we balanced it
out, you know, and so on.
All this shit that fucking women
through to guys, you know, ah,
that'll never happen. Ah, you
can't do that. If you do that,
then you're a fucking sexist.
We're going to fix the male female
dynamic by only examining the behavior of
men,
because those ladies are perfect.
I would love to know what sweatshop
makes those enough is enough. T shirts,
what do fuck is Michael Moore
urban lately? We'll actually,
it's a tee shirt sold here in Canada and
God knows he blows everybody north of
fucking Minnesota. He just
thinks that they, you know,
like every like Canada can do no wrong
despite the fact it's one of the most
overtly racist places I've ever
been to, um, the entire country.
You know what I mean?
But all you gotta do is put on a silly
hat and take some syrup out of a fucking
tree. And then Michael Moore's just like,
oh my God, these people are amazing.
Um, oh, pill. Why would
you do that? Why, why,
why would you have such a nice
friendly podcast? And then,
you know, just have to pick on, you know,
punch up bill, why can't you punch up?
So what I've learned here about
Vancouver, uh, other than it's,
it's beautiful and that they like,
they like buildings that look like
the buildings that Godzilla steps on.
I've noticed that, um, there's a lot
of, a lot of money from China here,
you know, I don't know what
the fuck happened in China,
but some sort of crackdown happened and
there was a bunch of rich Chinese people
where they were just like, oh fuck, we
gotta get our money out of this country.
And they started buying up property
along sunset strip bunch of places in the
United States and evidently
here in Vancouver and I gotta,
I gotta commend
mmm.
Chinese people with money. Those people
know where to fucking buy. You know,
although I think Vancouver's smarter
than La with the global warming, without,
you know, it's lush land up here
with all the water, you know,
lakes and everything.
It's absolutely beautiful.
Um,
I dunno,
that must be incredible to leave
China and come to Vancouver.
We can actually have space, but then it'd
be weird because you'd miss, you know,
you'd miss your country.
Right.
But,
uh,
I know just haven't been over there how
crowded it is and how dirty the air is.
It's got to be fucking incredible because
I think it's incredible just coming up
from la you.
Um,
and it was like a fucking zillion people.
All these people coming out here login,
that Goddamn skis skiing
is fucking incredible.
But I gotta tell you literally have
to be like your own Roadie, you know?
And there was all these people like,
you know, you got to go snowboard man.
You can just have that like a backpack.
Just throw it over your fucking shoulders.
Right.
It seems to be like I was
just sort of analyzing it,
like skiing scares the shit out of me
cause it's like every year is some fucking
guy around my age, jubilee, people my age,
you know, late forties, early fifties.
And they just come down a trail and they
hit a tree and then that's just fucking
it. But the last time I
skied, I was in Utah and, uh,
doing a gig out there and the comedian
I was working with wanted to go skiing.
So we went,
I fucking dislocated my thumb and like
nine times I thought I was going to blow
out my niece and I vowed I would
never go again. And if I did,
I would go snowboarding.
I would much rather deal with a broken
tailbone or fucked up risks than a blown
out knee. Um, you know, in my,
if my advanced age. Um, so anyways,
I am going to go over to the venue
right now because, uh, they allegedly,
they got a drum kit
backstage at that place.
So I think I'm gonna go over there and
go jam man and some fucking tunes. Good,
clean fun. And then I'm going to
do my two shows and listen to this.
I come home,
I go to bed and then I have to get up
at four in the morning because I have to
call.
Uh,
I got a call back east cause I got a big
show coming up in Boston and I got to
sell a bunch of tickets. So, and they
want me to come on the radio live.
And uh,
so that's going to be my day.
So I'm gonna wake up at four in
the fucking morning, do that shit,
and then go to the goddamn
report and then come home.
And my daughter's going to
be like, fucking bouncing
off the walls ready to play.
But you know what? It's going to be
great. You know what's cool is she, uh,
we have this doorway to our house
where it's got like, you know,
you got the door and then along
both sides that has like these,
those old fashioned like little windows
that go from the top all the way down to
the bottom. So, uh, it's the greatest
thing ever when you'd come home,
cause she's looking through smiling at
yet. But it's the worst when you leave,
you know,
cause she has like the saddest look
on her face because now she actually
understands when you're leaving. So, um,
and I got a feeling it's
only gonna get worse.
I just don't want to get to
the point where it's like,
I'm never want to be the point where
I leave so much that it's no big deal.
You know, like I remember
long time ago, Danny Gans,
the late Danny Gans told a story of how
we ended up in Vegas is his kid drew a
family portrait and it was the mother
and all the kids. And then he goes, oh,
that's great.
Where's Daddy?
And then she pointed and she had drawn
an airplane and he was on the airplane
flying away. It was like, oh, fuck. Um,
but what am I going to deal? This is
what the fuck I do for a living. Uh,
we also announced some dates
over, uh, two dates, um,
one in Dublin and one in, uh, London.
And I know I got some shit from people.
Why don't you come here?
Why don't you come there?
I'm going to do more of an
extensive tour through Europe. Uh,
at some point I just have to figure out,
I got a balanced my new life
here with the waste and kid, um,
by definitely want to get to places
that had been before in places that I've
never been a, I just had to figure out
how to do it. But when I go to, um,
that Dublin in London Gig,
that's,
that's the week of my 50th birthday.
So I'm doing Dublin,
uh, first and then I'm
doing Royal Albert Hall,
which is insane. Then I'm going
to be there. I can't believe it.
And that's going to be for
my 50th birthday. And uh,
then I'm taking a week off and
I ain't going with, you know,
my wife and kid and everything and
that's how I'm going to celebrate.
I'm turning 50, man. What the
fuck? So I don't know. Most,
a lot of my friends didn't make it this
far, so I'm not going to bitch about it,
but if it's a big number.
Okay. Hey, that's some rough
one. All right. All right,
well that's the podcast.
Thank you guys for listening.
Thank you everybody up here in Vancouver,
they came up to the show last
night and are coming tonight.
Amazing crowd last night and I think it's
going to be more of the same tonight.
Have a great weekend yet cunts
and I'll talk to you on that.
[inaudible] [inaudible]
[inaudible]
hey,
what's up everybody?
It's bill burr and it is the
Monday morning podcast from Monday,
March the eighth 2010 Oh my God.
Could you believe the Oscars last night?
I can't believe that Kelly Wigan and faith
didn't get best supporting cont for a
let's make a fucking
Afghan in the 18 hundreds
do you know I'm actually still in San
Jose right now and I was supposed to have
a show tonight.
I'm actually recording this on Sunday.
I was supposed to have a show tonight,
but it got,
because everybody evidently is
watching the fucking Oscars.
I can understand if you're abroad and
you want to watch that shit, I get it.
That's like your Superbowl.
We get to sit there and watch the
different dresses in which couple is with
which couple and who just broke up and
are they there with their new boyfriend
or girlfriend and oh my God.
Did they ignore each other on the red
carpet and look at some fucking twats Yank
back face as she talks about their shoes.
I get that.
But where the fuck were
the men and San Jose who I,
we had enough fucking balls left
and their relationship to be like,
you know what? I'm not going to your
stupid fucking Oscar party. Okay.
Cause I don't want to listen to fucking
98 different reads of Oh my God.
You know. Oh my God, why is he
wearing that chest? Oh my God,
she looks so beautiful.
Oh my God.
That was like the best speech Aba.
Huh?
Is that what you did? He's sitting
in a cubicle right now as a man.
Is that what you did last night?
Cause if he did,
he should be hanging in your
fucking head. Huh? What happened?
Let's go down memory lane.
Okay,
go all the way back to high school when
you're still at a set of balls between
your fucking legs. Remember that they
were brand new and they were ready to go.
I've got a question for you. Where the
fuck did they go? Cause you different,
you definitely didn't have them.
Men of San Jose because you weren't at
my fucking show last night to the point
it had to be canceled.
Granted, I'm not going to lie.
About a fucking month and a half ago,
a married couple came out of a bar,
got into with the Bouncer,
cops showed up and he fucking tased
the dude's wife and shot the guy in the
abdomen. And the dude damn near bled
out right in front of the Improv here.
Look it up online. They got the picture.
You know, after there's a shooting,
they clean up the mess.
There's always the fucking old ketchup
stains on the sidewalk and a couple of
articles of clothing and it's
fucking hilarious. And then right,
right next to it they had the marquee
and it still said Eddie Griffin.
It was funny. So yeah, I guess that
isn't good for fucking business. But, um,
I gotta tell you,
man,
I had a great time coming up here and
I've avoided coming to San Jose because I
was worried that, uh, basically
what happened Sunday night,
I thought it was going to happen all
week because I don't know what is about
California. I just feel like if you're
not, if you're not a fucking Latino comic,
you know,
I just don't or are super famous.
You're not gonna sell any
tickets out here. Cause you know,
people put that in my head. Um, but no,
a lot of people came out on a Saturday
night and they actually had a balcony.
That was the thing about on Friday,
nobody showed up. Right. So there I am.
I'm standing in this huge fucking theater
in the entire upper deck is empty.
I felt like I was performing at
a fucking royals game. You know,
I felt like I should've been like singing
the national anthem or something like
that and then yelling at
my manager wondering what
happened to my fucking music
career that I couldn't at least
sing it like an angel's game.
All those fucking idiots gotta come out
there with their, they have their deck,
goddamn noise makers.
How lame are you,
his fans that the ownership is
basically saying, you know what?
You guys have such a lack of
passion. We need them. We need to,
to invent something to make it sound like
you guys care way more than you really
do here.
Here's a couple inflatable
fucking plastic balloons.
Just slam them together. We'll even get a
monkey. I have a crazy monkey out there.
Fucking angels. Um, anyways,
what am I doing here? What the fuck
am I talking about? Um, I actually,
I had a great weekend and uh,
believe it or not,
you wouldn't know it from my voice and
I found a great Sushi place out here at
checkout. Smile. Susi Sushi.
If you get a chance to,
I don't know where the fuck it is, but
you have the Internet, right? Let me,
I'm fucking walking around right now.
I'm looking out the window.
They got a museum across the street
and they have a star trek exhibition.
And you should have seen
these fucking nerds.
You should have seen these
fucking nerds just, just,
just standing outside,
like waiting for a museum to open.
That's when you know you're a fucking
nerd. Okay. Everybody's gone to museum.
But who the fuck has ever stood outside
of museum with your face pressed against
the glass,
waiting for the fucking thing to open up.
You know, Jesus cry. I mean, I I
see back in the day you're what?
You're waiting for fucking concert
tickets. You know what I mean?
Back in the day when they used to have
like actually have record stores and the
artists would come through and you'd be
standing outside strawberries records
and tapes, you know, waiting to have
your cassette signed by Brian Adams.
What did I pick? Bryan
Adams. I'll tell you why.
Because I am staying at a very nice hotel
as I've made it to that level in this
business. All right. I
am on the 14th floor,
the Penthouse fucking level.
Although I just have a suite.
I haven't gotten to that level yet
and I'm looking out the barren fucking
landscape here as far as
people go. Anyways. Um,
but anyways,
I went down to the fucking place to have
breakfast in the second I walked in.
Right. All I see is his cloth
napkins in leather bound menus.
So right there, you know, it's going
to be like 58 bucks for an Omelette.
So all I want to do is stop and turn
around and get the fuck out of the place.
But do I, of course I don't. You know why?
Because there's so few people in there
that everybody looked at me when I came
in and it reminded me of this time
when I went to this titty bar in Troy,
New York,
I believe it was Troy,
New York was called the cloud
night and he perverts out there.
You know what the fuck I'm talking about.
It's not really,
it's sort of a strip club,
sort of a guy's house.
I would have to describe it as,
I just remember there was an upstairs
when he came walking in that literally
look like some old lady should it down
in her house coat and just be like,
all right, can you, can you stop all
that strapping? I'm trying to sleep. Um,
and then some sort of double wide trailer
that's sold videos that was attached
to the other side of it. But
anyways, long story short,
I went in there with two other
people who will remain nameless,
cause I don't name names in the fucking
podcast because I'm old school. Um,
so I can't even fucking
remember who they are. Anyways,
I've talked to my cell phone
so fucking much. So anyways,
I walk into the goddamn place,
we all walk in and the second we walk in,
all we want to do is
turn around and walk out.
But there's so few fucking
people in there. Everybody's
looking at us, the dancer,
the fucking Dj, the fucking, uh,
porky guy who runs the goddamn
place and the two fucking, uh,
immigrant truckers who was sitting in
there, I believe they will Yugoslavian.
I can't remember what. So, you know,
you just fucking go in and sit down.
So I went in and I sat down at
this fucking breakfast place.
I'm back to the breakfast
place or I try to keep up.
I'm playing these fucking brain
games on the Internet. All right.
My fucking brain is sharp.
It's coming back. Um, got,
I'm lonely. Anyways. Um,
so I sit down at this fucking
breakfast place and uh,
there's this a medium size woman
who suffers from vocal fry.
And for those of you who didn't major in
communications and didn't have to take
a career speech class,
vocal fry is basically, uh,
a way of speaking where you're not,
you're not forcing enough air
through your vocal chords.
So you start your talk like this.
Have you ever,
you ever heard people talk like that?
Oh my God,
I was up at Amy's house the other day
and I just felt like she was giving me
this vibe. Or you have the
other people who start off
where they, they, they, they,
they, they push enough air
through their vocal cords,
but then towards the end
they, they, they taper off.
Today everyone, we're going to be
reading about a lady who, yeah, blah,
blah, blah, blah, blah. Bababa mad
at that fucking drives you nuts.
And never used to bug me until I took a
class on it. Now I can't stop hearing.
So this fucking idiot is sitting
there talking like the typical,
like, I dunno, she
sounded very intelligent,
but all she was talking about
was like us magazine Shit.
And meanwhile I was listening
to a instrumental of a
Brian Adams song over the
fucking radio,
you know,
and Brian and his first came out and
he had the Fonzi leather jacket. Right.
And you're like, wow, this guy's good.
He's got some decent tunes, you know.
Got My first meal, 60, remember
that? And when he was so young,
you thought that that actually rocked,
but it wasn't bad for pub.
And then he just fucking jumped the shark
where it's just like, you know what?
I can't fucking do this anymore.
My face is breaking out.
I can't fucking do it anymore.
I'm just going to sell out.
I want to write a song for chicks.
Richard Marx can do it. So can I,
and then he had that song.
Yeah.
Okay.
[inaudible]
it up.
[inaudible] that song I chair.
Yeah, that stupid fucking song.
They used to make receptionist tear up
all across this country when it would
come on and a dental office.
Um,
they had an instrumental version of that
going on as I ate my fucking scrambled
eggs and listen to this fat fuck.
Talk about little house on
the prairie with vocal fry.
So that was probably the low
point of the weekend. Um,
I don't even know what I'm talking about.
You know what I did want to hype.
I want it to hype. Jesus Christ.
That was only 10 minutes.
There's no fucking way
I'm making this one.
This one's going to be short and
sweet everybody or shortened mediocre,
however you want to fucking call it.
Let's hit the refresh. Pray page.
Let's see how the Bruins and the penguins
are doing. Bruins need to win this one.
Got To make sure we make the playoffs so
we can fucking lose in the first round.
Still one to one. After two
periods, two friends of mine,
Billy Gardell and Randy Bowman
or Bauman are at the, uh,
at the penguins game right now.
Randy Bowman from a Jim and
Randy showed WTV in Pittsburgh.
Have a fucking listen. They're sitting
there talking shit, texting me,
talking shit.
You know,
right before the game about how the
penguins were going to kill the Bruins.
You know, we're having an off year and
lo and behold, you know, an hour goes by,
there's no shit talking.
So I go on the Internet and there it is
zero zero after the first fucking period
fucking asshole penguin.
So you know,
Harry sending of the Bruins was actually
debating suing the Pittsburgh Penguins
when they switched to black and
gold for stealing the Bruins colors.
You know, I'm going to pause here and
let the people in Pittsburgh exhale
be like, hey, look at Pittsburgh
Steelers. You tried to do too.
Ruins had been around since before the
fucking stealers and the Steelers back in
the day used to basically
have yellow uniforms.
They're that big stupid yellow helmet.
That's what they had. All right.
And the only black you had was
a couple of little stripes.
That's all it was back then.
When you play the old 23 skidoo the long,
I say the long pass when you were doing
that shit. So I don't want to hear it.
Um, and plus, you know what I mean? Who,
who fuck takes the exact same colors
as another team in the same league.
Okay. You started off with your gay little
baby blue fucking penguin. You know,
first of all your penguins.
Why am I talking? Shit,
I'm going to get hit with the
obvious one was the last time.
You guys want a cup 19 here. We need to
then shut the fuck up bill. Fine. I will.
All right. You just keep joy.
That fucking whiny pussy.
He's not a pussy,
but have you ever seen,
I haven't seen anybody wine the way
Cindy Crosby wine since fucking,
he's like Danny Ainge on skates pow,
pow goes,
saw played fucking hockey and was a
good looking guy with full ruby red lips
from Nova Scotia.
All right,
so whatever,
let's hit refresh again.
Do at least make the end of the
fucking period here. Come on. Berlin's.
There we go. The end of two. One to one.
What do you guys say now
they have Billy Gardell
fucking cock sucker. All right. Um,
what was I trying to say here? Um,
oh, I know I wanted to hype is, uh,
one of the fans here on the podcast
who will also remain nameless, um,
has started a fan page for the
Monday morning podcast. Okay.
So I'm actually going to the
next level with this podcast. Um,
a lot of times I make references
and uh, you know, people, you know,
don't have time to look them up or
maybe you don't want to go all over the
internet trying to figure out
what the fuck I'm talking about.
This guy has a bunch of uh, you know,
has links to some of the references. He,
you know,
does all that Photoshop stuff.
He does all that computer stuff
that I don't know how to describe.
But basically if you'd like to check it
out at the end of the podcast or maybe
follow along,
you can go to a page called
www.themmpodcast.com www.themmpodcast.com.
No spaces. Okay. And now you go,
I'm hyping that for the week.
Um, see, this is why I
don't hype Shit. Now I just,
whatever flow I just fucking
head is out the goddamn window.
What else did I do here?
You know what I like about San Jose
is it is actually a hockey town.
Like I'm in my hotel,
they have the NHL Channel and I was
sitting there watching hockey night in
Canada, which is Saturday
night. Um, and I,
what the fuck was I watching?
I was watching Toronto verus Ottawa
and a that had to go do my show.
But coming up they had a,
the La kings verse to Canadians with
any luck, they fucking beat him.
Did they beat him? You know
what? I'm going to check.
God knows I've got nothing else to talk
about on this fucking podcast. Um, no.
You know what,
let's continue this sports theme just
so we can get rid of all the people who
aren't into sports and are into
other things like politics.
The fuck is up with that once the
deal with people who are informed. Um,
on a number of weeks ago, I actually,
I ripped Peyton manning a new asshole.
And upon listening back to it,
you know,
I actually sounded like half of fucking
retard. I will definitely admit that.
But I still stand by my opinions and I
kept bringing up a guy by the name of
Terry Bradshaw who has four
Superbowl rings and uh, you know,
everybody hit me dude. The only two
from like 20 plank, I can fucking huge.
Well they have a great article on Terry
Bradshaw in a sporting news magazine
this week or this month. I don't
really read this magazine, but I'm,
that kid from Nebraska
was on the cover that uh,
Dima Dima Tamu Kong, Su Damo Kong sue.
I don't know.
He's got a great fucking name and uh,
the Patriots needed defensive tackle,
but I know we're not going to
draft high enough to get that guy.
But I just wanted to read about,
cause I figured maybe they talk about
other defensive tackles that were
available because I have
no life. Um, but anyways,
I opened it up and Lo and behold, there
was a great article about Terry Bradshaw,
which basically backs up what the fuck I
was talking about. At least in my world.
It does.
And uh,
and they mentioned right in the beginning
it said a Bradshaw won his fourth and
final Superbowl ring with
an MVP performance for the
Steelers at the rose bowl
among quarterbacks.
Only Joe Montana has that record and it's
quite possibly none will ever surpass
it. Okay. All you Peyton
manning fans out there,
do you think he's going to get five
fucking rings? They'll get four.
I think he could possibly get three.
He's not getting four though. All right.
And this is coming from fucking Terry
Bradshaw, a man who played the game.
This is what,
this is a quote from the article.
The only thing that matters in the
prose is winning the Superbowl.
I've never had anyone come up to
me in my life and say, hey Terri,
how many yards did you throw? Four.
How many touchdown passes do you have?
It's all about rinks.
Does that sound familiar?
Go listen to the fucking
February 8th podcast.
Maybe Terry listens to my podcast.
Oh, fucking arrogant. Is that? Um,
but then he says, uh, he says
it's all about rings, but dude,
the shit that this guy took,
you know,
I knew in the beginning of his career
that this guy had a rough time in
Pittsburgh and everybody,
you know, basically treated
him like a dumb redneck and,
uh, kind of like what they
did with John Rocker. Oh,
always fought John rocker got a bum deal
because I was living in New York and
they were basically calling
this guy a fucking moron,
redneck and not so many words.
And then he comes out and
starts trash in New York.
And then typical media,
they get to step away.
Like they didn't insight any of it,
you know,
and all the mets fans get to act like
they weren't fucking yelling shit at him.
I used to be doing a bit
about that. That, uh,
that of the punchline was basically
you had date rapists and wife beaters
throwing batteries at a bigot.
That was basically,
that was my little fucking social
commentary on the John Rocker incident.
Let me get back to this shit
and not supporting anything
that John Rock has said,
but you know what I mean?
It's like, you know,
if you're going to FAU fucking
throw rocks, rocks at a,
at a, at a Hornet's nest.
Yeah. Yeah. I don't know. Dad did I
almost just say you're going to get stung.
You know what I almost just created,
there was one of those southern fucking
expressions that I love so much faster
and Turkey shit through a tin horn.
I'll tell you that boy,
that boy fuck a rock up.
You thought a snake was under it.
Anybody from down south can just send
me a whole list of those fucking things.
If I already done this on the
podcast and I don't remember,
I absolutely love those fucking
expressions that Boyd fuck mud.
I don't even know what they mean.
That boy would fuck a rock if he
thought his snake was under it.
How does that make any sense? But,
but, but when I love about is,
even though it doesn't make sense,
you,
you understand what the person is
saying and there's a genius to that.
So anyways, um, let me, uh, let, let's
read about Terry Bradshaw's Er, er,
the early part of his fucking
career basically. Yeah, they were,
they were shitting all over it. Well,
why don't we have Terry it here.
You said you have to understand something.
My first five years were not the best.
I had shit thrown in my face.
I was booed, criticized,
called stupid and dumb
players talking about,
we're saying this is players on his teams
were saying, ah, we win. In spite of him,
he stutters in the huddle.
I had so much of that shit thrown at me.
I got bitter about it.
And my coach,
who I thought never defended me in
public chuck, no. Um, the thing was,
I was never his chosen one.
I had to sit back and come to grips with
all that and it was very painful for me.
It wasn't a storybook career.
So I take a great deal of pride and being
the quarterback of the team that won
all those super bowls. Yeah. And the
guy never gets to fucking respect.
Do you know before Superbowl 13?
Uh,
Thomas Hollywood Henderson said Terry
Bradshaw couldn't spell cat if you spotted
them to see in the a.
So they asked Bradshaw about this
and if you watch football, you know,
we always comes off like this guy just
being all silly and joking around,
but he goes, well, it tick me off.
The thing that ticked me
off was nobody defended me.
Who came out on my team and
said, bullshit. He calls
the place, he sets it up.
Who defended me? Chuck Noll didn't,
didn't defend me. The only guy knows,
said something was Joe Greene.
And then here I got to deal with
this thing going into the Superbowl.
What the hell am I going to do?
I'm smart enough to know not to get in
that argument with Hollywood Henderson
through the media because
it's a distraction. Um, I
don't have time for that shit.
Okay. So I can't spell cat. If
you spot me the c and the t, uh,
that's some good shit. Congratulations.
Then you go out and you kicked our asses.
How much? How's my spelling look now
you're the one who had to go to prison.
Hey, chuck it there. Terry's an angry
mother fucker or whatever. I love it.
I love it. You know, something that
he never went back to Pittsburgh.
I didn't even notice that shit
when he was done. He just left.
He doesn't even talk to any of the
players. And he said, he goes, I mean,
it's kind of a failure of my personality.
I don't know.
It's a really interesting article
because if you watch him on a,
whatever the hell this show is called,
the NFL pregame, he still plays it up.
Like he says, you know, this, this just,
just this country boy. But he isn't,
he's fucking sharp as attack.
And uh,
he didn't like the way he was treated
in Pittsburgh. And I enjoy that.
I enjoy that considering those guys,
uh,
how seriously they take their team and
their fucking quarterback at game four
super bowls. He treated them like
such shit. You know, I just like,
I like when teams do that to their
fucking players cause it makes Boston fans
look better cause God knows where
bunch of fucking assholes, you know,
kind of like when Montreal
booed Patrick was out of town.
I love bringing this shit up and then
he goes out to fucking Colorado in
immediately wins a Stanley Cup and then
like four years later wins another one.
I love that now Montreal hasn't been a
factor since fucking 1993 I love that
too.
It's over there.
Last dynasty was 1979 they dominated
a 16 league that spilled over into the
expansion six and then everybody got
their shit together and you haven't heard
anything from those motherfuckers sense
and they're still walking around with
their chest puffed out about some shit
that they did back in the three stooges
error. You know, it's fucking over
30 years ago. It's been 30 years since
you guys dominated the fucking Nhl.
All right,
so get off your goddamn high horses.
All right dad out to get me a couple of
emails. Okay. Let's continue on with the,
with the podcast here. Um,
here's a couple of videos.
If you want to watch this one that
I wanted you guys to check out. Um,
there's a video of your van Halen Fan.
Go on Youtube and check out van Halen
and it's a song in the cradle will rock.
If you just search that,
a bunch of videos will come up and
click on this second video down and uh,
just look what David Lee Roth is wearing.
It's absolutely fucking hilarious.
But I'm telling you,
as funny as it is,
there's going to be a part of
you being like, God dammit,
I wish I could get away with
wearing something like that.
Can you imagine the amount of pussy I
would get if I wore something like had the
balls to wear something like that?
For those of you who aren't near a
fucking, I'll basically describe it,
who aren't near a fucking
computer right now.
Maybe you're on a treadmill trying to
work off that Burgee to Carl's Jr at two
in the morning. No one,
you shouldn't have done it.
We woke up this morning feeling like you
had a fucking anchor in your stomach.
It goes fucking sweat it off.
He's basically wearing a
picture. If you, if you,
if you had a zoot suit made out of
Spandex and all you were wearing was the
pants. So they basically came up right
underneath your fucking chest. Right.
And then you remember those,
you remember those fucking,
and they're in their purple sparkle
to all right. And then that's it.
You don't have anything
else on other than,
do you remember those boots that those
whores used to wear an aspen in like the
late seventies early eighties where they
look like they skinned a woolly mammoth.
He has on White, wooly,
mammoth snow boots.
And the greatest thing is the crowd is
just fucking stick cause it's early on in
their career. I don't know if it's from
another country. I have no fucking idea.
I haven't watched it in awhile,
but I was just remembering it and I
wanted you guys just check it out.
Jesus Christ.
I told that fucking story in real time.
All right, here's another one. Another
youtube video. Somebody sent me,
it says a checkout Dwarf
midgets killer movie
Tie, m. U. A. T. H. A. I, this is
basically, it's, it's very, uh,
very accurately descriptive.
Uh, described it.
It's one guy is a dwarf and the other
guy's a midget or a little person as the
new way class that they invented
a little person and they are, uh,
they're fighting somewhere,
I'm going to guess,
and maybe the Philippines and it's a
Muay Thai fight and it starts off funny.
Then you think it's fake because the
midget keeps hitting the door off with the
exact same fucking punch.
The dwarf keeps trying to kneel knee,
neither midget and the chest
and the midget keeps coming
with an overhand right.
And I was kept thinking,
why the fuck is he keeps,
why the fuck does he keep throwing
the same punch? This must be fake.
But then I realized that the boxing gloves
on the midget actually go beyond his
elbow. So he couldn't throw
a hook if he wanted to.
And then after that,
it just becomes sad.
There's something about the dwarfs face
where he just really looks like he's
getting, he's physically at paint. The
midget has, you know, we still got that,
that Christmas twinkle in his eye.
He seems like he's having a good time.
He's got a little bit
of swagger in his water.
She's probably getting some pussy
after the show, you know. And uh,
that's a good question. Would you have a
lot of Midget Bang you women out there?
I know some guys have banked
a little person, but I was
just wondering, you know,
if he just laid down on your stomach
and you just felt like that, like that
at wiggle and eight year
old riding you from behind,
do you know how long your hair would have
to be so you could actually pull it in
that position? Why am I being such an
asshole this week? I don't know why.
All right, next, uh, next
youtube video. I'll tell you why.
Because I don't have a fucking show.
I don't have a show tonight
and I'm waiting to take a
red eye, JetBlue, JetBlue,
back to a f.
Jfk.
I'm not looking forward to going back
to New York this time of year with that
fucking weather. I really have
not missed the winner whatsoever.
That's a big thing they asked in the east
coast. Don't you miss the four seasons?
What Frankie Valli and those guys here,
is that when you say,
do I miss the four seasons? No,
I don't. No, I don't. I like it.
I like being old and being in the
retirement community that is Los Angeles.
I like it. It's, you know
what La is like, it's like a,
it's like Florida for somebody
who's still middle aged, you know,
you go to Florida, does it die?
That's the last place I'll go,
go out there and get me a gator boat,
you know, that's what I'm going to do.
That's how I'm going to parachute out
of my life. I'm going to, uh, yeah.
I'll probably get a divorce and just
say, listen, I'm cashing in my chips.
I can't do this. We had kids all rights
fucking over there out of the house.
What do we do? Stare at each other
for the rest of fucking time.
So I sit there and watch watching you
slowly gumming those waffles that used to
be able to tear through an English
muffin in a minute and a half.
Now we sit here for fucking
37 minutes as I watched.
I don't want to live that life with
you. Okay? We had a great time.
I give you a high five,
but I'm afraid I'm going to break
his shoulder and then I'll go.
Then I'm going to go down to Florida
and I'm just going to get one of those
fucking boats with the fan on the back.
And I'm going to give,
I'm going to give everglade tours is I
want to play some Pentair and some ACDC.
I'm going to have on affected
southern accent and that's it.
And I'm gonna live off my DVD money
even though I won't exist anymore.
Um, and I'm addressed all in
khaki. Okay, let's continue on. Um,
the next youtube video that
you can look at is, uh,
there's one called a public access
TV hosts bombarded with prank calls,
is the name of it.
I don't know if this is the right video.
Somebody sent this one to me
and I accidentally deleted it.
So I just buy him describing it.
I think this is the one,
so look it up and it's basically a guy
in public access trying to talk about gun
control. And it's such a low budget
that, you know, it's not pre,
it's basically live and he
puts his phone number up there.
So somebody calls in realize is it's,
you know,
realizes that it's alive and
tells them to go fuck himself.
And then the entire audience,
like a bunch of Goddamn children call in
in all they're saying is just the dirty
as shit that they can basically think of.
The best guys are the ones who actually
start talking about gun control for a
minute. So this guy actually feels
like he's having a discussion
and right as the guys
starts to engage with them,
they tell them to go fuck himself. So if
you're an angry prek like me, it's an I,
it's actually a a, it's a
nice one. So with that, um,
I have been on lumosity.com
for all of last week, uh,
trying to get my BPI score to go up,
which is,
I don't even know what
the fuck it stands for.
Basically the higher the number you
have, the less a moron. I don't know.
I was going to say retarded, but
I don't like using that word. Uh,
even though I've already said it
five times as fucking podcasts,
the less dumb you are I guess are the
smarter you are, the higher it is. Right.
I got confused in the middle of it.
I don't know.
I'm worried about my brain right now,
everybody because it's feeling fuzzy
and I think a lot of it has to do with
talking on my cell phone too much and
I'm trying to cut down on that like a
cigarette smoker and I've been
going to this, this website,
Lumosity Dotcom and has these,
these games that challenge your brain.
It's fucking awesome. And they got
everything out. Any, any type of,
any type of stuff that
you could be thinking of?
I don't know if I talked about this last
week, so I'll kind of blow through it.
It's Lumosity, l,U , m
o, s. I. T, Y. Dot Com.
Somebody else also suggested one that was,
um,
I don't know how to read it because
it's a website here. That's all,
I don't know how to say it here. It's,
it's www.no spaces here. P, O, s.
I. T. S. C. I. E. N. C e. So it's
posted science, Pos, it, science.com. Um,
and they have these brain games and I
really think in an a number of years,
that's where I did talk about this last
week, that the, that they're basically,
instead of having all these, these
exercise shows at night that involves,
you know, getting fucking abs
and all that type of shit,
they are actually going to be
selling stuff late at night.
That's going to be basically
crunches for your brain. And um,
I would recommend it. It's Kinda
been my new thing that I do out here.
I told you I've been trying to learn,
learn how to write with my right hand.
I'll tell you about that shit.
I'm a lefty and somebody,
this comedian was telling me about
this book that he was reading that uh,
if you actually do things
with your opposite hand,
it opens up different areas
of your brain. And, um,
so I've been doing that, you know,
I'm writing with my right hand.
I've been throwing shit around my,
my hotel room with my left hand.
I'm kind of fucked up where I,
I, I kind of jump back and forth,
play guitar left to I play drums,
righty. I play sports right handed.
I write lefthanded I can use tools
either hand fucking rub one out with the
left, but in a pinch.
Okay, let's plow ahead.
So this is the type of
Shit I've been doing.
So I've been learning how to write
with my right hand and I basically,
my hand writing with
my right hand looks at,
looks like my handwriting
in like fourth grade. Um,
it looks like if I,
if I was in the fourth grade and um,
I just saw a ghost. That's the way
it looks. It's looking very spooky.
But, uh, I've also been trying to
learn how to become a better speller.
I just ain't no something like I always
make fun of how the fact that I'm a
fucking moron and I'm like Terry Bradshaw,
I definitely play up my stupidity,
but there's definitely a seed of a,
or maybe some people would say a deep
well of stupidity that I actually have.
And most of it, um, is
art. It just laziness.
I mean,
there's no reason why I should know how
to spell the word restaurant at my age.
I've been to a bunch of them and I've
tried to spell it a million times.
And for the life of me, I always forget
if the u comes after the first a Oh,
the second a and m I've tried this a
number of times and I'm going to try to
stick with it is I just as I,
you know,
tried to type an email and rather than
just hitting spellcheck and just moving
on with my life, I'm trying to
actually make a list of words.
I don't know how to sell, sell,
spell, see how my brain's fucked up.
Um, and then what I do is I, then
I write, I write the word properly,
like 10 times in a row. Um, but
I write it with my right hand.
So I'm kind of doing two things at once
and it's fucking hilarious because I
kind of left this shit out and I was
just thinking of the poor cleaning lady
coming in here.
Like one of the words I was learning
how to spell was penitentiary.
So I have penitentiary
written like fucking 12 times
in this spooky I'm writing
with my opposite hand,
fucking penmanship.
And I just kept thinking of the shining
all work and no play makes jack a dull
boy, you know? So, uh, I dunno,
trying to become a smarter human being.
Am I boring the shit out of you?
Because I think that last
segment was a little boring,
but I'm into this shit man. I'm sick
of just knowing stuff about sports.
I actually,
you know what,
I'm going to Europe in two weeks and I
desperately do not want to come off as
the typical stupid American.
At least I'm in shape. Okay.
So I'm going to be real, you know,
representing us nicely in that category.
The fact that I'm 41 years old and I'm
still fucking in shape. Jesus Christ,
I almost fell backwards on this chair.
I didn't understand how far away the
curtains were. I should have gone with it.
At least it would have been fucking funny.
Let me see if I can lean back here.
Easy, easy, easy. It's not working. Um,
oh Jesus. Oh Jesus. Hang on one second.
Hello. Hey, let me call you
back in like 20 minutes. Okay.
Okay, cool. All right. But um,
so anyways, uh, the
fuck am I talking about?
I got a, um, I got this magazine,
Scientific American because I'm like,
I can't keep reading these
fucking sports magazines. And two,
there was a guy in there,
these egg heads when they want to,
as much as I'd love trash and
people, if you notice, you know,
I just insult the way you
look and I say fuck a lot,
but these guys are actually intelligent
human beings and this guy was making fun
of people who tell stories.
You ever see those stories
where people say they died,
I was dead for two minutes and then I
came back and then they come on and they
start talking about the
stuff that they saw.
But that the way this scientist guy
breaks the shit down scientist guy that I
really just say that the
way this dude just shines,
Dude Rye do I break shit down?
Um, it's just fucking brilliant.
He basically says, you're not dead.
You had a near death experience.
You were in a a a near death state.
You weren't dead if you were dead,
you dead.
They can't bring you back from being dead.
All right.
Even if you fucking hard
stops just because your heart
stops the dying process.
This guy was the way he broke it down
and he said it can take anywhere from a
couple of minutes to a couple of hours
to occur depending on the conditions.
So even if somebody,
unless you get just
fucking blown up vaporized,
even if somebody shoots
you in the fucking heart,
your brain is still going to be firing,
synapsis and or whatever. The Fox.
I'm too stupid to know.
What it is,
but it still takes another couple of
minutes and other stuff like he said,
can take up to a couple of hours.
So these fucking people who think they're
dead or not dead and they're coming on
TV talking about the shit they saw, like
they, like they were in another fucking,
I dunno universe and they weren't.
So he basically in the
Deepak Chopra is to you know,
is on this Larry King show
describing what's going on.
So the guy basically concludes it with
this when a cause one other scientists
was actually kind of agreeing with
Deek Pock Chopra by saying, you know,
there's some stuff out there that we
just, you know, science, you know,
has no explanation for.
And this guy says, so what?
The fact that we cannot fully explain a
mystery without natural means does not
mean it requires a
supernatural explanation.
It just means we don't know everything.
Such uncertainty is at the very heart
of science and is what makes it such a
challenging enterprise.
And in that moment there was a clap of
thunder and I realized that science is
religion for intelligent people.
This guy isn't saying that there's no god,
but he's also not listening to some guy
half naked dancing around a fucking fire
with a chicken foot. You know what I
mean? So I think that's what I think.
I think science is religion
for intelligent people.
And I think religion and a lot
of ways is science for morons.
Whenever they can't explain something,
they invent stories of people having,
you know, all you can eat fish coming out
of a wicker basket or fucking, you know,
you got to have faith. You've got to have
faith. It's a fucking cop out. You know,
if you went to go buy a fucking car
and you go, all right, let me look,
the car wouldn't start up.
Don't worry. Don't worry.
One of these days that engine's coming
back and it's going to be mad and it's
going to be judging you.
It's ridiculous. You know,
Jesus, I don't want to get off on this
fucking rant, but definitely check it out,
man. If you want to read some cool stuff,
it's called scientific American. And uh,
I dunno, I'm kind of on this mission.
I'm, I'm sick of being a moron,
so it could be in, you know, I'm sick
of being fucking stupid. I really am.
Um, so anyways, let's get to, uh,
let's get to underrated overrated.
Um,
what are we 38 minutes and look at me.
I've really could fucking run my
mouth when I want to before I get into
underrated.
Overrated.
I gotta read this one and I'm going to
need some help from you guys on this.
Um, listen to this one. Uh,
this is from some dude. Uh,
I believe he's in Italy and he said,
um,
I kill women's Libidos for a living.
All right, here we go. Fucking strap
yourselves in for this one. Hey, Bill.
I just got out of my second of my
two longterm relationships, um,
three plus years, both of which
eerily started and ended the same.
Uh,
both of these girls were well above
average in their sexual enlightenment when
we started dating.
I'm not saying they were super freaky,
but the kind of girls that have a porno
collection that can rival most guys and
the toys to match.
Also the kind of girls that while you're
home visiting your parents for the
holidays,
we'll want to sneak away from the dinner
table and fucking in the bathroom.
[inaudible] okay. Anyways, um,
it seems that the standards
for most of these relations,
the standard for most relationship is
that you fuck like rabbits during the
first year. If you manage to
make it past the one year mark,
there is an exponential decay in the
pussy rationing until you get married or
have kids at which time you're pretty
much done with the sex except for
birthdays in the anniversary.
However, the section,
these two relationships kept going
strong through the second year,
at which point it completely dropped
off. And I'm not just, I don't,
I'm not kidding,
I'm talking just done.
I had to pull out every trick in the book
just to get his sympathy fucking once
every couple of weeks.
Um,
I'm in a committed relationship
and love these girls.
I guess you were in a committed
relationship and you love these girls.
So I guess she didn't fuck
around. All right. Um,
and love these girls enough to put up
with the bullshit with the idea that we'll
be able to work through the issue and
get back on track. However, as I learned,
once the pussy is boarded up,
it's out of business for good.
It's like those fucking horrific strip
malls that have been abandoned since the
80s when whatever shit,
boom economy in the area made those
fucking people think they were going to go
somewhere. So inevitably when these
relationships and I end up, uh,
I get red,
my,
my fucking straight a report card on how
much I'm such a great guy and I'm loved
so much and they don't want to
lose me as a part of their lives,
but they're just not sexually
attracted to me anymore.
And that is the fucking and that, that,
and this is the best fucking part.
They don't know why.
They don't know why then not sexually
attracted to me anymore and really wish
they could change it seriously.
What the fuck no man
wants to admit to himself,
let alone an audience that
he's not getting alone.
They, he's not getting that.
He's not getting it done
between the sheets. However,
I can honestly say that I do. All
right. I'm no fucking Ron Jeremy,
but I get the job done.
I would understand the plight of these
woman if I was a Ferb blasting them.
I don't know what that means.
What does that mean?
Just jumping on them like an 18 year old
pounding away or wanting to do the same
shit over and over again.
But I usually make a pretty good damn
effort to make sure things stay fun in the
bedroom. All right. Okay. Last
two fucking paragraphs. Uh,
let me just, let me just a paraphrase
is he basically says that he's like, uh,
William h Macy's character in the cooler.
Um,
and he's saying that he's getting really
bitter and he wants to go out right now
and go meet a woman,
fuck the shit out of her for three months
and then give her the same speech that
just happened to him. Um, all right. Okay.
First of all,
don't do that.
Don't deliberately go out and hurt
somebody because you dated two people who
hurt you. That's just, it's,
it's bad. They don't deserve
it. They didn't hurt you.
So don't do that. All right. Um, I,
I don't know what I mean.
Yeah.
I'd have to have more details
of what the fuck's going on,
but I will tell you this from,
I know a lot of people,
they get into a relationship with
somebody and it doesn't go right.
They find out that it's not
what they're looking for.
And then they go out and then
they immediately basically
start dating the same
person again. It's not literally
the same person, but it's basically,
you know, like, just to make it simple,
if a woman went out and was Dayton,
met some guy at a fucking truck stop
and he turns out to be an asshole.
He's driving a truck, fucking a bunch of
other women around the country. She goes,
I'll never fucking get with a
piece of shit like that again.
And where does she go? She goes
right back down to the truck stop,
which is the same gene
pool of fucking people.
And I think it's very interesting that
you met two girls who seemed like they
were the exact same right down to when
they want it to stop fucking you and I
gotta admit,
okay,
I guess a woman having a porn collection
is healthy on some level, but that,
you know, I don't know as far as I
could girl you're going to marry.
It's like you want your girl,
it's that fine line.
You want them to fuck your brains out,
but do you really want to bang,
have them want to fuck you in your
parents house? I mean, I dunno dude.
I mean, I, I what I, what
I would guess is I would,
I would start fishing in a different lake.
It sounds to me like you're a
fucking goddamn trout. Again.
Can't fucking believe it. You
know, go out in the ocean,
you'll catch something else.
You know what I'm saying?
I think he got the same person
again. I mean, but I mean,
I would literally have to fucking be
knowing what you're doing in the bedroom,
which I don't want to know.
Um,
well what about you?
Do you start taking,
I guess you said you don't take her off
cause that's another thing that happens
in relationships. You know,
there's like, you know,
big thing with women is
they like kissing and uh,
guys are very focused on the,
on, on the finish line, the goal.
So you know, you're getting
that relationship like we
haven't had sex in a while.
You want to have sex when
you start getting in that
fucking thing it, you know,
and you just start scheduling it.
I how does your day look?
Maybe around four. Okay.
Okay. We will fuck at four,
you know, and you know, you're not even
self conscious so there's no excitement.
You just fucking take your clothes off.
Like you're getting strip searched on
your way to serving time at fucking, uh,
some penitentiary.
Penitentiary,
p e n I t and t I a r y penitentiary.
Sorry.
It's one of the words I learned this
week and I was trying to remember Rikers
island and I couldn't at that point. So
do it. I don't know what to tell you.
The bottom line. I don't give a fuck
who you are. How I'm in love you.
I was somebody after a while,
you're going to get sick of fucking him.
That's what happens.
Um,
I dunno,
I dunno what's going on.
I don't know if you have some sort of
like delayed halitosis where for the two
years you have wonderful breath and
then all of a sudden it's unbearable.
I'm just fucking with you. I want to
give you a complex, but I'm just saying,
I don't know what I would try to,
to meet girls in a different place.
I would start with that.
And um,
I dunno. I Dunno dude. This one
is beyond me. I've never, uh,
I mean,
part of me wants to say you'd be,
you're being a little too hard on
yourself here. Uh, but whatever,
go out there and, uh, you know, I'll go
bank some fucking women. Yes. Single,
go out there banks and
fuck a woman and is always,
always talk to women that you think
errata eleague always do that shit.
The worst thing they can do is say no,
but one of them is going to fucking say
yes and that'll give you more confidence
and you'll keep moving up the draft board.
Next thing you know,
you polling pussy out of the first
round rather than drafting like you're
fucking won the Superbowl last year.
You know, having that 28th pick,
praying that the female version of
fucking Dan Marino still around.
That didn't make sense. But you
know what I'm saying? Um, anyways,
am I almost done here?
46 minutes in 46 minutes into the podcast.
Let's wrap this shit up here. People with
a little bit of underrated overrated.
Shall we underrated a bill.
Last week you got an email
from a fan that recounted eh,
his sister's Wiccan wedding.
Personally,
I think the ritual was that
was discussed in the wedding.
His fucking mind numbingly insane,
but part of me has to give it up to the
couple that got married. I'll, sorry.
Underrated is a having balls.
Um, they knew their ritual would,
would not be well received, but they
did not give a fuck. It was their day,
and they had the conviction
to do what they wanted,
even knowing that their family and guests
would not warmly received the whole
jibberish chanting and
bloodletting. Okay. So there you go.
Having the balls to fucking annoyed
everyone in your family. Um,
and other quick thing, here's some
people are traveling to Boston.
They know that I grew up there and I also
fucking travel around the country and
this guy said, hey bill, I'm going there
with my wife. She used to, she, um,
she used to live there, but I would also,
uh, you know, so she knows where to go.
I'd like to know,
you know,
have you tell me where to fuck the
gum paraphrasing obviously. Um,
I haven't lived there
since 1995 dudes. So, um,
I'm going to try to tell you to go to
some of my favorite places from a back in
the day.
I would start,
go to [inaudible] liquors on route
one in saga right before, you know,
get a good six pack and you maybe
some Michelob and then go up to the,
uh, go up to the cow alone.
Get some fucking Chinese food.
And of course another great
liquor store out in, uh,
out in the Boston areas out in Brockton,
Massachusetts.
Go to Blanchard's liquor store.
I'll buy the West Gate Mall.
You might want to check if that's still
there, but I know the bowling alley is,
that's a great place.
You know,
go out there and put on some flock of
seagulls and try to talk to some chick
with way too much.
Uh,
who drew a triangle of
pink on both of her cheeks?
I'm just fucking with you. The
penalty. Go to a Bruins game.
Go and stop by the penalty box. That's
a good bar. It's really alcohol based.
Stay away from the freedom trail.
Okay. Stay away from the freedom trail.
I don't know about you guys, but there's
nothing more boring to me anyways.
Then the revolutionary war. It
is mind numbingly boring. Uh,
with the old weaponry.
It's like, you know,
it's like the original Atari after you
saw this playstation shit we've been
doing for the last, you know, 50
years. So, oh, you hear that shit?
Did she sing it again?
Wait a second. Wait for it.
Not The fucking game.
The violin.
Can you hear it?
Probably can't fucking hear.
No,
I
blah blah, blah, blah. All right. Um, oh,
when somebody sent me something,
and this is the last thing
I'll tell you guys before I'll,
I'll tell you all to have a good
fucking week as I always do.
Trying to add on a nice
positive note. Uh, hey,
let me hit refresh here just to see who
won this food's one in this fucking game.
Come on, refresh Jesus Christ.
He isn't it unbelievable how quickly
you fucking computer gets old.
It's like cool for the first fucking
week and then you download a couple of
things and then it's like,
you know,
it's like Brad Pitt at the beginning of
that movie where he played the old baby.
Anybody see that movie?
I don't think I've ever laughed so fucking
hard in my life when that guy came in
and he was trying to get some pussy
and he hears and he looks down,
there was that little old baby.
You want to talk about killing a
fucking a woman's, a guy's libido.
The fuck is going on with my computer.
I didn't have the thing.
I actually have dial up right now.
You can believe it.
That's probably another one of the
problems are right. Here we go. Come on.
Come on. You fucking cunts.
Two to one. Pittsburg,
eight oh four left. I like it
though. I forget the name of the guy,
but we have a new defense man.
Maybe that'll help us to make up for
the fact that we don't have Phil Kessel
anymore even though for some reason a
lot of people don't like him. So anyways,
this guy sent me this last thing.
I'll read you guys.
This guy sent me something about a,
you know I was talking about when you
going to go buy things and people ask for
your phone number and all this fucking
information and it fucking creeps me out.
Every time they do that,
I just think that they should play in
the beginning of that iron main song,
the prisoner,
he remembered that from the eighties
do you remember how that thing went?
You remember this
then new number two was number one.
You are number six most cycle laugh ever.
Can you imagine if your fucking dad,
you would laugh at you like
that back in the day. Be like,
son, how many beers did you have the
night? You're just like, I just had to
all right, he just fucking Dallas in the
light start and it's going to be over.
So anyways, this fucking guy. Does that
make any sense by the way? I don't know.
I'm fucking sitting here
with one microphone.
No headphones in a fucking hotel
room. This is what you get. All right,
so this guy and said,
Bill,
can you believe how much
fucking information people
are willing to give away for
no to strangers for no reason.
He goes,
I got my haircut the other day and
the first thing they say to me before,
hello or what can I do for you is the
first thing out of the gate is what's your
phone number? So I say, why do you
need my phone number? She says,
so we know who you are when you come in.
Which is bullshit because they
don't know you when you come in.
They still have to ask what
your goddamn number is.
C got to love someone who actually fucking
uses their brain. So anyway, she goes,
he says,
I don't want to give you my number.
So then she scarfs in his face and says,
we don't stand the
information out to anyone.
It's just to keep track of
you here. That's it. Um,
and then she says, uh, then
okay, then the guy says,
he the Guy Rick wrote
this really badly here.
So then I guess he responds to that
doesn't make me feel any better.
You don't need my phone
number to cut my hair.
Then there's slag does this fine,
whatever that sounded exactly like your
exaggerated impression of a dumb broad.
Then she goes, how about your
address too? This is fucking,
you know what all these corporations are
sharing this information to figure out
exactly what you buy when you buy it,
what you liked the best.
So they can just fucking, I
don't know what, you know,
Jack, the prices of the
shit up. So anyways, um, she
goes, how about your address?
And the guy goes, what are you going to
do? Drop the haircut off at my house.
Just cut my fucking,
ah,
now there's three people in line behind
me in this worthless tub of come.
Jesus leans around me and says, and
says, I guess to the people behind them.
Sorry. This takes longer when they,
then he writes, they, you know,
don't give any information and
then he says sarcastically. Oh,
I see.
I'm the one compliment a complicating
this transaction and it's not even her
fault. It's her. Oh, and
it's not even her fault.
It's her corporate creep bosses and all
the fucking sheep that let people do
whatever they want. Sorry,
this is so long. Well,
you should apologize to my listeners
because they had to listen to me read it.
Yeah, man. Don't give those
people your fucking phone numbers.
Don't give him your address. I do that.
Can we get your phone number? I had. No,
you can't. We're not going to do anything
with it. That's fine. That's fine.
I know you're not going
to do anything with it.
I don't want you to have my phone number.
We need to call me up and see
how my fucking haircuts going.
Is it still short and you
think you need an adjustment?
Did I tell you that story?
But when I went into cvs and that guy who,
look what the peewee Herman Haircut, there
was two, two foreigners in front of me,
they barely spoke English and they,
he asked if they want to one of those
savy saved cards and they said no.
And he goes, that's all right, I'll
just scan one anyways. And he scans it.
So I walk up and I'm ready for this guy.
He goes,
do you have our little savy safe car? And
I say, no, I don't. And he goes, well,
I'll just scan it anyways. And I
got, no, I don't want you doing.
And then he scanned it and I said, I said,
excuse me, what did I just say to you?
I just said, I don't want that. And you
scan it anyways. Why did you just do that?
And he goes, it's all right. I want
scan it, I'll scan it. And I go, what?
What do you get? Like half a cent for
every person that you get. You know that,
that, that you get on the fucking list
there and he goes, no, I don't. It's like,
really? Is that why he can't
make eye contact with me?
You fucking piece of shit.
He probably didn't even unscattered
the Goddamn thing, you know?
I don't understand people that help
out corporations. I just don't,
have they done anything to demonstrate
that they give a flying fuck about you or
the drinking water in your town?
Don't help those cons. I mean,
you can if you want to, but
that's just, I would just,
I think it would be a better world if
these fucking pricks didn't know every
goddamn thing about you.
You know?
Pretty soon you're going to walk in there
and they're going to fucking asked if
you can put a did it.
They can just bug you like gene
Hackman in the conversation. Right.
All right dude, I don't know what the
fuck I'm talking about. You know what?
I'm going to go down and Melissa,
this lady singer songs,
so I don't have to think there's
a nice little crowd down there.
Has got to be at least
26 people down there,
which I think in downtown San
Jose actually constitutes a mob.
Maybe somebody will get tased and shot
in the abdomen. I don't know what.
All right, that's the podcast
for this week. Thank you
guys so much for listening.
I am currently revamping my website and
I hope that everything's going to be up
to speed. I recently went over
10,000 people on my mailing list,
so I'm really excited about that. And,
uh, if you want to know what's going on,
you know, especially
like, you see, you know,
when I switched over to a lipsin with
the podcast and all that fucking shit,
if you were out of the loop, it's
because you weren't on my mailing list.
I'm not sure. You know how funny
is this? How funny is this? Uh,
how fucking hypocritical and Mike,
I just said,
don't give you phone number out to these
Hans. And now here I am asking for
your web address. I wrote 20 people.
All right,
I'll stop.
[inaudible]
[inaudible].