Okay.
Hey, what's going on? It's Bill Burr and
it's time for the Thursday afternoon?
Just before Friday. Monday
morning podcast and ahhh
just checking. Yeah,
just checking in on you. I'm
just checking in on your, hello.
This is Susan Blue's team calling. Um,
that's a character I see. We still
call up a buddy of mine all the time.
They pretend to be as casting director
and I would just call them up with the
worst fucking auditions. Every, hello?
This is Susan Bloomstein calling.
I have an audition for
you with flora feature.
Okay.
Do you have a problem with being naked
around other men in positions that
involves you staring at your
ankles? If you have a prob, if not,
give me a cool stupid shit like
that. It was always like, you know,
something that I guess would be considered
homophobic as instead of just being
funny, you know?
Is it homophobic to suggest that he would
be uncomfortable staring at his ankle?
Ankles, I should say.
Yeah,
and the company of other men.
I don't know what's going on.
How was your Thursday? Did you get paid
today? Huh? Did they write some numbers?
On a piece of paper and then you stuck
it in a machine and somehow you can get
waffles. Okay.
Yeah, man.
All the money's in the air now.
I don't know where it is. Yeah,
no safe to say either. Some white
dude has all of it. Russian dude,
which his guest is a white dude, but
white dude means American dude, right?
Or English, right? Russian
dude or Chinese dude.
One of them's got it. Maybe somebody
in Singapore. He has all the money,
Japanese guy. And of course you've
got the fucking Saudi princess.
They got something like six
people have it all right now.
And the rest of us just get pieces
of paper with numbers on it.
But as long as we believe in it,
no matter what they say on TV,
no matter how bad they say it's getting,
as long as we just continue
to fucking believe in it,
just keep writing numbers to each
other. Right? Next thing you know,
I got a shirt. You got a
Taco? Everybody's happy.
Susan Blum, Steen colleague. Um, anyways,
uh, so here's what's going on with
me last night. Me and the lovely Nia.
My beautiful lady,
we went down and saw a ag pop.
He has a new album out the post pop
depression and I'm basically like 90% of
Queens of the stone age.
Who was backing him up? Uh,
John Theatre was not on drums,
um, but it was pretty much,
I think the rest of the band and Iggy
pop out model was fucking amazing show.
I'd lucked into these tickets.
I was doing a comedy show.
I ran into somebody that
works for the band. They said,
we've got a couple extra
tickets. Do you want to go?
My freckle stood up at
attention and of course I went,
I went down there and God damn it, what
an amazing show. Silverman opened up,
she fucking crushed it.
And I'm Maggie Pot man.
There's a bucket list
right there. Bucket list.
Wanted to go see the guy
fucking comes out there, right?
He's got it on a sports coat with no
shirt underneath that. He's 68 years old.
All right. After one song,
the code is gone and he's
prance around with no shirt on.
68 years old.
It was some fucking shit guy. Just
doesn't give a fuck. I'm gonna fuck,
I'm going to post a picture of
the guy. You know what I mean?
He's still in great shape, you know? Sure.
There's a little less this city issues
here or there with the skin, but I mean,
other than that, the guy looks like he
can do more pushups than I could ever do.
I hope I look that good
at his age. You know,
when he's still got that beautiful
Marsha Brady fucking haircut.
Gorgeous hair. Oh God. I was jealous. Um,
anyways, the band absolutely
fucking smashed it.
He was all over the stage. Um, it was,
it was fucking incredible,
man. It was just,
it just an absolutely amazing night.
And then me and Nia finished it off
as much as I'm trying to get in shape.
One of the great things to do out here
in Los Angeles is to hit your favorite
fucking Taco truck or
late night taco spot. Um,
it's just the best. And there was one a,
I got a buddy of mine cut another comedian
for shot who's like a connoisseur of
all the taco trucks.
I was basically a guy,
I went down just east of the
fucking one west of the one 10,
um, you know, and like Beverly Boulevard,
what do you got? And He fucking,
he gave me like three taco trucks,
like Google mapped all the way back to
my house and we ended up stopping off at
one and a, Oh fuck. I didn't
get any Tacos, actually.
Got a God damn case of DHEA,
which is the classic default
White Guy Order at a taco truck.
You know. Can I get a chicken
case today? Can I get one away?
I'll be technically that you said even
Mexican is she has changed with chicken.
Hell, we do that. Um, it was
just a, a, a, a great night.
And um, another night where
I didn't smoke a cigar.
I haven't smoked a cigar since
February 16th. And uh, you know,
you have a problem with something when
you know the exact date, you know of,
uh, when you stopped doing
it, you know other shit.
If you just don't give a fuck, you just
like, you want to go to McDonald's?
Yeah, no. When's the last
time you ate there? Oh,
I don't know man. I spent
a while. We'll get year.
That's when you don't have a
price. That's, that's when,
if there was an issue of addiction,
it's just completely out
of your fucking life.
But I know the exact date was
February 16th. I know where I was.
I know what I smoked and I know
what I felt like when I had it.
And I've been thinking about
it every fucking day and I'm,
I'm trying to go on a little
bit of a run here. Cause if, uh,
I don't cut the shit out of my life this
summer, I will be a four years smoker.
Like what the fuck?
What am I doing? Um, so,
but I've been holding fast with
these uh, fast are holding strong,
whatever the fucking expression is.
I only have two a month. Alright.
I two in January,
two and a half in February
because I started smoking
when it wasn't lit well and
I've got another one, so I have one and
a half that nice. That's not bad. Right?
Come on. You guys aren't doctors
generally speaking? I should be all right.
My Body can handle that. Two and a have
fucking days. I mean two and a half,
two a month. Once every 14 days.
I still fucking stupid. Maybe
I'll just go down to one a month.
I want to be special occasion guy. I
figure I'll smoke one at the rose bowl.
Smoke one super bowl Sunday my birthday.
Uh,
what else you got flagged day then.
I don't give a fuck about that.
It's a bunch of Jewish
holidays in September.
I am in show business as a nod to
them. That'd be really selfish.
Like I give a shit, right? Like
I give a shit about, you know,
like I'm actually acknowledging
another religions. Real reasons I was,
I'm just looking for an
excuse to smoke a cigar tall.
My Jewish brothers and sisters
out there and a sign of support.
What are you going to deal, Bill? Huh?
Make a donation to the
museum of tolerance. No,
I am going to smoke a Cuban cigar
and honor to all of your wonderful
contributions to comedy in show business.
Okay.
Like for a year, that
would be perfect. Right?
There's not a fucking doctor on
the planet. They always got it.
They always get it. That job
is just a rain on your parade.
I saw if I went in and say, doc, look,
I smoked for a year. Is that bad?
And be a getaway. You know, it's, you
know, it's not bad, but they always go.
Ideally. Yeah.
Ideally I'd live in a fucking bubble and
I would be breathe perfect fucking air
and I would drink clean
water and I have, um,
a microbiotic what the fuck are you
doing doc? You gotta be doing something
going in here, taking
everybody's blood pressure,
all God damn day looking
at fucking skin tags.
You're telling me you
don't have an outlet?
Um,
I dunno. So anyways, having settled
that probably smoke word next week,
but I liked this month, this
month is going good because,
um, you know, I've already
like, you know, my,
the first two months of the year
I really feel like I should,
my hands should be shaking as I'm
talking about, this is so bad.
I want to smoke. I, uh,
I had my first one January 1st and
then January 8th I had the second one.
I was like, fuck,
the month isn't even half over and I
going to white knuckle at the rest of the
way. And then I did it again in February.
I smoked more on like the fifth and then
one on like this I guess the 16th then
I got another two fucking weeks.
So now I feel like I'm ahead of
the game cause it's like the 10th.
If I can just make it to like the 15th,
you know,
then I can actually go on a run and
do one every week for four weeks.
Then white knuckle it through
April. Oh, it just sucks.
How come everything fun
fucking kills you. You know,
just fucking kills you sitting around
Eating Goddamn yogurt by the way.
You know, I figured out what was
causing the train, not the lead,
the fucking station. I became
mobilly Parfait, right.
And I went down to this shoe shop and
they will fucking raving about this.
You know, this all natural
yogurt with coconut in it.
You know all that probiotic has
probiotics in it. This is, you know,
this isn't negative biotics. This is
positive pro. This is proactive biotic.
You have two kinds of bacteria within
your intestinal tract. Shut the fuck up.
I put this stuff in them. I
couldn't, I couldn't shit for days.
I just kept beating it cause they that
down at the juice shack there. Right.
They kept telling me how
healthy it was and a little did.
A little did I know I was
building like a fucking wall.
You know what sets city?
They're in Greece with all,
it's the whole city's just a
bunch of white walls, you know?
That's what I was building in my stomach.
Where are you built? I don't know.
It's the first thing I thought
of. I go fuck yourself. You know,
I'd like to see you not shit for three
days and try to dance around it and keep
it funny. Okay. How did
I get this mood? Um,
then he was, hold on one second. Hold
on. Nancy Reagan died. Everybody,
yeah,
she died and a lot of people were
really upset about that. You know,
she was a great woman. I'll tell
you what made her great. Uh, the,
the shape she kept herself in,
considering her husband had jelly
beans all over the fucking place.
The fact that she could just say
no to those goddamn things, right.
Walking around. There's something
about being that skinny though.
After a while though, it's just
like you live for fucking ever,
but you just get like a bird person.
You know?
Like if she was my, uh, grandmother,
I would have built like a giant bird cage
that are hung from the ceiling I just
made. I'd make it go in there
and perch on it, you know,
I'm not opening the door unless you
tell me. I'm still in the, well Nancy.
All right. I guess I would say
grandma Reagan's Greg and um,
all right, this one, there's been,
this whole podcast has gone off the
fucking rails, so too goddamn distracted.
Him talking about putting dead first
ladies and birdcages. That's not right,
is it? He's such a weird fellow that
Reagan, some people you talked to,
he singlehandedly defeated
the Russians. Reality is,
didn't he come off the fucking bench
and he did. He hit the last three.
You know, he the dagger, he
put the game away. I would say,
you know,
by tricking them into thinking that we
were actually going to have shit up and
outer space to stop this
shit from coming over here.
You know,
that's a weird
thing about trying to bomb somebody from
the other side of the fucking world.
If you're too lazy to fly over, you
got to start. You got to shoot him.
Remember Robert Parishes foul
shot. You remember the rainbow.
That's how you got to do it.
You actually got to send it in
because of the curvature of the earth.
You got to send it fucking up
and over. You know what I mean?
It's like when you're sitting on the
couch and you got a Napkin and you want to
throw it into a barrel, but your
fucking office chair was right there.
You got to go up and over.
You know they do that with missiles.
Somebody actually figured
that out sometimes.
Some super fucking intelligent
scientist guy, right.
As opposed to the really dumb ones that
they put in the nuclear programs. Right.
Bill, this guy had just sit
there and like figure that out.
You know,
out of our airspace ended the
troposphere up into the stratosphere.
Whoever the fuck it goes
right out to outer space.
Reedus the atmosphere without
blowing up right on the White House.
Nothing but president. Right. They're
just sitting there talking shit,
what a fucking job. You know,
and there's some other psycho, you
know, they got cameras in spaces,
some shit or somebody flying around with
that direct TV satellite on the back of
his plane just falling around.
Brezhnev and Gorbachev trying
to figure out where they're at.
So they always have the exact
coordinates. That's what it,
that's the level of stress like
Obama has and all these guys.
That's why they age like 90 years.
Cause they know the other team, right?
They go and Billy Belicheck on a,
you know they got cameras on you,
right on the top of your fucking
head, wherever you go. You know,
I'd be all parent.
I'd be doing fucking head fakes as I
was walking down the hall to the Oval
Office. Right. I wouldn't even
go in the Oval Office saying,
I'm not going in there. I
would have, I'd have a double,
I'd always be down in
the basement, you know.
Then years later after I died, you know,
all my staff would start fucking
coming out talking shit about me.
He's a very fearful man for all
the bravado during his speeches,
he spent the entire eight
years of his presidency in the,
the, well, we're not allowed
to say how far down it goes,
but let's just say there's one hell
of a basement under that house. Um,
do you even think he fucking lives there?
There's no fucking way he lives there.
He just lives there. You ever seen the
White House? It's just right there.
You know, he hasn't lived
there. I bet there's a fucking,
you take an elevator that's just like a,
and when Steve jobs used to make those
fucking speeches at those nerd fest,
right? They go down there, you know,
he come out and he's fucking jeans and
no belt and he just ah, look at Dan
[inaudible] and all the nerds
are like, oh God. Oh God.
I think that's what. Then he just
fucking Lee. Nobody knew where he lived.
Bye Bye.
What is Bill Gates have a
more reclusive fucking house.
Is The house reclusive bill? Does
it, does the house make the choice
to be introverted? Whatever. Yeah,
he has, he has a fucking house.
No one could get to.
I can't get anywhere fucking
near Bill Gates House. Right.
But the White House, you can
walk right up to the gate. Right?
You can come right up to it. Is
this going to put me on a list? Um,
I bet. What's his face? I Bet Bill Gates
has got a fucking, God damn, you know,
remember that stat star wars thing that
Reagan wanted to put up for fucking,
you know the Robert Parish nuclear warhead
rainbow shot from the Kremlin, right?
I bet he's got those for like
drones. I bet he hates drones.
He's all pissed off. How dare you
send my technology back there. Guy.
I think he's an evil motherfucker and
that's why it gives away all that money.
You know what I mean?
It's weird. He's like,
he's like the sociopath with a heart of
gold. He's kind of like Dexter. Right.
But if he was like in the laptop's
rather than just cutting up people,
but it's only the bad people. I was
never able to get past that. Look at you.
God Damn you look good. Really? Yeah.
Yeah. Oh yeah. What do you mean really?
You've got to hitch my wagon to a dog.
Fucking totally superficial. All right.
You look hot and you better keep looking
hard cause I'll tell you right now,
I'll go right down to the used car
lot and I'll start shopping. Oh yeah,
I'll trade gin. I'm not going to
trade you in and about. I don't know.
You're a classic though.
You're one of those those ones that's
going to last for awhile. You know,
I've been treating you well.
Changing the fluids every
3000 miles out is gross.
Disgusting. I'm well
thank you for saying that.
I think I feel like I went out to a show
last night and had some drinks and ate
some late night tacos. Yeah,
she did. It was so much fun.
Did you talk about the
show? Yeah. How about ag?
Put confidence of Biggie pop going out.
This 68 has more swag
than all of you bitches.
Why are you checking the listeners?
I don't know cause it's funny cause
you're hung over and you don't, yeah,
I don't mean to attack the
listeners. I'm just saying. Yeah,
this wacky had out there.
It was the whole band and ag of course
is legendary. That was a great show.
I'm really glad I went. You know,
I wasn't feeling up to it but I'm
glad it's a great name for an album.
200 posts. The Post pop did a post
pop depression. Yeah, very good.
It was awesome.
And the band was all wearing custom
YSL for those of you who are in,
what is that? Designer clothing
YSL. Is he a San Laurel?
He Santa Raul. He's in Laurel. Yeah.
So they were all wearing custom YSL.
Even the roadies, like
the crew was wearing like,
like trousers and ties from
YSL, which is pretty dope.
Like Josh looked great in that suit,
didn't he? Whenever you say trousers,
I think of that Classic Classic Louis
C K joke when he used to talk about
whenever he does. Yeah.
When I would call phone sex,
he'd always get that 70 year old
woman. I'm taking off your trousers.
I think we need to bring Clios
water dish in here. Yeah,
cause she's laying in the sun.
Why don't you go do that cause or grab
another mic if you're going to be on
this. No I'm not. I just came
in today. Say Hi, I'm Jesus.
I have to go to the gym. That was one
of my favorite dumb jokes of all time.
What is it? Gay Horsey. Hey,
I'm sorry. Come on. You gotta admit
that's funny on some level. Um,
all right. So anyways, what
was I talking about? Oh,
I was talking about Bill
Gates Swat in a way.
The fucking drugs and having more
security than a old town there.
Oh, town in the fucking
a maze. Home blown. Yeah.
Polaroid of the sun.
Yeah,
she's done one hike and she's
done. It's already fucking hot out.
He had global warming Nini.
You're looking fucking good.
All right, Baden.
Oh,
go to the gym. Keep it looking
good. That's part of your contract.
Show me shut up. Um, all right.
I fucking hate this whole password
thing. You know, for the, I,
I figured out what the fuck was
wrong with my eye, my iTunes,
which is basically,
I can't listen to anything that I've
downloaded on my fucking laptop because I
have too many other devices that
have already been accepted by iTunes,
so I have to deactivate some other
shit. I finally figured that out.
I didn't figure it out. I just
went on. I went on the Internet.
I basically typed in, uh,
police. Give me the answer.
I went there looking at you to
go right back to the sun. Cleo,
she fucking loves the Sun. Um, all right.
What else did I want to talk about?
All the garage gym is becoming a reality.
It's be coming out
reality. Allie. Allie Audi.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Um, no thanks to fucking rogue fitness.
Jesus Christ. What an arrogant
Goddamn company that is.
I specifically asked that company as a
celebrity in my mind to send me a bunch
of free shit for my garage so that I
could then hype their company to my 40
listeners. And can you believe
this? I hope you're sitting down.
Can you believe they never
got back to me? All right.
Well because I'm fucking
immature. I got to go vengeance.
Now I have to add my vengeance on that
company. This is what I'm going to do.
I am going to buy all
of this shit from them.
That's what I'm going to do. And then
you know what? When they call me and say,
hey, thanks for using it, I'm not
going to take that phone call.
All they getting out of me is the price
they want for their fucking goods.
All right. Does that make any
sense? Yeah. I don't know.
I just throw it out there. They never
get back to me. I was half serious.
I don't like,
I don't like people giving me free shit
cause then they fucking own you on some
level anyways. You know. Hey, you know,
remember that time I gave you a chin up
bar? I mean what the fuck? All right,
I'll give you a ride to the airport.
Fuck you know, you just, you just,
you can't get out of it. You
can't get out of it. So anyways,
I am going to fucking do this thing up.
This is, this is, this is the game plan.
I'm getting that rogue fitness
thing that collapse. It, it,
you can fold back into the wall. I'm
getting a workout bench. You know,
I'm so excited for that cause I'm so
sick of going to the fucking gym and
there's always some, there's
always somebody on it.
I have somebody who's always
benching right. And uh,
I can also do squats and I'll be able
to do pull ups and then I got my atomic
holds and am I gonna put
those above where my truck is?
I'll just have to pull my truck
out, which I know kind of sucks,
but it gives a fuck. I'm going to
have an a poxy floor put in, right?
And then Nia wants an adjustable
speed bag over in the corner,
which is great cause all I'll have
to do is adjust it like twice.
And just like the bicycle I bought
her, she's never going to use it again.
Then I can just lock that
fucker into position. Right.
We'll get into dated a
boarded, a beaded above, right.
We're gonna have to put it in a corner.
I'm worried about the noise, you know,
banging on, you know, blowing out
my ear drums. Forget about that.
Annoying the shit out of my neighbors
because everybody out here lives on top of
one another. So, um,
I figured if I do that and then I'm gonna
have those interlocking rubber things
underneath all the gym area, I'll have
a place where I can skip rope. Right.
I can do my pull ups.
My only thing is I'm getting rid of my
pull up and dip station thing that I have
and I'll be able to do the pull ups
still, but I won't be able to do dips.
So if anybody knows of
an attachment that works.
I was thinking of just having the
handles coming out of the wall.
If they make something like that, which
would look really weird for some reason.
What are the, what is those
fucking Porto glory holes?
It's like the glory hole of fucking,
it's like the glory hole of
workout equipment to just
have like the dip fucking
things just coming out of the wall right
now. What have I got? A perverted mind.
What the fuck do you want from me? Uh,
how long into this fucking thing are we?
23 minutes, Michael Jordan. Alright,
here we go. Here we go. Let's, uh,
let's read a little bit of
advertising. All right. Oh fuck.
I didn't talk about self cars.
I got the biggest argument with
fucking forest shot today. Oh,
we will go and we never get an
arguments. We would just fucking eat it.
He's like a scientist and I'm a dope,
so that's just fucking right there.
That's just a recipe
for, to go off the rails.
I brought up forest
before and if you're, um,
okay.
Um, I think he's a Ted. He's
going to be in Nashville soon.
I'm sure he has a website.
He, uh, he actually,
he opens for Jim Jeffries all the
time. Um, he's fucking hilarious.
Like I would go hiking with somebody
who wasn't funny. You know what I mean?
It's bad enough when you get to work
with a comic that isn't that funny.
But if you're going to walk next to
him for like an hour and a half though,
I'll tell you that's a rough
one. You know. All right.
Tracker or track are smart cars,
smart phones, smart homes.
Technology has made everything smart.
Abstract too, you know.
No, I like everybody says
okay.
Freddo all right.
But losing your stuff still makes
Matt feeble feel fucking stupid.
Tracker
makes losing things a thing of the
past tracker is a coin size device that
locates misplaced keys,
wallets, bags, computers,
anything in seconds. Just pair
tracker to your smartphone.
Attach it to anything. Put it on
your Dick. Where are my balls?
Right next to mine.
Yay. Thank you. Tracker. Yeah.
Um, you can find you get it. You get
what the fuck it is? Lose your phone.
Press a button. Can't
find your nuts there.
They are a with over 1.5 I hate
when they overexplain that thick.
It's like I get it. I got it.
The first two sentences with over 1.5
million devices tracker has the largest
crowd gps network in the world,
so your last item shows up on
a map. Even if it's miles away,
never lose anything. Again with tracker,
just think if tracker was on everything,
no one would steal anything
anymore. Yes, they would.
They'd figure out how to go around.
Okay.
Whatever. Listeners to the show,
get a special discount of 40%
off your first tracker device.
Go to the tracker.com go to the
tracker.com and enter Promo Code burpee.
You are are the hardest thing you'll
ever have to find is their website.
Oh yeah. What about love?
Can you put this on?
They're going to do that in that stupid
dating site with that stupid piano
[inaudible] the Doodoo and that Chicco
[inaudible]
the fucking bitch.
The one who makes me [inaudible]
sandwich. Yeah. Ooh,
that's the longer version. They
never show that one. All right,
go to tracker.com right now and at the
Promo Code Burger for 40% off. Again,
that's tracker.com Promo Code Burn.
I use brain when you got
technology, self-driving
fucking cars. Okay.
Self driving cars is so fucking stupid.
One of the great things about cars is
the amount of people that they kill every
year, which is great for the environment.
And then you can have these
fucking robots and it was, Ooh,
it's going to be great. I could stare
at my smartphone as I drive to work.
[inaudible]
gimme think all these fucking now
what are these robots? You know,
just decide one day that they're sick
of being the Goddamn Limo driver and
driving us around and they
kind of share a look, you know,
at a red light.
And that starts a revolution just like
in the Ukraine where it just took a
couple of jerk offs on Facebook. And
next thing you know, all Putin is going,
you know what? Maybe we need to
Robert Parish a little closer,
do a little fucking lay
up. Alright, trunk club,
everybody. If you're
anything like me, honey,
then you know exactly what you like and
how it is nap to the 12 down to the six
bitches, except when
you're in the wine aisle.
I thought that just said trannies probably
cause I was doing that fucking hacky
gay accent. Tannins and
terrors mean nothing to you.
It means nothing to me. I don't even
know what they are. Types of wine,
I'm guessing unless you
happen to be a fancy pants.
Professional sommeliers.
Okay.
I hate when people just make somebody
like your fancy pants because you
understand something that
takes a little bit of brains.
I respect anybody that understands why
and I like those people. They look at it,
they swirl it around, they shoved their
fucking honker in there, you know,
put it in their mouth.
They lived swirl around.
Let the different flavors hit
him. You know, tasting the barrel,
tasting history. They let it go down
there. Suffocates it hit stick. Good.
Okay.
They live across the debt
woman half their age,
the pointed something flashy and they
slip it roofie in her drink. Right.
They finished the pudding
commercial. Sorry. All right.
Okay. Where am I? Here? Okay.
Please include all the falling
points during your read.
I'll do as many as I can. How about that?
Well, with club Debbie Club, Debbie,
a self driving cars set for me. I'm
special. The guessing game is over club.
Debbie, don't vote. No, don't
vote for JB already voted for me.
And it's enough bushes. It's the
world's only personalized wine club.
And your wines are sent directly
to your door. Not only just club.
Debbie clipped Debbie and wish don
was down in Rome cell. Where's d? Ron?
That's why I come. Give everyone
nicknames. Send you wine.
They send you wine that you will love
drinking. That's because club Daddy,
I can speak Spanish. Easy. Six
question quiz figures out your pallets.
Uh, so that, so that every body,
that bottle you get your
fucking like Jesus Christ club.
Debbie got a ranch is re is leading
the grape to glass wine revolution.
They worked directly with the
vineyards to cut out the middlemen,
which saves you money. Oh yeah,
you're gonna pay those
immigrant workers anymore money.
Then you're going to send some
of that savings. They're away.
Maybe they can get a new
fucking hat club. Debbie,
him buying a plane on an aquifer even
offers you a no risk guarantee that you
will love what they send
you or your money back.
And Right now club w in weapons of mass
destruction is offering my listeners 50%
off your first order. And when you go
to club Debbie, a war president club
w.com/burr wine. A wine should
be fun. Not Pretentious. Why?
Why does it have to take
all the fucking class?
So I think it should be a classy goddamn
thing and I think he should take the
time to learn about it.
If you want to get into it rather than
go fucking figure it all out for me.
Why don't you use club Debbie? I
was safe during my watch, right?
Why can't you use this
thing to educate yourself?
Why does it have to all be about taking
your hands off the fucking wheel and
letting some robot pick it out
for you? Oh my tree stump. Why?
It should be fun. Not Pretentious.
Evidently start learning as you drink.
I guess they're saying learning is you
start drinking club.com/ [inaudible]
you'll even get 50% off your
first order. Think about that.
Turn your teeth gray
for 50% off. That's club
dabi.com/burn all right, one more.
Can you guys sit through this one
more fucking reading here? Legal Zoom.
To run a successful business, you need
to make the most of your time and money.
Good News.
Legals can help you save both during
national small business month.
I fucked that up, but I
have the right voice, right?
Legal Zoom as the smart
way to start your business.
Right now when you
incorporate or form an LLC,
you could also save money on some
of the basics to get up and running.
That didn't seem like
that made sense to me.
Like a three month trial on quickbooks
online accounting software and a domain
name for a year through web.com both at
no chach after your business is set up,
legal zoom can can help with a lot more.
Reviewing content contracts and dealing
with day to day legal hurdles takes time
away from growing your business.
That's what legal zooms
business legal plan is for.
You get legal advice for your business
from independent attorneys licensed in 48
states. Oh, the lower 48 or you,
including Alaska and Hawaii and
maybe not Wyoming and Michigan.
Who knows? You can also get access
to NDAs, lease agreements, and more.
The best part is you won't
get charged by the hour.
Since legalzoom isn't a law farm,
instead you pay for low a low monthly
fee fee. Jesus Christ. How long is this?
Save Time and money starting and running
your business during national small
business month@legalzoom.com today.
Don't forget to enter Burr and
the referral box at checkout.
That's legalzoom.com
legalzoom.com all right,
there you go. Um, hey.
Did anybody see that fucking hilarious.
Twitter back and forth between
Kanye West in a, a dead mouse,
a dead mouse, whoever the fuck
he says, name I guess card.
You took a screenshot and in the
fucking screenshot allegedly there was
something up there that
showed some website where he
was pirating the software.
That fucking DJ guy. So,
Huh?
Oh fuck. I gotta pause this and it
says we might have a leak somewhere.
Yeah. Jeez Dan, that not too
bad. Just a little fucking leak.
The jade trap downstairs.
Yeah. Never fucking ends. Um, anyways,
so Kanye took a screenshot
and I guess his dead mouse.
Dead Mouse Demo five. How the
fuck he say his name? I'm old.
I should know how to say it. Um,
I guess he made this software
that helps you make an album.
And evidently Kanye allegedly had a
website open where you could illegally
downloaded. So he called him out. He goes,
you're not making enough money
to pay for this software.
You gotta fucking pirate my shit.
And he just wrote Dick on it.
So Kanye comes back with the barrage of
Shit just trashing this DJ talking about
his mouse head. They got a fan in
there. Mike, I'm bring my daughter.
She's a big fan of Minnie mouse, blah
blah, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
Just like, just like a
corporation, you know, just,
just sending reams of paper
over, like on better call Saul,
trying to fucking delay
it. But nowhere in it did.
The man denied that he didn't fall.
They fucking didn't steal it as far as
I could tell. He just, he just, to me,
he immediately capitulation
just immediately switched
it from you stole my shit
to Da, which with your
fucking mouse head. Right.
Okay.
I actually wanted to fucking jump into
the middle of it to give the DJ help
because he kind of was fucking
taken the bait. It was just,
it's like what a check
does. You know what I mean?
They're so fucking good at
arguing that they fucking,
they spin you off like you got them
dead to rights and by the time you come
through the whole thing you're like, I
had a fuck did I lose that? Cause they,
they got, you never reacted that shit.
He should've just laid back, you know,
on the ropes. Let Kanye Punch himself out
and then just say yes. So like I said,
you stole my shit, you know,
and how's it go with the mouse head going
to take shifts from so many who wear a
leather miniskirt throughout
a whole fucking tour. I mean,
there was so much shit
he could've said back,
but he should have stayed in
the pocket. I was just like,
I was watching that the way I was
watching like a comedian and a Heckler,
you know? Then I was reading, I was
rooting for the, I was rooting for the DJ.
There's room for the DJ in that
one, provided if that the guy stole.
If he didn't, either way it was
fucking entertaining, you know,
nice Twitter battle then. Nice.
Is it funny how I'm not into robots
driving cars, but I like a, I like,
I like it. I like a good Twitter
back and forth. You know,
that's the Thursday afternoon, just
before Friday, Monday morning podcast.
I'm, you come some music once again.
We always post at the MM podcast.
A Twitter feed will always tell you
what the music is. Andrew always posted.
I don't know what it is. I
am an old man. I am just,
I am just now trying to update, um,
my music. Oh my God. I gotta tell you
what I was doing the other day. Holy Shit.
I was listening to a, I
downloaded all this shit, right?
Alabama shakes. Fucking love the new one.
That album that they have was to shit.
The weekend. I'll listen to
that. Actually liked that shit.
I got to tell you what was
funny though was Ah, fuck.
I already forgot his name.
Kendrick Lamar. I'm so fucking old.
Help me out here guys. I,
I don't know anything that's going on
with any of these people. Kendrick Lamar,
I'm sitting there, I have to admit,
I did have this old guy thought and
I was embarrassed that I had it.
I was listening to his album and I get
to this song and he just keeps going.
This dick ain't free. Right. And I'm just,
and all I could just kept
thinking was this one a grammy.
And I'm not saying it didn't deserve it,
but I don't know what
the people look like,
who fucking vote for the grammys.
But the way people complain about it and
now they're always giving it to white
people. Right. Like the Oscars,
I'm imagining it's a bunch of
white people in 50s and 60s right.
It takes a while.
I would think to establish yourself
enough to even be considered, you know,
to be on that shit.
And I'm just picturing all these fucking
50 and 60 year old white people just
sitting there and listening to
these dick ain't free. Right.
And they go like, you know, like they
can relate to that on some level going,
I had this like connects with me, I'm
going to vote with this. You know,
they probably just drive down the hood
and stand there for 20 minutes and count
how many times somebody drives by d eight,
three driving by and they are right.
There's enough people listened to it.
We've got to give it to
them. Um, so anyways,
but it is the embarrassing thing I
was in, I was, I listened to too.
I got to make sure I say his name
right. It's Ed. Is it Sheehan?
Uh, for fuck sakes belts. You don't
know any, I did call him with this guy.
He was fucking great. I think he's
great. I just don't fuck it. Sharon.
Sharon will go share it. And
I was listening to his album
and I was this, I was
listening to that song. One,
I was listening to Ed Sheeran, one in, uh,
in a Toyota Prius and I was sitting
there going, I am enjoying this.
Like what happened to me? I used to
be, I and I used to fucking listen.
I want to happen.
Okay.
But when I really look back at the
shit that I used to think was bad,
as some of it was bad as
stuff, a lot of it, you know,
say which people will say about a
sensitive fellow like this Ed Eddie here,
right. You know, he does dress like a man,
unlike the bands that I listened to in
the 80s where they came up just full on.
Not only did they dress like chicks,
they dress like hot chicks
trying to hang on. They, they,
they were really like the first house,
a real housewives when you look back
at a lot of it, you know what I mean?
Um, I guess still they were still in
their prime in their twenties. Um,
I dunno. So whatever those are the
albums that I was listening to this week.
I literally went from 1970 82,
you know, I went from
like 19, I don't know,
late sixties to late eighties was what
the Fuck I've been listening to for the
last, I don't know how many since I
worked in a fucking warehouse in the 80s.
And then I immediately went
to like 2014, 2015, 2016.
And uh, I, I survived.
I somehow survived and I actually
enjoy the shit so it, um, I dunno,
I dunno if it's going to help me. I
don't know what the point of it is,
but all I know is it's, it's
okay.
I don't know. That's funny to me. This
deck eight free Lao of, of the year.
Um, I'll listen to it
more. I'll try to, I mean,
it's going into some really white ears
here though. It's probably actually a,
uh,
it probably says more about him
as an artist if I don't get it,
you know what I mean? Then if I get it,
he probably doesn't want me to get it.
Like, I don't want some 48 year
old white guy like in my shit.
Um, oh, maybe I'm wrong. The fuck
do I know. Anyways, fuck off.
I'll talk to you on Monday.
[inaudible] [inaudible]
[inaudible]
hey, what's going on? And spelt births
the Monday morning podcasts on Monday,
June 14th, 2010. How the hell
are you? Are you good? Did
you have a good weekend?
Did you, did you go down to that place
with the thing I heard it was nice.
What's it nice? It is
nice. All that's nice.
My son,
he had a recital this weekend
and we were so nervous.
He was all a flustered and more suburban.
Talk about shit that nobody cares about
because frank was in the back with the
garden hose. It froze up over the wedding.
So we have to buy a new
one of those. So you know,
Frank Corsi goes on the Internet and he
just starts researching all about those
holos houses. Okay. All
right. Yeah. I don't know.
Can you imagine just these sitting there
at the end of a culdesac like that is
your fucking reality. Rather
than having a wine cellar,
I would just have a secret room of
fucking porn with Kleenex for me.
The rub one out or just sit there
crying at what became of my life.
I need, can you go out
and fix his bicycle? No.
Why doesn't he go climb a fucking tree?
Yeah.
Jesus Christ. What? What did they
do in the 18 hundreds you want to?
Why the environment so fucked
up? That's it right there buddy.
You just don't want to go out. It'd be
a part of your kids' lives. I don't.
That's why I told you I enjoyed
condoms. I didn't enjoy condoms.
I just didn't want to bust one in
you without one on and now I did.
And now look at it. Look at my face
sweetheart. Can't you see the misery?
Fuck them.
Well, he half looks like, Yo, you go
fix this fucking bike. I'm not yelling.
I'm no, I'm not
[inaudible]
first testicle.
[inaudible] somewhat tunic and
dangle master the forest with the
[inaudible]. I can show you the trade
case files to these guys, to his cohorts,
asleep in the chair.
[inaudible]
twice. Don't take shit from
anybody. Question Mark, Bill.
Sometimes you end your podcast with go
fuck yourselves and don't take shit from
anyone. Well, let me tell you
my story. Back in November,
a cop pulled me over, roughed me up,
was a huge asshole and wrote up
every rinky dinky ticket he could.
Okay, now wait a minute. What happened?
You were just driving down the street
and this guy just pulled you over.
I need a little bit of the backstory.
Here was this guy, did you know,
did he get into a big fight with his wife
and then took it out on you or we did
you say something wise to the
guy and he said, all right,
I'm not in the fucking mood anyways,
let's see if we can figure it out here.
At the end of the
altercation, I shook his hand,
look him straight in the eyes
and gave him that look that says,
I will see you in court, asshole.
I showed up in court this
Monday to defend myself.
My plan was to stand before that asshole
and having him explain his actions to
me in a court of law. And Dude,
this ain't gonna workout unless she
had a witness. I wanted to ask him.
Even then, that doesn't work out.
I wanted to ask them if twisting my arm
so much that I couldn't use it for a few
days was justified. I wanted to ask
him why he decided that me five,
six 175 pounds was a threat to him.
Six foot to six foot three 250
that he need to hit me from behind.
Um, don't call me an Asshole, but
I'm not 100% by in this story.
Cause you didn't say what
happened before this.
This guy just did this. Is this guy
like the fucking worst cop ever?
I don't know. Here we go. I wanted to,
I wanted to know why he needed to demean
me while I was handcuffed in the back
of the patty wagon.
I then wanted to ask him
how many excessive force
complaints he had against him.
The answer is four of
shit. So I'm wrong here.
I wanted to ask him
how his marriage ended.
His ex wife has a restraining
order against him for
domestic violence. Alright,
I tap out. You're right.
You're right. Sorry. Uh,
I wanted to ask him what part of
protect and serve did he not understand?
I wanted to end the questioning with him
explaining how he got caught on a cell
phone camera. Assaulting a motorist.
You can look up the video on
youtube under Milwaukee police.
Lambeau driver, l a m B o driver.
Here's what sucks in Milwaukee.
If the cop that wrote you the ticket,
this doesn't show up in court,
your case is dismissed and you don't
have to pay anything. Well, guess,
guess why I told you that the piece
of shit didn't show up in court. Ah,
that's awful. I need advice.
Do I let this all be water under the
bridge or do I take this fucker down?
I really want justice, but I don't
want to be beaten by other cops.
What should I do? Um,
well I think you just shed some light.
Milwaukee police, Lambeau driver.
All my listeners will probably
look up and watch that. Um,
no, this guy sounds like a dangerous guy.
Look, you know, this is,
this is what I would do if I was
going to try to take this dude down.
What I would do is, you know what
the local news loves doing now.
They love showing like youtube videos
and they love talking about Twitter and
all that type of stuff because they're
desperately trying to get the kids in
people cause they're losing all this
viewership to a, to the Internet.
So the fact
that you, you have this
controversial thing,
you have this fucked up law and you
have a youtube video of this guy,
um, that makes, that's like one of
those perfect little pieces, you know,
coming up next Milwaukee police
officer a little out of line,
check out the youtube video that
everybody's been talking about,
all the lower that you could go that
way. Uh, but yeah, I mean you're,
you're taking a a, you're definitely
going to take a fucking risk.
Um,
you know, so you know,
Rodney King died this week and that
brought up that whole video and all that
type of shit. And I know, you
know, the guy just pulled over.
That's what you supposed to
do. I know. I mean, look,
whose kid knew Rodney King was going to
get beat down no matter what. I mean,
if you've run from the fucking cops,
I don't give a fuck who you are.
You've got to get beat down.
But if you get back up,
you charge him a couple of times
absent fucking loosely. But you know,
there's gotta be a way to take a guy
down without giving them 12 fucking skull
fractures. You know what I'm saying?
It's, I don't know. It's, it's, it's,
it's a fucking fabulous job and then
it's a really dangerous job. If,
if the wrong kind of person
gets, uh, gets the job,
why didn't my phone just
go off? Oh, that's right. I
gotta do that Shit. So, um,
I don't know. Personally, I can't,
I can't ever watch that
Rodney King thing again.
That's like fucking most brutal thing
ever. And actually when you watch that,
now you go, thank God they got fucking a,
what do you call those things? Taser.
What do you call? What do you Cleo,
what do you call those things? What
do they call those things that you,
they just, uh, they zap you.
Do you guys ever see that one?
Um, that one where they, the cop.
What the fuck do you call those
things? He got tased. He got fucking,
is it a taser? Cleo? Why am I so dumb?
Ah, fucking love this dog.
You know that Cleo? MMM.
Underrated. Having a dog. It's the
best fucking thing ever. Anyways, this,
this I got, I got to get you this
youtube video. Now that I brought it up.
It's a, it's basically,
they're doing a demonstration
of one of those fucking things.
Whatever the fuck you call
them. That I just can't think,
why do I keep saying it's a taser?
I know. It's not a, is it a taser?
He got tazed. I don't care.
Fuck it. My brain is mush.
So anyways, there's one cop
gonna Zap another cop to a,
the demonstrate it to
the class and look, man,
I don't give a fuck how
much of a man you are.
You get fucking Zap with electricity.
You're going to make a noise.
Most guys go like all raw and
they fucking go down a, um,
this guy fucking shoots it at the guy.
And this dude sounds like he's
like ending an opera. He gets,
he's like
just fucking drunk. He does literally
something like that and drops.
And I just love how the cop who shoots
them tries to act like he just didn't
scream out like a little fucking
girl. Man. It's hilarious. But uh,
but getting back to that, yeah,
dude, that's, that's a serious, um,
that's a serious thing.
And you and you, you know,
if this guy really is
as bad as you're saying,
you know,
the right thing is not to let it go.
The right thing is to try and shed some
light on it and hopefully that they can
get this guy off the force because
he's given decent cops a bad name.
There you go. So, but your,
your worries are definitely a,
you know, valid.
I mean, considering none of those
cops during the Rodney King,
none of them got fucking, they got,
they got off. He can get off doing that.
I mean, Jesus Christ, you know,
that dude who shot that kid on that
platform and in Oakland that was fucking
brutal. He's like, oh, I thought
it was my a was my house keys.
I didn't realize it was my gun.
And he fucking got away with that.
I'm not trashing cops, I'm just saying,
I'm not saying they're all fucking bad,
but I'm just saying it's a, it's
practically fucking impossible.
Um,
it literally, even if you have video,
I think you have to have the combination
of having video and then you have to
be,
you have to be a certain level of a
wealth and influence because if you're
broke, you know, I don't think
that they're, that, you know, you,
there's no way they're just going
to be like, yeah, go fuck yourself.
You'd done, you know, and then when
you add racism into it, I mean,
you're pretty much, it's
pretty much game set match,
which is fucking unfortunate.
So, um, I don't know.
I'm talking about society way
beyond my fucking intellect,
so I'm going to tap out here.
Yeah.
Alrighty. Trash. Fucking hair metal.
And I'm gonna have fucking angry, uh,
psycho cops.
I don't really
[inaudible].
Um, all right. Lights, camera dumped bill.
I'm a 29 year old guy and recently
broke up with a funny attractive and all
around Greg girl. Oh Gee. Why
Sir would you do that? You ask.
All right.
Um,
two things.
Her Dad was born without teeth and you're
worried your baby will [inaudible] if
you braid with her or,
or a,
she has got something going
on in the vaginal area,
some sort of odor stinky pussy. I
don't know. Well, here we go. Well,
let me tell you,
this girl and I had been dating for about
three months and we had a great thing
going. She's half Afro Cuban,
half Puerto Rican and really sexy.
She had a rough upbringing, but I
didn't care because she's honest,
easy going and not bitchy. Like so many
girls I've dated. She was a bit needy,
but I didn't mind. Um,
we were out at a bar one night having
a few drinks and I was feeling pretty
good.
I was looking at a couple of floozies
at the end of the bar and I asked her if
she's ever been with another woman.
She coyly looked at me and said, yes,
good stuff. I thought, yeah, dude,
this is a fucking fantasy right here.
Fucking red shoe diaries.
And then I proceeded with,
have you ever been in a threesome
with two girls and a guy again?
She answered yes. Okay. Kind
of slutty, but I'm no saint.
While I couldn't stop the, Oh God,
you're going to go for the rotisserie
question. What's in the box?
Ah, here we go. Here we go. Strap
yourselves in for this one. Well,
I couldn't stop there, so I asked, have
you ever had a threesome with two guys?
She looked down at the ground
and she looked up a bit ashamed,
Lee and said yes. Wow. Skank alert.
I thought I then asked
her one more question.
I knew this one could back for
where the fuck do you go from here?
Like throwing the high heat to Albert
Albert pool host. I finally asked,
wait, have you ever been in a porn?
She then blushed and look me
in the eye and said, yeah,
I looked at her calmly and was
like, oh, but inside I was like,
Jesus fucking Christ.
Yes. Well, you should,
you know those first couple. I mean,
you can look at it. Let, let's, let's
break this down here. All right.
She's been with a,
she's had a threesome with another
girl and a guy who gets that.
That's who gives a fuck
right there. All right.
You're already knew she banged
another guy. All right? But, uh,
the fact that she also did it with
another girl, that takes a little fucking,
uh, that tones down his dick in her pussy.
Right? This is how guys think. Women,
I'm sorry. All right. That's something
that, that's something in the, uh,
the credit. Is it the credit bill? Why,
why, why do you try to talk accounting?
Shit. You're too dumb. All right, that
one's all right. The two guys thing.
Now you can look the other way on that.
Maybe if if it was in another state,
but it can't be in the same state because
if you run into one of the two guys
that fucking, you know, we're high
fiving is they fucking banged our,
that mean I d I dunno about that one.
But then the third one she did a porno.
I mean, yeah, no, that's a,
you've got to walk away from that
or are you have to go to NASA to get
tested for the latest fucking STDs,
I would think. And then also
God knows what's going on. Uh,
mentally that you would do that.
Yeah.
What? I just like sex. No, no,
no. There's something going on.
Who doesn't like sex? I don't
know. Anyways, plowing ahead. See,
so she egos. So basically she had moved
down to Los Angeles when she was 20.
She's now 25 and after a
short stint in the military,
somehow she got into the porn
industry for eight months.
She did everything [inaudible].
Fox sucked the whole Shebang.
I asked her if I could see her video,
but she wouldn't tell
me her performer name.
It said vehemently that it would be
impossible to find her body of work.
I asked her why she got
into porn and she replies
because I wanted some feeling in
my life and then he rides down.
G is, yeah, dude. Ah, this poor
girl. Something happened to her.
The thing was she was clean,
had a good job and I really liked her
and the sex was great. Yeah. Obviously,
you know, it was funny,
there was something you
wrote the beginning where I
just thought she was going
to be good. 29 year old guy,
attractive all around Greg girl.
Oh, the fact that you said she
had a rough brain upbringing,
but she was easygoing and honest and
not bitchy right there. I was like,
that girl's good in bed. It just
seemed like a kind of free open person.
I don't know. I didn't know if she was
going to be that open. Oh Geez. Um,
anyways, the thing was she
was clean and I have a bla.
The sex was great,
but I couldn't stop picturing her in some
sleazy porno that was probably filmed
in some junkyard on labrea.
So I went to ask for a friend's advice.
Most of my guys were telling me to dumper
my gay friends told me it was fabulous
and that I should overlook it.
I didn't even bother asking my girlfriends
because they would automatically
reject her and assume I had aids.
There you go. Keep your options open.
So regretfully I dumped her.
I felt terrible and obviously didn't tell
her it was because she was a porn star
because she would have been
ashamed for the rest of her life.
And I was happy that she was honest with
me. I've done my fair share of sleeves,
but this was too much. My question
bill was, Bill, my question bill,
was it wrong for me to dump or for
some decisions she made years ago?
Should I have stayed with her?
What would have you done? Um,
oh, you don't want to know what I
would've done. I'm a fucking degenerate.
So let's you, you seem
like a good person. Um,
dude,
when you're trying to find the person
you're going to spend the rest of your
life with, you have to have a
list of criteria. All right.
Sound like you're still young, so there's
no reason to compromise. All right?
I mean,
when you get with somebody like that and
you're going to live with them and you
will, you get with anybody, you're
taking on all of their fucking baggage.
All right? You're only three
months in and you know,
people who go into the porn
industry, they're, you know,
it's like people would come, comedians
were not healthy individuals. Okay.
And that is like a specific
area that I just, I just,
this is just my own personal nonmedical
feeling that you're just not a healthy
person. Something awful happened and that
line, I just wanted to feel something.
I mean, something bad happened to
her, caused her to wall herself off.
I don't even want to try to
guess what, but you know,
there's nothing wrong with anything
that she did personally, you know,
technically, and she was honest with it.
It all comes down to whether or not
you want to deal with it. All right?
And if you feel that you know,
you want to deal with it and that there
was this sort of connection that you
just had, this girl
had to be in your life,
then you're going to have to learn
to live with it and get past it.
Um,
but I would be definitely,
I would definitely be concerned with, uh,
certain mental issues,
um, now like she's insane.
And then I would also
be concerned with, uh,
sexual boundaries, you know?
Okay.
Like would she have any,
and could she remain faithful after a
while and when you settle into the seven
year itch or whatever,
and you really start needing to work at
the relationship and it's feeling boring
and she needs to feel something
again, is she going to go back to that
leather couch from that
show? Martin my n, you know,
down on fucking the valley and get
banged again. I mean, I don't know.
I don't know. That is a,
a, that is, you know what,
that is beyond my skills. I don't
know how to tame that horse.
I could tell you that right fucking
now. I don't, I have no fucking clue.
That's a a, you know what,
that's a Dr drew question.
That is a classic Dr Drew
Question. And that guy,
within two seconds we'll get right
to the core of it. I would call,
I would call in love line, man, if you're
out here, call him up. Cause that's a,
that's a great one. Um,
yeah, I guess you'd have
to figure out is, is,
has she worked through whatever the fuck
she was working through and now she's
ready to, I mean, I dunno. Hey,
those are some good looking
girls down there. And she's like,
yeah they are or whatever. Like, I mean,
if you kept steering in that direction,
you'd probably get fucking
threesome right there. Um,
so there's that, there's that option.
The option that you have is if you're
with her, like I think that that's,
that's a selfish fucking and a shallow
reason to stay with somebody longterm.
Uh, yeah. Jesus. I don't know.
[inaudible] [inaudible]
red fish markets to police in the
corner gun and Phil, you, yes,
photos he did for like a breath for
the shooter said please don't do that.
[inaudible].
Um, all right. Beef curtain advice.
And for those of you in the states,
that's a slang for the
WHO, Huh? Beef curtains.
Do the math. Think about it. All
right, you ready? Okay, here we go.
Here's the situation. I have a
wonderful girl in my life. Uh,
what in one she doesn't know how
to fuck. That's what I'm guessing.
I'm guessing this is where it's going.
I have wonderful girl in my life.
Great attitude, humor, big tits, nice ass
and a good family. Jesus Christ. Dude,
marry this girl. Sure. It seems
good for now. But I have one issue.
She also has some mean beef curtains
and he put in parentheses, Pussy Lips.
Just in case I didn't know
a, that kind of bugged me.
Bug the ever living shit
out of me. Whenever we get
down to the dirty business.
So much a,
so to the point I looked up some cosmetic
surgery that basically gives the beef
curtains a trim job and
beauties the vagina.
Wow. Dude. Why? All right. Now,
before I read the rest of this,
if you're going to fucking ask
me how to have this conversation,
like listen, love, I love you, I love
you, I love you family. I love you,
your heart, everything. But is there
any way you can trim your beef curtains?
Maybe you can get away with it cause
you've got that cool accent. I don't know.
But she has it too, so she's
not going to give a fuck.
You can maybe pull this off with
some foreign chick anyways. Um,
so he looks up cosmetic surgery
to try on a beautiful vagina.
Now I know by now I must sound like a
douchebag focusing on the little things.
No, cause women do that too. Women
focus on little things like that,
that that's a serious issue. Dude. Sex
is a big fucking thing. But anyways,
he says what my thinking is I'm
truly gonna pull the trigger.
He spelt it that way and keep this woman
all the myself for the rest of my life.
RNI entitled to have a great looking
Vage to look at for as long as our bodies
don't wrinkle away. Wow.
I know there's a lot of women are fucking
annoyed by this one. Yeah. Went by.
She a fucking Dick in your wrinkled balls.
Why don't you get a face lift
for your sack there buddy.
I know they're all say that I'm,
how can I ever bring this
option up to her without,
I knew he's going to ask me
without completely destroying
her feelings or making
her hate me for being so pussy
conscious. Thanks for the read.
Now go fuck yourself. All right.
This is a simple one, dude.
There is no fucking way
you can bring that up to her without
absolutely completely destroying her
feelings. So you either need
to accept this or you have to,
you have to let her go.
That's it. That's it.
I mean, I would think that if you
actually truly cared about this girl,
now all the chicks are
going to be like, oh,
I know he had a heart
underneath all those c words.
Um, if you truly care about this girl, uh,
I would think that that wouldn't matter.
You know and if she looks the way she,
she's saying you saying that she looks,
I mean what, what are we talking here?
Like how far down these things
hanging isn't like you know,
I mean if she got him both of them
piers could you like do like a,
could you like a better, let's say,
could you be like the like that Olympic,
the fuck is that thing
who you're on the rings.
Could you do that and still swing your
feet up and not hit her pussy and we
talking like it's that bad.
You know if you did the iron cross
would your head be in her pussy?
Like how far these things
hanging down? Hey now
what's the deal with deep gardens?
All right dude, there's no way there's,
there's no fucking way and don't don't
do that to her cause she can't do
anything about that.
If she had a problem with her fucking
vaginal area you would have known by now
because she would have been self conscious
and she would have brought it up the
way.
Sometimes girls do about parts of their
bodies and they are super self conscious
about their bodies because we're
so fucking visual. All right.
I told you one time when the
first girls I ever hooked up with,
when I got her shirt off and her bra off,
she rolled her eyes and I thought she
was thinking that. I was like, oh my God.
Like I'm not doing it for like she's
rolling her eyes. Like this guy's lame.
And I found out later she was self
conscious about the size of her breasts.
So I totally took it
the wrong fucking way.
I made it all about me cause I'm
self involved. So a Duh. Yeah,
don't do that to her. All
right. Either you can.
That's when you just
suddenly have in your head.
Either you accept that
shit or you move on,
but there's no reason to hurt this person
because you're a shallow Kent like me.
All right.
All right. Cheers mate.
[inaudible]
[inaudible].