Hey, what's going on? It's bill bird.
It's time for the Thursday afternoon.
Just before Friday,
Monday morning podcast and
ah,
just checking in. Oh, you,
what's going on? How are Ya?
There's some happy people out there.
There's some sad people out.
There was a wonderful couple of days
of soccer. Here are the World Cop,
France or Hall Beats Belgium
and England falls to Croatia.
It's coming,
omits calming. Oh my folly. Looked it
up to see like why do they keep saying
that it's coming home?
You know,
I immediately assume like,
well obviously England must've won the
most championships and this is their
arrogant fucking way of being like, yeah,
this is where it rightfully belongs.
Kind of like when the Yankees win a
world series and then all those fucking
talking heads on on Espn
logo and everything is all
is right in baseball again.
It's why.
Why?
Because a toward had million dollar team
on a fucking play off series play off.
Turns out that's not what it is.
Evidently the game of soccer now
this might our football footie,
whatever the fuck you call it.
Evidently it was according to the English.
It was created in England.
They were the ones who decided despite
the fact that you have four limbs,
you can only use two.
They wanted a degree of difficulty.
They weren't like the animals over here.
You know where we get bored and
they're like, pick it up, you know,
tackle them, which meant jump on his
back and throw him to the fucking ground.
I now tackle over there
as you trip somebody,
you stick your foot out in your triple.
So evidently it started over there.
That's what they're saying.
So that's what it meant because I
thought it meant that they had the most
championships. And then I looked
up all time World Cup champions.
All right. What you gotta do?
How the fuck do you not to do?
I don't give a fuck what the sport is.
I want to know who dominated.
Turns out Brazil since
1930 they won the most.
They've won five 58 60 to 70 94 2002
which is a fucking lot considering it's
every four years. How many have
there been? One, two, three,
four, five, six, seven, eight,
nine, 10, 11, 12, 13, 14, 1520.
This is a 21st one.
They've won 21,
like whatever fucking was at
20% of 25% of them than Germany.
Auntie. Yeah, they, they
got for Italy has four. Oh,
they should have had five in
[inaudible] 94 I remember that one. Uh,
Argentina hand, God, that
guy, whatever his name was.
Uh, the hell was that guy's
name? Diego or some shit.
What the fuck was his name?
I used to know his name.
Okay.
And were those fucking names where it's
just like the second they gave him that
his name is just like, pussy is going
to be rated down on this guy. Right.
Um, I forget the hand to God
guy. That guy, it was weird.
He was like in shape and he also look fat.
What the fuck was his name?
Okay.
Diego Era Gamo was something like that.
I can't fucking remember. Then. Uh,
I got my hope. I say this right. I
always, always was Uruguay urgh away,
won it twice. And then England,
France, and Spain of all one at once.
That's interesting cause I thought Spain
was a powerhouse and I would've thought
in England when a bunch way back in the
day when it's probably just a bunch of
white guys running around.
Right? Yeah. I also don't want,
so that's why they say it's coming home.
It's not some arrogant shit. It's like,
Hey, you know, this game at the
whole world loves, you know,
not to pat ourselves on the back,
but guess what? We came up with it.
It's our shit. Okay. Every, you
know, you know what I mean? You know,
it's not just all about colonization.
The caste system.
Yeah.
And it's slaving people of other colors
around the world. It's not just about,
that's not all we did. Okay. Yay.
Hey, you want to focus on the
negative? You can do that. Okay.
But you can't deny that the beautiful
game of football known as soccer rover
here in the states as we sit
around eating Arby's, right.
Was evidently created in England.
I don't know when they did it.
You'd think for it to have a World Cup
by 1934 to sweep the fucking nation.
Wait a minute.
Yeah.
They also had an empire back then. Oh, I
get it. So they came up with this game.
They'd come in,
they'd fucking take you over.
They'd fucking kill a bunch of
people. And everybody was like, man,
these guys are fucking assholes,
man. Settle down. Settle down.
We're gonna teach you a little game.
All right? You can't use your arms.
A lot of you had your arms chopped
off because you couldn't find any gold
anyways. So this is going to work
real well for you all. I can use it.
Your fate in your fucking had
and the game spread like
wildfire across the globe
as England expanded her empire.
I never understood why it was considered
female. Was that the tone it down?
There was a bunch of Luna tick guys going
around the world going and this is a
nice place to live. Too Bad. There's other
people here. What can we do about this?
Everybody does it right? Everybody's
done it since the beginning of time. You,
you go back,
you go back far enough in history books.
This is what all guilty white
people do. Everybody. Yeah.
You know a Africans and slave, the other
African jewelry. Would you say that shit,
try get past it. You know it's like the
Billy Joel Song. We didn't start the fire,
which has got to be the most classic,
the most classic fucking
baby boomer response. I mean,
what a fucking baby. He couldn't even
take a little bit of responsibility,
you know, hey, you know we,
we can start here and he
starts naming all this shit.
Half of it is like pop stars
like Marilyn Monroe. What did,
what did she have to
do with foreign policy?
I know she fucked a couple of
Kennedy's but I mean other than that,
I don't think that dictated
whether or not we went into Cuba.
Doris Day fucking
[inaudible] to Bubba.
Papa trouble into sue as the fucky.
He must've been on blow what he
wrote that song. It's like, Billy,
are you going to take any responsibility
for the self centered cons that the
baby boom generation was? I'm not saying
everything you did was bad. I mean,
he invented the Frisbee,
right?
Was that you guys or was
that the greatest generation?
Yeah.
I don't know.
Somewhere in there there's gotta be
truth right from the greatest generation.
Okay.
You know, that generation also didn't
want to play baseball. Jackie Robinson,
by the way, uh, to the
baby boomers who are,
you know, widely considered the
most selfish cons, you know,
this country has ever produced, right?
Just sitting around staring at the navel,
you know, this is the dawning
of the age of Aquarius,
right? That's the same
generation that gave us hippies,
but truly Birkenstocks,
you know,
fucking in the mud at a concert. I used
to have a theory way back in the day,
you know, when they talked about HIV and
aids, they always said that, you know,
it was some, somebody, you know,
always try something about a monkey or
some shit and some guy in France. Got It.
Um, I never thought it was then. I
used to have a theory that, you know,
if you watch the woodstocks tapes and
you just see all those naked white people
rolling around fucking each
other in the mud, I mean,
he can't tell me that something
didn't come out of that, you know,
at least a stronger strain of the mumps.
Right.
So anyways, to get back to it,
you know, I was, I was, uh,
working as an actor.
I was acting during the last couple of
days and I was talking to this dude going
like,
yeah,
how come England keeps saying it's coming
home when they were talking about the
World Cup? And he goes, is
that what they're saying?
Those colonizing constantly
fucking dude went off. No.
It's just like, you know, white
people when we're not all bad. I mean,
there's some things,
you know,
Blue Windows curtains, you know,
we've done some nice things,
you know, now you can look out
your house and see all the,
the lack of opportunity, right. Right.
From inside your house without people.
Am I actually taking credit for
windows? I Dunno. I have no idea.
I don't read. Oh, speaking
of which, oh my God.
Oh my God.
I said on my last podcast that the
Obama's bought an $82 million house.
Turned out it was an eight
point $1 million house.
It wasn't even 8.2 million.
That's how off I was and
this is my favorite thing.
So now all these people are
like, what? They're all gone.
Why don't you do your fucking homework
man? Like nothing makes people flip out.
Not even religion, unless you make fun
of Muslims to those fucking lunatics.
A liable to do something,
but fucking if you make,
if you make fun of like
a Democrat or Republican,
nothing brings people out of the woodwork.
So all these people are like,
why don't you do your fucking homework?
Blah Blah. Which is hilarious.
This whole podcast is based
on me not doing any homework,
not reading whatsoever.
So I'm just going to tell
you political concept there.
You've got a lot of fucking nerve.
A lot.
I just said AIDS came for white people
fucking in the mud at Woodstock.
Are you going to come back at
me on that one? What did you do?
Your fucking homework,
man.
Okay.
This whole podcast exists for
one reason and one reason only.
It's to make you feel smarter.
Ice.
We here at the Monday
morning podcast and by we,
I mean me in the voices in
my head that agree with me.
We hear it.
The Monday morning podcast set
the bar so low that even you,
you know with that college that you went
to that advertised on television and
you drove yourself there and they like
living there was not even an option.
They didn't have dorms.
They just, you know,
was your college one giant sad building?
Look at like a high school for
people in their twenties yeah, yeah.
That's who you are. And you
know what, even you get to
feel smart on this podcast.
So my favorite thing is,
yeah,
if you go back and you listen to my
podcasts on Monday when I thought I was so
fucking write about the Obamas buying
this $82 million house is somebody
actually wrote into the podcast and
goes, you know bill, I love you,
but why don't you do your homework?
Obama just signed a $62 million book deal.
Okay.
And this is what's fucking hilarious.
He's telling me to do my homework.
He didn't even do the homework to look
up to double check what the fuck I said
even say if it was true,
he just took it for granted that I said
$82 million house and then he's like,
he took that as truth and started
looking up the guy's fucking book deal.
So why don't you do your
fucking homework man. All right.
For the 9 million time.
Okay on this podcast.
Okay.
Do not take anything I say seriously?
You can disagree with the web and
you can correct me and all that,
but just don't get upset
and don't be fucking surprised that I,
I fucking don't read.
And then my,
my facts might be off
by a good $72 million.
Okay.
You know,
if you guys sound like all you fucking
political cuts out there bitching at me,
you sound like all these fucking fat
actresses out here who are bitching about
Hollywood acting as though they're
surprised that so much of this fucking
industry is based on how you look.
What was that really a shocker?
Had He never been to a movie?
You didn't notice a trend.
Do you think it's just you?
Yeah.
You know what I mean? You fucking
sloppy tits. Who's having a rough time?
I'm a fucking bald redhead and male.
I have no sympathy for you.
Okay?
No, he's knocking down their fucking door
to put me in an action movie. You know,
I could be hell boy. Do a fucking cycle
of steroids. I already have the head.
You just fucking painted
red and you're ready to go.
I could do a headstand and fucking
my head would turned so red.
You could save feeds the amount of money
you'd save on makeup and time alone.
Bill, do a fucking handstand.
Okay, you're in the scene.
Um,
yeah.
Anyways,
so I guess the Obamas bought an
eight point $1 million house,
not an $82 million house,
which then led me into this whole thing.
Like he's on his, he, this is
his third book that he's written.
It's like he was writing
books while he was president.
Aren't you supposed to be
running the fucking country?
Fucking sitting there dealing with the
Russians and all these terrorist groups
and all that shit.
And then you're like fucking at nighttime,
take out a little legal pad. It was the
best of times. It was the worst of times.
These fucking assholes
out right in the books.
They always get like somebody else.
It's like written by Bill Clinton and the
other guy who actually wrote the book.
Yeah, I want to run a thriller. Well, how
about you and me Ron it right. Like, Oh,
you'll put your name and put my name on
the cover and then you lock write it.
What is that book about?
You've got to write what you know.
It's gotta be something about somebody
fucking sneak around on his wife. Right.
Sticking cigars and people. Oh, it's too
on the nose. I wanted to be challenged.
I wrote about a guy who was faithful.
Um, sorry for the bad Bill Clinton.
Uh, now you guys spill once
you do your whole book.
The book is actually bugs experiences,
Oxford,
Oxford in England,
the home where it all started.
I take both of those games.
I was working both days,
so I have to go back and watch
them and I gotta tell you, man,
I am so fucking sold in that game though.
I don't know what happened.
I had so much fun making fun of soccer
all these fucking years. And it's uh,
it's crazy. And then watching the
highlights of when a goal is scored,
like my whole,
my whole complaint about the sport
is what makes the sport so great.
The fact that scoring is so God
damn difficult. The fucking,
that the emotion that gets led
off when these people score.
I mean, Jesus Christ, like in my country,
if you dump a beer on somebody's
after some sort of point is scored,
you're going to get into a fight over
there. I mean, it looked like a fucking,
I dunno what it looked like.
It looked like a,
a sports bar combined with
the money shot in a porno.
Everybody's jumping up and down,
just spray and booze all over the place.
Part of me that was a little
annoying. Like why, why,
why are you wasting all that good
boots? You know, cause I'm a, I'm,
I'm, I'm taking another
month off. You don't me.
Okay.
I impose my own little fucking
sabbaticals, you know what
I mean? And after that,
that my little excursion over
there to Europe, oh my God,
there's just I aisle that says Rasaka
the 1664 bet fucking beer tastes so god
damn good in that Goddamn
glass in that one cafe,
uh, over there in Europe, over there
in France. Right then I refuse, I've,
I've seen it over here and I've been
tempted to buy it and it's like,
I'm not going to fucking do it
because this is what happens.
Like when you go to Ireland and you drink
Guinness over there and then you come
back here and you want to continue it,
it fucking sucks.
And you know what else I did? You
know, it's just unbelievably like,
just on another level is
Indian food in England.
Yeah.
I went to this fucking place. The Indian
food was so goddamn good. I've been, I,
I've ordered it twice since then.
Once in France it was okay.
And then I ordered it here
in la in it fucking sucked.
And it was like, I got
to walk away, you know,
it's like you go to Paris and he
come home and be like, you know,
I'm going to have a French breakfast.
I'm going to get a, I saw. Right.
And then you'd go down to the
fucking supermarket and you get an,
and it's like somebody pulled
it out of this shoe, you know,
it just all goes back to
the when in Rome thing.
Okay.
Yes. Go on. Um, you know what I mean?
That's the only thing that sucks
about traveling. You know what I mean?
Like, uh, I'm, I'm, I think I'm going
to do a Gig in buffalo coming up.
I haven't been there in fucking forever.
And what's going to happen is I'm going
to go to Duffy's or that other fucking
place with,
you know,
where they came up with buffalo wings
and I'm going to eat them and they're
going to be so goddamn good.
And then I'm going to come back out here.
I'm going to have that fucking crack
in my, my, my system going, well,
I'm going to get,
I gotta get some wings out here and
when eat them and they're going to suck.
And then it's just depressing.
Do you like I the only place to get
good wings in Buffalo? It really is.
I've never gone to any other place other
than buffalo that really knows how to
make good buffalo wings.
That's it.
Now I just lob that out there for all
of you guys to lose your fucking shoe.
Yeah.
She, which brought low jockey. Good.
Okay.
But you want to do is go to Cincinnati.
You can go to fucking mfi
stay of the best ones.
I followed Joe Rogan on all social media
and he posted this really fascinating
thing that within 10 minutes I was like,
I don't even know what the
fuck this guy's talking about.
He was talking something about fasting
and how it's actually could be good
for you. I mean, I've read, I mean,
Dick Gregory wrote a whole bunch of
books on this type of Shit, right?
Rest his soul and a saying
how, you know, let's see.
Oregon's rejuvenate and
all of that type of shit.
And I thought it was really fascinating.
Until about 10 minutes in, I realized I,
I didn't understand what the guy was
talking about and I looked at him and he
was not in the best of shape. He
looked a little mushy, you know,
which I would think would
happen if you fast it,
you'd get a little fleshy cause
your body would keep eating muscle.
You know what I mean? I
Dunno. But anyways, um,
the fuck was my point.
Let's talking about food out cheeses.
I don't fucking know. I have no
idea. Troubled in this. Sue is
JFK blown away.
Tips the table over like a fucking baby.
MMM.
Why am I talking about that?
Because I was watching TV late night
and I watched all these old 80s
videos
and that song came on,
you know,
I'm telling you my new show is 77 sunset
strip with FM Zimbalist jr who I was
always a big fan of cause that FBI
show and uh, and I've been, you know,
I've been maintain,
you know,
I think yesterday was the first day I
snapped while driving in a while and it
felt weird and I immediately
dialed it back down and my move for all
you other angry guys out there like me
and you're not angry, you're
not an angry guy. You just,
that's your default emotion.
Like, you know what I mean?
I'd like to really be an angry guy.
You just have to be like walking
around seeding, which I don't,
I walk around totally normal and then
something happens and I fucking flip out,
you know, and have a fucking meltdown
and then it just takes people. It's just,
it's so fucking over the
top that everybody forgets
what a great guy was for the
previous four hours.
That's essentially what it is.
And it's like a fucking five
minute meltdown, you know,
it's like, what about the other
four hours when I was a good guy?
And it's just like no bill.
No what you did in that five
minutes negated all that.
It's like doing four hours of fucking
cardio and then sitting down and eating a
box of fucking Oreo cookies. It's
just, it, you just negated all of that.
It's over. You still a fat fuck
emotionally. So anyways, I,
I listened to baseball,
I listened to the red
sox on Sirius Xm and uh,
actually watched, then I came home
that's making me watch them again.
Fucking Chris sales up God damn beast.
You watched the game last night when he
walked that guy and he didn't think that
he walked him and he got fucking mad
cause he started throwing like 98,
99 miles an hour on the corners.
That crazy delivery.
Um, I dunno, we shall see that.
I don't know who that bum was that they
brought in the fucking eighth inning.
Then almost gate, we were up four to
nothing and he's like, you know what?
Let's make the gamblers nervous is an
nice fatty hanging out over the plate.
Bam. Base head, boom. Double four to one,
load them up and they finally got him
out of there. Then our relief pitcher,
I don't know anybody's name,
that guy who comes out there,
he hangs his arm like he's
driving a shirt or some shit.
He came out there and shut
them the fuck down. Um,
so I'm,
I'm like a,
I'm back into that shit and I'm actually
going to be really sad when the World
Cup's over.
When is the finals out on Saturday?
That's going to be crazy
one match for all the fucking models.
Can you imagine if that comes
down to penalty kicks again?
I used to think that was the
stupidest fucking thing ever.
Like a world basketball, basketball
championship coming down to foul shots.
You know what I mean? That would just be
like boring as shit. But now I get it.
I get it.
Because if you fuck it up,
I really feel like the goaltender has
like no pressure cause all he has to do is
just guess,
you know,
I love that they're guessing it's just a
total guests. And when they guess, right,
they guess, right. They
stand up like, yeah, like,
like there was some sort of intelligent
thought there. It's just like left, right,
left, right diving left.
Fuck you went right. Um,
that always, it's always funny
when they guess wrong when they're,
they start to dive that way and they
realized that guy went the other way and
you just watched the goaltender, like
his whole body goes limp. Like, ah,
I should tell the other way and he
just fucking lands on the grass. Um,
but the pressure on the shooter,
they don't want to miss the net.
So I,
I,
I'm gathering it takes massive balls to
try to shoot it up top to go top corner,
which why wouldn't you just go there?
He's not going to fucking get that.
Cause it's like,
what if I miss then I'm that cunt that
fucking missed for the rest of my fucking
life in fat, crooked, great teeth,
fish and chip eating.
Fucking assholes can get my grill
everywhere I go for the rest of my life.
People who never accomplish it now can
take out the failure of their life on me
cause I tried to go top shelf. What
do you guys call it? What do we do?
What do you guys call shelfs
over them? The Bonnet. The boot.
What the fuck do you always have
some stupid fucking name for it? Um,
I've noticed that I'm cooking shows.
Every ingredient you guys pronounce
differently. Oregano, Oregon.
No tomato,
tomato.
Bazell Basel Second. They just fucking
with me. There wasn't one thing.
Do we hate England that much?
By the end of it,
I really think that we would like to
summer school kids that came over here in
like the weird religious people.
Yeah.
We all came over here and you had
people who weren't good in school.
Fucking people that were too into religion
and those two people combined made
Americans.
That's why I am the product of that.
And I thought an eight point $1
million house was $82 million.
Why don't you do your homework,
but you go fuck yourself.
Do my homework. I'm not in
fucking school. All right.
I didn't get in this business to think.
All right, let me, uh, let me read it.
A little bit of advertising here.
JFK blown away.
A tipping over your fucking table.
I still love Billy Joel
cause he got so hammered,
he drove his car through his fucking
neighbor's living room window. I mean,
can you, can you loan him enough sugar
in your lifetime to get past that?
You know, every day I'd be
knocking on the door. Hey Man,
if you want to borrow a rake or a
wheel barrow, anything, anything,
you know Barrow by the way,
not barrel roll out the Barrow where
Ray can some fuck and leaves a,
by the way, Dean del Ray from the
letter B talk podcast on all things.
Comedy has the legendary Henry
Rollins on his podcast this week.
This is a dream guests for Dean del race.
He want to listen to them.
Fan Boy out while asking
all the questions.
You always wanted to hear Henry
Rollins answer. Give a take a few,
um, checking out in the all things
coming network. Let there be talk.
Dean del Rey with the Great Henry
Rollins who had such a funny bit on iron
maiden. He actually made
me question whether I was,
I am more on for liking the band and then
of course I put on one of their songs
and I was like, no I
wasn't. I wasn't right.
It sounds like we read this book about
a bloke who had wings and he flew too
close to the sun.
So this song's about a bloke who put some
wings on and flew too close to the sun.
Um, alright, put your box.
Butcher box delivers healthy 100% grass
fed and grass finished beef free range,
organic chicken and this right.
This is the money shot right
here and heritage bread,
pork [inaudible] pork chop I've ever
had in my life that I ever made in my
house. I think maybe one time and
went to some five star restaurant.
You know the ref fucking chefs
walking around wearing clogs.
You've got to go to one of those places,
you know,
and there's all these old bald guys
like me with these skinny young broads,
you know, Aka their second
or third wife. You know,
you gotta go to a place like that.
If you don't want to drop that kind of
cash and you still want to the best pork
chop you ever going to have you get,
you gotta get butchered bucks.
All right there, there's my personal
file that I just made it personal. Okay.
The incredible quality of butcher box
meets starts with the commitment to
raising animals humanely and free of
antibiotics and hormones before they kill
them. Each box comes with at
least nine to 11 pounds of meat,
which is enough for 24 individual sized
meals. You could feed a fucking army.
You can choose from five different
box types. All beef, beef and chicken,
beef and pork mixed box.
Go crazy man.
Throws many animals in there. As you can
custom box let you choose your own cuts.
Come on, man. It's the fucking
get the grill.
Go and and get some butcher box.
This ad always makes me hungry.
That's how good the food has been.
A antibiotic slash hormone free butcher
box believes in healthier food system
where everyone has access to
meets the way nature intended.
Now like these cows in mainstream where
they got the fake tits in the fucking
botox. All right, you
want the original ones,
free of antibiotics and hormones
and humanely raised on open pasture.
Let them walk around.
Um,
selection is amazing.
Bushbucks carefully curated the finest
selection and cuts and makes it a breeze
to customize your own delivery.
Build your own box to get exactly
what you and your family love.
Choose your delivery frequency.
With the customization. It's uh,
with customizable subscription recipes
are available on butcher box's websites
and videos are available
to fall along a butcher.
Bucky can't fucking lose all rights
to receive free bacon for life.
The dream of every goddamn mediator
out there plus $10 off your order.
Go to butcher box.com.
Click on the big bacon banner on the
homepage and use bur at checkout.
Go now, limited time offer. All right.
Four sigmatic that that said Stigmata
this episode is brought to you by four
sigmatic four sigmatic the leading online
purveyors of shrooms, man. That's right.
There's Shalon shrooms on the Internet,
but really this company sells mushroom
coffee that actually tastes great.
It is damn good for you. I fucking love
mushrooms. I would actually try this.
You know, I love mushroom soup. I've
always wanted to try mushrooms. You know,
I know. I know where you're
going to say. Talk to Ari.
Shaffir four sigmatic um,
is from Finland. So you know, it's good.
The same country that gave
you Santa Claus. Angry beards
two
go. Rask. I hit how it says the
goaltender for the Boston Bruins.
Like he didn't already know that.
And of course, mushroom coffee.
Did you know that Finnish people consume
more coffee per capita than any other
country? Almost three times more
than Americans. I don't like that.
We're losing to them.
And coffee.
Mushroom coffee has half the
caffeine of regular coffee,
but it's twice as magical. It's
easy on the gut, less acidic,
and you don't get the jittery feeling
you get from regular coffee too.
And I'm sold. I'd love a nice hot cup
of fucking mushroom coffee right now.
Um, evidently I'm drinking the mushroom
coffee with lion's Mane and Chaga.
Lion's mane. There's hair in the
fucking coffee. Tastes just like coffee.
Not like mushrooms.
Oh.
Oh,
okay. Oh, they told me not to say it
tastes like mushrooms. I guess it doesn't,
it tastes like coffee. Lion's mane
mushroom is your brain's best friend.
Long used by Buddhist monks. They
never lose their shit. Right.
To help with focus during meditation.
I gotta try this shit perfect
for when I need to get shit done.
Think of it as supercharged
instant coffee. Come.
I like how this is all in the past tense.
Like I've done this in my life
has changed for the better,
but I'm sold coming easy to use
carry single serving packets.
Perfect tick take to work for travel or
when you're on the go get 50% off your
first purchase with code
burpee you are just go do
foursigmatic.com and
try it out for yourself.
Okay.
You Know Nas is going to
come out with his coat,
his own coffee cold for illmatic.
Right.
And to see me made with, I don't know,
maybe we'd and mushrooms, I don't know.
Is he into that shit? I
have no idea. Uh, me undies,
um, me undies are made with a
sustainably sourced material.
Oh wait a minute, but a boop, boop.
Me undies me on [inaudible] the
world cop is coming home due to,
to, to beyond [inaudible] beyond
ease is sick of fucking being alone.
But then England,
lots of the Croatians,
now that Cup is still on vacation and
ain't coming home and he fucking time soon
. Sorry to everybody over
there. Congratulations Croatia.
I love that.
Number 10 number 10 on Croatia.
That fucking guy is a play
of France has a great team.
I don't know who to root for here.
I obviously love France. Patty. Oh,
I have a great time when I'm over
there, but I gotta tell you, man,
Croatian system, good luck and God damn
people. And it's only 4.1 million of them.
According to Pete Davidson,
there's more people in New York then
there's in their entire country and they
are in the finals.
So I think I kind of have to root for them
cause they're the underdogs again.
Oh fuck it. I'm ruined for Croatia.
All right. How does it like got here?
I got to hear the national anthem.
I gotta learn that by
Saturday. Oh fuck. And Croatia.
There's only 4 million cons.
Croatia national,
national fun.
I almost wrote fucking anthem.
Anthem.
You know this is going to be some fucking
Dracula, Eastern European shit. Oh,
by the way, that tour is going down.
I'm getting all the dates. Okay.
I'm not talking shit.
I'm going out there.
Croatian national anthem
with English lyrics.
Let's not very probation. Is it? What
do they speak over their [inaudible]
all right,
let's, oh, it's only two and a half
minutes long. I'm already liking this.
It's like a Beatles song. Well,
where's the fucking, where's the music?
It's scrolling. Scrolling, scrolling.
[inaudible]
all right. There's no fucking way I'm
going to be able to lend us. Ah, right.
Oh,
it comes down.
Woo.
It's very cinematic. You know
what? I like it. I like it.
God dammit. It's very cinematic. Um,
yeah,
I like ours too. I was the big, it's,
it's based off a drinking song. You know,
we did, we pulled the Jimmy page when
we wrote it. Like out on the tiles.
I guess Jason Bond. I'm told that story
on, that's Super Group show on VH one
way back in the day,
right?
That I'm out on the tiles.
You know that de
[inaudible] weapon weapon dead,
dead,
but dead could go by Junko Beko but
Dadda Dadda ba Ba da Ba da Ba da Ba da by
debit,
but a dead dead.
[inaudible] MMM.
That was actually a drink at some,
I'm out on the towels.
I had a little Jenkin of some men of
something and I'm out on the Taos.
So Jimmy just, you know, I guess John came
in singing that and Jimmy's like, Ryan,
what said someone that's already
been written. Um, Mondays,
Mondays are made with sustainably
sourced material from beechwood trees.
They're naturally soft,
makes a fabric that won't sag
down or write up. Trust me.
Once you put on a pair, you'll get it.
Feel free to improvise here. A boy,
what you love about me on these,
I love the way it cradles my fucking nuts.
I'm Mandy's is. So you'll love your
first pair. If you're not happy,
they'll do whatever they can
to get you into the right pair.
They'll send a fucking horny and
had another one. And if they can't
keep them and they'll refund you.
So it's really is risk-free.
Try the best underwear ever.
And if you're already part of the me,
these fam,
what up fam? Tell your friends about
it through their referral program.
They'll get a discount and
you'll get a store credit when,
when it's like Amway meets
fucking underwear. Still not sure.
Well me undies has a deal for my
listeners. First Time purchasers get 50
10% off their first pair of me
undies and shipping is free.
That's 15% off plus free shipping and a
guarantee that you and your me undies,
we'll be happy to gather.
I can't see me wearing Noah
and these bud these against my
balls. Get your butt over to me
undies.com and treat yourself,
um,
me and you and you and me to get your
15% off your first pair for free shipping
and 100% satisfaction guarantee.
Go to [inaudible] dot com
slash [inaudible] that's
[inaudible] dot com slash bar
and lastly,
but not leastly
helix.com oh,
after this I'm going to tell you about
my standup setting had Leslie. Uh,
there's nobody on the planet like you.
You're special. You have something to say.
And by all means,
please emote about it on social media.
Do you know I actually tweeted
about this on the Twitter there.
They actually had a Hashtag a
hashtag things I don't tolerate.
Oh my God. It had to be the most self
serving fucking thing ever since.
Just as such an excuse for
everybody to see. What a wonderful,
open minded person you are.
Things they don't tolerate.
Dig It. Ci mean people, Pva,
tickle and people who are weaker.
Know is that all obvious shift
hashtag things that taste good.
Ice Cream, cookies. Um,
he works. Uh, there's nobody
on the planet like you.
So why the fuck would you buy a generic
mattress built for everyone else?
Maybe cause you hate shopping.
I don't know.
Next please mention all the talking points
below while I will, if you write it,
I'll read it.
Helic sleep matches your body to the
perfect mattress so you get the best sleep
of your life.
They developed nine different
mattresses tailored to specific person,
specific body types and sleep preferences.
All right, so everybody's different,
but there's only nine different designs.
Maybe there's all kinds of offshoots.
You're not like everybody else.
You're like one in nine
people. Uh, just go to a Heloc,
sleep.com/burr take their two minutes
sleep quiz and they'll match you to a
mattress that's perfect for you.
Controlling your body to provide
unprecedented and better sleep.
30% of Helix sleep.
Customers report better sleep
after switching to their
customized mattress from
Helen's sleep. Right now they're
offering, hey Neil, what's up? Come here.
The lovely knee,
everybody for up to $125
off all mattress orders.
Nia, do you realize that you're
a unique human being? Yes.
You're unique human being. You're only
like one out of every nine people.
One out of every nine. Well, these
guys make unique mattress. Not Yay,
said everybody's the same, but they
have nine different mattress types. Oh,
that's Hellickson, Kate, to get 125 wait,
is it hell no, I'm confused.
I don't know either.
If they never told me he looks okay.
Oh, I feel like I knew this
and now I don't remember.
Hey, you finish reading this.
Whether you're a side sleeper, hot
sleeper, like a plush or fun bed,
they've got the mattress that will fit
just right. Get up to 125% off at Helix.
sleep.com/. Burn. That's the Heloc.
sleep.com/burn for a $125
off your mattress order.
He looks sleep.com/burr.
There you go. Yeah. Does it rhyme
with Felix? I don't think it does.
I think it's Helux. I feel
like I knew this. I feel like
I gave you shit about it.
Okay. And now I don't remember. Now
you don't remember? Hey, so last night
I went, last night I
was out and about, uh,
went to a bobcat.
Goldthwait has a new show
on true TV called bobcat.
Goldthwait. Uh, was it
monsters and um, misfits,
misfits in monster or something like that.
I don't know what it is,
but it's on true TV. I watched an
episode of it last night. It's fucking,
it's classic bobcat. It's totally
original. If you just look up,
if you just search bobcat
Goldthwait right. If you do that,
you're going to find it. It's on
true TV. Well, those last name,
what was the last night?
Wednesday? Yes. Wednesday.
So Wednesday night at 10 o'clock on
true TV. That's all right. There you go.
So I went down to the premiere.
I got there late because
I was working as an actor.
I had to take off my little fucking
tight when I was done acting. Yeah,
I was feeling guilty because I wanted
to go down there. I had friends,
I had to see them,
but I hadn't done standup in a minute.
And I'm going to be in Portland
and Seattle this weekend,
so I got to shake the fucking rust off.
I wish I could go to Portland and Seattle
with you. Well Nia, it's only a
southwest or Alaskan flight away.
Yeah. I want to go. I want
to have a friend in Portland.
I've always wanted to see Portland and
I just feel like the microphone is so
close to my [inaudible].
Oh, sorry. Um,
yeah. And I've never been to
Seattle either. Both places.
I've been wanting to go.
I invited you. Yeah, you did.
Can I get back to my story? Oh,
sorry. So this is what I love
about La. So I'm walking out,
I ubered over right. Smoke a cigar with
one of my great friends in this business.
And then I was walking out going out,
man, I didn't do standup. Should I pause?
I don't want to fucking Uber over
there. And then Uber Home, fuck this.
So I just started walking home
and I walked by a fucking,
oh this.
And there was these young comics
parking out front, a comedy show coming.
They saw me coming down the
street and they laugh, hey,
want to go to a comedy show?
I now, and they go, do you
want to go up? I'm like, Nah,
thank you though. And then I walked
about 10 feet. I was like, fuck it.
I need to get a set in.
And I went in there and I did a set at
Hooters last night upstairs in the big
room, the main room in the main room.
It was a bunch of young kids there
while you were there? No.
What about the Buffalo Shrimp?
Yeah, I literally walked
in. It was awesome.
They put me on like the fucking president.
They put me on immediately. I went up.
I did. Um, of course bill, everybody
knows you at Hooters. I, um,
I went on and I said, I do tend to
15. I feel like I did around 12.
It felt like a 12. I got my labs, I shake
the rust off and I fucking walked out.
It was great. Perfect. Then I walked out,
walked halfway down the block and there
was a taxi, which I love old school,
and I got into it. I say, I say, you work.
And he goes, he goes, yes. And I got in.
I go, how you doing? He goes,
yeah. So, so I was like, all right,
I appreciate that. And he goes,
and he left this mother fucker where
they fucking fucking drive it home.
Just curse. I can be myself just
cursing everybody in the way.
So you had a good night last night? I
had a great night. Yes. Without alcohol.
I don't need it, man. Can we just
talk about Hooters for a second?
I really love the, the
Buffalo Shrimp. What is,
yeah, it's shrimp with buffalo
sauce. It's just like, oh.
And they give you like this blue cheese
dipping sauce to go with it. Oh my God,
it's too blue cheese
is the most disgusting.
One of one of the more disgusting foods.
You know that we watched an undercover
brother and they were talking about how
white people like white people, like
very underrated movie, by the way.
It's so funny. Yeah. Oh, um,
white people like Manet's and evidently
black people don't, I don't fucking know.
Um, my, whatever. I don't
know what I like Manny's
within reason. I like, man,
he's like, man, he's on fries.
I like mayonnaise on roast beef.
I like eating Manet's in front of
people that don't enjoy Manet's. Um,
no. I like, uh, but blue cheese
is just, fuck God. It's like
Buffalo shrimp and, and blue cheese.
Oh my God. It's just like, it's like a,
it's like mucus. It's gross.
I think when you eat wings,
you're just eat the wings. You don't
even use any of this size. No rant.
What about ranch? What do, what
are your feelings about ranch? Oh,
it's all right.
I just
know that for a man he is, you know, I
like ketchup. I like ketchup. Manet's
mustard. I like the Basic Maryam.
I'm a basic white dude.
I like pickles. Yup. Uh,
I like, I like a snake. Here's,
here's a nice little surprise here.
You can see that I've traveled.
I like a stuffed. All of
does that make me interesting?
Now my walking it out. Do you,
what's that? Some dance they did
in Atlanta. God from years ago.
Oh God. I'm on Instagram. I know. All
the latest dances are really neat.
I want you to get up and do
the mashed potato for me.
I got to get you to do a a in my
feelings challenge. All right,
go ahead and do it. Well, the dance,
you got to play the song. It's a dance.
It's a dance that you do to
Drake song called in my feelings.
I can't stand drinking. Do
you love me? Are you writing?
You haven't seen it. I can't.
I can't stand that guy.
Not Literally that guy you used to,
you use,
you use the electric. He used the
car, always whining about somebody.
It's just like he,
he's got this great life.
He's banging models and I've got to sit
there and listen to whining about the
model that he used to fuck. Who doesn't
call them back anymore? It's like Drake.
You would just fucking or she moved on.
He's emotional.
He isn't,
he's selfish.
Um,
but he loves magic magic.
I've seen like three different videos
of him running away after a trick.
That's what's really funny
about black people as you can.
You can see somebody hustling you,
lying to you and all that type of shit.
You know the like he just just,
you can smell bullshit
from a mile of fucking way,
but you get a magician does a card trick.
You guys run away like he's a witch.
Yeah. What the fuck was, yeah.
Cause that's that devil shit.
Fuck around with magic and it's that.
It's slight ahead near all that.
Oh No, that's the devil. Yeah.
If that guy could do that shit,
if that guy could do that shit,
he would just fucking like
levitate into a bank vault.
You wouldn't be fucking hustle and
doing magic on a street corner. Right.
It's still
it just playing with evil forces.
That's what the magic shit.
All right.
Play with evil forces with the magic shit.
You heard that that
should be on a tee shirt
playing with the evil forces,
with the magic shit
that has to be in a rap song has to be
in something I don't like hate Drake.
I just like, his fucking
music is just like, you don't,
you don't like those guys that just call
up and they just dump your day the day
on you. It's just like, dude,
you ever in a good mood?
What happened now Drake,
people are coming for him
trying to expose, you know,
his family life that he was trying
to keep private, you know? Yeah.
That's none of my business. I
call him anymore. That was weak.
That was week doing that shit.
[inaudible] we didn't start the
fire. All right. I gotta get,
I gotta get off my tape. Oh my God. I hate
is that video Charlie Chaplin.
Teddy Roosevelt fucking
people from the past.
Baba Baba [inaudible] stop
fucking avoiding the topic.
Saying a generation did
a lot of shitty things.
Trouble in this too is it's the worst
line ever. All right. Having said that,
I love a,
I like a lot of his songs.
I feel like you don't talk enough
about stuff that you enjoy.
I feel like you're now going to talk
about what you don't like about me and the
relationship.
Yep.
So I feel like you don't talk enough
about the things that you like.
You always talk about
what you can don't like.
And I just see what's going on and on how,
I love soccer and I hated
soccer and I love it.
But there's been this whole
fucking transformation. Yeah,
I missed that part because
you focus on the negative. No,
I think you have a nice guy.
He's such a hassle.
We finally became friends again.
We're buddies again because of the
work that I've put in like skews me.
What about me now?
I told you,
you becoming like this goth chick that
shops at hot topic. That was your vibe.
Gloom and doom.
A lot of really a modern references today.
Today not exist anymore. I don't
know. Do they? I don't know.
I haven't been to a mall in awhile,
so fuck you haven't,
last time I talked to you. Where
are you? I'm at the Grove. Oh yeah.
But they don't have a hot topic. So
do they still exist? I don't know.
They're high end. All
right, go ahead. Shit on me.
What do you got? No, no, you're right.
We're friends again after
having a little moment there.
So now I'm going to keep it positive.
I think you're great.
I think that you are stick with the devil
shit with the creepy vibes or whatever
the fuck you said. Um, oh God. Anyways,
I was trying to end on an upbeat
note. Um, who wore it better?
The Marvin Gaye beard.
Drake or Marvin Gaye. Oh,
Marvin Gaye. Obviously rock the Marvin
Gaye beard. Better than Drake would.
Who would that red hat better?
Marvin Gaye or Jacques Cousteau.
Marvin Gaye.
And now my goal is to try to get you,
not to say Marvin Gaye.
Um, who was more important? God,
I can't go that route. You'll
get upset with that one. Oh,
I didn't even have anything there.
Where'd you have to keep
saying Marvin Gates and Improv?
He should have to Jacques Cousteau.
Then I can go on the French way.
I had the ocean outlet. You
just paid him into a corner. Oh,
so it's my fault that you're
not, uh, I dunno. Good at Improv.
Yeah.
I killed upstairs at who?
In the big room and didn't even bother
to give buffalo shrimp. It's like, yeah,
I was too busy killing
upstairs at a hooter.
So when is your next uploaders see at
the Hooters and Hollywood and in the big
room? Well, I guess they're
moving, they're moving their
show across the street to,
uh, looters. I don't fucking know.
Whatever's across the street,
that fucking Hollywood boulevard,
you know, we didn't have,
we didn't have any fire for the cigars
there, so I had to go into tourist play,
have been fire cell.
We rubbed some matches bucket to gather,
um,
and went into one of those
touristy places and I bought a,
I love California lighter for my buddy
who hates la, which is worth twice.
And then it broke.
Yeah,
it was like three bucks and then it ran
out of lighter fluid. They're so cheap.
All those, like they're always going, hey
man, we got souvenirs for $5. It's like,
no, you need to be solidly
souvenirs for 50 cents, if that.
My favorite thing is when you go to
New York and they have that, you know,
that that foam rubber thing where you
wear the crown from the fucking statue of
Liberty. People walk around with that.
Like, I went to New York and I got this.
Can you imagine how many of those are
floating around the fucking ocean?
Some poor fucking porpoises trying to
swallow that thing. All right, we're out.
I'm out of time yet cause I got, I got
shit to do here. Or is it 52 minutes? Um,
thank you for coming on here
in bringing the positivity.
I try. I'll do better next,
huh? I'll do better next time.
You did great with Devil Shit
with the evil stuff over there.
Whatever the fuck you said. Um,
all right, that's the podcast.
Thank you everybody for
listening. Uh, you know,
my apologies to anybody out
there who is offended. Um,
I don't apologize. All right. That's
something that a mature adult does. Uh,
please enjoy the music and it'll half
hour of a greatest hits from a Thursday
afternoon podcasts just before Friday,
Monday morning
podcast, whatever. Fuck I say and
I have a great couple of days.
You can send a check in and
you're thirsty. Go fine.
[inaudible] [inaudible]
traveled as much as we have
[inaudible] live in houses.
Some of the slight,
the loose,
you guys see that car.
I just saw a commercial
for Kentucky Fried Chicken where the
parents are all excited because the two
bratty kids won't sit
still at the dinner table,
but they got them this fucking
chicken and they're feeding it to the,
basically very subtly saying that there's
drugs in this chicken that will make
you a spastic children. Chill the fuck out
and spastic. I mean like, you know, not,
not the way they mean it
over there in Great Britain,
you can't say that on the comedy.
So you can say it in a comedy club over
in Scotland, but you'll have a rough,
you'll have a rough go of it if you
say the kid was spastic over there,
that means like severely
mentally challenged over here.
It just means you're not
going to get laid to you at 26
when
you were in Grad school looking
over a fucking cadaver, right,
with some other fucking nerve narrowed.
Right.
And you're just sitting there going,
you know the ankle bones
connected to the knee bone. Right.
Has any of this made any sense?
What shouldn't?
It's fucking Sunday night and I am spent
and I got a whole bunch of Shit I have
to do tomorrow so I got to do it
tonight. All right, I'm off my game.
All right, you, you cleanse your liver and
like 42 43 days or something like that.
Every drunk guy knows has
told me that if he drunk,
I know that does not
have a medical degree.
Has told me that if you go 42 43 days
you will cleanse your liver at least to
the booze.
You know now if you fucking,
you start doing blow or a,
you know,
eating a bunch of trans fat fucking
food or feeding your kids Kentucky Fried
fucking chicken,
Jesus Christ.
What happened to parents
that you got a drug,
your kids to keep them under control,
you know, you know what it is.
Kids don't respect their parents, they
respect him, but they don't respect like,
oh my God, this, this
person could wring my neck,
could pick me up by my hair.
Right.
Could grab a paddle and fucking,
you know,
mostly hit my ass,
but also kinda hit my lower back
because I'm squirming right.
That doesn't exist anymore. So now these
kids are so fucking out of control.
These people have to go down to
Kentucky Fried Chicken. Okay.
And I,
I,
I use the term chicken very loosely
to go down and whatever that is,
that's in that bucket. Okay.
If it doesn't have a beak,
it doesn't have feet. If
it's fucking, you know,
justice, it's breasts is sticking out
like the cast on fucking, uh, what was,
what was that show with the Italians
there on New Jersey shore. Jersey shore.
Right. My world. That's
not a fucking chicken.
You know,
you want the chicken that looked like
Mark McGuire in his rookie season.
You don't want to eat the chicken.
That looks like mark McGwire when
he fucking played for the cardinals,
you know,
do you eat a regular fucking chicken?
First of all,
it's going to look like a pigeon to
you because you so used to seeing those
roided up once that they have murderer's
row that you got down there at your
fucking Shaws, right? You
Vons, you, JC Penney's,
wherever the fuck you buy your
goddamn chicken, you go down,
you go down to any one of the
main stream fucking supermarkets.
Okay. And I swear to God, when you get
to the chicken section, okay, if you,
if you slept for the last 30 years,
like that Van Gundy guy under the
bridge or whatever his fucking name is,
Van Morrison, the hell's his
name, Rip Van Winkle. Right.
It was one of those people,
one of the vans. Um,
if you slept for the last 30
years and you went down, okay.
And they showed you what a chicken
was, you'd be like, ah. You'd be like,
that ain't no chicken. Okay. It's a
goddamn Turkey. I know. Fucking yeah, die.
No fucking Turkey.
When I say what
I no such thing as a mad pad.
Fucking chicken can't
be done. No Sir. No Sir.
Get off my property. Okay. I'm, I'm
done with your witchcraft. Okay. Hey,
I said get the fuck Outta here.
The fuck off my property.
MMM
honey, get the gun. Um, yeah,
you would think it was a fucking Turkey.
And the thing is, is now it's a chicken.
And I remember I watched
one of those food inks,
one of those fucking liberal
goddamn things, you know,
talking about flying carpets in
electric roads and all that bullshit.
Somewhere in there they were
talking about, you know,
the food supply and I'll poison it
is poisonous poisoning than it is.
It is.
Um,
so I fucking went down to a
farmer's fucking mom and um,
I said, I wanna, I wanna,
I wanna all I want, I want,
I want an all natural fucking chicken.
I can't even talk. I'm so tired.
One an all natural chicken.
The guy goes,
these are all natural. And I said,
all natural. And he goes, well,
I'm like, come on, where is it?
And he had to walk around the
corner sitting over there, lonely.
I swear to God, looking like a dove look
going in. Somebody killed the fucking,
he goes right there.
That one right there is 100% all natural.
Nothing's wrong with it. And
I was like, I was like, what?
That's what a chicken is
supposed to look like.
And he raised his eyebrows and he,
he kind of put his lips together
so they were a straight line.
And then he nodded, you know, that
looked at people do like, like, yeah,
I'm in the Matrix. I realize
I'm in the Matrix. You know,
I knocked the bitch up so I got to be
selling these roided up chickens. No.
Um, anyways, anyway, what
the fuck I'm talking about?
So basically that's what these
people are eating over there. Okay.
There they are drugging up
their kids,
but I can't get mad at him because I
actually did that to Charlie Murphy and
Darnell Rawlings. I've told
this story before, Hey,
I'll tell it against my fucking podcast.
I actually drug I the exact thing that
they're doing in their Kentucky Fried
Chicken commercial where they're trying
to get their kids to sit still by just
feeding them so full of these fucking
trans fats from these roided up beatless
fucking chickens with their Dolly
Parton breasts. Disses right.
I did that to fucking Darnell and Charlie.
I was hung over and we taken a car
service from Chicago xannies up to one of
those whenever the fuck it was
Saint Charles was a three city run
and one of them was Saint Charles.
So we're getting in the fucking Limo,
Don L's in rare form.
Charlie's in rare form their fucking
Gavin and trash and people and me and
everybody and I just don't
want to hear it. I'm like,
I don't want to listen to these fucking
guys running that Goddamn yaps in the
back of this car the whole fucking way up.
I want a nice quiet ride.
This is going to suck.
And I walked outside,
hung over and I walked into
this Chicago where you know,
almost got hit by three
fat people. And, um,
I looked up the street and I saw it,
I saw Popeye's and I was like,
oh,
thank God.
And I fucking walked in there and I got
all this fucking Popeye's chicken with
biscuits and all of this shit food.
And I brought it back to the car.
And as the car pulled up,
they came out and I say, guys, I
got to sell some. I got some food.
And they were like, oh, that's
fucking great. You know,
they were hungry or whatever.
And they started showering that
fucking Popeye's food. And I sat back,
nibbling on drumstick,
and I swear to God,
10 minutes later they were asleep.
I'm not lying.
They were fucking asleep,
snoring the whole way up. And I was
just sitting there, loving life,
the whole fucking write up. And I, you
know what, I admitted to him later,
they thought it was funny,
but that's basically what it
is. They call it the Itis,
that's what they call it.
When you eat that shit food and
then you have to go to sleep,
they call it the Itis, I guess. And
by they, I mean African Americans.
Um, they call it the fucking
Itus and that's what the gut,
and I learned that from don because I
don't know how that man stayed in shape,
but he had the worst diet.
He's one of those guys who
like you stopped for gas
and he comes out of the gas
station with like one of
those gas station hotdogs
and he would eat it and then he would
immediately fall asleep. And I got,
I would say to Charlie, look at this guy
were, he's sleeping. And Chad be like,
yeah man,
he got the itis.
Let me explain that to me and what
that little bit of information,
it went into my evil white brain and I
drug my two African American friends way
back in the year 2005.
Um,
and that's a little chicken story for you.
What time did you like dad? Everybody.
So that's what the fuck
they're saying right there.
That's what Kentucky Fried
Chicken is allegedly saying.
I guess they have to say a legit,
so that lawyers on retainer don't attack
my fucking podcast as far as I can
tell. I'm asking you right now, uh,
Kentucky Fried Chicken hiding
behind your fucking letters, KFC.
Is that what the fuck you do?
Is that what you're saying?
Yeah.
If you've got kids who are not stimulated
enough that they can't even sit down,
if you haven't read yet to have run them
around, you got to tie your kids out.
Open the door. You send them out in
the fucking yard. Go ahead. Go outside,
get outside and play.
That's what you do.
Like a Goddamn one of
those fucking Irish dogs.
It was bred to have to to herd sheep.
You've got to let that fucking thing
run around. Run around in circles. Guy,
get out there, take a ball, and you
just fucking throw it out in traffic.
Let the dog run around. Dodgy cars that
comes in, it's going to lay down. Okay?
It's not going to jump all over.
Company sticking it's cold nose
right in their fucking who has.
That's what you gotta do with your kids.
You've got to send them outside, right?
But to catch a Predator and all
these other fucking shows, you know,
all these shows on TV where people
forget they're kids are in a car with the
windows rolled up.
Their kids are too fucking dumb to roll
them down or they're too weak because
they haven't gone outside and climb to
fucking tree and they stay in there and
their, their brains get
cooked like a boxer, you know?
Okay.
Do you know that dog boxes?
They know they don't do well in this sun.
Well we'll need to do fat kids. If you
leave the windows rolled up, you know,
and they got those weak arms at all.
That doesn't like the most tedious things
they ever did was take a wrapper off
of a fucking, uh, an ice
cream sandwich. Right?
You can't leave them in the car.
My mother left us in the car all the
fucking time. She would go to school.
She was going to school during the day
trying to further her education as she
left five fucking kids in the car with
the windows rolled up and money for
Burger King. And she would say
to us, just go into the Burger.
That's the only time you were
to leave this car over the left,
over the next three fucking
hours when I'm in class.
And she would disappear around the
corner after we set. Absolutely mom.
And she walked away. And uh, we
immediately would get out of the car,
start up and down the streets in Boston.
We go into fucking burger king and we,
we'd have something to eat.
Do you know what,
what happened?
Nowadays they just saw five fucking
dirty face kids walking up and down,
calm AV Boylston street
going into a burger king,
look like the cast to fucking nanny.
Someone would've filmed it and
my mother would have been in,
Jay would have taken
us away, you know, but,
but they didn't cause there was no
cameras back then or videotape ones.
I mean there was, but only the
people add them on like the news
and a young Steven Spielberg. So we went
in there and we fucking got some food,
Kline bunk cars and fucking yelled
at people and Shit, you know,
hanging on plant parking
meters and all that. Hence,
we had the fucking forearm strength to
roll down the windows and none of us ever
had an issue in the car.
And you know what?
I think that's one to grow on today.
You go people,
I'm not saying KFC is food,
I'm not, I'm just kidding.
I'm not saying it's bad food. Every
once in awhile, who's kitten home?
Every once in we don't go would be great
if he could just fucking do heroin the
way you can eat McDonald's. Just like
every once in awhile he'd just be like,
you know what? Yeah, let's
just fucking tie off.
Not off for the rest of the fucking day.
And like the people that work
understood it, you know? Hey,
where were you yesterday? Od and yeah,
I got this black tar heroin came in.
You know, I hadn't done it like three
months away. Figured fuck it. Oh,
is that what you did? How
was it? I wasn't, you know,
like, like you went to Aruba,
you said October was all ice.
I don't remember shit
she can do, you know,
you get addicted to
[inaudible].
That's fine.
Hey,
what's going on?
It's bill Belper and it is the
Monday morning podcast for Monday,
July 12th,
all la.
I'm sorry,
I was really gonna act like I could speak
Spanish there all although you'll soy
comical, anemia, maybe litchi
or numb on Santa Bent.
The loan A's Una COMESA.
I actually,
if you can't tell,
I've actually finally broken open my
Rosetta stone that I got for Christmas two
and a half fucking years
ago. Whatever it is. Yeah,
I got it for a year and a half ago.
December of 2008 I got
a the Rosetta stone.
Um, oh God. Yeah. Black or Negro.
Roho um, I, I got it, dude.
It's the shit. It's a shit.
I'm going to be fluent in Spanish.
I've always wanted to learn
another language and I am
trying to immerse myself.
That's what I'm trying to do. I'm trying
to immerse myself in the language.
I'm listening to it on the radio.
I'm also listening to it. Uh,
you know, I'm listening to shit
like this on a, on my iTunes,
hoping I can pick up some
shit. You know, you gotta,
you gotta immerse yourself in this shit.
You got to listen to stuff like this.
A fucking great.
Is that
got to have a fucking be able
to fucking no. What that means.
Sing that have pigment in my chest
so I can actually wear that open.
I'm going to go stab a ball.
Latino shirt.
How much pussy would you get if he
could fucking, it's just unbelievable.
It's half the shit that they say.
It sounds like fucking dirty talk when
you're banging a girl in need yet.
Pipit itchy. That means a girl who's
drinking them is drinking milk.
There's no way to say that without,
just sounded like you're fucking, yeah,
Nina. Vivid, itchy. Hey, next time
you guys are banging your girl. Okay.
You got a Doggie style. Just lean down in
her ear and just feel like, ah, it itchy,
needy of vivid,
itchy.
Shall we even have an orgasm or fucking
world around and elbow when you,
you in the face either way. Either
way. It's going to be funny,
but I want to be fluent in that Shit
and uh, I'm liking Rosetta stone.
I really like it. You sit there and
you put on like a, a bill, Bellamy,
Janet Jackson sort of headset,
you know, and uh, yeah,
you put it on some stretchy
pants and then you put,
you put in the fucking CD Rom or whatever
the hell it is. And then they just,
they just start speaking to you like
you're a baby sitting in the crib.
That's exactly what it is.
Two very stereotypical Mexican look and
faces just sort of peer into the screen,
like you're laying in the crib and then
they just start speaking to you and they
tickle your tummy. It's, it's
tremendous. It's a tremendous,
it's a tremendous way to
nom. I'm just fucking around,
dude. It's awesome. It's a,
if you ever thinking about
doing it, like, you know,
I always wanted to learn to
speak a different language.
Whenever I rode the subway,
I was nervous that Puerto Rican
through actually calling me bad words.
What does [inaudible] mean?
Um, is that even Puerto Rican?
This is what's killing me.
This is how fucking what I am.
I actually believe that I'm
going to learn this shit. Uh,
El Nina Bibliology,
I'm going to learn this shit and uh,
therefore I will be able to go
to Mexico, Cuba, Puerto Rico,
Brazil or whatever, and be able to
understand every motherfucker out there,
even though people I know this dude
who is Cuban and he tells me it's,
it's really different. Not totally
different, but, um, I mean, I don't know.
He seemed a little peeved when I was
like, yeah, and I can go to fucking Cuba.
I can go to Dominican Republic.
It's not the fucking same thing.
All right, sorry. You know
when it's one of those things,
I'm not even trying to be offensive and
I offended you, but it's like, you know,
do you think when I go to Ireland
or I went, I went to Scotland.
I can understand those fuckers,
everything that they said,
but I knew what they was saying.
Am I being ignorant right here?
Do you guys, is it a complete,
it's not a completely different
language. Ah, they'll,
Nina Bibby lit.
You can't say that and fucking Cuba
and they won't know what you're talking
about. Is that because economy, communism,
you know,
I already stopped this podcast and
started it again because I'm doing this
Sunday morning.
My fucking brain isn't awake yet.
Stuttering like a goddamn jackass.
Ah.
Pantaloneys Sabbat
doors will not come Isa.
I can't fucking wait. I can't wait
the first time somebody from uh,
I was going to say somebody from
another language. That's how dumb I am.
Somebody speaking Spanish talk shit
about me because I'll tell you right now,
I would fucking do it all the time.
I would do it all the Goddamn time.
If English was the second language was
not the main language of this country.
And I had another English speaking
friends in and I was walking around people
who did not understand English and it'll
be our own little private language.
I would be shitting on people,
right and left perverted stuff.
Can you imagine that? If nobody understood
English, everybody just spoke Spanish,
right? Your bosses, some can't,
but she's got a nice rack and you sit
in there and she could literally walk by
and like, dude, I would tit, fuck
this bitch right on a Goddamn desk.
And then turn around me. Oh
La me boss. Ah, you know,
no wonder they're so fucking laid
back. They can get it out. I gotta sit.
I got to sit on all this goddamn rage
because I don't have some secret fucking
language. All right. All right. Mexicans.
I mean you fucking hide out and
I'm breaking down your code.
So I'm telling you this time next year,
you better watch your tongue. Okay, good.
All the I could turn learning
another language seat,
see it and see here me stuttering.
It's in the morning only I could turn
speaking another language and my only,
I could turn a the language,
relax Mexico,
just relax.
Just really listen to a couple of my
podcasts and realize how fucking stupid I
am. And also how I get totally psycho
into something for about 10 days.
And then I just walk away from it and
then it just sits there gathering dust on
my desk.
Anyways,
so it was a big week this weekend
in sports. It's actually, uh,
what time is it right now?
It's 10 43 and this is the funny thing.
In 17 minutes,
the World Cup final is starting,
which is basically the championship,
one of the true
championships of the world.
It's the entire world competes for it.
And as big a fucking sports fan as I am,
I could give a shit.
The only thing that I would find less
interesting than the World Cup final was
the Lebron James Hour long
press conference to announce
what team he's going to
fucking go to. You know,
that's actually bullshit.
I totally respect the game of soccer.
It just,
it fucking bores the shit out of me.
And A,
we have a number of soccer fans on here
and they send me emails and they get mad
at me. They say, says, Dear Bill Dude,
until you have a better
understanding of the game,
you gotta stop ragging on soccer.
Find someone that knows a little bit
about the game and take some fucking time
and watch a couple of games.
Dude, watch the World Cup finals.
Uh, exclamation point. What?
Cause you fucking say so. Um,
do you realize that if you added up
everyone that watched the NFL, the NBA,
the Nhl,
and MLB,
you would only have about half as
many people that watch soccer do.
Do you realize that?
I'm not so fucking stupid that I don't
realize that you just pulled that stat
out of your ass.
Give me some numbers you didn't.
You said you would have about
PAF is about really? Yeah.
You're going to guesstimate there.
Put that in your pipe and smoke it bill.
Thanks dude. All right.
This is the deal. All right.
I'm so sick of these fucking soccer
cunts trying to convince me that it's an
exciting sport. Do you think that
I haven't sat down and watched it
earlier this year when I watched
the Olympics, I got into curling.
I was watching the cross country skiing.
Will you shoot the gun?
I'm very open minded when
it comes to sports. Okay.
But to sit there and killed two,
three fucking hours of my day to watch
a zero to zero fucking game and watching
these guys flop around like a bunch of
Goddamn POW goes Saul's every 10 fucking
minutes. It's, it's, I try, dude.
I tried it just because the whole
fucking world is watching the sport.
Does it mean that I should?
All right.
The whole world was wearing an acid wash
jeans and the lay fucking eighties I
followed that trend and I
got the embarrassing God
damn pictures to prove it.
Where the fuck did that get me?
You know what I like about soccer?
I like the highlights,
the highlights, you know,
and they show it in slow motion motion.
Absolutely gorgeous sport to watch,
but to sit there for fucking two hours
listening to those God damn mosquito
horns, you're really
asking too much. All right,
everybody flopping around like a
bunch of God damn fucking girls.
Get off the goddamn ground.
Fucking pussies.
The guy doesn't even touch you
and you flop around on the ground.
It's so a feminine. That's what
I can't stand about that sport.
You know this guy did bring
up a good point. He goes,
you're telling me the basketball
players. Yes. Basketball players do.
Basketball is a very fucking a feminine
sport when it comes to that shit.
That fake fucking flopping around.
Yeah,
no other, you know, that's the
closest thing. I'm trying to think.
There's a couple guys in the NHL,
look,
there's always going to be a couple
of broads in every sport, you know,
but at least in, in, in the NHL
soccer fan, you know what they have,
they have a penalty for pretending that
somebody hit you two minutes. You get,
it's called diving.
Two minutes for diving,
get up you fag and getting
the Goddamn penalty box.
I was, I dunno, I, I, dude, I tried. I
fucking tried. I tried to watch the shit.
I don't give a fuck.
Um,
I find the Premiere League
way more enjoyable to watch.
I can watch that game, but I got to
tell you like, I don't know what it is.
I start to get a headache and I get a
little bit of a stomach ache when I'm
watching it because the amount of
effort that I have to put in to,
you know,
do,
to sit there and in two hours of your
fucking life to watch a one to nothing
game. That's why, you know,
so I think I finally figured out why
they fight in Nhl hockey cause you can
actually have a one to nothing
fucking game. So, you know,
then we basically have guys going, it's
legal to smash somebody's, you know,
against the boards. You can
drop the gloves, he could fight.
There's a lot of other exciting things
that, that, that do happen. All right?
But to sit there for two fucking hours.
Oh my God. Oh my God. Oh my
God. Ah, yeah, yeah, yeah,
yeah. Ooh, ah,
it's the sports equivalent
to fucking blue balls.
I don't fucking like it. I really
don't. I just don't. I don't like it.
I don't fucking like it.
Okay.
And you can't make me fucking like
it because the whole world likes it.
All right. Is this is a major part
of the fucking world that, you know,
they, they take out a high grade piece
of sandpaper and then they, they,
they rubbed the girl's fucking clips off.
That doesn't mean that I think it's
right. Wow. That was really disgusting.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry. 12 minutes into
the podcast, getting that fucking gross.
I should have saved that towards
the end for the die hard fans. Um,
so anyways, that, that Lebron
James Announcement, um,
speaking of mind numbingly boring.
Um,
I listen to think about fucking
soccer. Like I'm invited to this, this,
this party where they're going to watch
the finals and whenever you find a
person who's really into
soccer, you know, yeah,
they always get like the
little soccer shirt on.
They always have like these little
fucking wimpy torsos. If you notice,
that was the last time you saw somebody
jacked that was into fucking soccer.
You don't always have like those little
fucking, those little European torsos,
you know,
your little seventh grade bodies.
It does anybody lift weights or do
pushups or anything in fucking Europe?
Do you just,
you just take the torso God gave you and
then you just start stuffing fish and
chips down your fucking throat and you
just let it all sort of slide down until
you look like Jethro Tull. Um, all right.
I think I've tried that shit enough.
Let's trash in American sports.
Let's talk about fucking
Lebron James and his fucking,
first of all, his howdy doody
puppets shirt that he wore. You know,
there really is this theory out there
that black guys are so cool that they
really can wear any type of clothing
and make it look good. Well,
that was an example when it doesn't
quite always work. I mean, that was a,
I don't know what that was.
That looked like he was going to go
sing on the Grand Ole Opry in like 1948.
Um, all right, the fuck
am I talking about?
Let's get into this whole
podcast thing. Alright. Uh,
the Lebron James one hour announcement
for everybody out there who's saying how
fucking lame it was. Um, you
know who's fault that is?
It's your own God damn fault.
It's your own fucking fault for
sitting there and watching it. Okay?
It's not like ESPN lied.
They told you what it was going to be.
[inaudible] this is going to be a one
hour special of an athlete announcing
which team he's going to go
fucking play for. I mean,
how long should that realistically take?
It's like the fucking Oscars.
How long should it take to be and to,
to take to just fucking be like
in the Oscar goes to Sean Connery
and the Oscar for the best fucking
dress in a period piece goes to Claire,
Bill Billingsley,
Bill Billingsley clear bill Billingsley
fucking Douche bag. Go Burn.
Not even fucking awake.
Trying to do a podcast to get it out of
the Goddamn way to go to some stupid ass
fucking party that's showing the finals
of a sport that he doesn't give a fuck
about. That starts in
nine minutes. Oh my God.
Somebody hit fucking
record. Um, yeah. I mean,
you knew what the fuck it was going to
be. Why did you even watch it? I mean,
can't you tell that that day,
that guy just got some fucking horrific
and he just got horrific advice from his
people around him who they were just like,
we're going to create the biggest
media stir ever. All right,
we'll go to Chicago first. We'll gain
some interests. We'll go to the Knicks,
we'll get some interested. We'll
go down and fucking man, oh,
where the fuck is he going to?
Who gives a shit?
Nobody cares except the people in
those fucking towns. I gotta tell you,
I really did enjoy him. Fucking, you know,
tear in the hearts on in
Knicks fans because as always,
New York fans are the most fucking,
just like a,
that's the sense of entitlement that
fans of New York sports have just because
they live in New York City.
If I have to watch one
more fucking asshole on TV,
talk about the big stage in
New York. Okay. Overrated.
Underrated for this week. Overrated.
The big stage in New York,
there's only one big stage in New York.
It's in fucking Yankee stadium.
That's the only big stage that is in New
York. 27 championships. You go there,
there is pressure to win.
What is this big like when Lebron
didn't pick fucking in New York? I'm on,
you know, I'm online and I read three
comments and I'm like, there you go.
That's enough evidence for me.
I'm going to judge every new
fan in New York right now.
They were all sitting there going like,
oh, he was afraid of the bright lights.
He couldn't handle the big stage
of New York. Let me ask you this,
Nick fans,
where is the big fucking stage for
professional basketball in New York City?
Huh? Madison Square Garden, that place,
the biggest thing that happens in Madison
Square Garden every year is Elton John
comes there and sell. He fucking
sells out 20 shows. You know
Bruce Springsteen comes there and
sings his songs about New Jersey.
The circus comes once a fucking year.
Those are the biggest days every year.
And Madison Square Garden.
All right, and in case you don't
know what I'm talking about,
next time you go there and there's
yet another horrific played by May,
by either the fucking
rangers or the Knicks,
and you look up and discussed to that,
to the sports gods,
like what the fuck?
When you're done praying for some messiah
to come in there and save those two
pathetic fucking franchises,
look up at the ceiling
and tell me what you see.
A striking lack of
championship fucking banners.
I'll even give you the goddamn
answers you dumped. Fucks.
There is no big stage and
it's so fucking disrespectful.
I've everybody to say that all the
fucking time. Talking about Amy,
you know when they talk about
the biggest stage in, in major,
Major League baseball team, what do they
say? Fenway Park. How about Saint Louis?
Say they got,
they got 10 fucking world series titles.
That's not even a good example.
It's not like the Knicks are in
second place with titles. Dude,
Yankee stadium is the big stage and
made major league baseball. Okay?
The fucking Celtics have
17 NBA championships that
we're all one in Boston.
All right. The Los Angeles Lakers,
11 titles have been one there.
They once a year they hold hands with
somebody from Minnesota and they add the
five that we're in. That's,
that's the thing right there.
The Minneapolis Lakers have more
titles than the fucking New York next.
Do you guys understand that?
That a team that's dead,
that fucking moved west.
All right.
That moved fucking West around the same
time the Brooklyn Dodgers went out to la
still has three more
fucking titles than you do.
You don't have a big stage there and
nobody is afraid to play in New York City
and there's certainly not afraid
to play the fucking Knicks.
So get off your own dicks.
I'm sick of it. All right.
The jets haven't won it since 69 the
Knicks haven't wanted since 73 the mets
haven't won it since fucking 86
who else has left? The giants
are, are a respectable franchise.
That's the best you have. You have
a respectable franchise that is one.
The same amount of Superbowls is the
patriots, the packers, the Redskins,
and the Raiders.
The giants are in the middle of the pack.
All right?
There's no big fucking stage.
And they sit there and they act like
these sports writers in New York.
These fat man tinted jackasses,
these fill mush nics are going intimidate
a guy at the level of fucking Lebron
James. They're not. I hate to
tell it to you in New York.
The reason why he didn't go to Madison
Square Garden is cause she has suck.
That's why,
I mean think about that.
Who the fuck wouldn't want to
go play in New York? You know,
New York is the city is the
Paris of fucking of America.
It's the best fucking city we have.
All right.
But just because there's a bunch of
people outside of Madison Square Garden
succeeding and doing some shit,
most of whom aren't even
from New York by the way.
That's another thing.
New Yorkers think they're the shit
just because they live there just
because they're standing on the corner
of fucking 52nd and third eaten a slice.
You know, if I can mark it
there, I'll make an anywhere.
Are you really making it with your dirty
fucking sneakers standing there outside
of Tad steaks?
You're not doing shit.
None of you are all you fucking pieces
of Shit fucking gathering outside of
fucking port authority.
Yeah. That's another thing of, Oh
man, I'm trashing the York this week.
I don't give a fuck. Listen to me. I
don't give a fuck who bill. Really?
You're being dangerous.
It's dangerous to make
the alarm Bray and a data resol.
Um,
do Frank Sinatra's from New Jersey.
Okay. He was bridge and tunnel.
Okay.
The kind of the kind of guy that Paris
Hilton wouldn't have fucked in one of her
whore night clubs down there
in the meatpacking district.
If he came in and said,
oh,
I live in Hoboken,
she would have turned a little pointy
nose up to the ceiling and walked away,
or in a big fucking Sasquatch
feet that she tries to hide.
Bye Jack. And a god Goddamn fucking
ass in the air to eye level.
No girls would have banged that guy.
But what did he do? He came in there,
he came in there and he fucking sang a
song and he took over your fucking city,
the way a bunch of people from other
states that you fucking New Yorkers looked
down on.
We come in there all the time.
We come in there and we blow away half
the fucking talent in New York because
you guys are standing there
eating a slice of pizza,
looking at the fucking empire state
building going, oh, it's open all night.
You're not doing shit.
You don't have a big stage.
You have a sorry ass fucking NBA team.
You know this.
How dumb the fucking nics are.
Isaiah Thomas,
there was a league called the CBA that
did find for like 30 fucking years and
then s what's his face?
Isaiah Thomas.
Thomas became president of the
league and in like three, four years,
I don't have the fucking stats. I don't
know, five years. It went out of business.
Okay. I'm not talking about, you know,
a winning franchise went
to a losing franchise.
I'm not talking about a
franchise that existed in a city,
had to move.
I'm not even saying the franchise folded.
I'm talking about an
entire fucking league.
He got it to controls.
He pushed the yolk forward and just flew
the shit right into the goddamn ground.
All right?
And like bugs bunny.
He stepped out right before it hit the
ground before any of it got on him and
then the next go.
Yet that's our guy.
That's the guy we're going to get to
run the f a fucking NBA franchise.
The guy who fucking
flew bootleg NBA into the goddamn
ground. That's the fucking dude. See,
that's why Lebron didn't come.
Not because he's afraid of the big stage.
You want to know who is afraid
of the big stage? Jeff Weaver.
Jeff Weaver was afraid of the big stage.
Okay?
But Lebron James is not afraid
of the big, the big stage. Okay?
He could fucking put his nuts on Jeff
waivers chest and hold them down in the
deep end of a fucking pool.
All right?
He's not afraid of fucking
Madison Square Garden
and I also thought it
was really fucking ironic
of the three emails that
I read by New Yorkers,
which I'm now judging all of them,
they were going like, you know Miami.
That's Dwayne Wade's town. If he goes
down there and wins a championship there,
nobody's going to respect him.
Can you fucking believe a New Yorker had
the balls to say that with the fucking
pile on team that the Yankees have
been for the last 12 fucking years?
Every goddamn free agent on the fucking
planet just clinging to Derek Jeters
leg. Show me how to do
it. I want to win one too.
Huh? Roger Clemens, that fat buffalo wing,
Eaton Jackass. Was it
hard up in Toronto? Roger.
Then he fucking comes down there
and jumps in the fucking Limo.
The fucking balls are these New York
fans to sit there and question somebody's
piling on another team to go in a fucking
championship. I, I can't even take it.
I think I've got to drink some throat
coat tea that I mentioned that on this
podcast cause I already deleted the
other one when I was annoyed with how
fucking unfunny I was.
Um,
ground when I go out on a limb here and
say that the ratings for this in New
York City are going to be kind of low
this week I've got this throat coat tea,
which is a great, if you stand on stage
and you don't know how to write a joke,
you have to scream at jokes or even
feel like to call your girlfriend and
comment at the top of your lungs.
You know, you have to do that.
And then the next day you want to do it
again. But you throw his two tore up.
You can't do it. Well get organic
throat coat tea. Everybody.
You could call your girl account seven
days a week. Three and 65 days a year.
That'd be a great commercial, right? Just
have the girl crying in the background.
Sitting down in the fetal position is
you're fucking sitting in the field.
Fetal position bill curled up
in the fetal position bill.
He had dumb fuck. All right, let's see.
What did I do so far in this podcast?
I pissed off anyone who isn't from America
or I guess you know
Americans who are also into soccer and
then I trashed a a giant media market.
See right there bill.
That's why New York is such the
big stage because it's worded
the biggest media markets in
all of the fucking cook for you.
How pathetic are you fucking teams that
you've got to bring up the level of
media in your city,
the level of media gimme a fucking break.
Two Championship banners,
1970 fucking three do you know in 1973
the Chevy Vega was considered a sports
car.
And if you go on the game show network,
people lose their fucking
minds about that car, you know,
and you can win.
And then they opened the current
Brad Little Chevy Vega and these people
with their fucking big Greg Greg Bait,
Brady fucking belt buckles,
and they're fucking,
ah, who's that dude from? Knocked
up, observe and report their,
there's Seth Rogan fucking Afros go
absolutely fucking ape shit over a Chevy
Vega.
That's when you guys won it last.
People from are dying of old
fucking age on that team.
Who Do you have an attorney? Who are
the fucking, the Nix, the greats.
Who Do you got?
Bill Bradley Dodd.
He became a senator and
then he fucking died.
This is what it is.
You want to get down to brass tacks here?
What's really bugging me is, uh, in
Boston we only have four sports teams.
Okay. We're playing a fucking, you know,
we got one, one bullet in the chamber
and those cuts down there in New York,
they're doubled down in two out of
the four fucking sports every year.
This split and fucking aces
in two different sports.
So they pad their stats with
championships. But I respect the Yankees.
The Yankees are the greatest
franchise in an an all for sports.
They got the fucking championships.
You have to respect it. They got them.
And I would never ever try to act like
somebody was afraid to play in Boston
because of the media or whatever the fuck
that you know or call it the big stage
in Boston.
All right.
I would never do that out of
respect for the fucking Yankees.
The fact that they have 20 more
fucking championships than we do.
Okay,
so give me the fucking respect that
I deserve as a Boston Celtics Fan,
that we have 15 more fucking NBA
championships than you do fucking idiots.
The big state.
I'm so sick of these fat
mantated shitheads with their
fucking game worn jerseys
and they yell shit at players on the
field and they think that they're
intimidating them.
You know like the fact that you got a d
up Kobe Bryant that you know that night
isn't enough to make you nervous?
No,
it's the fat fuck with the
shaved head and fucking row 58 g
who Stew's Chanten airball it. They don't
care. They don't even fucking hear it.
They don't even hear it. Lebron James
is not afraid to go to New York.
He wanted to win. All right? That's
why the fuck he went to Miami.
But uh, you know, and I would really
love it and this is the deal if,
if the fucking Lakers didn't exist,
um,
with this stupid tee shirts claiming that
the Los Angeles Lakers have fucking 16,
because that's what the t shirt says.
It says Los Angeles
Lakers 16 championships,
not Los Angeles Slash Minneapolis Lakers.
Um,
so now I have to become a Miami heat fan.
I really do. But just for the record,
dude, I don't like any of this shit.
I didn't like the 2008 Boston Celtics.
I didn't like that either.
Where you just go out and,
and just everybody piles on one team.
I don't fucking like it.
I don't like this age of the super teams.
It's a,
yeah, I don't even, that's not, I don't
know what it is anymore. It's like the,
it's like a,
it's sports are becoming like what
wreath retail stores have become.
They're all like these super stores now.
There's not like just the regular
hardware store. That example,
I use every podcast.
It's always a hardware store with me,
but fucking one trick pony. It's
all fucking, it's all Walmarts now.
Home depots best buys,
all of that type of shit.
And uh,
I dunno,
it's not the same kind of pride like,
uh,
that you had back in the day when you
watched red Arrow back get some unknown
center from Golden State.
You know Robert Parish,
who the fuck knew who he was before he
came to the Celtics and he goes after
Kevin Mchale wasn't a highly touted
draft pick and then Larry Bird,
he works on for like three fucking years
and gets them to come to the Celtics
like that with some interesting shit.
But nowadays when you got
shit like Kevin Mchale,
a former Celtic is working for the
grizzlies and he gives the fucking Celtics
Kevin Garnett for nothing,
for nothing.
Decimates an entire fucking franchise.
The same way Jerry West is fucking
working from Memphis and gives the fucking
Lakers Pau Gasol for nothing. I mean,
it's, I don't know. I don't fucking know.
And the fact that these fucking knick
fans are sitting there talking about that
guy piling on as the god Damn Yankees
are Erin negotiations to try to get cliff
Lee. Like they don't have enough
with fucking sabbatical. Aja Burnett,
Marianna Rivera,
fucking Alex Rodriguez,
Al fucking to share all those guys.
I love all the names of fading away cause
I don't even watch baseball anymore.
It's such a fucking stupid goddamn sport.
Um,
dude, if the Yankees got cliff Lee, you
might as well just mail them the trophy,
you know, and um, this is what it is.
I Dunno if I'm just as crabby old man.
I'm really trying to find the art in,
uh,
signing all these free agents because
it just seems to me like whoever has the
most fucking money
will eventually get most
of the best guys in.
Occasionally you'll lose out on a guy,
occasionally a cliff Lee,
we'll go to the rangers,
you know,
or somebody will pick the fucking angels
or maybe they'll go to the fucking red
sox or something like that.
But generally speaking,
you start with the fucking Yankees
and then it just goes down. I Dunno,
I just doesn't seem like there's any
fucking skill that I had just spent over
five. You know what it is. I'm on my
fucking period this week, half hour a rag.
Ragging about that shit. Let's get to uh,
let's keep, let's just totally fucking,
uh, make a left turn here. And, uh,
somebody asked me some for
some advices week. All right,
here we go. This is, this
is now, this is a quote.
This is a situation that I think a lot
of people that all embrace can deal with.
Um, let's see here. Uh, hey
bill, huge fan. Love you. Comedy.
Pull a good book, but the hope
this won't get too long. Um,
it starts with one of my good
friends going out with this girl. Uh,
they went out for a body of right
off the bat. You know, you can't,
can't you tell where this is going?
This story starts with one of my good
friends going out with this girl.
They went out for about a year or
two to honor on and off. Come on,
Bill. Focus here. Just try to
read this smoothly. All right,
let's start over and starts with one of
my good friends going out with this girl.
They went out for about a year or
two on and off. I'm still though,
even when they were together,
they were never really good in quotes.
Here we go.
They fought basically all the time and
just didn't seem right for each other
though.
G Gee,
you know where this is going during
the early stages of their relationship.
My friend thought I had
a thing for her old Judy.
She's a,
she is a good looking girl.
She is a good looking girl and I was
friends with her before they even got
together.
Dude,
you are so justifying what the fuck
you either did or about ready to do.
I love it.
They weren't really good for each other.
Even when they were together, they
just, there was something missing.
I actually knew her before
he did. Um, here we go.
She is a good looking girl and I was
friends with her before they were even
together.
I admit I might have inadvertently been
a little flirty with her sometimes.
Oh, I'm sorry. It was I just flirting
there. Do you have a future at uh,
at BP the next time they pollute an
entire Gulf of a nation that they're not
even citizens of and they need to bring
somebody out to stand behind the podium.
Dude,
this is fucking great.
I might have inadvertently
been a little flirty with her.
How the fuck do you even do that? How do
you inadvertently flirt with somebody?
Why are you really look beautiful in
that dress? I'll tell you if you will.
My girlfriend, I have a debit.
Duh. I mean, wait, what the
fuck do you go with? Oh,
I'm sorry. I'm sorry. That's right.
You're not my girlfriend. I'm sorry.
I thought you were my girlfriend for a
second. What was I thinking? Jesus Christ.
I'm so embarrassed. My face
turning red. Oh my God.
I was just inadvertently
flirting with you right then. Ah,
Jesus. Uh, here we go. But he
goes, this is what he says.
I might have inadvertently been a
little flirty with her sometimes,
but that shit always happens
with a guy and a girl.
I think do the level of
guilt just weighing you down
as you're trying to justify
all of this? Uh, either
way I told him, um,
I didn't like her,
which was true dude,
stop lying to yourself
anyways, it passed. However,
I always got this
feeling that there was a,
there was still an undertone that
he resented me since then. Yeah.
Probably because of all the inadvertent
flirting and the fact that you were
emoting that they weren't right for
each other. Um, but anyways, let's,
let's, let's fast forward as
he says, fast forward now.
They've been broken up for at least
a year and don't talk. She says,
uh, he randomly texts
her Texas, her texts her,
Jesus Christ. I can't even fucking
read. She says he randomly texted her,
but uh, that she doesn't ever
answer him. But regardless of that,
now this girl likes me. What? Oh my God,
I didn't see that coming.
Wait a minute. Anyways,
but she actually likes me and basically
says she wants to fuck my voice.
Just cracked in the perfect.
Says she wants to fuck.
Am I getting excited?
I need some more throat coat here and
basically says she wants to fuck. Um,
she tells me stuff like she wishes she
went out with me instead of him to begin
with.
Now I do all right with girls,
but I don't have them
lining up or anything.
So I'm not trying to let a
virtual shirt thing passed me by.
Oh my God. And this is when it's
getting Jerry Springer here.
Uh, with most guys. I don't, I,
I'd feel like they'd not care if I went
forward or at least understand why I
did.
Do you realize what you're saying?
I think most guys wouldn't care if their
best friend went out and bang their
fucking ex-girlfriend within
a year of them going out.
I think that they'd understand.
So anyways, he goes,
I think most guys wanted to stand,
but this buddy of mine is a little nuts
and it's also a situation where he's the
type of guy that if he were in my
position, he do the same thing. Ah, dude,
you just justifying, you don't even need
my advice, you're going to do it. Um,
my other friend who knows the
whole situation says I should,
but others I've talked to
about it. Say I shouldn't. Uh,
the last I talked to her,
she said she wanted to hang out just me
and her and then I should let her know
when I want to. Uh, all right. I
guess this seems getting kind of long.
I have one question.
Do I have any justification and
fucking this girl and two, if I do,
would you say I should go through with it?
Okay.
All right,
sir.
There there's just this just a
ton of shit going on here. Okay.
Right off the bat. Um, you have
to be honest with yourself.
All right? You weren't inadvertently
flirting with this girl.
You actually probably,
uh,
like this girl before this guy even got
with her. Or maybe the fact that the guy,
your friend got with her
and he was banging her,
made you all of a sudden interested in
her. See, I don't know you as a person,
you could be a very sadistic,
a human being. Actually,
I'm going to go out on a
limb and say you're not,
because the fact that you actually
give a fuck enough to write me and ask
whether you should do this,
that means you actually have
some sort of guilt about it. Um,
so you won't get off on bang in
your fucking, uh, best friends,
ex-girlfriend a two. There's a lot of
shit here that could blow up in your face.
Okay? In a perfect world, all right,
you're a man and you say,
you know what a,
that's not going to be worth
the, the, the blow back.
It's not going to be worth the
fucking damage that I'm going to do.
This guy's my best friend.
I don't even though he would do it to me,
I'm not going to do it to him.
And then I also need to stop being
friends with this guy because anybody who
would go out and fuck my ex girlfriend
within a year is not truly a friend.
I need to get better friends.
But despite all that,
I'm still not going to do what the
fuck he would have done just because he
would've done it to me.
And you just walk away from the situation
and you go out and you chat up some
other fucking broads. That's, that is
like, if you want to be knighted someday,
buy one of those fucking broads over
there and a in the castle in England,
you know, if you want to go over there
with Surf Surf Phil Collins looking on
and get knighted,
that's what the fuck you do.
But if you're going to bang this broad,
um,
you've already fucked up.
Okay.
Fucking your best friend's ex girlfriend.
It's like committing a murder you
want is few people involved is humanly
possible.
I learned that on an episode of uninformed
when we had a cop come in and me and
my, uh, cohost Joe to
Rosa were saying that,
um, you know, we were trying to come up
with how to commit the perfect murder.
And I remember said, okay, I get me and
a buddy of mine, he goes right there,
you fucked up right there. You fucked up.
He goes, the more people you bring in,
the bigger chance you have
of getting caught. You know,
cause you're not going to rat yourself
out. But the other guy, if he gets scared,
might go down to the police station
and try to cop a plea. All right?
That's the same shit with this. If you're
going to fuck your best friend's girl,
ex-girlfriend, you don't go around
and ask other friends going, dude,
should I do with
you?
Don't.
And you already did. All right.
And then the other side of it is,
mmm, I don't know how the
two of these people broke up,
but uh,
you know,
Hell hath no fury like a woman scorned.
And for all, you know, this
chick might be a fucking psycho.
All right? I mean, I
think it's a good thing
that he's texting her and
not the other way around
and that she is not texting him back.
Granted,
you're taking her word for it,
that that's what the situation is now.
For all you know, it's the
reverse. And if it is the reverse,
she wants some sort of vengeance,
which means she goes out and bangs his
best friend and then low and behold feels
guilty the next day and then
has to tell him, all right,
just to let you know
that is on the fucking table.
If you really want to know whether or
not you want a jerk, if you want a jerk,
if you want to fucking,
I got ahead of myself here.
If you want to fuck this girl and not
just go jerk off to her and after he had
done,
if you still want a Banger,
you want a banger and then just fucking
man up and deal with the fucking
consequences of it and go out and
bang her because who gives a fuck?
Because someday you're going to be
80 and who gives a shit, you know?
Or on the other side, if you actually have
feelings for this girl, that's a whole,
then you should definitely do it.
If you actually feel like this girl could
be the girl that you're going to spend
your life with,
then I would definitely say go for it.
Knowing full well that your
friendship with this other guy is, uh,
is going to end. MMM. I Dunno.
So Dude, you know what, it's
fucking on you. You know,
if you asked me what I do at a yeah,
I would have back in the day I would have,
but now that I'm an older,
wiser man, I wouldn't,
I would just fucking rub one out to
her and then be afterwards going, oh,
thank God I didn't fucking do that.
Thank God I didn't do that. And I was,
I would also fucking not hang out with
the other guy because any guy friend of
mine that would fuck an ex girlfriend
of mine within a fucking year, I,
I wouldn't want to be friends with.
Yeah.
Even though I just
described all of my friends
do it.
I don't know what to tell you.
Um,
you probably shouldn't do what you
should. You shouldn't, dude, you should.
And you should go out and go fucking bank
somebody else. You shouldn't. All right.
But I feel like a hypocrite because
I would, I would. But then again,
I'm also a fucking 42 year old
guy. Never got married. So when,
so you're listening to a
complete fucking scumbag here.
So Jesus Christ, this is why I
don't have a fucking advice show,
you know, because in my
attempt to be honest, I, I, I,
I tell you both things, do
it. Don't do it. I would,
but you shouldn't have a nice day.
Um, you know what? Let's,
let's go to the listeners.
I would love to hear from
the women because they,
they're going to have on both sides. They
can have like, you shouldn't do that,
your friend. And then they're also
going to be mad on some level.
Like why did guys feel like they own
somebody just because they youth to go out
with them?
Because we are territorial,
were territorial that way.
And you have to understand that whoever
you've banged in your life as a female,
um, for the rest of your
life, that pussies not yours
anymore. It belongs to him.
And you can say it's yours.
It isn't because he fucked it.
All right? You know what?
I, I feel like, you know,
there wasn't enough
ignorance on this podcast,
so I feel like I had to just
say something stupid like that.
But that's how guys work. And,
um, I didn't even ask you,
this is your best friend.
Is he bigger than you are physically?
Can he beat you down?
Does he take Jujitsu classes?
Um, has he ever had any
murderous thoughts that he,
I'm sort of divulge to you at a,
you know,
a night of drinking too many
Tequila shots and you see an agony,
darker side of him. You know, there's,
there's a whole bunch of Shit, ah,
this is what she got to do.
This is what you gotta do.
Go out and get yourself a
fucking pimp hat. All right?
And this is what you have to do.
You've got to go to this girl and you,
you just got to lay it on the fucking
table. That's what you gotta do.
You just gotta be honest
with her and just say, look
sweetheart,
I have wanted to fuck you
since 2006 you don't say that,
but basically you finesse
your way into that.
You've got to tell her that
you've wanted to hook up with her.
And the only reason why you
didn't, this is the deal. This is
all right. Well, we had a little technical
difficulty there. I left you hanging.
Sorry about that.
The batteries just died.
I was right in the middle of trying to
tell this dude how we could go out and
bang this girl.
Now I gotta fucking stick this into the
goddamn girl garageband and splice it
together,
which I already did that this point.
So why even bitch about it when you
listen to this fucking thing? All right,
let me wrap this Goddamn podcast up by
telling this kid how to go out and fuck
his best friend's ex girlfriend. All
right? This is what you do. You gotta,
you gotta have a talk with
this girl before you do it.
Don't just go over there and
just fucking sneak over there.
You know,
with this nervous excitement fucking rail,
this girl bust your nut and then realize,
oh my God,
I have no fucking feelings for this girl.
And then you know,
risking that she'll then,
you know, be resentful.
All the bullshit I said on
the first fucking installment
of this Goddamn podcast,
this is what you gotta do. You gotta
fucking get everything out in the open.
All right?
In fucking let her convince you that it's
the right fucking thing to do and get
her to say that she ain't gonna say shit.
All right.
Get her to say that. And when she
says she's not going to say Shit,
you have to read her.
All right?
Like a fucking seasoned goddamn pro.
You know,
the 27 fucking, uh, pantomimes align,
whatever that fucking goddamn
movie was true romance.
You gotta look at her and Jay, you have
to, you have to make a fucking assessment.
If this girl can keep
your fucking mouth shut
by presenting these
scenarios, you up. Look,
I'm going to get worried that tomorrow.
What if you're going to wake up feeling
guilty and then you have to confess to
him, you know, I'm not going to
feel, I'm not gonna feel guilty.
Yeah, you are. You're just
fucking, I don't know.
I'm really giving you shit advice.
Do what?
I'm trying to give you a fucking scumbag
way to go out and go do this shit.
Just like,
I dunno.
I'm fucking bad at this,
man.
I have to be in the moment that what the
fuck dirtbag goddamn thing would I be
saying? All right, this is what you
do. You don't go over a fucking places.
What you do don't go over a goddamn
place. See, this is the hard thing.
Now you've got to go out. You've
got to meet her in public. Okay?
So there's no sexual fucking tension
that you can act on. All right?
So your Dick won't be like, dude, she's
fine. She's not lying. She's not lying.
She's going to be cool.
What you have to do is, um,
you're going to meet in a public
place where then people can see a CTO.
This is just a, it's just a fact. It's a,
it's a tough one. Tell you why to do it.
If you can actually fucking pull this off,
why don't you write me back and
tell you, tell, tell me how you,
how the fuck he did it.
I remember a long time ago,
I was in the beginning of a relationship
and I was banging is still banging this
other psycho on the side
and uh,
like a dirt bag,
you know?
And I remember there was gonna be a point
where the two of them were going to be
at the same fucking place.
So I just dealt with it. But I,
that was it before we hooked up,
I just said, look, you've
got to be honest with you.
This girl I'm coming down with, we're
new. I'm starting to have feelings for
all right.
I told her that I cleaned up everything
on the side, which I haven't with you,
so I need you to not act weird
when I fucking come down
there. If I don't, you know,
if I'm not saying hello to you. Okay.
That was before I hooked up with her.
She's like, fine, fine.
And then when she went down there
and then she did that. Cool.
Because in her head she's probably
holding out like maybe if I had cool,
he'll see how fucking cool I am and then
I want to be with me and not this other
bitch.
And meanwhile I fucking got away with it.
And you know what a part of me died?
Another fucking chunk of my soul came
out and said, dirty fucking game.
It's a dirty goddamn game. I'm a piece
of shit. Don't fucking listen to me.
All right, what else do we got
this week? But by the way, dude,
now that I've talked about a
for 10 fucking minutes, you got,
you got to write a Spec and
let us know what happened.
All right?
You know, I realize this might be like
one of those stupid Hollywood movies.
And then I realized that's not the
person I wanted to be it. If you do that,
I don't want to fucking hear it. But if
you don't, if you do the dirty bullshit,
I want to hear about it.
Okay. Would I be the worst fucking life
coach ever? Um, all right, here's a,
here's a segment,
corporate costs.
Hey Bill,
for someone who flies as much as you do,
can you take a shot at explaining the
logic behind why a one way ticket almost
costs more than a round trip.
Um,
for a domestic fuck
for domestic flights, maybe
this isn't a problem. However,
I'm flying from your, uh,
from Europe at the end of the month on
a one way ticket and it costs one and a
half times more than a round trip chip
ticket. And I immediately said, well,
why don't you buy the round trip ticket?
And he addresses this
immediately and says,
and if the airline company can prove
that I purchased a roundtrip ticket,
it with the intent of not using
the return for the flight,
they can legally charge for the
price difference between the fares.
What the fuck is this normal business
practice? I hate to tell you it,
but it is because that's how
corrupt are fucking government is.
That's how powerful corporations
are around the fucking world. They,
they do whatever they,
whatever they want to do.
And they have this thing where every
quarter they have to show a profit,
all right? Oh, actually they have to, to,
to show more of a profit
than the previous quarter.
They can't even just have the same
amount of profit. It's not enough.
And basically they've legally run out
of ways to create revenue streams.
So what they're doing now
is they're just stealing.
They're stealing from people. All
right? If you have a one way ticket,
that means you're going home or you're
starting a new life and you want to get
the fuck out of where you're at.
So that's why they know that they can
charge you a ton of fucking money.
All right? And then we'll watch some buys,
a round trip ticket, then we'll fucking,
we'll just write this little bill here
and we'll have the senator who we fucking
paid for his goddamn campaign helped
push it through. Isn't that how it works?
They just call the senator. I
don't know anything. Um, yeah, no,
it's a piece of shit thing.
So what you gotta do is you have to
vandalize the airplane. All right?
Do something to vandalize the fucking
airplane. Now that you don't even do that,
cause all they're going to do is
just pass that expense onto us.
This is what you have to do.
Um,
you have to find out who it
is that came up with that.
Who created that? Who was, uh,
who was the lobbyist who push that thing
through how that somehow became legal.
You've got to find out where they
live and then you just gotta.
You gotta tailor them the whole
fucking week. Get their patterns down,
figure out when they go to
the Goddamn Jim. All Right,
borrow a pair of pantyhose
from your fucking girlfriend.
Put it over your head,
height and some shrubs.
And when that dude comes walking out of
the gym with that fucking towel around
his neck,
you just blast them right in the face
and then you fucking choke them with it.
Your choke him.
You Mush his face into the mulch
and you'd be like desperate,
a one way ticket from fucking hall
and back to the state yet can't,
and then you get in your fucking
Ford Festiva and you drive away.
That's the only way to get back at
him. And, uh, and if you do that,
I'll give you a free DVD, a
underrated overrated for the week, uh,
underrated, the movie waiting. Uh, it's
all about the world of restaurant waiters,
cooks, it, et cetera. It's
funny, honest and quite gross.
I imagine it is because I've worked in
a couple of fucking restaurants in the
shit that goes on.
You know,
the shit that you'll do when you're not
cooking for a family member is really a,
it's staggering. I'll leave
it at that. Um, overrated. Um,
this is pretty bitter.
But anyways,
when you watch the special features on
a DVD and there's always the making of
feature, far too many of these
features, including the movie waiting,
then I just recommended have the actors
and the directors jokingly calling
others on the film, useless,
awful, amateur, amateurish,
etc. Uh, they'll talk about how the
whole film is a disaster and we'll, uh,
and we'll go straight to video.
Get it. They don't really mean it.
They're joking around. Lol, lol. See,
I told you it was a better one. Yeah,
I guess, you know, I
of understand, I mean,
how many times can you
just sit there and go,
Aston Kutcher was absolutely brilliant
in Madame of the butterfly or the
butterfly effect, whatever the
fuck it was called. Um, that scene,
his reaction here is right up with
Bruce Willis in die hard part three.
When he turns around and looks at the
greenscreen and pretends to be looking at
a jumbo jet, it was absolutely
some of the best act. I mean,
how long could you listen to that so
they gotta make fun of themselves. Um,
I would go with arrogance.
I would just talk about my scenes
and how fucking amazing I am. Um,
while I was pointing out the
dumb shit that I did in it, uh,
youtube videos for the week and do
this, I'm going to tell you, man,
I think I'm recommending,
or at least the listeners of my podcast,
we're recommended some of the
funniest and best fucking, uh,
youtube videos out there. How great. Well
those youtube videos last week, you know,
all right,
here's one duck face song search,
duck face song like quack,
quack, duck face song. Um,
this is an amazing one.
Search,
fake Yoyo trickster fool's,
every TV station everywhere. I mean,
granted it could have been shorter,
but fake Yoyo trickster fool's,
every TV station everywhere.
This is hilarious.
This guy goes on and he claims to be a
Yoyo champion and he actually sucks at it
and he talks all this shit and then he
goes on there and he can't pull off any
tricks and he just stands there and
leaves the morning news guy with the
awkwardness of him completely failing
and not handling the failing and just
leaving it in the lap of the reporter and
it's, uh, it's fucking awesome. Um, AH,
here's one for all you kids and I'm going
to use the young kid where this one is
epic. Um, this one isn't on Youtube.
This is how cutting edge the
Monday morning podcast is. Uh,
go to www.everythingisterrible.com.
And then search for the video.
This is hip hop and uh,
it's awesome.
It's a fucking white lady's soccer mom,
you know, and she's going to
let you know what time it is.
I'm going to leave it at that. Everything
is terrible.com. I'm a couple more,
uh, for all you knick fans out
there who are licking your wounds,
go to go search a Lebron James
Decision interview parody.
I think you'll enjoy that one immensely.
Uh,
for all you death metal fans who have
a sense of humor and because this one
really hinges on actually
knowing the song,
there's a band called Cannibal corpse and
the name of the song is hammer smashed
face.
And if you don't already know that song,
I suggest you listen to it first.
Listened to Cannibal corpse hammer
smashed face for as long as you can,
unless you're death metal
fan. And then you'll love it,
um, or a fan of comedy. Um,
and then go to search
Cannibal Corpse Hammer,
smash his face smashed face,
Disney radio version,
some fucking genius out
there. Basically, you know,
I guess death metal is a lot of like,
I dunno,
the darker cords and he turned them all,
plays the same court but in a major court,
which are they happier once and then
he sings the song with the same lyrics.
It's fucking great. Um, and
that is it. You know what,
I didn't bring up asides from
fro hyping, uh, the month, uh,
the MM podcast.com,
um,
is um, uh, and all of this Lebron Shit.
I didn't really bring up like the fans
of fucking Cleveland and yet another
fucking blow that those people
have to take. I mean that just,
it's brutal between the industry
leaving that town and then I'll,
you know,
cc Sabathia he went,
ended up going in New York.
Manny Ramirez went to Boston,
Jim told went to Philly.
I mean,
they had the team and now they
finally get like fucking arguably,
I would say the next Kobe level player.
He's got a way to go.
But the next Coby level player player in
Lebron James gave him a reason to go to
the downtown area. It sucks. It
sucks because downtown Cleveland,
if you really look at the buildings,
if he can look,
pass the scary homeless people
and really look at the buildings,
uh, it's beautiful. It's
just that, you know,
getting back to these corporate clients,
they just pulled up stakes and they left
because they were sick of paying people
a fair wage and they were sick of having
to pay for health insurance and they
wanted to have some eight year old go put
the fucking grill on a Goddamn fucking
caprice classic. I don't fucking
know. Same thing with Detroit.
Those all those cities, Buffalo, all of
them, if you look at them, the buildings,
they're very,
they're,
they're beautiful cities and you can see
what they used to be and it's a fucking
shame. Um, I dunno, I dunno
how to bring them back,
you know, buy American, which is why
I'm going to get the fucking challenger.
Okay.
And if I find out that it's actually
put together down and fucking Honduras,
I'm going to be fucking pissed.
All right.
Al Challenger is dodge not put together
in fucking whatever the fucking thing is.
I'm going to learn Spanish. God dammit,
and I'm going to have two podcasts.
I'll have one in fucking a on glaze
in one in fucking spend. Y'All,
would that be great?
Then I could find that I could actually
trash people in their native language
about how much soccer is fucking
boring. All right. That is a,
that's a podcast for this
week. A, um, once again,
thanks for everybody to contributing.
Please visit the MM podcast.com if you
want, if you don't want to search youtube,
it's a fucking pain in the ass or then
you got to go to why everything is
terrible.com. If you just want them all
in a night. Nice, neat little package.
Like those little fucking things.
You know when your,
when your girl's got a birthday
and you just go down to the spine,
you get her a little fucking
fancy soaps and everything.
We got youtube videos package just like
that with a nice little bow on them.
And uh, all the references that I make
like Bill Bradley and all that bullshit.
Go to the MLM,
podcast.com.
I'm going to be at the Montreal
comedy festival this week.
I'll be doing David
Letterman next week, but, um,
that's neither here nor there because
I'll be doing a podcast next Monday before
I tape in any way,
so I can talk to you guys about what
it's like to be sitting around the day of
doing a David Letterman spot.
That is it. Ah, God bless you.
I'll talk to you later.
[inaudible]
[inaudible].