Yeah.
Hey, what's going on? Hey. Oh,
what's going on?
It's,
it's Bill Burr and this is the
Thursday afternoon. Just before Friday.
Monday morning podcast.
And
Ahhh,
just checking in on you. Just
check. Oh, I'm eating my balls.
Do do do do do do on a damn
stage pan, pan, pa pan.
Oh whoa. Freckles is paying the
fucking price. He's paying the price.
Every comedian that has the
special coming up, you know,
in the next couple of weeks, whenever
the fuck they're putting it out. I,
I believe the rumor I heard a rumor.
Bananarama oh yeah. When are they
going to get back together? Huh? Fuck.
Every year that goes by,
everybody was talking about when's guns
and roses going to get back together
Wednesday axl and slash going.
But what about Banana Rama?
I heard a rumor they ever getting back
together for a summer fucking tour.
Um, I'm paying the price. Every God damn
all the comedians out there paid, uh,
who have a special coming out is that
you just go on stage and you have,
you know, you got nothing.
You got one little fucking,
you got one little pea shooter and then
you've got a slingshot and a fucking
whatever,
two months earlier you had a Howard sir,
have a fucking act and it's
the weirdest fucking thing.
Just imagine if a whatever,
if you're an athlete or something,
like every couple of years you had
to relearn that. All the mechanics,
but you just couldn't hit the jump
shot anymore. He had to fucking, yeah,
that that shot was in my repertoire.
Now I've got to relearn how to fucking
do this and but in a different way.
I've got to do it and then I got to shoot
it with my left hand now because they
already saw me do it with my right hand.
And then the more you fucking do it,
the more hours you put
out. Right. Then you go.
When I got to bounce
it off my fucking head,
cause you know you can't keep
doing the same shit or everybody's,
I got more of this say do
that reminds me of this thing.
You Oh the guy with this person. Right.
You just got to fucking deal with that.
So last night, you know, and of course
they have to go on after Ian Edwards,
I a n Edwards.
It was like that guy.
All he has is a level fucking
material just up there murdering.
And uh,
I went up there with my lip
[inaudible] basic fucking horse shit.
I was in a really fucking dark place.
It's funny to be in a dark place and then
like, you know, mentally just like, uh,
and then to be talking about the
shit that I was talking about and um,
yeah,
I dunno, but I got to plow through
this shit. Um, as far as like, uh,
I got to get past my anger and I'm telling
you this fucking exercise that I did
that I'm really starting
to think my shoulders.
How fuck do you put your shoulders up?
Remember that better? I used to do,
I think I was stuck in a defensive posture
like shell shot.
You know what I mean?
There's only so many times you can get
slapped in the back of the head by bigger
kids before you shoulders
are just naturally up.
Like you're already beginning to block
whatever's coming at your fucking head.
And I think I was kind of
stuck in that and um, you know,
I was talking to some people about
that and it was like, well, you know,
there's physical layer.
Yeah.
And then there's the emotional fucking
trauma of what's going on with your life.
And there's certain people
that think they're related.
I don't know if you guys are
into that hit me shit man.
But you look up this stuff,
you know,
this is like one of these things
when you go to look this up,
you completely leave the
medical profession in the
United States of America.
Like you start like the doctors slowly
start wearing less and less shoes as you
start to go further east with your, your,
you're looking for medical solutions.
You know, if you're looking for a
medical solution in the United States of,
of the Americas,
it's going to be a guy in wingtip
shoes with fucking dark socks,
you know, fully clothed, be in
like, okay, yeah, you got a,
your rotator cuff is taped up though.
We need to go in and operate
and take the middle. Yeah.
Carl over the wall while
the fucking MCL and all,
they're going to give you this
straight fucking how the body works.
We've done an MRI. This is what the
fuck is going on with your body.
But then as you start to go,
you know,
you start to step away from that shit
that the pharmaceutical companies and all
that,
not saying it's all bad,
not saying it's all Ben was the
last time we had a plague. You know,
for as much as the pharmaceutical
companies allegedly
allegedly created a heroin
epidemic in this country by handing
out opiates like Flintstone vitamins to
fucking adults. Uh, you
know, there's also, you know,
because nobody's walking around with
scurvy, so that's something, right?
I guess no one really walked
around with scurvy bill.
He had to be on a fucking
boat, lost at sea, you know,
no wind in your sails and
iron maiden singing, right.
The car safely A. Dot. It is.
Hi. Um, so, uh, yeah,
but the further you go down that rabbit
hole, like, uh, the, the fucking,
the longer the hair gets,
then there's like, you know,
more loose fitting clothes,
then it becomes sandals.
And then just sort of the more he knew
me and even very your liking like this.
And then I get all fucking uncomfortable.
Um, I'll look up some stuff.
Let me hit pause here and I'm going to
look up some shit about like the memories.
Let me, let me see what this fucking
doctor looks like. Our perfect,
perfect fucking pervert.
So I looked up memories held in,
in the media that came up was in body.
So of course Wikipedia has something
that's just going to be like, you know,
the old right there, Fred. So the
first thing I scrolled down too,
that was not Wikipedia was tiny Buddha.
All right.
And I swear to God,
it says how to release the painful
memories and emotions stored in your body.
Uh, Jennifer Sterling, of course, now
they're going to let a woman do something,
right? They're not going to
let her in the wingtip world.
So the picture you see is some
Antonio Banderas looking guy with the,
uh, I call it the gay cut t
shirt. You know, you know,
you know the v Neck t shirt
that the fucking gay guys were,
cause they're all fucking in crazy shape.
You know what I mean?
It's not the dad bod cut.
It's the gay male fucking cut where they
have chess cleavage because they have
0% body fat.
So the guys dressed white on white
with the gay cut t and yoga pants,
no fucking shoes.
And he's on the beach,
not a hospitality found.
He looks like fucking a good look.
And Tom Hanks in cast away. If he didn't
give a fuck that he was cast away,
cast away.
Yeah.
And he didn't need to talk to a soccer
ball because he was so fucking centered
and he breathed his way through.
How the fuck did he become a castaway?
I can't even remember.
Yeah,
it must've been his ship sank. Right.
What was he flying with? Amelia Earhart.
I Dunno.
Was it one of those Tarantino movies
where he kind of fucks with history?
All right.
The cure for pain is in the pain,
says somebody named Rumi and
then it says free download,
Buddha desktop wallpaper.
That kind of kills it.
You know when you have a good Jesus
or Buddha or Muhammad like wallpaper,
you know what I mean? Kinda cheeses it
up a little bit now you think, okay,
it's all right. Let me read
it. My Best Yoga voice,
your body keeps a physical
memory of all your experiences.
You have lots of memories stored in your
brain that you can recount in any given
moment, even called names. Faces. Yeah,
get out of my fucking brain works what
you fucking sandwich smelled like.
But over time these memories fade or
change as time passes as and we mature.
However, even when the memory
begins to fade for you,
rank get to the fucking point.
It lives in your body,
in the form of a physical
sensation and behavior patterns.
The body doesn't forget. Now, Jesus,
what's your body from Hell's kitchen?
And that was for fucking 20 years
ago. You fucking pee shit, right?
Your brain's all forgiving
like, hey man, like, you know,
not gonna lie. I didn't enjoy it
when it happened, but you know, God,
I mean just the sunny day, just
go out and enjoy it. All right.
The events of our lives leave
physical imprints in our bodies,
especially when we experience
trauma. Can I? Okay.
Stress and all this shit that
caused the body to fight, flee,
or freeze in order to cope. This is what
I'm saying. I think I was all fucking,
I was in a a,
you know,
after you take a couple of fucking right
left to their head, you just Kinda,
you just walk around.
I just thought I,
you know, I have like
fucking 40 years ago,
whenever the fuck I was in high school,
40 years ago,
was I 18? No, that was 30
years ago. 30 years ago.
I was fucking 18 yeah,
I'm a,
you knew that phone was gonna
ring. Ah, what, who is this?
Who the hell is this? I, I
should've put it on pause.
Who is this?
Hello?
Hello.
Oh,
for fuck's sake.
Can you believe someone would
pocket down me during my podcast?
You know what's funny is I don't
even know who the fuck that was.
I have no idea who the fuck that was.
They have no idea who the fuck I am. I,
that's what's always fascinated
me about when you just fucking,
you just dial a wrong number.
I've said this before, right?
You dial a number and somebody says hello
and you're like, yeah, hey, is a is is,
is frank there? And they're
like, whoa. And you're like cry.
And they're like, oh, I'm sorry.
They're like,
I'm sorry you have the wrong number.
Now I get wrong numbers.
Everybody gets wrong numbers.
Here's my question to you.
Do you think you've ever
accidentally called somebody famous?
You know what I mean? Like
you just fucking, uh, I dunno.
You just dial the wrong number and like
Bill Clinton picked up or fuck it Obama,
we'll throw a Republican in there.
George Bush hang, she's Danny, right?
He fucking picks up and you get,
he has to go through the same shit as you
like is frank there? And he said, hey,
where did you say, I just know Brittany's
additional frank e f g. H I love it.
And then they read the fucking number t
like, you don't know what your number is.
Is this blob? No, it isn't.
That's why there is no frank here.
Um, anyways, let me continue on.
All right, well fuck all this shit. How
do I get it out of me? Cause my body,
it never forgets.
It's like fucking Niamh listen,
if you punch me in the
fucking in seventh grade, um,
wait a minute.
I love that they finally gave Jamie
Foxx the fucking Liam Neeson Merle.
He has a movie coming out where it's one
of those movies like you fuck with my
family. I'm going to fucking kill
you. It's about time. You know,
they ran out a young white guys to give
that to and then they just kept going
over and like, Liam Neeson me, let me
know that guys. Like, what is he like?
[inaudible] 83 then he play like
fucking Obi wan Kenobi or some shit.
Um, all right, the first tool
to put your emotional toolkit,
the first tool to put in your
emotional toolkit, and this is why,
this is why I've never been
able to get through this shit
because I was getting no,
because I'm fucked up.
But when I start to go down this road
of doctors who don't wear shoes like it
said, okay, the pictures that they have,
okay, this is how to set new year's goals.
You'll actually enjoy pursuing and it's
a stick figure sitting on a rainbow
staring up at the sun with a
big goofy smile on its face.
And uh, I don't know about you
guys, but where I came from,
that sort of happiness was not allowed.
You basically were not allowed to be
happy and it was shamed. Fuck off.
Oh No. Wait. Why am I letting that
react? I, why am I reacting to that?
I have the power. I could've, you know,
it's funny, right before he started this,
I was thinking I should go into the
settings and I should just turn it off.
And I didn't.
So I created this situation,
not a dead Steve Jobs.
Huh?
You know,
I guess I could get upset with Steve Jobs
with how fucking many times that thing
rings before it goes to voicemail.
But then I imagined that I could actually
go into settings and I could determine
that. I just don't have the patients.
All right. The first tool, okay guys,
your first tool to put in
your emotional toolkit.
This is the type of class I would go
to with Nia and she would just feel me
either starting to get mad or just
laughing at the thing as she being the
fucking angel that she is. An open
fucking channel would be like, okay,
what is the first emotional tool?
It's cause she's a woman.
She gets to fucking do that to be
like, oh my God, let's get some smores.
They get to be like that.
We're not, you know, no,
you don't have a fucking bottle opener.
You've gotta use your teeth. You know,
it's just,
it's stupid guy shit.
And then if you don't know how to fucking
do that thing where you bring your
beer up to the counter
and fucking slam it down,
you know you're somehow less of a man.
Um,
I like how I'm putting all of my issues
on you guys. All right. Let's say we go,
okay. The first tool to put in your
emotional toolbox, non judgment.
Ah, fuck. I mean, there goes
my standup career. I mean,
my entire fucking life is judging people.
All right?
When you feel emotionally triggered
and tempted to turn to food or other
addictive behaviors for comfort,
I'm not f well, maybe I am a drunk.
Try not to judge the reaction. Our
bodies are programmed to seek pleasure,
not discomfort.
So it's natural to try and find something
to sue the pain and make yourself feel
better. The need to suit yourself with
food. I'm not a fat fuck or other means,
doesn't make you a bad person.
It makes you human. Oh God.
This is just so gross.
The second tool per mission,
the third tool release, I can't even
read this, the fourth to forgiveness.
Finally time.
Oh my God,
I'm going to the wrong website. Jennifer
sterling is an emotional eating coach.
Well, what the fuck is to say
I've met the wrong website.
She helps women to stop eating their
feelings and release the physical and
mental emotional weight that keeps
them from feeling the absolute best.
Download the cravings decoder
guide and uncover the hidden,
hidden emotional meeting behind
your food cravings. I don't know.
I don't want to be a
fucking negative person,
but doesn't that sound a fucking generic?
I was craving a peanut butter and jelly
sandwich. Okay. What that means is this.
All right, where do you
store your emotions? Where
do you store your emotions?
All right. Now, this person has a phd,
so imagining that they're going
to be wearing more clothes,
they don't even have a picture.
It may surprise you that emotions are
not the sole product of your brain,
but our experience, my fees, Roger,
this isn't going to say the same shit as
the last website and these emotions can
be triggered through your body
work, meditation, breathing,
blah, blah, blah, blah.
Use one half. All right, well, you know,
evidently I'm never going to get scared
cause I can't get through this shit.
Well certainly not while doing
a fucking podcast. You Moron.
Why did you just call yourself
a more on there? Is that,
is that really what you thought or is
that what people told you when you were
younger?
That's the type of shit where you just
want to grab the person by their ankles
and drag them out of their chair
and they just walk out of the room.
You know me from that session.
Um,
Jesus Christ, I'm up against the dude. Is
this what it's like to become a parent?
You just suddenly become hyper aware
of how unqualified you are and what a
fucking moron you want to like someone's
going to be looking at me like I have
questions. Hey, I'm going to be talking
to my kid like, Hey, join the club.
You think any of this
shit makes sense to me?
At least you're a kid and
you can have the comfort of,
of of it's okay that you don't know
shit. Where did he get to be? My Age.
And you don't have an excuse, you
know, and it's that fucking, uh,
whenever the fuck is in the
Micheal Ray Richardson, Tyson,
Sicily to whatever this fucking name is
quiet leaf Tyson,
I forget what his name is, Ken.
Like fucking the, the, the,
the guy who looks like the cop on the
black cop on Barney Miller who fucking
knows about black holes in the universe
and is a fine wine connoisseur.
Um, you know, that's the kind of
person you need is a debt. That guy,
that guy's got fucking answers. You
know, I was reading a thing on him. Um,
I got it. I can never remember
this guy's fucking name.
Last name is Tyson to graph Tyson.
Tyson scientist. Tyson
sites. We'll go with that.
Is going to be this Mike Tyson's football,
Neil degrasse Tyson.
This is why he's the shit, because not
only is the unbelievably intelligent,
he knows that we came from trees or some
shit, whatever the fuck he was saying,
you know, thank God I don't do heavy
drugs. When I watched that guy show,
all right.
He also was talking about how he's into
wine and he was talking about how when
you, whatever you finish a bottle of wine,
you fill it up with water or you go to,
you know, and you're pouring it out.
It does that Glub Glub glub thing.
He was just going,
what'd you do?
Is You just turn the bottle
is you turn the bottle,
it causes a swirling effect and uh, uh,
basically because it's swirling down,
then there's that whole in the middle,
lets the air go in. So as, as the, uh,
liquids coming out in the
air can freely flow in
to take up the space that the liquid
once had. And it just flows right out.
Plus it looks,
it looks fucking cool as you do it.
So the next time you pour a big fucking
glass of wine for some real housewife,
you know,
gets,
you can't wait to hold her botox
face in your hands. You know,
you don't want to fuck it up by Glub glub
glub in it into a giant glass because
it might go all over a fucking dress
that she's going to wear once, you know,
hey look, you know that, that's what
I get out of Neil degrasse Tyson.
I watched that show and I'm
like, God damn it. You know,
as much as this guy just told me
where we came from in the
universe millions of years
ago or whatever, thousands,
I don't know, you know, go back
to Jesus. That was only what,
a couple thousand years ago. Um, as
much as he's teaching me about that,
he's also on the side showing
me how to bang a real housewife.
Um, anyways, so I've continued to uh,
get rid of shit and
I'm still in my office.
That's how much shit I had had two
closets and everything in my room and I've
fucking,
I've gotten rid of everything and I might
even do another pass cause I have to
tell you, I fucking walk in
there now and I'm relaxed.
I had no idea that when you walk in and
there's a ton of shit that the level of
stress that was bringing me, I'm fucking
relaxed. And like there's my drum kit,
there's my guitar, there's
where I keep my pens, you know,
get it out of here. Anything that's
coming in the house, get it the fuck out.
And so then yesterday, of
course, you know, you know,
women are, you know, you know,
you know, they are, I mean, if,
if they're not fucking, you know,
watching the real housewives show, if
they're not eating something that they're,
they're on Amazon buying something.
They just, they, they, they,
they fucking consume
shit. So, um, you know,
and spend the holidays. So we've had a
bunch of boxes, people sending US stuff,
we're sending them shit in it by my front
door every day there's these fucking
boxes. Okay. So what I always do is
I take our fucking address off it,
I put it through the papers,
right?
Then I cut the boxes up and then I take
them over to this fucking place that, uh,
you know, one of those mailboxes separate
places, you know. And I say, Hey,
go is some free fucking boxes.
They take it now.
I don't know if they throw
it out like goodwill,
but I feel like I made the fucking effort,
you know,
but I can't fucking keep the goddamn door
clean and I cut up like fucking 20 of
these goddamn boxes, you know? Did
you went to have a fucking baby?
Everybody's sends your shit. Everybody
sending you shed socks, shoes, swings,
follow this shit.
And it's just like,
I just love the amount of socks
that they send you. It's like,
it's not gonna be able to walk for like
the first fucking, I dunno, six months.
What does it need socks for?
We didn't get me a hang glider.
I mean just that doesn't
even make any fucking sense.
I know you get the baby's
got to keep his feet warm,
but does it have to have one pair
of socks for every fucking day,
but six month life, you
know, and then what?
You've got all these little socks,
it's going to grow out of them and like
fucking tits out used to see what level
of a con would you have to be to
look at the cutest thing ever.
A little baby socks and it still
makes ship set. See what I'm saying?
Oh, tell your freckles. Need some help
here. Um, all right, let's get to, uh,
some of the, uh, let's get to some of the
announcements. Oh, by the way, everybody,
I keep forgetting to promote this,
uh, the Patrice O'neil comedy benefit,
the fifth annual,
uh,
Patrice O'Neal comedy benefit.
I still have a nice photo on the wall.
Somebody did have this
great painting of him,
the perfect size and all that that I will
never get rid of. Now, having said that,
I don't need anymore. Um, all right.
Patrice O'Neal comedy benefit.
This is the fifth annual one at the
New York City Center. All right,
we're going to post the link and all
of that. There's a, it's a 2000 seater.
We've got a couple of
hundred seats left and, um,
it's a great way to
start your year. And, um,
it's one of my favorite shows of the year.
Um,
just getting to see all of the,
uh,
just all my friends and now it's becoming
like newer guys that were influenced
by Patrice and then they come
and they talk about, you know,
the amazing comic that he was. And, uh,
I got to tell you that will never not be
in the back of my head cause I love the
guy to death. But it's also like
whenever someone will come up to me and,
and give me a high compliment,
you know,
as far as where I am in the comedy
world right now as a standup comedian,
I always think that's,
cause Patrice is in here right now and
Mitch Hedberg and Geraldo and all these
other monsters that we lost.
So this is an incredible
benefit. And it, uh, you know,
through the money that we've raised,
his mother's been able to get a
condominium and she's living great.
She doesn't have to worry about
anything, you know, you know,
the only thing, you know, and that's, um,
a really a belief of mine
that when somebody passes
and their family members or
you know, the only thing they should
have to deal with his degree from it,
which unfortunately you
never totally get passed,
but they shouldn't also have to
deal with all this other stuff,
which is why we continued to do the
benefit because I always hated when I was
coming up,
when there was an unexpected death and
the person had a family and all of that
type of shit. You know, it's like you
do one benefit and it's like, okay,
here's your bag, a loot, you know,
try to make this last for the next
20, 30, 40, 50 fucking years. Um,
I dunno.
So that's why we continue to do it.
Plus it keeps the memory of him alive
and all of his comedy out there.
Uh, that is the hope. Anyways. Okay,
so now I want to, the advertising,
the Black Tux. Dotcom. All right.
Looking great for a wedding or a special
event has never been easier with black
Tux dotcom
with high quality rental
suits and Tuxedos.
Why is this itchy
delivered to your doorstep?
The Black Tux is giving guys a
new way to rent and get this.
The black Tux offers free home.
Try On's try ons so you can see the fit
and feel the quality of your suit months
before your event to these fucking
companies. Man, this is like,
you're not going to have to
leave your house anymore.
You can get food sent to your house.
Wine, Cindy, a house and a fucking Tuxedo.
You know,
and God knows whores have always been
at willing to come to your fuck is you
[inaudible] right there.
This is the list is the final.
This is a final piece of the puzzle.
Like you putting together
a championship team,
all you were missing
was to fucking Tuxedos.
You go to blue apron and
get your fucking food right?
You go to fucking loot crate to get
your t shirt that you're going to wear
underneath all the bullshit. You go to
a fucking something at me undies, right?
To get your sexy Greg Louganis on right.
And then you've got the fucking Roger,
Roger Moore, right Sean Connery
Tux. How do you, how do you do this?
It's the best part is just done
completely online. No trips to the Tuxedo.
Tuxedo shop required. The Black
Tux. Dot. All that's the worst.
When you go to the Tuxedo shop,
there's always that guy who's been
there for like forever and he's got that
fucking tape measure
around his fucking neck.
Whatever the fuck you call that thing,
you know the,
you know those people don't clean their
ears to the point that everything just
turns black in there.
It looks like somebody lit a firecracker
off and both their fucking ears, sorry.
The Black tux.com lets you create your
look or choose from tons of styles,
selected outfits starting at just $95.
These suits have a modern fit and are
made from the Italian fine Italian wool,
the highest quality on the rental market.
You're going to buy a fucking wool suit.
Okay.
And if you have any questions or issues
their expert yet, why is this itchy?
It's got gotta be some new kind of
wool like mad at a modal or something.
And if you have any questions or issues,
their expert customer care has
your back every step of the way.
After ordering your suit will
arrive 14 days before your event.
Why don't I pay attention to Camas?
After ordering comma,
your suit will arrive 14
days before your event.
That's a full two weeks to try it
on and make sure everything fits.
If anything is less than perfect,
the black Tux will send you a
free replacement right away.
When your event's over,
just drop your rental back in the mail.
Shipping is free both ways.
How easy is that to get
statted now visit the black
tux.com/berbee you are and experience a
new way to rent the black tux.com/burr
alright.
Thethe though.
See so fuck you man. Alright.
Siso is the place for comedy.
They won't tell you how amazing they add,
but I will.
Thethe though is amazing.
See? So I just feel like,
you know what wasn't my fault?
Anybody says c.
So is is, I don't know if they don't
take responsibility for their actions,
but CSO, anybody does that is, it's
going to be see some amazing content.
See that it's comedy for
nerds by comedy nerds. CSO,
spelled s e s o Sierra,
Echo,
Echo Sierra Oscar is the new ad free
streaming service bringing you are
hilarious. Original series,
handpicked classics,
weeks of Standup specials and
more bingeable comedy anytime,
anywhere. CSO. Every episode of SNL.
Yeah.
Including new episodes the day
after they air the tonight show,
starring Jimmy Fallon,
late night with Seth fucking my,
the day after it airs. And even, uh,
they even have classics like
30 rocks, 30 Rock, sorry.
Parks and recreation
and saved by the bell.
30 rocks as a documentary
on crack cocaine. Sorry.
Even British comedies like the original
office. What's Ricky your vase? He's got,
uh,
the entire Monty python catalog,
the it crowd and Steve
Coogan as Alan Partridge, uh,
discovered the big names in comedy and
watch the icons before they made it big
like Louis C k what? He had hair.
Ah, there was no reason to do that.
You know, a fuck you like the
original you when you had a life. Um,
Chelsea Peretti Amy fucking shoe.
Okay.
Bo Burnham and so many more critically
acclaimed originals and exclusive content
like harmonquest created by comedian Dan
Harmon and funny as hell a variety show
featuring such comedians as Jim
Jefferies and Hannibal Burress.
If you're serious about comedy,
you gotta try CSO streaming anytime,
anywhere on any virtual devices. It
mirrors this add way too. Fucking long.
CSO is ad free,
just three 99 per month.
That's less than what you paid for a latte
or an artisan cold brew coffee you're
holding right now,
your bearded con.
And right now my listeners can
try CSO for free for two months.
When you use the Promo Code Burdett,
check it out,
shows you can't get anywhere else from
critically acclaimed original series to
all 40 plus years of SNL. That's
why I'm getting it right there. See,
so is the only original play is the
only place that offers every episode,
every made and new episodes
the day after the air.
Just go to seeso.com right now to sign
up for two months for free with the Promo
Code radar@checkoutthatseeso.com
promo code birth. Check it out.
You can do it for fucking free.
Oh look who's here
are borrow friends' Boto Boop,
boop me on
[inaudible]
doctors who don't wear shoes.
Bodu too.
Mandy's me undies.
Ricky Gervais' drinks brew.
Why any fucking house,
the Golden Globes are always balls feel.
Nobody knows.
But if he had on me on these,
his voice would even be higher
when any made fucking milk.
I'm fond of fucking Mel
Gibson. Oh yeah. All right.
Mandy's picture of world we're putting
on a new pair of underwear isn't just
fresh. That's fucking
gross. You know what I mean?
As opposed to what Dale balls hanging
in the things you're stepping into a
better day.
Think about underwear.
It's the first thing you put
on the last thing you take off.
Unless you Matthew mcconaughey,
why would you settle for anything less
than the best feeling underwear on the
planet? Uh, please include all of the
falling point. I always include them.
If you write it. I will
read it. If you build it,
they will come beyond these focuses
solely on producing the most comfortable
underwear you've ever experienced.
It's just a,
what is going on with
other people's underwear.
It's attack in my track over here.
My undies from my friends at me undies.
We're not friends.
I never met these fucking people sent me
a few pairs awhile back and now I can't
imagine wearing anything else. Of course
I can. Okay. I'm a very fluid person.
All right. If I don't have me
undies. Oh, whereby my Hanes, he's,
oh my fruit Allume zs.
Uh, it's really easy. Uh,
it's really makes each day that much
better for the price of two cocktails.
Me On these dwell, you know,
thi to cocktails, home pores.
We talk in or out at a fucking bar.
Beyond these,
we'll deliver your new pair of favorite
underwear right to your doorstep.
Better Day guarantee you try them on
if they're not at the most comfortable,
best feeling fucking
underwear you've ever had.
There were funds you and let you
keep your first pair for free.
Included in the price is
the sweet touch of modal,
a special fabric made with the best
in class raw materials that are
scientifically proven to be
three times softer than cotton,
scientifically proven by what the
scientists that you hired that are on your
payroll. Maybe it's only two
and a half times. Who knows?
I'll let my balls be the judge of that.
Your Uber Cozy underwear undies are
sold exclusively on me undies website.
While you're on joy free shipping in the
US and Canada, uh, for a limited time,
everyone in my audience gets 20%
off. Uh, they're not cradles,
uh, oil makeup for women to, uh, but
you have to go to our special URL,
[inaudible] dot com slash burr with
the Mandy's better day guarantee.
You have nothing to lose.
So don't wait any longer.
Go to [inaudible] dot com slash
bird right now, 20% off your order.
That's [inaudible] dot com slash burr
no longer will your balls fall out the
side of your underwear with this snug fit.
And if they do beyond these will,
I don't know what they'll do, but all I
know is it's going to be the sweetest,
softest ball roll to
the left or the right,
depending on where your junk is that you
ever felt in your life before it starts.
It's free, fall down to your
fucking kneecap. Um, all
right. That was disgusting.
It was disgusting.
It wasn't socially redeemable and I don't
think anybody became a better person
listening to it. Um, all right,
so is that the podcast?
That is the podcast.
Um,
now when I get off the podcast,
I'm going to go look at these
barefoot doctors. You know,
I can't fucking believe
they, that, you know, the
misrepresented that fucking site.
You know, they have some guy sitting
there, right, with the gay cut tee shirt.
And I'm sitting there thinking like,
all right,
this is going to be for angry Fuckos like
me. And it's for a bunch of women who,
uh, every time, uh, their
boyfriend says, hey, you know,
I don't feel like getting a going and see
that movie tonight. I'd rather stay in.
They go, oh they go in, they eat a
fucking death by chocolate fucking thing.
I don't know. I don't even want to
complain about anymore. I really don't.
I'm just freaking out cause
they got a kid come in.
I would just like the kid to show up
already so I can get on with that part of
my life. I suppose this is what,
this is literally what it's like.
Sometimes this reminds me obviously too
much emotionally heightened state than
this,
but I always remember when I would be
standing on the side of the stage and it
was just a fucking brutal crowd and I
knew that they were going to scream and
yell the entire fucking show and it
was just going to be 45 minutes of pure
fucking hell. I always remember just
the worst part was not going out there.
It was waiting the second I got out there,
I didn't give a shit because it's
just like every second I'm out here
is one less is I'm a second
closer to this fucking being over.
It's like doing cardio,
getting on the fucking thing and doing
it is not a fucking problem. It's,
it's the stretching beforehand,
you know,
putting on the workout clothes,
dragging your ass over to the machine.
The second you get on the thing,
I'm in literally 30 seconds into it.
You'll listen to your tone.
Do you have a good fucking time?
Everything is fucking great. It's, it's
the getting, it's the getting there,
at least for me. And you know what?
I think that that's, you know,
it's something that we can all relate to,
is it, I don't fucking know. Anyways, uh,
I start to watch the Celtics
last night against Utah. Uh,
I got to watch that one cause I think
the Bruins had planned today and, uh,
I'm trying to do this.
I'm going to watch every Bruins and
every Celtic game that I possibly can.
It's fun.
I've got to tell you something I never
realized because I haven't watched it so
long.
When you watch NBA hoop,
it's so easy to start to get to know
your team because they've got a starting
five, you know what I mean? Patriot's.
You got 11 guys on our offense,
11 guys on defense.
Basketball has five
five starters that play.
They start both ways.
Offense and defense run down the fucking
coordinating on defense. You know,
I guess the Bruins just to have a
starting line and then they're starting to
defense when that's five and then
they got a goalie. But thing about,
well how many,
you know,
I don't know how many fucking
players are in a hockey team.
How fucked up is that? All these years
of watch and I don't like football.
There's like 41 42 people you know
of which if you know like 10 of them,
you kind of know your fucking team.
What do you guys think? I'm going to say
there's like 25 guys. Well, let's see,
there's four fucking lines. Four
lines, three guys in a line.
That's 12 you got two goaltenders
that's 14 and then you've got like what?
Eight defensemen? Something
like that. Six to eight. Yeah.
I'm going to say about 25 and then you've
got like the guys who don't get in the
game, you know with the, with the WHO's
hockey stuff doesn't smell it off.
At least their, their practice
stuff probably smells. I'm sure.
How many players on a hockey team,
I'm gonna say 25
under the NHL rules,
each team is allowed to have up to 18
players with additional two goalkeepers
for a total of 20. That's
it. Well, there's really no,
excuse me not knowing it's only 20
players, right. That's when you're on a,
on a crazy level of a sports fan is if
you can name all fucking 20 players on
your hockey team and all what
11 guys on the basketball team.
Just for the simple fact that they fucking
overlap, I would say. And by the way,
my,
my wife taped these sports jeopardy's
that were posted by Dan Patrick by judging
by some of the questions. It was a
little dated, but uh, I was like,
finally a jeopardy.
I'm going to do well on it.
And I still got my fucking ass kicked
because it was, it was fucking hard shit.
Like who is he? Oh, like
they had like, uh, uh,
bankrupt teams teams that went
bankrupt yet it know the owner's name.
If you know the owner's name,
it's like you're watching fucking
sports talk radio and all of that.
Shaking me a fucking break. Wait,
what? What's wrong with you? Yeah.
I'll tell you why. No, our specialty
fucking coach, you get to that level.
You know what? I'm just babbling here.
I don't have fucking time to do this.
All I was doing was checking in on you
and that, that's, that's the podcast.
Have a great weekend yet conch and
um, no, no, no, no. Why am I, why?
You know what? Why do I say that?
You know why I fucking say that?
Because I'm defensive. I actually
said something nice to you about. Ah,
what are you a fucking shot right
then my shoulders started coming up.
I hope you guys have a wonderful
rest of your week. I can't do this.
I can't fucking do with have a great
weekend. You fucking cunts. All right.
Can I see that in the most
loving way possible? All right.
Did that make you uncomfortable? Good.
Welcome to my fucking world and a here.
Let's do a little bit of music and
then afterwards we'll play some, uh,
some clips from a
podcasts gone by Thursday.
Then those one a fucking have maybe
on Monday. Who knows? All right.
Go fuck yourselves.
We'll talk to you on Monday.
[inaudible]
Hey, what's going on? A Bill Barr
and this is the money, the morning
podcast, the first one for 2009. So
I want to take some time to wait.
Sorry. I tried to, I tried
to, I tried to come out nice.
I tried to start it by being, I can't
do it. I just can't say something nice.
Why can't I just start my podcast and be
like, hey, happy new year everybody. Hi.
Hope you had a nice Christmas. You
know, even though I feel that I,
I can't get myself to say it,
I have to mock it.
I have to say happy new year in a silly
voice. You know, I can't just be like,
hey, happy and a happy new. I
can't even do it. Happy New Year,
you know,
that doesn't sound happy or sad or angry.
It just sounds like I'm
reading it off the cue card.
We tried to give it the
feeling it deserves. Hey,
let me try again. Uh Oh, I got a
phone call. Hang on one second.
Hang on. Whoa. Hang on one
second. Hello. Hey Dan.
What's going on man? Uh, uh, I'm actually,
I'm finishing up a podcast. Can I, can I
call you right back and like a beautiful,
I do buy. Yeah. Okay. That's
the fucking text, man.
God Damn Tax Man. It'd
be fucking you. I think.
Hey actually got ahead a little bit.
And then what do they do to
come out and they just fucking,
I make the perfect amount of fucking money
in this country. You know what I mean?
I'm not rich enough to fucking afford
somebody to tell the IRS to go fuck
themselves and I'm not broke, so I'm,
I'm the fucking, you know what I am and
when he wants you to discovery channel,
you know that, that fucking a
gazelle that's walking with a limp.
That's what I am.
The fucking lines,
their ears perk up and they try to
separate me from the fucking heard.
That's who I am. When the tax man comes
around from God damn fucking assholes.
All right, sorry. You know, potholes
all up and down my fucking street.
You know what I mean?
Why don't I pay you when I just go
down a fucking home depot and buy some
Goddamn tarn I'll fall. Can you buy
car at home depot? I'm sure you can,
but God knows there's nobody
there to help you find it. Huh?
50,000 fucking square foot store with
200 foot ceilings and they got like three
people with aprons walking around.
You ask them any question.
They don't know where the fuck
having a planning section.
I fucking bitch shut up to
go hang yourself with your
rate. But no, I don't need,
you're not, you're not the problem. You're
not the problem. You're the poor worker.
Sorry about that. Do you
know what they actually did?
They got those automated, uh,
they got those automated cashiers out
here at the grocery store and you know,
I get out and there's a whole
bunch of people just lining up,
lining up out the cooperations fire.
Other Americans,
I swear to God,
if you're one of my podcasts members
and you go to the grocery store and you,
you stand in that automated line,
I want you to delete yourself
as one of my friends. Okay?
I have a zero fucking
tolerance for that shit.
It's unbelievable how stupid people are
and I love how they have like the one
employee where his job is literally
to stand there and teach you how to
basically do his job so
that they can then fire you.
And I know what the corporation
is going to do. They have it.
It's going to help cut costs on
food. Really. You got eight people,
they're making $8 an hour.
That's 64 bucks an hour.
You got a thousand people in
here buying cornflakes. What do,
what do I save half a cent on my
fruity pebbles? You fucking cunts.
That was the first count
of 2009 right there.
People stand in line,
help keep a fellow American
at work. Huh? Blah blah blah,
blah, blah, blah, blah, blah,
blah. Dude, I'm not even joking.
Don't do that.
Don't do that shit.
These fucking parking structures
with their pay stations.
Now I have to be the parking attendant.
I don't work here. I got it for free.
I got to do this for fucking free and
put another guy out of work who now is
walking around trying to fight to find
a job for all I know he's gonna start
writing jokes. You know,
don't do that shit.
Don't, don't. Okay. You know me?
Yes. You don't know me. You think you know
me cause you listen to me every Monday,
but I'm telling something about myself.
I don't give a fuck what you do.
This is the one time where I'm going
to get up on my goddamn soapbox, okay?
Which is really difficult for me because
I got a big head and my equilibrium
starts to fuck with me when I stand up
on soapboxes, which is why I know preach,
but I'm going to preach on this one. Do
not do that. Go to the grocery store.
Stand in line.
Okay.
Let that mother of three keep her job.
Or that that fucking convicted drunk
driver was trying to put his life back
together again.
Let them keep their jobs.
Do not stand and learn how to do.
You're going to do their job for
fucking free and it's not quicker.
And in the future you're going to
actually have to fucking stand there.
And you know what happens when you need
to price check on a fucking cantaloupe?
You have to go do it.
I don't,
I just fucking blows my mind.
We're already pumping our
guests around gas people.
When's it gonna stop? Huh?
Okay. I had a hell of a week.
All right. Actually, you know what?
I want to know how you guys feel about
that stuff. I am. I am. I, you know,
do you feel like I have a really good
point there because I feel I do all my,
you know,
if I was living in the 18 hundreds,
would I be the guy going stop churning
butter? No. Keep churning butter.
Don't let them do this for no,
but that's not even a fair example
because it's not like there was,
maybe there was a bunch of butter chairs.
If they could tell him,
I'll come up with automated buttered
butter churning. You know what?
I really paid my painting myself into
a corner with that, that reference.
I really had nothing there.
All right.
But I still think I made a
good point there. All right,
let's talk about my week.
I had a fucking insane week and,
um,
I went to the rose bowl with
a fellow comedian and uh,
I'm not gonna name his name. Usually I'll
do that. Maybe give somebody, you know,
bump up their friends or that type of
stuff, which I'd love to do for this guy,
but my behavior was so,
uh,
colorful. That's the word I'll
use that you know, just in case,
you know what I mean? I'm old
school. I don't name names.
When I start talking about a semi crimes
that I committed, not really committing,
well I guess being drunk
in public is a crime bill.
Why don't you shut the fuck up and get to
the story and we'll, I'll be the judge.
Fine. Fine. Okay. You guys with all
the tension beginning of 2009 you know,
you guys be more relaxed this year.
You know things going to be
fad in 2000 and maven link.
They gotta rhyme, you know, just
make it rhyme and then, then, then,
then I'm supposed to feel good.
You know,
and I'm not supposed to notice that last
year it was things that are going to be
great in 2008 and now you've knocked it
down. Now it's things that would be fine.
Thanks. It'd be great, man.
They going to be fine. No,
don't freak out in 2010. Oh, did they
combine this with Canada in 2011?
Why am I fucking checking myself out at
a grocery store and I'm not getting paid
for it? Okay. So my name is,
I go to the rose bowl with a comedian.
We're just going to call him Joe.
All right.
Cause that's the classic alias name.
When you don't want to get somebody
in trouble, you just call him Joe.
But the ironic thing is this
guy's name is actually Joe.
So me and Joe,
we go to the a fellow comedian and you
can try to figure out who the fuck he is
and it's not fiscal. Um, we
go to the Rose Bowl and uh,
we had great intentions. Okay. Let
me paint a picture for you. Okay.
When you go to the rose bowl,
it's one of the great
tailgating experiences you'll
ever have. First of all,
you go into the Rose Bowl,
okay?
The granddaddy of them all home have
a bunch of Superbowls Superbowls with
polluted that, that bowl, uh,
if you see that famous Lynn Swann catch
that wasn't made there actually realized
that was made at Temple University,
wasn't it?
I don't fucking know
that there's been a on,
I know that Jackie Slater one where
he dropped the ball. That's right.
That that cowboys Steelers won
the greatest fucking, I dunno,
clash of two powerhouse
teams I ever saw was the uh,
I dunno,
whatever they played once you're fucking
things there and I don't have the
information in front of me and I'm
really killing the momentum of the story.
So anyway, so you go there, right?
And you get right behind the Rosebowl
is what I'm assuming is an 18 hole golf
course.
Cause God knows that's how big it felt
at the end of the game when I was two
shit faced and we couldn't find
the car and we walked before.
But that, that I'm getting ahead of
myself. You know what I'm foreshadowing,
I'm doing what all great movies.
Do you know what I mean?
You go see a movie whenever they
show movie about a guy who dies,
everybody knows he's going to die.
So they show them diet in the beginning
and then the next scene is they go back
to his childhood.
You know what I mean?
Except they never do that with the Elvis
movie because then they'd have to start
the movie with some fat, Fuck Diane on
the toilet and no one wants to do that.
I'll just
[inaudible] is that my pancreas?
PLOP. Um, anyways,
so Jesus Christ, let's get some
momentum here. So we fucking,
we go to this tailgate. All right.
And this is the deal. Basically,
there's just two of us and amongst us,
we have four hamburger patties,
two bags of chips, hamburger
buns, 12 pack of Bud Light,
12 pack of Budweiser,
and a Clint Eastwood canteen,
size of fucking crown royal,
and to Cuban cigars that I
snuck back from fucking Canada.
So we're ready to go. I got my
sunblock, we loaded up into the Prius,
which is, uh, which was just fucking
hilarious. You know, everybody,
everybody tries to outman people
at the, uh, at the tailgates,
people cone up there with, they
have their fucking, you know,
for two or pickups with the lift
kits, you know, their generators,
sky to fucking satellite dish
in a flat screen TV. You know,
I came there with a little Hibachi,
but whatever.
We had the big thing of crown royal,
so people and Cuban cigars.
So no one fucked with us, right?
So we're having a great time.
All of a sudden this lady comes
walking by and she's like, Hey,
do you want to buy a little ticket
holder fee? A ticket? I'm like,
absolutely sweetheart, 10 bucks a
whack. Let me get, let me get that.
Two Times they had baby, you know,
you got a cigar in your mouth,
you start getting a little swagger.
Some reason when he likes
starts rocking back and forth.
Like you've got to sing it like
you're going to sing an Elvis song.
I was feeling it and the great thing was
I didn't give a fuck about either team
USC or Penn State. I was just happy
to fucking be there, you know?
But I quickly realized most
people were for the Trojans.
So automatically I'm a cunt.
Second concert of the year,
I'm like, you know what,
I'm going to root for the,
I'm going root for Penn state because
this gives me way more chance to annoy
people. Plus, I, I've
never liked USC and uh,
most of it has to do back in the day.
I used to be a Notre Dame fan before
Lou Holtz with their holy or holier than
thou. We don't do steroids. Shut
the fuck up. Yes you do. All right.
I had acne when I was fucking a teenager.
Right. But it wasn't all over my back.
And I also couldn't pick up a
house. Okay. So you fucking,
people are doing steroids anyways.
And also,
I always hated the Trojans fight song.
They played every three seconds. Bad, bad,
bad, bad, bad. You know,
they came like half a yard.
And it also reminds me of Fleetwood Mac,
who I never liked. So fuck the Trojans.
Right? So anyway, so we're sitting
there, we're drinking, we're partying,
would equally eating burgers and a,
then we break up the crown royal after
we had polished off a good half a case
between the two of us.
It's probably nine 30 in the morning
and we just started pounding this crown
royal,
which is going down like fucking Koolaid.
I was really impressed with my ability
or at least the the makers of crown royal
that is some smooth shit. So, uh,
so basically we start walking towards
the stadium and the alcohol is flowing
through me and that's when
I go into my transformation.
I don't know what happens
to me at sporting events,
but instantly I just become the loud guy.
I feel like I'm,
I'm doing a comedy show.
I want to make the people around me
laugh and I also want to irritate as many
fucking people as I can.
So I start walking in there
and I quickly notice, um,
all I know I went to go buy a program.
I'm trying to put this all back
together cause I was pretty drunk. I go,
just to give you an idea of,
of the mood that I was in,
I get to about a hundred
yards from the stadium.
This lady's selling
programs and she's like, Oh,
I get you program can come on and get the
bar graphs and like, I fuck it. I want,
I want a souvenir. So I walk up and like,
how much are they? She's like, 10 bucks.
My God,
I find,
so this other guy comes walking up
because how much for the programs?
And The lady's like 10 bucks, right?
And the guy starts bitching Ted,
my kid be right. So I'm standing there,
I got a Cuban cigar. I go, you know what?
Let me get another one, two times.
Let me get two of those. All right,
one for you over there. And the
guy's like, really? I go, Hey,
I go take a look at me. They
go, you know, you're looking at,
you're looking at a big shot.
Take a good look. There's not a,
there's not a lot of us left. I swear
to God, I said that and I was so drunk.
I was only half joking.
Like,
I knew I was being an asshole,
but like I was only half had fucking
Cuban cigar. Go Fuck Yourself.
I'm a big shot. Let's get a
program for this fag over here.
Who's bitching about 10 PUCO still
Rosebowl in bitches about a $10 fucking
program.
You know what I mean?
He should have been de pants and he should
have his tickets removed right there
and sent right back to wherever
the fuck he, Kiki came from,
send to an Applebee's, watched
the game there. All right.
Kind of fucking behaviors. That is
the granddaddy of them all. Thank you.
Fucking money out and play the
Goddamn game. All right. So anyways,
so I'm hammered, right? And we're
fucking, we're walking and uh,
I don't know what happened. We got
into the stadium, everything was cool.
And then they have this weird
sort of like, they funnel you in,
cause it's a really old
stadium. It's like, you know,
it's like trying to go through the
Lincoln tunnel like five o'clock at night.
It's a pain in the ass.
So I'm standing there,
I'm getting frustrated because
it's getting close to kick off.
And I hate missing kickoff.
So I'm getting pissed.
And I noticed that the Penn state fans,
they got this chant where one of them,
I don't know where it just yells,
we are.
And then all the Penn state fans go Penn
state. And then the dude yells again,
we are. And they all go Penn state
and they say it like five times.
And then the end, the guy who
starts the chant goes thank you.
And then everybody screams,
yo welcome.
And I immediately noticed that it annoyed
the shit out of all these UFC fence.
You know,
cause they kind of felt like it was a
home game cause they were out there.
So next thing you know, I even
think it, next thing you know,
coming out of my mouth, I'm
going, we are, I'm not even,
I'm a from Penn state, I don't know shit.
Right. But I just still going, we god,
let's go with Penn State Penn state.
And I'm like Dang you. And they're
like, Yo, welcome. I'm like,
this is fucking awesome.
I can do this the whole game and annoy
the shit out of people around me. So
like it took us 20 minutes,
20 minutes to get through the tunnel.
And I swear to God, I was
like, perfect timing light.
As we got through the tunnel,
this chick is finishing
singing the national anthem
as we just take in the rose
bowl on a sunny California day,
everybody's wearing their Trojan colors.
Everybody's wearing that Penn state.
There's pompoms.
People are going fucking nuts.
And this lady's like, Eh, no,
Ho up the wave.
And what is,
she finished a fucking stealth bomber.
Flies right over the goddamn top. I'm
shifts like it's like a fucking acid trip.
I almost passed out. Right? So now
you know we've got end zone seats,
you know, evidently I'm not a big shot
and we'll wait at the top of the stadium,
which is a really rough thing to
negotiate when you're a redhead drinking
whiskey in the sun, right? So
we get all the way up to like row
whatever, fucking triple f and you know,
it's an old stadium. Okay.
And you know, back in the day,
like you would tall if you will, like
five foot six when the stadium was built.
And now,
you know,
with fucking growth hormones and
all the preservatives in the food,
we basically outgrown the stadium's,
not to mention the cheesecake factories
that have these fucking people go to
every other day.
So I'm trying to walk a tight rope down.
I'm literally acting this out on my
bedroom, by the way. This is how,
into these stories I get to tell.
So I'm literally walking a fucking tight
rope trying to get down to my seat and
I just become that guy.
I fell, I didn't fall.
I sorta like,
like Lyft.
It was like almost like I was on his show.
I was the only guy in a ship that
was in a fucking perfect storm.
And all of a sudden the whole thing
just listed to the right side.
And I landed on this like
55 year old lady back.
Didn't like land like I was doing.
I was on one foot and I,
I put a knife forearm little,
I'll Samuelson in front of the net fucking
action right on a pack and I was so
drunk it took me,
I swear to God,
they at least 28 seconds to get off her
and the entire time I am apologizing
with my fucking cigar whiskey
breaths just got on site. Uh,
I'm on the side of the fight and I just
couldn't get off because I,
the only way to get off or was to put all
my weight on my forearm and use her as
a Bannister to push me back up because
nobody's fucking helping me because I'm
obviously the drunk guy.
You don't want to touch me.
So 28 seconds to trying to figure out if
I have the quad strength to pull myself
up without pushing off the
back of this old lady's neck.
I finally just say fuck
it and just drive my,
the meat of my forearm right between
her shoulder blades and I get up,
I apologize profusely and I don't
know what Joe was doing at this point.
He was fucking probably just
standing there watching the game.
But basically we finally get to our seats.
It was unreal.
I didn't know what, we got to
our seats and I, we turn around,
we faced the game to watch the game and
next thing you know this lady is just
screaming at us.
She's like,
hey screaming and she's yelling, you
can't smoke in here. And I'm like,
what the fuck is she talking about?
Because I put my my cigar out.
I'm gonna tell you to do the
fucking Cuban is sweet too, man.
I smoked that thing all the
way down like a Goddamn Roach.
It's like burning my fucking fingers
and she's yelling, stop smoking.
I'm like the fuck she talking about
do I smell like a cigar? And I turned,
I looked,
I looked to my right and Joe is standing
there with the fucking Cuban cigars
still lit in his mouth.
I don't know how the fuck he got a pass.
Security I think is cause we
had our tickets, those tickets,
things I bought around our neck. I don't
know if he headed down by his side,
but he's sitting there chomping on
it like fucking Archie bunker. So
you know, in defense of me, if she just
turned around and she had just said,
hey guys, um, you know that, you
know, I don't know if you know,
but there's no smoking in here.
Yeah. I would've been like, you know,
I'm a happy drunk. I swear to God, I'm
angry when I'm sober, but I sweat it.
I'm a happy drunk. I just
would've been like, hey, so I
bought that. We didn't know,
oh, what do you use a right, good
luck, uh, by how high, whatever.
I would've kept it at that,
but she fucking was yelling at us,
so I don't like being yelled at.
And I like the info.
I like fucking with people and I'm shit
faced and Joe is of the same ilk and
then that's when it all started,
she just based, she's like,
hey, she goes, there's no smoking in here.
And then immediately I just go
and I just go and was like, Hey,
says who? She goes at California.
You. I had to smoke indoors.
We're like, we're outside. And she goes,
you're not allowed to smoke it. And I go,
you're not my mother. This
isn't our section. This isn't
your section. Turn around.
Right. I just kept being an
asshole. And then finally she goes,
I'm going to call security. And
I'm like, call them. She goes,
I'm going to call him. I go, go
ahead and call him in. In my head,
my brain is going, Bill, shut up, shut up.
You're going to get 90 seconds into the
game, you're going to get kicked out.
And I just couldn't stop myself. I
just kept saying, call him, call him.
And then,
then she made some sort of comment,
I think about the size of Joe's
knows. And then he said, hey,
he goes, you need to lose a hundred
pounds to talk to me, bitch. He said,
Eh, the guy to the left of us
turned around and he's like, Hey,
I got my kit, I got my kid
here, what are you cursive?
And then Joe goes, well then don't
bring them to a fucking football.
So now I'm doing that laugh.
You know that last way,
like your mouth is wide open,
but there's no air coming in or out.
I'm having the time of my life
and then the fucking guy goes,
he goes, I'm going to call
security. And then I'm just,
then at once again I'm going call up,
I'm going to call him
God and call up call.
I was just calling that bluff because
we was so fucking jam packed and I knew
they weren't going to walk
down there and go do that.
So that lady makes
another fucking comment.
At which point Joe makes another comment
about her weight and then she just
turns down and it's like mark and yells
down to her husband and next thing you
know this fucking dude comes running
over and he starts screaming at it.
Since he's screaming at us,
this spray is coming out of his mouth
all over his wife. So it was easy.
I didn't fucking, I was just going,
sir, sir, you're spitting on your wife.
And once you know, that whole thing
was pathetic. He was like 53 but like,
and I'm 40 and I'm thinking like that
and I'm too old to fight this guy.
You know, it was just, Oh God,
I'm trying to piece this together.
And so we all sit down,
right? So then we sit down.
I think Joe would put out the cigar.
Maybe it was just holding it down.
I don't know what was going on.
But now by this time we'd
already missed the kickoff.
The Trojan's get the ball and I think
this is the basically the one good play
Penn state made all day. They Trojans
their first play. I think offense,
they handed off the ball and they tried
to do like some sort of sweep the Penn
state defense strung out and just stuck
this guy either for no gain on full,
like lots of one yard.
And then Joe go,
I forgot to mention is
a good six foot four,
just a huge guy just start screaming
like an inch from the back of the Lady's
head. Who's a Trojan Fan. He just
starts screaming like, Nah, Nah,
Nah. I said, I can't believe
like her hair wasn't moving.
He was yelling so loud as a she,
I know she turned around and she had
that shit up noxious. That's just the,
it was, it was, it was
great. It was fucking great.
And then basically what would
have for the rest of the game,
shit would calm down and then we would,
we would,
I don't know,
we would mumble something about her and
then she would fucking yell down to her
husband and then he'd come
over threatening to kick
our ass and we would just
laugh at them. And then, I don't
know, I just realized I was so drunk,
I can't even remember the rest. I
remember it was the very end of the game,
uh,
somebody,
Joe or somebody said something about the
score and then the lady in front of us
goes, yeah, I'm surprised you
can count that high. I go, yeah,
why don't you try counting calories?
Right. Something real mean like that.
And then once again, she's like
mark. And then at this point,
half the crowd and left
because of such a blowout,
this two comes over and he
starts fucking screaming at me.
Doesn't scream at Joe
because Joe is six foot four.
He yells at me cause I'm fucking barely
five 10 and I'm a fucking redhead. Right?
Even with the shaved head,
I still look like fucking howdy duty.
So he starts yelling at me
and he keeps telling me, yeah,
I'm going to fire you down on the field.
That's all he kept saying.
He kept telling me he's going to grab
me and fire me down on the fucking field
and I was just, you know, and
I was just being an asshole.
Good dead do it. I'm going to fight on
bail. You said that you already said that.
You already said you already said
it. You fucking cunt. All right,
you got to do it.
You would have and you didn't so you're
not so sit down and shut the fuck up.
Which is funny because
by the end of the game,
everyone in the stands somehow
liked us and hated those people.
I mean half of it was
because they were assholes.
The other half was they couldn't
hear the shit that we will mumble.
And at this dude's wife
pool,
I know at this point he might
have a little bit of sympathy for,
but I mean I'm telling
you she was, she was, uh,
she was an asshole and she's the
one who made it personal first.
She made the comment about
Joe's knows she, uh, oh,
she was doing real hacky lines too.
She's told me I was ugly.
She goes and I always can lose
weight, you know, which, uh,
I believe I saw during the second
season of def jam and um, you know,
and I thought,
well,
we will come in with was a lot more
clever and if it was a battle of the bands
in a standup situation,
I think we won. So, uh,
basically what ended up happening,
I know this is a long ass fucking story.
I don't even have time for questions
this week, but long story short,
we ended up walking out.
Um,
I want to believe that somehow the lady
in front of us to who was being a jerk
had a bunch of these dark streaks. On the
back of a shirt towards the end of it.
I don't know what it was.
It almost looked like a
ashes from a cigar. But um,
I know that that didn't happen because
there's no smoking in there. But anyways,
we go to leave and we're
basically so drunk.
I don't know man.
It took us like fucking nine hours,
literally took us 50
minutes to find our car.
And I think it was calmer for being such
assholes in, in, in, in the stadium.
And I don't, I don't know who the fuck
set up the parking lot things out there,
but they basically,
the way they do the sections on this golf
course is they have like balloons that
they just have numbers, number
one, number two, number three.
But they're not lit up so you
can't really see them at night.
So you walk out of the stadium
drunk and you look up and you see,
I saw the number to where we were,
where we were parked and, but you know,
you've got to follow the path because
you can't walk through the sand traps and
shit like that.
So you look down for half a second,
then you look up and there's like a big
fucking oak tree in front of you and now
you don't know where you are.
It's like the end of the shining without
the shrubs. It's a fucking golf course,
right?
So and you're far enough away from the
stadium where you can't get your bearings
and were just wandering around and
around and around and it's getting to the
point like you know like hypothermia is
becoming an issue because it's a desert.
It starts getting cold,
was shit faced and we just can find a car.
It was like a Blair witch. We kept coming
back to the same goddamn ladies' teas,
whatever the fuck we were.
And then I lost all confidence in
my ability to find the damn car.
So I start following Joe, who is
convinced, even though we both know we're,
we're parked in section two,
we went from section three,
section four to section five,
and he keeps telling me to go in that
direction because for some reason he
thinks numerically it's going
to go three, four, five to,
I dunno, took us an hour to
find the fucking car. And uh,
at that point I started sobering up and
I started thinking about a behavior and
I was starting to thinking like, yeah, I
Kinda Kinda feel like an asshole. Yeah.
You know, I shouldn't say I
shouldn't taken the higher ground,
even though that girl was a con,
you know? And he was just like,
what are you talking about? What are
you talking about? She was a cunt.
We treated her like one in and that's it.
That's what I love about that guy.
He just, he just breaks it down
to the simplest fucking point.
Hey Buddy, I got my kid here. Well, don't
take your kid to a fucking football game,
which, you know, I know that's
harsh, especially if you have kids.
But think about it.
Think about it.
Why would you bring your kid to his
professional to sporting of that?
Not only that,
that the guy with the kid is being
hypocritical because he was made before he
had a kid. All right? He was having the
time of his fucking life and what now?
Cause he has a kid now all
of a sudden I'm supposed to,
I'm supposed to fucking act my age.
You know,
it's like the fucking
baby boom generation.
They banked so much to fucking in the
mud Woodstock that by the time I come
around there's herpes and aids and all
this shit. And then they, you know,
then they come around with their don't
do drugs where a condom shit after they
had the time of their fucking lives.
I'm so glad all of them I get in debt.
Whole generation is getting hip
replacements now with their fucking cause.
They all had that fucking Olivia Newton
John High impact aerobics tape that they
did try and to stay in shape.
That's the one good fucking thing.
Consider I gotta fuck with the God
damn trash bag around my dick my entire
career. Right. The very least,
I at least knew to stretch
before you lifted weights.
And I also dangerous of high impact
aerobics. Okay. When I did my aerobics,
I definitely was rocking the leg warmers,
but I did not let my feet
leave the ground. Okay. Um,
so anyways, so that's
my rose bowl story. Um,
it's a fucking law when I know that, but
I think it had some nice moments. But um,
yeah. But getting back to that, what do
you guys think about that stuff? You know,
sporting events are not for children.
Okay.
And I know they always try to talk
about the good old days of sports.
The girl days of sports is bullshit.
Okay.
When I was a kid, first football game
I went to, I was fucking terrified.
I was terrified.
It was not a place for kids.
It was a place for adults who hadn't
achieved what they thought they were going
to achieve in life to get their
fucking anger and frustration out.
People within loveless
marriages, you know, people,
you know,
people who could tell they were going
to get laid off the next week or maybe
they already got laid off and they just
wanted to get it out. Okay. And they,
you know, they've now turned going
to a fucking football game into like,
you're standing in line with a bunch
of people waiting to get their kids,
you know, photo taken with
Santa Claus. You know,
and even if you go further back than
my childhood, which was seventies,
early eighties, um, if
you go back to the 1950s,
they talk about that. Oh, the good old
days of sports or what do you mean what,
when, uh, when they finally let a black
guy playing baseball and they said, well,
fucking black cat on the field and all
that racist shit that was going on.
Can you imagine the shit that was
getting yelled in the stands when Billy
crystal was going down the ground
and go watch the mic, boy, your boy,
I got myself a hotdog and assess Barilla.
You know,
they always tell those stories about
how great it was back then. It wasn't,
it wasn't great. They were
way more racist, way more
ignorant, way more sexist.
And people went to the games and
they saw Johnny Unitas. Okay.
So now for some reason,
now it's my turn to be an asshole and be
a drunk and have a good time and all of
a sudden I have to take everything down
a level, you know, not now. Now it's,
it's Chuckie cheese time. It isn't.
And I know you guys are saying,
well that's because you don't have a
kid right now. No, fuck that. Fuck that.
I wouldn't bring my kid to the game.
Or if I brought the kids to the games,
I would prepare him. I prepare them, you
know, this is what's going to happen.
Okay. You might see a
fight, you know, hey,
dad might even get in one. No, I'm
not. I never took it to that level.
But you know what I mean?
I think, uh, I don't know,
but it, it did help guilty. I am from my,
my behavior that I actually pulled
up a quote from George Orwell who,
uh, granted, this is from Wikipedia,
which the other day I looked up something
that I knew something about and was
completely inaccurate.
But this is according to
Wikipedia, George Orwell said,
serious sport has nothing to do
with fair play. It's a bound up.
It's bound up with hatred,
jealousy, boastfulness,
disregard of all rules and
sadistic pleasures, pleasures
in witnessing violence.
In other words, it's war minus
the shooting. Exactly. Now,
why the fuck would you bring a
child to that? And not only that,
when was George Orwell alive
a long fucking time ago?
I don't know when he was
alive. One of you, right?
1984. He didn't write it in 83.
I know that he wasn't like the 30.
Stephanie. I'm just saying. See,
that's how he described sports
back then. So guys, like, you know,
these Billy crystal guys,
we'll always do those little
heartwarming stories about, uh, you know,
their baseball cards and going down to
the baseball stadium and acting like it
was this fucking, you know, this
time that was lost, you know,
George Orwell right there
according to Wikipedia,
think I proved my point.
I'm a moron,
but I did have a good time and I'm
gonna tell you like this right now,
if you ever get a chance in your
life to smoke a Cuban cigar,
definitely do it all right.
Because I'm not even a big smoker.
And I could tell how fucking amazing
that cigar was because I've drank fine
wines and I can't tell the difference,
you know?
And it took me a long time to be
comfortable with myself, you know,
and he goes through the whole long
process of spinning the big red wine glass
around. I see. Read up on
wine to try to learn. So I, I,
you know about it.
So I wouldn't feel so fucking stupid when
they bring a nice bottle of wine over
and I'm like, you know, this tastes like
the shit I used to drink in high school.
You know, I learned
that, you know, red wine,
the reason why it's in a bigger glass is
because something about the oxygen and
you want it to believe more and how to,
you know,
move it around the fucking table and
then you shove your fucking nose all the
way in it and yet put it in.
You switch it all around your mouth.
I've got all the moves down and I'm
like, swallow it. I'm like, yes,
this tastes like every other fucking
red wine I've ever had. That's not true.
I can tell the difference between like,
you know,
a Cabernet or Merlot
or something like that,
but like I can't tell like the
difference between a 1499 bottle and a,
a $60 bottle and uh, you know, I guess
I'm trying to say with this podcast,
I'm not that cultured.
Okay. All right. Well,
so why don't you guys chime in what that,
okay. Like, whoa. Do you think David,
they should have a kids section. Should
they just have a Chucky cheese section?
It's not my fault.
You're knocked her up and you can't
go to a game and have a good time now.
You know, you want to be getting
drunk with me. All right.
See what I just did there.
That's how I made myself write,
made this guy who can't
even defend himself, uh,
actually be secretly agreeing
with me. That's how I do it. Um,
did I mention I have a rat
problem? Um, I have, uh,
I have a really nice apartment, but
the garage I have is a glorified shack.
Like if they ever decide to do the
Hatfields and McCoys TV series,
they could shoot it on location
in my garage. Okay. Is a
rotting out hunk of shit.
And even though the door comes down, um,
the hole in the back of the garage, he,
granted you couldn't
drive my car out of it,
but a fucking rat could crawl into it on
a rainy night and then crawl up into my
engine and sleep.
This mother Fucker,
I took my car down to get it service
and they took out the air conditioner
filter and it was rat shit in there.
And I got to pause for everybody
going, hey, God is good.
So you know, being a man, I'm like, okay,
operation kill the fucking
rat is now in motion.
And I sat there and I thought,
how can I kill this motherfucker?
And basically what I did was I went to um,
a smaller hardware cause fuck home depot
and there are eight people in aprons.
Um,
and I bought a
$114 worth of those rat glue traps and
I got a couple of really big cardboard
boxes and then I took some duct tape
because when you don't know what the fuck
you doing,
duck tape is always a solution.
And I duct taped 28 of
these mother fuckers,
I think over 30, I think I lost count
how many I did on all these box on,
on two big boxes,
side by fucking side.
And I split them underneath my
car. Okay. You want to get dry?
Why don't you try to get, try and
get by that now? I don't know,
cause rats are intelligent now.
I don't know if what I have in my garage
right now is the star wars plan that
Ronald Reagan always dreamed of.
I don't know if I have the red version
of that or if I have the Maginot line,
you know, magical line. Anybody?
Amen. You want to read up on that one?
That's one of the classic military
blenders of all time. Basically,
Germany invaded, you know, France in
World War One. It was trench warfare,
ton, ton of loss of life. They
came in, they got invaded,
they got overrun and all that,
blah, blah, blah, blah, Blah shit.
So they wanted to make sure that they
would never happen again because they were
worried about Germany, you
know? And why wouldn't you Ben?
So they decided to build like
this is called the Maginot line.
And it was permanent trenches with these,
these fucking basically built in.
I don't look like an anti,
it wasn't anti aircraft.
That was the problem that killed him. That
was fucking, uh, like machine gun nests,
like permanent all the way around and
they spent all this fucking money on it.
And what's Hilarious, by the time
they went to war with Germany again,
they had perfected the aircraft and they
basically just flew right up and over
all the fucking trenches, you
know, drop bombs on them and shit.
And they once again took over fucking
France and I'm so, I don't know.
I don't know if the rat laughed
at it, brought into the, you know,
a couple friends over this
shit inside of my car,
but I'm going to kill that fucker.
And all you animal lovers can go fuck
yourselves because I'm not losing a
$23,000 automobile to a fucking in.
All right.
I'm going to show him why I live inside.
And I don't have to shit on an air
conditional fields filter. Okay,
let's get the podcast questions,
Shelly people.
Um, I'll let you guys know how it goes
if I kill the rat or not. All right.
Podcast question number one. Bill since
you're a patriots fan, I got to ask you,
what's your honest opinion
on the Tuck rule game? Uh,
I'm a raider fan and I think that was
hands down the biggest bullshit call and
the history of sports.
And still to this day I carry it with me.
The fact that the eight and eight charges
made the play offs over the 11 and
five patriots made me happy inside.
And while I respect Tom Brady
is one of the great all time.
Qbs if he snapped his leg in three places,
places I'd be a happy man.
Okay. Um, for those of you
who aren't big sports fans,
the Tuck rule was basically is
basically a rule where the quarterback,
if he goes,
I basically goes into the passing motion,
doesn't throw the ball and if
he brings it back to his chest,
if somebody whacks the ball out,
then it's a considered an
incomplete pass or something.
I really should have looked up the
tough rule. And um, and you know,
basically the Raiders slap the ball
out of Brady's hand. They fell on it.
They had bought,
they won the game because it was a fumble
and then they brought out this the top
rule, which nobody had ever heard
of, including probably Tom Brady. Um,
when he wants to know what
is my feeling on that? Um,
I don't feel it was a big relax,
let me finish.
I don't feel it was the biggest
bullshit call in the history of sports.
I think it's the biggest bullshit
rule in the history of sports.
That's the thing. They made the right
call. The rule needed to be changed.
I think it's a bullshit rule. I think
that that should have been a fumble.
It is a fumble. He didn't talk and he
was going to throw it and he didn't,
and then he pulled it in. He
got slapped. It is a fumble,
but that's what it should be.
But because of the Tuck rule,
it was actually the right call.
But it's a bullshit rule and
I'm big enough to admit that.
But the reality is,
you know,
why that happened to you and why you
carry that with you. Oh, poor baby.
You've had to carry that
since. What, 2001 a poor baby.
You know what I had to carry for almost
20 years was that roughing the passer
call. You're probably
too young, remember this,
but we basically beat the fucking Raiders
in 1976 we had you guys beaten sugar
bay. Hamilton is coming in against Ken
Stabler. He jumps in the air. Once again,
I'm acting this out.
He jumps in the air as stabler
is going to release the ball.
He's in the fucking air.
The ball is released.
He slams into Ken Stabler and they call
roughing the passer like he was supposed
to change mid air. Now I don't
know if you guys know this shit,
but back then roughing the
passer was not a yardage penalty.
They basically put the ball where they
were trying to complete it and it was the
end of the game and they threw
a fucking 50 yard hail Mary.
They called roughing the passer,
so they gave him the ball.
Now it's not on the 50 they put it on
like the fucking three yard line and the
Raiders went in to go score.
That my friend was the biggest bullshit
call of all time because that was a
complete wrong interpretation of the rule.
Do you understand the difference?
The talk rule is a bullshit rule
that was interpreted correctly.
So the guy made the correct call.
He did make the correct call,
but I feel for you because
that was a bullshit that was a,
it's a bullshit rule and the
Raiders should have won that game.
But that was payback because the
Patriots should have beat you in 1976 but
because a lot of you rate
of fans are a lot younger,
you don't remember it or maybe
you don't want to remember,
but I carried that from
1976 to 2001 all right,
so that was 15 years.
All right, youngster,
you're only seven years into
your bullshit, so I have
no sympathy for you. Okay.
Sorry.
I get heated when it comes to sports
and he said something that was the next
thing. Let's, what's your, what's your
opinion on the field goal guy? You know,
everybody, a bunch of guys, I don't
want to fucking read this one.
I went too long and that when I get
get it kits and some other people,
I don't mind field goal kickers by the
way. Sorry. I still got my old laptop.
I'm trying to not hit this
button too much. All right bill.
Um, I want your can be
comedic opinion on something.
I was talking to a coworker of mine
about a girl that I had been seeing. Oh,
I love this question. This is a great
story. Everybody just settle in,
settle in and turn this, turn this down.
Turn this down. Cause I think this has,
does this have the word continent? I'm not
sure. Okay, here we go. All right bill,
I want you to comedic
opinion on something.
I was talking to a coworker of mine
about a girl that I had been seeing that
I've been kind of seeing.
I was telling him that one thing I
really like about her is how he wrote the
song, how her, how good
her smell, her hair smells.
Um, well there's Twat of a girl
that works with me, overheard us,
and decided to chime in by
saying shit like she wants,
she wants to meet the girl who would go
out with a guy like me and how she would
actually be nervous to be alone with me.
All right.
I know my reading out loud skills suck.
So let me just sort of paraphrase
what happens. This is at work.
He's kind of seeing this girl and he
says to a friend of his, yeah, you know,
seeing this girl, you know what? I really
love, your hair smells really great.
That's all I have to send
an instant conversation.
And then this other girl who's not even
in the conversation as they had god,
I'd love, I'd love to meet the girl
would go out with you. You know,
I'd be nervous to be alone with
you. Right? Completely uncalled for.
And he goes,
et cetera.
So now we recently found out that that
girl who chimed in just had an abortion
like a week and a half ago.
Jesus. But I brushed her off,
I, so I brushed her off,
but the bitch didn't stop.
She continued on by asking another female
worker if she'd be nervous to be alone
with me,
which my response was,
why don't you ask, why don't
we ask someone what it's
like to be alone with you?
Oh, wait a minute. That's
right. You killed it. Wow.
Wow. Wow. Dude. You said that at work.
Wow. Okay. Okay. And he basically says,
which shocked half of the people at
work and made the other half crack up
laughing. She called me an
insensitive asshole. Yeah. Okay.
But I could care less. To
me. She was asking for it.
It's not like she was just sitting there
minding her own business and I walked
up and said, what's new fetus
killer? What do you think, Bill?
Was I out of line or was it a kickass?
Come back.
Okay. Let me wrap my fucking
head around this. Um,
all right. First of all, it
was an unbelievable comeback.
It was a game set and match come back.
You know,
it was literally,
you know,
I dunno, she didn't even
bring a knife to a gunfight.
She was sitting there with a water
pistol and you took out a machete and you
fucking chopped her head off and I dunno,
held it up for everyone to
see and then you swung her,
her fucking head around by the ponytail
and threw it across the office is
basically what you did. Um, well
what do you think? Was I out of line?
Yeah.
I'm going to have to say yes because
I totally understand why you went there.
Like why you wanted to hurt her back
because what she was saying to you was
fucked up,
but she was fucked up on like level two
and then you went right to the penthouse
level. You know what I mean? I'm not
going to say level two. She was good.
She was a good a third of the
way up the building. Okay.
I don't know why I'm using a building
as an analogy, but I'm too deep now.
I have to go with this.
But you went right to the penthouse suite
and you kicked her ass right off of it,
and you didn't even do it on the side.
You know where they have that,
that canopy thing with a bellman stance,
we're in a three stooges mover. You,
you'd somehow live,
you kicked her out the backside of the
building right down into the fucking
alley where there's a rat way into
crawl up into my fucking car. Um,
yeah. What I would, what, I don't
know how old you are, but yeah,
you kind of went,
well,
you didn't have to go where you,
what you have to do as you get older, both
with men and women as psychologically,
you have to realize where they're
coming from and you have to understand,
especially knowing that she had just
had an abortion dude, which is fucking,
is, is, that's brutal for a guy
that goes through, you know,
if you have any sort of a
conscious, forget about a
woman who's actually caring,
you know what I'm saying?
And so the reason why she's saying that
she obviously is having difficulty with
her own relationships and is so fucking
insecure that to hear someone around her
actually may be making some
sort of connection and be
happy in that area of her
life is fucking with her so much that
it wasn't enough just to say the means
shipped to you.
She starts walking around the office like
trying to get people to like reinforce
her statement and to sort
of cock block you and um,
I understand why,
why you did that,
you know, you know, and
you've gotta understand why
you went to that level. Okay.
You went literally to that level
that had nothing to do with her.
That adds some shit to do
the baggage you are bringing.
I don't know what house you saw that you
came from a household like my household
where, uh, you know, somebody makes fun
of your shirt and you're like, yeah,
at least my fucking uncle isn't dead.
You know, you know, you just admit,
you immediately go way beyond
what was just said to you. So,
uh, was it out of line?
Definitely. Out of line, dude,
you shouldn't say shit like that at work.
I don't want you to lose your job,
but you know I'm not gonna lie to you.
It was fucking hilarious.
And not to mention who fell
after my Rosebowl story.
Who the fuck am I to say anybody
was out of line. I'm thinking,
you know where I'm at. This is like
your story. I'm trying to break it down.
How you ended up there is where I'm at
as a human being right now I'm still
doing the what's new fetus killer lines.
But I'm trying not to do that.
You know it's funny on a comedy stage,
but it's not funny at the Rose Bowl.
All right, but dude, I got,
I got to give you, you know,
I got to give you a fucking over the phone
high five on that one. That was just,
wow. Why don't we ask someone who's been
with alone with you. Oh wait a minute.
That's right.
You killed it.
There's no way people bursted out
laughing. That's one of those things,
if you found it funny,
you made that, you know,
you raise your eyebrows up like
holy shit and you got to walk away.
You know what I mean?
Somehow there has to be a corner within
10 yards for you to walk around so you
can let that left go. God dammit. That's,
that was brutal. But that was funny.
Come on women. You gotta laugh. You got
to know. That's funny. I know. I know.
It's brutal for, come
on. That was funny. Okay.
Uh, where are we going? Where are we
going? All right. US sports questions.
All of a sudden people really liked the
sports. Okay, another question, Bill.
What happened to our beloved teams
is a Boston Person. Do the Patriots,
try and keep Matt Cassel.
Knowing Tom Brady is rehabbing,
is rehab is slightly behind.
Um,
do the jets offer back the second round
they gained from spygate back for the
past? Ah, man, you going real detailed?
I have no idea what's
happened to our beloved team.
The Patriots had an unbelievable season.
And what I love about it is everyone
was questioning bills build Parcell bill
Parcell, Bill Belicheck because
of the spy gate thing. And uh,
you know,
look at this year after winning with
the six round pick three Superbowls,
seventh round draft pick, he goes 11
and five and almost wins the division.
I think he's proven himself as a fucking
coach. And uh, people always be like,
oh fucking spygate. But they got nothing.
They don't have an argument. And a,
the reason why I said bill Parcells is
because I really think that that guy is
overrated. You know, I think he's
really good at making a team good,
but he can't get them over the top.
And he throws temper tantrums when he
doesn't get his way. And he totally,
he's like the Larry Brown of football,
you know,
he's only won two Superbowls 86 and 90.
And who was his fucking defensive
coordinator? Bill Belicheck. All right.
He got to the Superbowl game
with the Patriots who was
his defensive coordinator?
Bill Belicheck. Right. You see
bill Belicheck has gone on.
It's won three super bowls.
Parcels has one, nothing, one,
nothing.
He changed the colors of team.
He definitely gets a winning
tradition going on there,
but he doesn't win. So, uh,
I'd rather have Bella in order
to realize he's a great coach.
I'm just still pissed that he'd,
he,
he announced that he was leaving our
team a week before we were going to play
super bowl for his own selfish reasons.
I really annoyed me. All right.
Question number on. Was he going for, um,
okay. For those of you not into sports,
here we go. Here's the non
sports stories. A bill.
When you do an appearance on a
big show like Letterman or Conan,
what's the protocol for
meeting the other guests?
Because the show hooked
that up automatically or the
guests isolated from each
other and the dressing
room and green rooms. Uh,
the reason I asked is NBC just recently
had a replay of your Conan episode that
you appeared on with
Keira Knightley was the headliner.
I assume one of the perks and doing the
show is getting to check out a famous
chicken person, right? Um, no you don't.
You are on a entirely different
floor than the actual famous people.
You're just the comedian. So I don't
know what it's like to do panel.
I've never done panel.
That's kind of one of my goals here for
2009 eight I can do pony a panel on one
of the later, later shows
like Carson Daly. I just have
to have something to hype.
Maybe I can do that then I'd love to do
that. But I've only been the comedian.
So basically, you know, you're
on kind of on your own floor.
Um, on Letterman you're on, you have
like your own floor to yourself,
which is cool and kind of creepy.
And then on Conan, you're,
when I did call and you know what,
I def you definitely more,
I don't know where they put the famous
people because I'm not near them.
But I did walk out and after
Chuck Norris did his sketch,
I made sure when he walked by
me, I shook his hand, you know,
thinking like that hand shook Bruce
Lee's hand, you know what I mean?
Or at least blocked his fucking kick or
some shit and whatever movie that was.
Um, but no, no, you don't get to meet
those people. Some, some people are cool.
You know, I remember once in
the first time we did Conan,
Mary Tyler Moore walked by, looked
into my room, smiled and said hello.
Um, you know, I think a lot of times
people are sitting back there thinking,
what stories am I going to tell you?
Get your head together and you're already
have your crew of people, you know,
people who book you in that
type of stuff. And, um,
cause personally before I go out and
do my set, like literally, you know,
once the show starts after the first
segment, I kind of send, you know,
all my people out of the room so I can
kind of just basically remember what my
opening joke is. So there
you go. All right. Um,
question numbers or whatever we're on.
I have these numbered wrong,
some reason says three, even
oil and it's like five. Uh,
I have a question about
your storytelling ability.
When you told the story about
getting the hot dog from pinks,
it was not only hilarious,
but I felt like I was there.
I suck at being able to replay
the funny shit that happens to me,
my family is and friends.
Does your story ability come naturally
or is it something that you've worked on?
How do you put together a good story?
Um,
I'm actually not the greatest storyteller.
I digress a lot and I'm trying to get
to get to the meat of it a lot better.
Um, but yeah, it just kinda comes
from telling a lot of stories, but uh,
but don't beat yourself up man.
You know,
there's a lot of people
who can't tell a story,
but it's more like they are the
story, you know what I mean? Like,
um,
I dunno,
I got a good friend of mine who he does
the funniest shit ever and he as you on
the ground, he does shit
offstage. I wouldn't do onstage.
And he has you on the ground laughing,
but he, he read, tells the story. It,
it doesn't sound like anything funny
happened, but like in the moment,
he's like the funniest guy.
You ever like a, it's weird.
Like I don't know how I
told that Rosebowl story.
I was just trying not to get
the other dude in trouble,
but the other dude kind of was the story.
Joe was fucking hilarious.
Um, I dunno. And then afterwards I'm,
I'm telling the story. I'm the story guy.
I tell the fucking story, but I'm
not the fucking story. All right.
I'm just a sad little man we
telling shit that I didn't do. Okay.
Question number six.
Um,
all right. Hey, what's the
word? Uh, Oh, you know what?
I got this one totally wrong.
Like someone asked me the other day,
a couple of weeks back about what I
think about the Chicago Blackhawks.
I was only mildly paying attention to him.
I didn't realize how good they were this
year and I started watching them. Um,
I think that they're going to go maybe
a couple rounds into the playoffs this
year. And, um,
also you asked me why the fuck did
the Bruins get rid of Thornton?
And I was saying why, you know, they
kind of blamed our shortcomings on him,
but I forgot that we got,
we got Phil Kessel in that trade.
So we did get something sort of a
trying to correct something there.
All right,
let me try to get to the rest of these.
All right.
Here's the new year's
resolutions. People, I know.
This is getting long news resolutions. Um,
I never understood. Yeah. You know what,
why don't I hate my shit this weekend.
Going to be at the Improv and Tampa,
go to Improv,
the number two.com for all the information
where you can click right on my
homepage. Please come out to
see me at the Improv in Tampa.
I got a whole new hour is shit.
And um, yeah, come on man.
You can't be just listening
to me for free and my podcast.
I know it's a tough economy,
but for the Christ,
they come out and fucking support me.
All right, New Year's resolutions. Um,
all right, Bill, a lot of people are
against him. Here's a guy I have. No,
I never understood the logic
of new year's resolutions.
There's turning 64 other days a year when
one can decide to do something better
for themselves.
Perhaps it's another marketing
scheme for capitalist bloodsuckers.
I'm hoping that we will make another
hoping that we'll make another irrational
decisions. It's not really a, it's more
of a statement. I kind of agree with that.
Um,
I absolutely hate new years resolutions.
People trick themselves into believing
that the best time to make changes and
start things is at the
beginning of the year.
I don't make New Year's resolutions
because they are an unnecessary.
I start every new year off with what I
refer to as my three golden rules. One,
laugh my ass off.
Every chance I get
to after I have done what I can,
I walk away from those things that
I cannot fix or resolve. And three,
I surround myself with people,
places and things I love most
and support who I am as a person.
Jesus Christ. There's somebody
who's healthy, huh? Um,
all right. What are, where are we
going here? Where are we going?
Let's wrap this fucking thing up
with the quick overrated, underrated,
and I'm actually going to pitch it because
you guys have been doing such a great
job here. Um, I'm going to say
overrated is the movie 300.
Um, that's, it's just
that it's laugh out loud.
Awful.
The second time you see it,
the first time you see it
visually it's really interesting,
but it's just the stupidest fucking
thing ever. It's complete meathead.
What it means to be a man. And
you know the, the, the kid,
you know was crying for his mother and
they fucking stick them in a loin cloth
out in the wilderness.
It's snowing out.
He's walking around in his bare feet and
he kills some sort of hybrid wolf slash
alien with a stick. And I'm supposed
to believe that. And, and, and,
you know,
and then they have the fight club moment
where he murders another fucking half
naked,
six year old with this kid.
There's smart dog and they kick
them down that fucking manhole.
And that one guy does stuff, the beautiful
back flip as he goes, it's fucking gay.
All right. And they take on an army
of 20,000. You know what I mean?
You know what that movie is.
That's the fantasy every man has after
he put these out in a bunch of women's,
saw him pussy out in like a bar
fight or something like that.
And then when you're driving home and you
start dreaming of the man you wish you
were and how you looked and
fucking, you know, mood lighting,
fuck that movie movie sucks.
It really sucks. Okay.
I think half those abs were painted on
once I saw that Janet Jackson does that,
you know that you can actually do some
shadowing there on the stomach. Okay.
Um, yes, somebody is some of radon rate
overrated. I losing your virginity.
Uh, but God, but God SEC's rules when
you figure it out later in life. Also,
my guitar playing to my friends
is underrated. Uh, Bill Burr,
the funniest men alive and chicken
wings are also under underrated.
The greatest food ever. Chicken
wings are great when you're younger,
but once your stomach is so full of
grease, when you're in the middle ages,
you can't eat them anymore.
So when joy underrated Jerky,
it's a good source of protein, low in
fat and it's tasty. Great snack. Yeah.
But you've got to go to a
truck stop to get it and uh,
there's always the danger of being raped
there, man or woman, um, underrated,
uh,
being in familiar enough company to talk
some serious shit and do some serious
ball busting.
There's nothing worse than going out
with some people you kind of know,
but you don't know enough
to know their limits.
So you can't mix it up verbally with
my friends at bars watching a game,
it's great knowing I don't
need to censor myself,
but with my girlfriend in general,
acquaintances on couples nights,
it feels like I'm eating with my
grandparents. It's all smallest talk,
no substance and I'm constantly censoring
myself. It's a psychological prison.
Exactly.
I'd have to agree with you on that one.
Totally would have to agree with you that
uh,
less couple of things.
I think that's basically it.
That's the podcast for this week. I hope
you enjoyed my long ass fucking stories.
Happy new year to everybody.
I hope you guys have a great new year
and I hope you can stick with the new
year's resolutions. Personally, I've
been, um, doing what I always do,
getting myself in shape the first half
of the year before I completely get back
out of shape and nose dive with some
Christmas cookies at the end of the year.
That's what I do. But, you know,
bikini season is coming up.
Um, yeah. You know, I did,
I actually bought that P90x thing that
they have late at night and I got to
admit, dude, it's the fucking shit.
Once you get past the guy hosting it,
you know, I don't know if I already
talked about this. He's, he's kind of a,
if you're doing a sketch about a personal
trainer and you imitated this guy,
they think that what you were doing
wasn't realistic. He goes, oh yeah.
P90X you know, talks to,
hey, there's a nice shoes or
almost as cool as mine. Okay,
let's drop down and do some crunches.
Um,
but after a while you get to
see that he's just, you know,
it's just a big insecure guy.
You know,
I think I talked about
this right halfway through.
He admits that his dad's through
a couple of no hitters, you know,
and you're like this, the pain. Right? And
you never lived up to him athletically.
Did Ya? Snide. You joined
a gym. At the very least,
you're trying to be in better shape than
your old man cause she just want a hug.
Did that make any sense? It
probably did. That's the podcast.
Thank you for listening.
And um, and uh, that's it.
I don't know how to end it. I never know
how to fucking let it go. See me, a Tampa,
go see me in Tampa at the
fucking, uh, the Improv and Tampa,
cause I'll be in Tampa,
in Florida at Tampa. Okay.
And also be at the end province Houston.
And I'm also coming back Boston,
my triumphant return to
Boston, Massachusetts. And uh,
all my dates are up, my
website, [inaudible] dot
com and all the information,
all the links,
all that shit.
And for those of you who are wondering
what happened to my date at the, uh,
Trump Taj Mahal, the Atlantic city,
whatever the fuck I was going to be,
um, I'm going to get a date up there.
We had to reschedule it. All right?
That is it.
God bless all of you and a fucking,
don't go to the automated lines at
grocery stores. All right. Love you.
So
[inaudible]
[inaudible].
Yes.
[inaudible] [inaudible]
[inaudible].