Okay.
Hey, what's going on? It's Bill Burr.
It's time for the Thursday afternoon.
Just before Friday, Monday
morning podcast. And
just checking. Just checking in
on you. Just checking in on you.
What's going on now? It's
been a sad week, you know,
for standup comedians.
It's been a sad week.
Joe De Rosa has decided to
retire. No, I'm kidding. Um,
why did I pick, why did I pick John
Room? Because his birthday's coming up.
Everybody wish Joe de Rosa happy
birthday on Sunday. All right.
On Twitter.
Yeah.
You call them twinkle toes. You call
them whatever you want, but just,
just, just wishing me happy
birthday. Anyways. Um,
what am I talking about here? Uh, it's a
sad day in stand up comedy because, uh,
that fucking Scaramucci guy got fired.
I know it happened a few days ago,
but I don't pay attention.
I don't do a podcast every couple of
days. What do you want from me? Huh? Well,
Bill, you know, we'd
like to fill, you know,
you know some Douche sent me something
on Twitter. He goes, hey bill,
please read the news before you
do your podcast on North Korea.
Shot off a nuclear warhead or a
missile or something. And I'm tilting.
My head goes, it wasn't no killer
with some sort of ballistic,
whatever the fuck that means. It's a
giant mad that could make it to Chicago.
That's the way I heard it.
And I looked it up and it wasn't nuclear.
So I wrote him back. I said, I come,
it wasn't nuclear.
You fucking dope.
Stop back and like you're too smart
to listen to my dumb podcast. I Dunno.
And then now whenever I call
people out on that, they go, oh,
she's looking for a reaction.
Oh, where are Ya? Ya. Yeah, yeah.
Take your comment and fucking go home.
Right. You're not in the sandbox anymore.
He got to run away. Huh? You're going to
go down there and hide under the scaredy
Yamada, Huh? Um, SCARAMUCCI
got fired. Fucking sucks.
Everybody says they want somebody honest.
And this guy goes in and he literally
just says what he's thinking.
I didn't know how to say
that guy. Renzi rance, r e I.
N c e tell me what it means to me.
Um,
rents he says is a fucking
paranoid schizophrenia.
Uh, paranoiacs, whatever the hell
that means. And he goes, I'm not sure.
Like Steve Bannon.
I'm not trying to suck my old caulk.
I'm not trying to build my own brand.
I'm here to serve the country.
I mean Jesus Christ.
What more do you want from
somebody in the White House?
Is it cause he said Cock,
is it,
cause he said fucking like these people
who go in there like Obama who speak
eloquently and just fucking,
you know,
hit a jump shot every fucking once in
a while. Now. My God, he's so cool.
I don't, I really don't. And I
fucking given up on people, you know,
that's how people are. And
when, when, when fucking, uh,
when George Karl had
died and what's his face?
The guy there who fucking
was always grabbing a,
or whatever the hell he was doing,
kept settling out of court, you know,
like led Zeppelin?
Yeah.
He does his tribute to George Carlin.
It's MD sitting there shitting on
him for fucking cursing too much.
I Dunno.
That's a fucking shame,
man. That is a f uh,
that is a real fucking shame
that that guy is gone. You know?
So what did we get it?
We're going to have somebody who we're
going to have a clean comic go in there
who still lies his ass off. But
where's the sweater? I mean,
if you can get past cock and fucking,
he basically said,
I'm not here for my own needs.
I'm not here to,
to advance myself. Actually, you
know, that's a lie. All right?
He's a liar too. But he was a fun
liar. Come on people. The Fun,
the guy was fun.
Okay.
He goes, I'm not a backstabber. I'm
more of a front stabber. I mean, this,
this was like,
it's like what if,
what if fucking somebody you watch good
fellas too much got to be in the office.
Right?
And he never took it debating class that
no one ever told them not to curse into
the microphone. I mean,
is it this one? I mean,
isn't that what the Internet is all about?
Isn't that why the Internet blew
up at the end of the fucking day?
Isn't that why it blew up.
It's not because you wanted to go on there
and research how fucking seagulls fly
from one side of the beach to the other
and all those other fun filled facts you
can find on a website you went on
cause you wanted to see Teddy's,
you wanted to see some pussy and
you wanted some uncensored language.
Isn't that what you wanted?
And look how much better society
is now because of the Internet.
Uh, you know something, if I
was ever on the debating team,
they would need to be another
person there. Okay. First of all,
because I'm not good at debating.
And second of all,
I ended up undoing all of my points
during my argument. You know,
like if you ever debated
me like the worst,
the most apprehensive you'd get is you
bring your eyebrows up like half. Like Oh,
oh, oh, okay. They come back then.
Okay. He just fucked the whole thing up.
He just fucked it all up like
Scaramucci did aren't you get him all,
look who's here. Hey, I know you're
doing your podcast and then leaving.
So where are you guys going?
Wow.
You got oatmeal on your forearm to
clean up and get ready to start the day.
Okay. Kiss Goodbye.
Little princess you. Huh?
You eating oatmeal and bananas?
Just like Yo man now. Huh? You got,
we got mush them up pretty good.
It's just called the podcast sweetheart.
About who?
No,
I'm talking about scare a
Moochie the MOOC. The MOOC.
I want to scare a MOOC audios will
judge. Oh yeah, the daily news.
[inaudible] and then the other one's a
Henry in our writing when Henry Good
milk came up with a Mooc. There it is.
That's what he would have had for the
fucking great.
Okay. All right ladies.
Okay, I'll go to work.
Bye Bye.
Alright.
Um, yeah, you know something.
Parenting has entered a new scary phase.
This is where she's mobile.
She's going mow bile
and I don't give a shit.
Like if there was a cobra on the floor,
she'd grab it by its neck and try
to stick it into her mouth. I mean,
I had her on the floor the other day.
I thought I had everything all cleaned
up and I got one of these casino rugs.
Basically you're the ones with all
the different colors on and be like,
oh my God. Is that from the Orient?
No, it's from fucking leash man.
Right. And uh, it's fucking, you know,
you can't see stuff.
So I remember I was stretching
before I worked out like an old man.
I got stretch, right? And I saw
one of those spongy earplugs on,
on the ground and I was like,
note to self, pick that up.
And I was just, you know,
being a neat freak, cause I've
never had a baby crawling around.
So long story short,
I'm hanging out here with my lovely wife.
My daughter's crawling on the
floor and I see her in a tongue,
looks like it's purple.
And I'm like,
what's says that are tongue with the
fuck's going on with their tongue?
And then she kind of was moving it
around a guy, I guess it's all right.
Cause the earplug was purple by the way.
She wasn't like losing oxygen and then,
yeah, he goes, yeah, no, she's looking
down. She's fine. Oh Jesus Christ.
I can pull that out
and I can't even begin
to tell you like the,
when something like hap that
happens to you, to your kid,
when you drive to work, you get in a
cab and you're gonna sit in the subway.
However the fuck you get to work, you ride
a tricycle with the giant front wheel,
however you get to work, you're not even
paying attention to what you're doing.
All that's going on is a
fucking movie in your head.
That would make Stanley Kubrick fucking,
I don't know what
Stephen came one of those
fucking guys freak out.
Like just the stuff I was thinking about.
Like you know,
the worst case scenario
of all of that and now,
so now there is nothing on the fucking
ground. All right, we got those things.
You stick on the tables on the corners,
you know,
so they don't hit the corner with their
head. Evidently it's okay. The rest of it,
they fucking give themself a
face rub along the fucking Dasha.
What is the dasher mostly you're going
to ask, cause you're not hockey fans.
That's a little ledge that goes around
the boards. The fucking boards do.
So anyways, we're doing the table
read today for episode three Oh three
episode three Oh three.
We're moving along.
We're doing an episode three Oh four next
week. We'll have five of them done by
the end of the month and a half way there.
Halfway there to writing
and then rewriting and then
the rewriting starts. Um,
but it's,
I think,
I feel like everybody knows the characters
this year and we're cruising along.
Knock on wood, knock on wood. So I
think this'll be a nice table read.
But Oh my God. Every once in awhile
a nice fucking lay up comes in.
You needed that guy. You needed scare
a mulch to fucking balance out Trump.
Cause everybody's doing Trump jokes
enough with the fucking Trump jokes.
Jesus fucking Christ. Oh my
God. What's going to happen?
The same fucking thing that happened
when Obama was in office. You're morons.
The exact same fucking thing.
Watch.
Just watch.
Watch how much our foreign policy to watch
out much fucking corporations have to
pay attention to the environment.
Watch how much bankers go to jail.
It's going to be the
exact same fucking thing.
And I'm not talking about minorities,
I'm not talking about illegal aliens.
It's white people. Stop acting like
you fucking life is gonna Change.
Like somebody is going to come
in and take your fucking SUV,
your little fucking bran
muffin or whatever the fuck
else she got at Starbucks.
All of these fucking assholes freaking
the fuck out, which I understand,
but where was this for the
last fucking eight years
and the eight years before that, the APA
and all the way back to Jimmy Carter,
Jimmy Carter was the last fucking real
man that was in the God damn office.
Look at him out there.
He's not out there fucking doing Payton's
waiting for his library to be built is
out there building houses.
I could God damn man,
but it's fucking hammer mouth Malthus.
These other fucking guys just sitting
around waiting for their library.
But you know there's a Roman,
all those presidential libraries that
you go in there for the rest of your life
and there's a group, he
just standing there, right?
And she just blows you the second you
walk in and the whole time she does,
you know
it's fucking true.
All right?
You don't think that's true then you
need to get on the Goddamn Internet. Um,
anyways,
plowing ahead here.
But he had a bolo tie.
Um, anyways, people, I don't, I don't
pay attention to politics. I don't,
I just do all of this shit's so then
people can air quote correct me on the
fucking,
on Twitter with their own misinformation.
It's a little game I like to call.
I don't have a name for it. Um,
anyway.
Scaramucci God dammit,
that guy should have
his own fucking podcast.
I would listen to that every fucking week.
Isn't that what you do now?
I love how everybody,
when they get fucking,
when they totally ruined their career,
their first fucking option is what I do.
Hey, did they start doing stand up?
Remember Charlie Shanie fucking two guys,
a girl and a fucking pizza place. He was
on that whatever the fuck his thing was.
Hey, there's two guys in there as a kid
and there's no chick. What am I gonna go?
I know you know exactly
what you're gonna do,
200 fucking episodes and make
it to syndication. Let me guess.
Do you got two dates in the same
fucking night? Now what are going to do?
But up but up up is the story.
No wonder he ended up doing all
those fucking drug. So would I.
How many fucking times can you just
sit there? Do what? Another episode.
Those poor people on those
fucking sitcoms match.
Once you get up to like
episode 80, 90, and just like,
and you know that you don't care anymore,
you know it's bad enough when you
don't care just the cruise there.
I just can't imagine walking out in
front of that fucking studio audience.
You know, you guys missed
it. I was actually,
I was in Hollywood during the
fucking heyday, that shit.
And uh,
used to always hear these stories about
all of these fucking shows. These,
they would be in like the, uh, they were
in the seventh season and they'd be like,
dude, they are heard. They don't
come in until Thursday. You know,
most of them don't even
show up to the table read.
Then they would blow up for her.
So Tuesday and Wednesday,
they wouldn't even
fucking come in Thursday.
They just do the block and
cause they have it so down,
you know,
I know I go sit on it, Richie,
and then I jump in the air,
cross my legs and sit in Howard
cutting hams chair. I got it.
How many of these fucking
episodes do we gotta do? Right.
They'd show up for the camera blocking,
which is basically,
so you know where you stand.
So you're going to be on camera,
you won't block anybody else.
And then the next day they do the
taping and then that was it. Yeah.
Um, anyways, these motherfuckers,
he's, I bet he does a podcast.
You know, they should start a podcast
network. Just the outcasts. Right.
And it should be like fucking Paula Deen.
Um,
uh, who's that guy who was a
fat fucking really weird guy.
Glenn Beck debt. That guy,
Jesus Christ. You know,
I used to watch him just
to feel emotionally stable.
He was like a character out of wrestling,
like kind of like a fucking,
I dunno like one of those high pitched,
uh,
who's that high pitch
guy who had the megaphone
and was like Bret Harte except he was
built like that guy from gladiator
gladiator. I forget what
that movie was called. Um,
anyways, they should
have them. Bill O'reilly.
Should you just stick them all on the
same network and they just sell them like,
you know, the main stream couldn't
handle it. Couldn't handle our truth.
We went out there were shaded
Lego will wait. It will,
everybody is asked what I do,
you know I in America label can't hate
on me cause I'll tell it like it is.
That's the male version of when a woman
goes like guides are like intimidated by
me. Now you're a cunt and you
sir are a racist more on, okay,
you're not telling it how it is.
Okay.
You're telling it how
you're fucking racist.
Parents told you how it is and then you
never left your town and then somehow
you got on television and then you started
saying the shit that you heard at the
local diner. Right. And then everybody
else with dirty boots are like, ah.
Right.
That's how it was.
So it was people, I don't know what
I'm talking about right now, you know?
I have no idea. Oh Man. Oh Jesus.
I'll tell you, me and my wife all,
we almost got into it. Oh, he almost
got into it this morning, you know,
fucking unreal. I had to work out this
morning to keep my figure in shape. Okay,
I've got to do this fucking podcast.
Then I got to go over the script and
then I have to go do a table read.
I got to do all of that before 10 o'clock
in the morning and I forget whatever
the fucking branch of the armed server
we do more before looking Millenium.
Oh yeah, you've got a
table. What do you do?
You march around and sing dirty limericks
birth
last decade.
Huh?
Woo Hoo.
That's what the fuck you do with.
Then you do some pull ups and all of a
sudden I'm supposed to fucking sit there
and feel like I haven't done anything.
I got to do what those guys are doing.
I've always wanted another adult with
more lines on the side of his sleeves
screaming at me. How can I
sign up for that? You know,
if I was a gun nut, I joined the fucking
military. That's what you want to do,
right? You know, you know what the
deal is. You start off with tin cans,
then you move up to squirrels,
then you shoot a bird, right?
And then eventually you're getting fucking
bored. Cause at the end of the day,
no matter how difficult it is,
no matter how much deer year,
and you've got to put on yourself,
you shooting something dumber than you,
at some point you want to go
after the ultimate brain, okay?
You've watched Jurassic
Park too many times.
You realize there's no real
Velo Razah pants or shirts,
whatever the fuck they goddamn things
where you realize there aren't enough of
those. You like, I'm joining the Goddamn
military. Right? That's what you do.
I wonder how many psychos did that,
you know,
they always say that they're doing
it for your freedom. Right? I joined,
I saw sharp can happen and I was like,
I'm not dead.
And then there are those people, come
on, somebody write me in anonymous,
what branch of the service? Or You
went, Huh? Are you in the coast guard?
You ever get the sense, what are
the people you're working with join?
Just because they wanted to see someone
half eaten by a shark pull 'em out of
the water just to see what it looks
like. You know, I think the coast guard,
that's, that's like the worst
fucking like out of all the jobs,
because the war never ends.
It never ends. You know,
hopefully at some point this shit will
end over in the Middle East, you know?
Um, I don't know how it ends, but
who the fuck knows? But anyways, um,
the coast guard,
it never fucking,
and that right there, I mean,
can you get the metal Avanti,
they should have a civilian saving a
dumb civilian medal of honor for the
fucking coast guard.
Do you realize every time there's like
a bad storm coming and that telling
everybody to stay inside and you get
like, oh, can you get excited? You know,
cause all they sent me
home from work early.
Oh we get to light a fire
in the fireplace, you know,
let's watch raising Arizona,
get the kids together,
all wrap up in a blanket and you
have a great fucking time. Oh Man.
Some smarts. That's why
I love you lady. Right?
You're getting ready. You know what
the fuck that door to the coast guard,
they have fucking palms are sweating.
Their stomach is in and not because they
know some stupid fuck is going to get
in his goddamn boat around his fucking
surfboard or his boogie board or some
dumb shit is going to go on
a fucking hike. All right,
and he's gonna to on.
You got to come get me.
And these people who are completely
safe got to get in there.
Fucking got to get enough fucking
helicopter fly out the middle of a fucking
hurricane to find some fucking dope in
his silly named yet who had to take the
fucking thing out right.
Had to show off in front of his trophy
fucking wipe and now they got to go out
there.
It's some poor bastard.
He's got a fucking jump out of a
helicopter in a hurricane into the fucking
ocean to try to get these fucking
dopes out of there, back to the lead.
So what they can breed and make more
stupid people so the people at the top of
the coast guard can keep making their
fucking blood money. We're taking college.
That right there is the
scariest fucking job.
I am terrified to the fucking ocean.
Okay.
You would not want to have a bunch
of mes in the Coast Guard. Okay.
Those fucking boats would just be sitting
there in the sun and on the day will
be yet that would be it. I would fucking,
I would be, we would be on the dock.
I'd be on the boat with a life jacket on
playing cards and I would get like this
distress car.
Yes.
Good. I'd be like, Hey Bri, Roger that at,
well, what the fuck you doing out there?
I don't want the frontal [inaudible] Kong.
Jesus Christ.
You went to fucking dance.
Although I don't,
that would be me.
I would have that meltdown every dime
and then I would do the job because
basically at the end of the day,
if I was in the coast guard,
that's how I have to fucking make my
living and now I have to go out there and
fish some fucking dope out there.
Is Anybody in the Coast Guard listening
to this? Can you please tell me?
There's no way when you phish
somebody out of the ocean. Okay.
And then you got to fucking go last
and then they send that
fucking hook down again. Right?
It's just sitting there
and 40 foot waves are
going up and down.
Okay.
When they were, when they fucking crank
you back up in that Goddamn helicopter,
there is no fucking way, you
know, talk some shit to that guy.
Is he sitting there with that fucking,
I almost got swallowed by the ocean.
Look on his face.
Whatever the fuck that looks like.
He knows he's fucking dumb. Right?
Do you must look them right
in the heg hey fuck head.
Next time you take your boat out,
why don't you make sure the fucking sun's
out and it's not a fucking whatever.
I'm, well, how are they bring a hurricane.
Fucking got Goddamn five hurricane.
It's unbelievable. You know what I
always think that they fucking look like?
I mean,
you just,
I would be so fucking embarrassed if I
ever did some dumb shit like that and
somebody had to go out, risk their
fucking life. Fly a fucking helicopter.
You're not supposed to fly. And turbulence
with helicopters. As far as I'm Mike,
my little knowledge of it and these
fucking guys got to go fly out until that
shit unfucking believable. Yeah.
They have to make a movie
about the Coast Guard, Huh?
Well I didn't say it.
I'm fucking make a movie about Doug made
a whole TV show about a fucking dolphin
saving people. They call him
flapper foot. He can pray.
You can always breath and then it comes
up and a few supposed to be there.
All right.
You have to make a fucking TV
show about a of a guy saving fish.
You know that f beached themselves and
you throw it back and maybe they did.
Was it free? Willy will actually,
we captured that one. I don't know.
I fight them for the old coast guard
ever fishes me out of the fucking ocean.
You know what the look I'm
going to have on my face.
Do you remember when Oj got arrested the
second time and he knew he was fucked
but he was trying to smile. Remember
that fucking that's still fucking look.
I would have on my face. I just
figured out. I know, I know.
You don't have to say is that the the,
you shouldn't say a fucking word to those
people after you pull them out of the
water. Even the gold
digging whore, you know,
you just talk to why he had enough.
Have you had enough ritual cock at this
point, sweetheart, why don't you go back,
finish up at community college and
build a real fucking life. Okay.
No, we didn't find your other glass
high heel. You fucking stripper.
You know, and then you take it
back to the base. Um, anyways,
sorry. Most of that was
just the stress in my day.
23 fucking minutes. All right,
let's read a little, uh, sweet,
a little bit of advertising here.
Shelly people
the Coast Guard.
What's their fight fights on?
If you're FOC and Dharma to go out
in the ocean Doretta hurricane.
It's our fucking job to go get you
even though we want you to drown.
Um, all right, let me get to the
advertising here. All right. Um, oh shit.
Here we go. Oh, club mother
fucker. All right, looking good.
Looking good.
Doesn't need to cost a fortune five four
club is revolutionizing the way men's
shop at five folk club.
They found a way to make great
looking clothes affordable for every
everyone.
Gary Oldman fat folk club also understands
that your time is extremely valuable.
You have video games to play
and porn to jerk off to.
Why wasted at the mall or
wandering around in the stores.
Why read a book each month?
They send you a curated box of two to
three items that are handpicked to match
the current season and your style.
Folk club partners with partners,
with cutting edge designers and brands.
So you'll get the same quality as
top designers clothes for way less.
They've been helping men
with fashion forever,
forever 15 years and shipped to
over 100,000 men every month.
Chris Paul and Mark Walberg use five
four club and Fido is featured in Gq,
vice in instyle among other publications.
They know what they're doing.
So if you know, that's okay.
Five folk club will help you build
your wardrobe one time a month.
I never fucking rent an, uh, an uh,
piece of advertisement that says
their fucking name more than this.
This is like listening to an
arrogant athlete. You know,
you know,
talking in first playable Barry bonds,
got to go there and do a Bay Mondo
because when you look good, you feel good.
It's a fact of life. You get a $120
worth of clothes for just $60 a month.
You can pause or cancel anytime,
no commitments.
And as a fan club member,
you'll also receive up to 50% off items
in their online shop and access to
exclusive members only items. Ah,
Jeez. You get the jacket there.
Free shipping and size exchanges.
Go to five folk club.com right now and
enter Promo Code burpee. You are our,
and they'll give you 50% off your
first month package plus a free pair of
sunglasses. No. Who wants to look cool?
That's 50% off your first package.
It ballclub spelled F I v e f o u r
o club.com Promo code birth five folk
club.com Promo code paper. Oh
look who's back. Oh, Jay's cried,
but oh dope.
Dope me undies me undies.
I got fat balls, Doo Doo, Doo
Doo. It was a birth defect.
I got too many nuts.
Five bows makes fucking none,
but don't worry,
my balls feel fine because I got that
velvety under wherever up my giant
stretched up fucking nut sack. I
really mean. All right, me undies.
Mondays are the softest, most comfortable
underwear you'll ever wear, period.
And a fucking story.
And summer is the perfect time to upgrade.
Upgrade your underwear drawer because
everyone is thinking about looking good
and feeling good because everyone is
on social media and me undies are the
ultimate feel good undies. Wouldn't you
love to take a selfie with you and nuts?
What? You couldn't do it
before this underwear? Um,
put your scrotum in a good mood.
Every pair of me undies is sustainably
sourced and made from micro modal, modal,
a fabric that is three times softer than
cotton according to the people at me on
these because me undies comes in all
kinds of colors and patterns and they
release new limited edition patterns
each month that will always sell out.
You know what me undies
needs to go up against? Uh,
what said gay underwear brand?
Uh,
a filthy pig or nasty pigman.
At that time.
I told you I was unfortunately going to
Charlie Murphy's funeral and I didn't
pack enough underwear and the only
fucking underwear place in my neighborhood
was right across the street and it
had like the banana hammock shit.
And I walked in there and there was
like cock rings and all this shit.
I ever tell you this story. So
I go, so I'm looking for the,
all the underwear is just like
fucking like atlas and all this.
So I finally got to the guy behind the
counter. I go, eight skews me, but I go,
do you got any? Uh, you got any normal
underwear? And he goes to find normal.
And I was like, I dunno, it doesn't
say nasty pig in the fucking waistband.
Yeah.
Does it say stretch out my ass on
the fucking right across the booty.
Cheeks skinny. Do you just got a pair of
black or Greg or white ones? I'm sorry,
my life isn't as exciting as yours.
Beyond these ought to go up
against those guys. You know,
you're doing all the different
colors in the patterns.
You know people who buy
nasty pig underwear.
Maybe you could get them on.
I don't think nasty pig is made
out of micro modal modal. Uh,
you got to see them for yourself for,
for right now,
you'll get 20% off your first pair and
receive free only at [inaudible] dot com
slash bird there's a reason me undies
has sold over 5 million pairs to date.
You'll feel it when you put them on.
Your Dick will stand at attention.
If you don't love your first
pair of me undies, they're free.
Get 20% off your first pair plus free
shipping@meundies.com slash bird.
That is me, [inaudible] dot com
slash [inaudible] dot com slash burr.
The soundbite [inaudible] was not written
by me undies and none of the things
I've Elbert said.
His meter in any way reflects the feelings
of anybody over here trying to make
you tick. Feel good in a pair
of underwear, pro flowers,
everybody. Pro Flowers. Hey,
it's August.
Why don't you take a bouquet of flowers
and put them in your girlfriend's face?
Huh?
Um,
talk about the last time you spontaneously
surprise someone with something
completely unexpected and how
it felt. Um, Jesus Christ.
I hope you don't send
this to fucking hope.
There's no serial killers with podcast.
Talk about the last time you spontaneously
surprise someone with something
completely unexpected and how it felt.
Picture in Hannibal Lecter. You remember
it was heart rate would even go up.
He's listening to the classical music.
I Dunno. Um, I would surprise my wife,
but she snoops too much.
She always figures out what the fuck
I'm doing and then I just be all right.
Fucking here it is.
All right.
Talk about what the Rose Bouquet bouquet
bouquet recently sent to you by profile
is look like and your overall impression
of it. Uh, well, I didn't receive it,
but I,
I have seen bouquets of roses before and
I know what they look like when they're
in the vase and uh, you know, it was,
yeah, those are flowers. Uh,
and they really smell like.
All right. Pro Flowers wants to help you
surprise someone for no reason at all.
Well. In other words, you want
to make more money selling
flowers. In other words,
there's no real fucking
holiday this month,
all while also surprising you with
a special deal. For my listeners,
get 20% off any other of their unique
summer Rose Rose bouquets or any other
boot K of 29 why are they
trying to fucking do this?
Just saying what the fuck you mean here?
This is the deal. There is no Easter.
There's no mother's Day.
There is no fucking Valentine's
Day unless it's her birthday.
There's no fucking reason to
get her flowers other than this.
Shut the fuck up for a couple of hours.
Okay? If you, if your girlfriend's
birthday is in this month, okay.
God knows Jesus didn't do anything in
August cause just like f one he took the
month off. Okay, so there's no Jesus
holiday. I don't know what Muhammad did.
I don't even want to get into Buddha.
But as far as me as a white male,
Hawaiian male Christian, there's
no holiday this month. Okay,
so you're probably sitting there going,
why the fuck would I get a flowers?
You know why? Because it means
something. It means more. Yes.
Opposed to do it on mother's Day. You're
supposed to do it on their birthday.
You're supposed to tip them upside down
on Christmas and use their fucking clam
is a vase on Christmas.
We all know this. Okay,
but you're not supposed to do it in
August and that's why you do it. Okay?
This is like when Michael Jordan used to
come to practice and rather than acting
like he was the best guy in the league,
he would practice like
he was going to get cut.
That's what you want to do with pro
flowers, so fuck their copy. All right?
You can get 20% off the summertime roses.
Go get some for your mother and August.
Just get him for and be like,
Yo, why didn't you do this?
Because you're the best mother
I ever could have asked for. Oh,
that's what you're going to
get right there. All Right,
and you get 20% off some or roses
or any on at bootcamp. Okay?
For fucking $29 or more,
go to pro flowers.com use my code.
Berbee you are are a checkout.
That's proflowers.com code bar.
Don't wake to make someone's
Day. That's it. 32 minutes.
32 like Oj Simpson. He's going
to be running. Wow. Come October.
What you're going to do when
Oj McCombs running wild on you?
I've had a pretty nonconfrontational life.
Yes you did.
Oj except for that night get killed. Two
people. Other than that, that was it.
Give us he that fucking documentary about
how he got fucking arrested the second
time when he went down there
to go get his shit, you know,
and then he had his buddy take out
his gun and then they didn't have his
memorabilia that he thought.
So then these other fucking assholes
started grabbing autograph Pete Rose
baseballs and then they took the guy's
cell phone and then it became an armed
robbery. I mean, I would have to also
think, depending on how that got,
got the memorabilia, I don't really
remember. All I know is that Jack Dude,
I can tell you this man.
Okay.
If I was a black guy who got away with
killing two white people and I would not
leave the fucking house for the rest
in me. That's where the fucking guy,
I don't know what he's thinking.
You know your run for 2000 yards and a
14 game season and then all of a sudden
you think you're invincible.
That fucking look on his face when he
gets arrested the second time where he
knows he's fucked and
yet he's trying to smile.
I was talking about that
yesterday in the writer's room.
It's the one of the funniest fucking
things I've ever seen. It's like that.
And there's one of ric flair
with somebody's interviewing
him and asking him,
what was it like the last time you
went to Japan and you see his love for
wrestling and he knew it was his last
day. He said, look at this picture,
what was going on? And
he was like, this was,
I knew this was my last time I was going
to Japan and he starts to fucking cry
and he doesn't want to cry,
you know,
cause he's the nature boy
and he's trying not to cry.
So he smiling while he's trying.
I can try not to cry.
I've never seen an actor do that in a
scene because if an actor starts to cry,
they can't help it. They're
like, oh good. I'm crying.
This is what the director wants.
Crying equals good acting.
I'm going to get an award.
All right.
Dan gets one with one tier. I got to
tears coming down that aren't, I mean,
I get a Golden Globe and a fucking Oscar,
right? All right, that's the podcast.
Please listen to this wonderful
music. Um, oh, by the way,
you know what do I finally
fucking got into? And I,
I used to trash him all the time.
Joe Rosa was right above Frank Zappa.
I could never get into it.
Granted, I was listening to fucking
hair metal. It was two and now, oh wait,
people always said Joe's garage.
Every time I read a fucking drummer
magazine for fucking 15 years,
every drummer was trying to get Vinnie
call you is high head sound in Yoga Joe's
garage. It's what they always said. You
know, I wanted to get that video call,
Uta high hats and Joe's garage.
And I always got to put on and I was like,
what the fuck is this?
I don't even know what's going on.
Is is frank mocking music is easy
trying to take what though? I just,
it was so far beyond anything.
I was listening to it.
It didn't sound good if you
can believe that. And um,
I finally just put it on in the car
and I also fucking had another 15 of
listening to music and actually trying
to expand my horizons from top 40 Horse
Shit that I had been listening to. And
uh, it's fucking unbelievable album.
It's fucking unbelievable.
So, uh, Joe de Rosa,
I trashed him so many goddamn times
about Frank Zappa so many times.
And I was like, Joe, you're
contrarian. You just like
it. Cause it's different djs.
I swear to God, if everybody like Frank
Zappa, you wouldn't fucking like him.
And he goes, that isn't true, Bill. I,
I, I hate you when you're freckled face.
And we would go back and forth,
back and forth as we drank the fucking
the brown devil then that's what we would
do. Okay. And Joe Rosa,
I'll tell you right now,
and I'm going to tell
them this on his birthday,
he was never more right about
Frank Zappa and he was never,
he was right about the
brown album with Primus.
And he was right about the fucking golden
girls. Okay. I saw the golden girls.
I saw four old ladies,
Joe de Rosa saw comedy gold.
I didn't see it the other night.
I was sitting and they went on,
if they were having a marathon,
I was trying to get my daughter to go to
sleep and I'm watching this shit that's
like 30 years old and I'm laughing my
ass off. I fucking love that show now.
You know. So my apologies to the Great
Joe de Rosa and happy birthday to him.
And Oh,
by the way,
if you guys would like to do meet the
biggest fucking favor you could ever do,
there's a few fucking tickets left
for Paul Versey stand up special.
His first one, his first
hour, then me, Pete Davidson,
Al Madrigal and all things comedy. We'll
be producing our first standup special.
We would love to sell this place
out. Okay. With so fucking close,
we could lie to Paul and say,
this is sold out.
We just want to sell these last
few tickets. If he could do it,
if he can make it down.
Okay.
It's at the Tarrytown theater in
beautiful Tarrytown, New York.
I mean this is like one of those again
at the beginning of a Tom Hanks movie
when he has the perfect life before he
decides to fucking go out there and get
stuck on a Goddamn island
talking to a volleyball, right.
This is where they would start member,
his neighborhood and like big,
when he was riding the fucking ball
with a little kid was riding the bike.
That's what this place looks like.
You could bring your lady up,
you can have a nice fucking dinner.
Me and Pete Davidson are going to go on
stage and fuck around at the same time
trying out new bits,
getting you guys warmed up,
and then Paul Verges can absolutely
fucking crush it. All right.
In all things come.
But he is producing it and
it's going to be great.
So please come down if you can.
I'll be hanging out in between shows.
You want to get a picture?
I'll sign shit.
Whatever the fuck I gotta do to get you
into the goddamn building. Um, that's it.
I'll be tweeting out a link. Let's
make it happen. Okay. That's it.
Enjoy the music and we'll be playing some,
a greatest hits of a Thursday afternoon,
just before Monday morning,
Friday in whatever the
hell they call this thing.
Over Thursday gone by and another
year possibly go fuck yourselves.
Have a great weekend concept.
[inaudible] [inaudible]
hey,
what's going on?
It's built bar and it is the
Monday morning podcast from Monday,
August the third,
why the fuck does it say November? You
know what? I thought I finally had it.
I was going to be like at 77 degrees
out chance at the high of 83 and now I'm
looking at says fucking November.
Why is that?
I Dunno. Why the fuck it does it? That
does to meet every God damn week. Oh,
it gives a shit, whatever.
It's August 3rd all right.
Another year flying by Jesus Christ.
Where is the summer going?
Huh? How many people have said that
to you already? Everybody always says,
is that where's the
thumber go egg every year?
It just seems to go by even faster.
I'd say it's amazing.
Like the first 20 years of my life,
it just seemed like it took forever.
But I'll tell you once she had 30 those
years, they just, they just, they fly by.
Oh, and if you have a kid, forget
about it. Just forget. I mean, I don't,
I don't even remember 35
to 46 nobody cares, lady.
Nobody cares. You're saying
the same shit. We got it.
Life goes by fast.
Okay.
Where is the time going?
I don't know.
I'm wasting a lot right now listening
to you going on your big long fucking
seemingly philosophical little rant about
where the fucking time is going. Well,
you're not really being,
you're not presenting any
one of philosophical shit.
Now you liked that people,
this is going to be a hybrid of
podcasts where I hit you with terms like
philosophical shit.
All right?
So don't be coming at me acting like I'm,
I'm getting all upper crust here.
That's your own insecurity
because you get nervous when I,
when I use terms like that.
All right? That's not my fault.
You went to a community college,
you know,
and you didn't have great teachers to
teach you about philosophical shit.
All right, whatever. This is
the Monday morning podcast.
I do one of these every single week
and um, I really enjoy doing them.
Um,
I don't know why cause you know why?
Cause I walk around my apartment and I
talked to myself anyways and when I have,
um, when I have headphones on and I
haven't talking into a microphone,
I don't feel as crazy.
Why am I dog is already asleep.
She's in heat right now.
Jesus Christ walking around
with a fucking swollen pussy.
That's what I got. Huh?
How was that? Yeah,
I hope you were eating when I
just said that. That's disgusting.
That's what the most disgusting
things I've ever said it. Anyways, I,
this is really going off
the rails quick this week.
People brand new conductor
here. Um, all right, let's,
let's get down to some shit here that
I want to talk about. First of all,
I have some homework for all of you guys.
Everyone who's listening
to this podcast and, um,
I gotta admit my podcast.
I think it's finally taking off because
in the last couple of weeks I've learned
that I don't have enough bandwidth
on iTunes for the amount of people
downloading it.
So I appreciate all the new listeners.
I got a computer nerd friend around
the corner who hopefully will solve the
problem tomorrow.
You know,
teach me how to get some
more bandwidth or whatever,
so more people can listen to it. I
get a ton of questions. So anyway,
so I feel like I'm starting to
build a force here. All right.
So maybe I can use this force for,
for like my own wishes.
You know that Jesus Christ said
didn't even for my own wishes, for,
for my own desires.
There we go.
So this is a required homework
for all of you this week.
All of you have to go out and you got,
you have to go see the movie, the orphan.
All right,
it is required because I want to
talk about that movie for a good 10,
15 minutes. I want to
talk about that movie. Um,
but I don't want to ruin it for people.
All right,
you have to go see that movie.
That movie is a throwback to classic,
I would say mid maybe late
eighties horror films where um,
they just kind of went off the rails
and they stopped building suspense.
So the whole thing just became funny
cause it was inadvertently a fucking
hilarious movie.
And uh,
I dunno a shit.
I want to talk about this.
I'm giving you guys one
fucking week next week.
I'm talking about that movie
because it was so, uh, it
was so ridiculous. You know,
this is,
I know it's a good horror movie is if I
go and see it and then when I get home
and I'm turning the lights out, you know,
I'm creeped out in my own apartment.
You know, as I walked by a hallway
and there's no light on, you know,
like to this day,
to this day when I'm on the road
and I go back to my hotel room,
every once in awhile I'll put the fucking
lights out and I'll expect like the TV
to come on and see the girl crawling out
of the well or to hear the phone ring
and I pick it up and it's going
to go seven days, you know,
cause that movie,
I don't know what it was about the ring,
that one stayed with me,
the Blair witch,
which is really a polarizing movie where
a lot of people look to those fucking
stupid, oh fuckers scared
all I, oh just fucking left.
And you know those people,
those people who go to scary movies and
they get to talk about how it didn't
scare them and how they laugh the whole
time as if that means if they were
actually confronted by
a psycho on the street,
they would have a better
chance of, uh, you know,
of surviving because they laughed
in a movie theater. I mean,
anybody can sit in a fucking movie and
just take themselves out of the movie and
just fell is just an actor. Oh, it's
fake blood. You can do that. You know,
I don't know.
Maybe this is me just getting fucking
defensive because the Blair witch scared
the shit out of me. You know, I
fucking bought that movie hook,
line and sinker in the end when that dude
was standing there facing the fucking
corner, it was just creepy. I
like when I can't see the monster.
That's my thing. Is that your thing, bill?
I don't remember asking you what your
thing is. Well then don't fucking listen.
Sorry. I'm going a, I'm kind of in
a mood right now. There's a lot.
I had a lot of devastating shit happened
to me this week. And not only that,
I was driving,
uh,
down the street out here and I
saw some lady had a, a sane on,
on the back of her, her Isuzu
trooper, everybody 1988,
Isuzu Trooper Zuzu however the
fuck you said. And it says, uh,
I might be slow, but I'm in front of
you, you know? And that's kind of person.
If someone dragged him out of the car
and started beating them repeatedly about
the head and neck,
as much as I would feel bad for the
person who's driving the zoo trooper,
he kind of be kind of asking for it,
you know,
why are you baiting people
to beat the [inaudible]?
That's what you're doing right there.
That's like Nan Nan ass shit. And uh,
you know, it's like, uh, I don't know.
There would be like me a,
I don't know,
in the 60s when the race
riots were going on, you know,
and having some fucking racial shit.
Oh my,
is it really bill? Is it really to
that level? Now? You're right, it is.
And I don't even go down that fucking
road. What a moron. Um, but anyway,
speaking of the 1988 Zuzu trooper,
and that's kind of been a new
thing that I have on my, uh,
my myspace page is I'm taking pictures
of random vehicles out here in Los
Angeles. Um, because I, I just,
you can't believe how long is,
if you're from the east coast,
you can not believe how
long cars last out here.
Some of the cars that like,
oh,
do you ever hang out with your friends?
You know, some high school buddies,
you know,
you haven't seen in awhile.
And then they bring up some kid who
moved in the second grade, you know,
hey, remember John Sarno,
remember that? And you were like,
holy fuck,
I have not thought about that kid since
1982 that is what it's like walking,
driving around out here.
I don't know if I told you this a couple
months back I saw a Pontiac t 1000 in
good condition out here.
Chocolate,
Brown Pontiac t 1000 and for those
of you who aren't in the cottage,
probably thing, oh t 1000
probably had some bulls. You know,
you could probably do a
burnout or whatever fucking
stupid thing those gearheads
do. Um, that I'm jealous of because
I don't know how to fix a car myself.
Um,
Pontiac team 1000 was actually
the Pontiac's answer to the show.
A Chevy Chevette,
which was a hatchback Chevy
Chevette and was also a very,
um, on its way to becoming
a hugely hacky joke.
When I first started in stand up,
one of the classic hacky jokes
when I first started was,
uh, people get on stage and be like,
Hey, I'm doing pretty good. You know,
you see my car outside? Yeah, I got,
the vet has Chevette and it'd be like,
Oh shit. I thought he was
done good about it. Go of it.
And then the guy, there's,
everybody's laughing.
The guy would be adjusting his sport
coat sleeves to make sure that they were
three quarters of the way
down his forearms to let you
know that he wasn't in an
office.
You know,
that's why he had the pastel colored tee
shirt underneath his sport coat to let
you know that he was, he was off
the grid. He was out of the Matrix.
He found a way to find
your daily grind uniform,
a fucking edgy.
That might be one of the worst
periods of fucking dress ever.
The late eighties stand up comedian.
Remember that with this skinny ties or
the fuck he's just, it's just in the,
in the, the, the was basically
the feathered mullet.
It was like Farrah Fawcett met at,
I don't know,
Billy Ray Cyrus. I got, I
got fucking nothing on that
one. But speaking of which,
let, let's, let's plow ahead.
So anyways, I, I have, uh,
I've been taking some pictures of
some pretty random fucking vehicles,
one of which I don't even know what
it was. It looks like a big RV.
I thought it was a Volkswagen.
It's missing the bumpers.
It literally looks like it's made out
of Styrofoam Styrofoam and I'm convinced
someone's living in it. Um, but anyways,
check those out on my myspace page
if you're bored. But hey bill,
why don't you get back to the podcast?
Fine.
I will and I will you probably wondering,
you know,
a couple minutes ago I said I
kind of had a devastating week.
Um, how do I get into this?
All right. Once again,
going back about a month
ago when the subject of,
uh, steroids in baseball came
up, I did not name a name,
but I said if one particular person
were to some for some reason get busted,
I guess it wasn't a, it was
h, g, h or whatever with
Hdh, whatever the fuck it is.
If they were to get busted that I was
going to be done with baseball and uh,
the person got busted and
a, that's it. I'm out.
I'm out. I'm out. Fuck baseball.
I don't know if I'm going to
be out forever, but fuck it.
I did catch myself for half
a second watching a Dodgers.
I think they're playing the cardinals.
I can't watch it. I literally,
I watched for like three seconds and then
Manny Ramirez came up and I was like,
Oh, here we go again. I'm done.
I'm fucking done with, you know,
what bugs me the most about all of
this shit. And um, you know, I got,
I got emails from a couple of Yankee
fans going on. Go now what now?
What you say vogue in [inaudible].
You know what a yeah, you're right.
You're absolutely right.
But I'll tell you,
us against you is even
roids verse Roids in Europe.
We are actually still a
couple ahead of us, but no,
it's roids verse Roids.
All right,
if you want to argue
the 2004 championship,
because I can't really think of
a cardinal that got caught. Uh,
I would have that argument
with somebody from St Louis.
But as far as Yankee fans go, I mean,
come on dude. All right. We, we, we,
you know, you guys did everything but
send a fucking center up to the plate.
You know what? That's what the Yankees
and red sox should be right now.
They should just have half men,
half horses and they just
come up to the plate.
You know,
you gotta put on a Jersey cause you
can't look at that little fuck in a,
you can't look at that. You know, you
know what it is when they come up to bat,
they're going,
they're going to need a
shirt cause they're going to
need a little pocket to put
that little fucking pan
flute in when they come up.
I think that that's what they should do.
So I gotta be honest with you,
I don't know what is going on in baseball,
but uh,
I'm not even mad at the players anymore.
What's really pissing me off at this point
is how the owners made all that money
and they're not being held
accountable on any level.
I really think like the last 10 years of
baseball was just a big marketing like
scheme to get everybody. Like how insane
is this country into baseball now?
I don't know if you guys remember,
but back in the early mid nineties,
it was really going downhill even
before the strike and all that.
Basically all you had was cal Ripken
was going to break Lou Gehrig's record
record record record. And, um,
he was like this throwback guy and he
was doing something that was really
respectable. Uh, you know, it was a record
that, okay, how much, I can't even talk.
What the fuck is wrong with me?
It's like Lou Gehrig went back to an
era that was considered, you know,
a golden age during America as far
as hard work and World War II when
segregation and water fountains and
all that other fucked up shit that they
don't really tell you ever noticed that
when they go back in time, you know,
when they talk about the golden years,
they, they or they talk about racism.
They never tell those two stories
at the same time. You know, America,
we made all this, you know,
made steel, steel workers.
I don't know all this type of shit and
the American card, all the type of stuff.
But they always, and then if they're
going to tell the racism story,
they just tell that one separately,
you know? All right, you could,
you could beat your wife.
The rule of thumb, you know,
what was the rule of
thumb? You can, you could,
you could beat your wife with a stick
no bigger than your thumb. You know,
you can't tell me girls weren't looking
at guys thumbs on first dates back then.
Those little five foot,
six inch do with little fucking little
sausage fingers so that Jesus could I
take the beat down from this guy
and I don't think I could, you know,
but then again, the women back then
it was like big milkmaids, you know,
they're all doughy.
Never see like the paintings from way
back in the day of like sexy women,
you know, they were raw.
They were definitely healthy.
So healthy fucking women. All right, I'm
getting off the track here. All right,
so let's get back to baseball.
So you fucking,
so basically what they did was I think
basketball and football were overtaking
him. I mean that's what I was watching.
Bird magic, Jordan, Isaiah, Thomas,
all those great teams, Dominique
Wilkins, all that stuff was going on.
Then in football,
I mean I went from the late seventies
Roger Starbuck beaten the Denver Broncos.
That was the first Superbowl I watched.
And I went right through, you know,
the last two Terry Bradshaw's Steeler
championships into Joe Montana,
Dan Marino, John Elway, right on through,
right on through, right up til like, uh,
I would say the end was maybe a
cowboy's dynasty
that year with the fuck happened
when the 40 niners played the,
the charger's in the
Superbowl. That's, that's when,
that's when the golden age you ended,
that was a bad one. Um, anyways,
but whatever. So no one was fucking
watching baseball. So then they just want,
they want, they, they juiced up the
ball, they made the ballparks smaller,
and then they just look the other way as
these fucking roided out dudes came up
and hit like 80 home runs as a third
baseman and they all made a shitload of
money and now they're leaving the
players to hold the fucking bag. Uh,
I don't know. I think it's
bullshit. So because of that,
I actually,
I'm beginning to try to find a
different sport that I can watch in the
summertime. And, uh,
I went to the x games in Carson,
California on Saturday and I watched
a little motorcross man. It was,
that was definitely, it was cool. But I,
I've never felt so old in my
life going down to that thing.
And I also did not fit in.
If you've never been to the x games
of motorcross Sorta Skateboard,
all that type of shit
to describe the crowd.
It's Sorta if Travis Barker and dog,
the bounty hunter had children,
that's what the crowd would fucking live.
Somehow they had 30,000 children. That's
what the fucking crowd would look like.
It was very, uh, everybody there, it
looked like they had at least one felony,
you know, and I'm dirty, filthy,
filthy Skanky fucking women
just, you know, I, you know,
[inaudible] is getting a tattoo.
Is that out yet? Is that it?
Has that gone the way of the bell bottom?
There is nothing more skanky or than
just fucking just tattoos on a woman.
It's just, you know, I don't know.
I remember there was a period where they
were kind of cute or whatever and then,
I dunno, it jumped the shark when
whoever coined the term the tramp stamp.
And if you live under a fucking log,
that's basically the tattoo on the small
of a woman's back that just really just
says that, you know, I fucked
a lot of guys in my sorority.
That's another major red flag when you
see a girl who has like a sorority tattoo
down around her ankle
that yeah. Um, I dunno,
I'm not saying don't marry her.
I'm just saying don't go to any of her
high school or college reunions because
there's going to be a lot of guys going
up shaking your hand with that look on
their face.
Like does this guy know that me and my
buddy fucking double teamed his fucking
wife, the mother of his children and
I know a lot of females right now.
What you're saying right now,
that's a double Saturday.
That's it. That was Santa.
How can we as a, how I'm a guy
can go out and blah blah blah.
And if a woman does it, she's
a whore. I'll tell you why.
This is actually a bit for my act
and I'm going to burn in my podcast.
I'll tell you why. Because for a
woman to get laid is absolutely,
there's no fucking skill involved.
All right?
You're getting laid is like me trying
to get fat kid eat ice cream. You know,
it's really, there's not a
lot of, you know, I guess
see what is is a guy is men have
to make women want to fuck us.
We have to come up, we have to
dazzle. We gotta put on a show.
We got to come up with some
sort of fucking angle to
get someone of the opposite
sex to touch us. You guys can you
just fucking lay down in a pool table.
You could bang everybody fucking bar.
There's no skill.
It's gluttonous. That's
what it is. It's gluttonous.
It's like watching a fat guy eat
ice cream in public and listen to
[inaudible] scary guy does
you? Nobody gives a shit.
But when I do, do I go, what?
The food? Fuck, because
you're a fat fuck.
That's why.
So getting back to the woman thing.
No respect,
no respect for your numbers
because you have a vagina.
All right, there we go. Jesus Christ Bell.
You went a long way on that one.
All right,
we're 20 minutes in and I don't think
I've ever felt more ignorant. Um,
all right, continuing on. Here's
something, um, that I wanted to, uh,
you know, I just realize the record
levels of kind of high here open,
not my screaming into this thing.
Um, anyways, one ever gives a fuck.
Uh, this is what you get. This is what you
get. What do they want to say this week?
Oh, I know. This is something I
would like, if anybody out there,
does anybody out there have a VHS
copy of the Superbowl with the rams?
Beat the titans?
I've never seen that.
Superbowl and it bugs me.
It's the only super
bowl since 1978 Broncos,
cowboys. It's the only one that I
missed. And when I say I missed it,
I missed the whole fucking thing.
Um,
and why was that?
I was dating some girl
and she wasn't into it.
Are you seeing my dog here?
Just go.
Sometimes I feel like I'm telling a story
and she's actually board. Um, anyways,
she wasn't into it and uh,
yeah,
so I ended up fucking hanging out with
her instead. Wow. Was that embarrassing?
And it ended up being,
course ended up being one of the
greatest Superbowls fucking ever.
I've never seen it. So if anybody has a
copy of it, please can you make me a copy?
Send me an email and uh, send
it my way. I'll trade you.
I'll trade you a fucking
DVD for a VHS copy of that.
Um, all right. There we go. That was
really fucking long way to go. All right,
let's try to get this thing back on
track. She can tell you, you can't,
you guys always tell when I'm searching
on my computer and my sentences become
more choppy. All right. Hey, Bill. Uh,
you talked about inadvertent racism on
your July 27th podcasts and I see what
you're saying.
Uh,
simply recognizing that certain dialects
can be found in whites, blacks, Asians,
et Cetera,
isn't really racist.
But the woman who emailed you about
shiny suits on Conan called you working
class or blue collar or some shit,
presumably based on your Boston accent
and you seem to take offense to it.
Just thought you'd want to know,
uh,
you're talking out of two sides
of your mouse here, miles here.
And I emailed her back and told her that
basically my entire act and the podcast
are based on talking out
of both sides of my mouth.
So I found that email hilarious.
But my point,
and I'm not going to stop blaming people
for not getting my point because I
understand how my complete inability
to present my points. Clearly.
My point is that,
you know,
each race does have an accent.
So if you were to say that sounds
sounded like an Asian dude. Oh,
that sounded like a black dude.
It's not racist.
You know,
it isn't,
I still can't fucking explain
this without sounding like a dick.
I look if,
if some,
if you were talking to some guy on
the phone and he's like, oh, hello, I,
I'd be over there very
nearly. Sure. And again,
he comes over and it was a black guy
when she be in the back of your head like
Jesus Christ, this guy, he sounded
like like a fucking Asian dude.
Now I'm not saying that all
Asian guy sound like that,
but if somebody sounds like that,
they are going to sound like they're Asian
and I'm also not a master of dialects,
so I am going to be doing an
exaggerated version of your people.
That's it. The same way def jam
comics go on TV and imitate.
White Guy's going, oh yeah, I got go
do my taxes. Holy Heck Gee. Willikers,
Jimmy gimme cricket. I mean, nobody
knows anyone who talks like that,
but you know what they're saying? Plus
it's comedy. It's a fucking joke, right?
That's all I'm saying. Okay, so
way back in the day, the Oj trial,
when a neighbor heard a voice and it
said it sounded like a black guy and they
tried to sit there and make that
unbelievable, the most racist thing ever.
It wasn't, you know, believe it or not.
Like let's look at gay guys.
One of the most fascinating accents ever.
Here's another bit I used to do in my act.
How gay guys come from all over
the country, all over the world.
Let's just stick with this country.
They come from all 50 states,
yet there is a gay accent.
Hi, how are you doing? Yes, Jesus, right?
Hacky, absolutely. But a 100% not true.
You can't say that.
And that fascinates me because I think
if you're a gay guy from down south,
you should be like, hey buddy, I knew
and I want to suck your fucking Dick.
What do you think about that? You
really got a nice buck there, buddy.
You know what I mean? Ah. Gives a fuck.
I'm so sick of trying to explain my
uninformed fucking views, whatever.
It's a podcast. Don't take it seriously.
Some people take it seriously. Yeah.
Who gives a shit? You know, just here
to know who they take it seriously.
Then it gives me something to read. So
please, for the love of God, keep, uh,
keep taking this shit
seriously. Um, all right,
here's another one for you.
We're going to be dealing a lot with
racist week evidently. Here's a very, uh,
he's a very, some of these emails,
they're getting a little serious here.
Here's one for you. Hey
Bill. Um, and um, I'm uh,
18 age old black man, you know, do
you guys proof read these things?
And I've always wanted to
interracially date since middle school.
I'm sorry.
Just had some fucking weed checks so
that literally sound like
I was getting choked up.
I've always wanted the interracially
dates middle school. Um,
but there is one short five 11 guy that
is always there to a mess up something
good. My Dad, my dad is what
you would call a buzzkill.
I'm a photographer from my
school and there was a girl, uh,
that I've been friends
with for awhile and uh,
almost every halftime at
the football games we would
talk one time she said, hey,
can I take a picture with you?
I was not going to say no because
the more you please women,
you went a little closer
to her pleasing you.
Oh God. Is that hilarious?
That's how a young man, thanks.
That's a whole nother subject.
You know what,
you actually want to be going in the
opposite direction a lot of the times.
But if she's a nice girl, yes. Be
Nice to wear anyways. Um, so anyways,
years she gets close to pleasing you.
But uh, as she climbed out of the stands,
I was running through my,
it was running through my head what my
old man would say because he makes me
show him the photos to see my
progress I guess is a photographer.
Um,
we had someone snapped the photo of us
and when I got home and put the photos up
from my old man, I tried
to skip it, but he sought,
I had to sit there for an hour in 45
minutes and listen to how white people did
US wrong for 400 years. And if
you, if you start liking them,
it's because you want to be them.
Bill A,
that's just the light version.
A couple of weeks ago we were at our
family reunion and we were watching tiger
woods. I said, the tiger
woods had a hot wife.
I really wish you recorded all of this.
And my dad butted in and said, is she hot?
Is She hot? Because she's white. Bill,
I tried to tell this shithead that I
love all women no matter what race. Um,
what am I know what the race is?
My old man flew off the handle.
I had to sit for three hours and listen
to him rant about the same shit I've
heard since I was 13. Stuff like,
you just hate black women, don't you?
He just want mud kids,
don't you? Jesus Christ.
If you do marry them,
you'll just be a dog to them.
And I always know and I always knew that
that yellow skinny yours would go to
your head.
Uh,
I guess that's lightskin it's
like a whole nother fucking thing.
High Yella doesn't that
mean light-skinned?
Anybody out there of a African persuasion
that can explain that to white people,
red boned and all that
shit. Um, anyways, uh,
so whatever more lightskin so thinks
he's a cut above. Can't hang out.
So what does your dad,
does your dad look like? Keith Robinson.
All right, that's for standup fence.
Anyways. Um, where'd we go?
What am I going with this?
I just lost my fucking plates.
Mud kids,
yellow skin. Jesus. When the fucking
ugliest emails ever. Um, Bill,
this is a bill. This is just
I short on me. I don't know what
you're writing here. I'm six.
One loved Jennifer Love Hewitt,
Vanessa and Hughes Rianna.
Ah, Jesus Christ. What the fuck?
And I always,
and I always that that
Chris Brown would backfire.
I always knew that that Chris Brown would
backfire and that Asian girls from the
beat and that Asian girl from the
beginning of true lies a girl is a girl.
And when you're, and when you are hungry
like a wolf, this kid's hilarious.
You do not want to settle for just one
kind of food. This guy basically. Yeah,
he's 18.
He wants to fuck on every continent.
He wants to bang a girl from every
racist is total normal behavior. Bill,
I've hated my family.
This has really become a
doctor. Phil here. Bill,
I have hated my family for fucking up my
life from birth with their divorce and
my mom died when I was 14. She us
iron man. I forgot about that part.
I would have been laughing here, but I
hated her like m and m hated his mom.
I'm living with my dad now for now because
I'm about to head to college and that
same girl is going to the same
college and she wants to hook up.
Bill helped me find an easy
way to tell my dad to fuck off.
Wow. Do, I don't know if you've
been listening to my podcast,
but do you really think I'm qualified
on any level to address the shit that's
going on here?
Do this is like,
this is like the perfect storm of stuff.
All right. All right. The first of all,
the mistake your dad's making
is by ranting and raving
at you for an hour and 45
minutes about what he doesn't want you
to do is the quickest way to make you run
out and go do it. All
right? And from what I,
I've my experience as a kid, obviously
I don't have any kids and uh, yeah,
he should be able to date whoever
you want a date. I will say this,
you're 18 don't get a girlfriend.
All right.
Stay single. Get out there,
figure out what you want.
And as you're going around fucking the,
uh,
entire rainbow of color out there,
be making a mental list of what
you're looking for in somebody to,
uh, to settle down with.
This is the shit that I,
this is all the shit that I didn't do
is I rudderlessly just bounced
from one fucking chick to another.
Um, nice way to tell you I an easy
way to tell your dad to fuck off.
Uh, you know what, why don't
you try agreeing with them,
you know, when he goes,
yeah, I knew that yellow skin
would go to your head. Be like,
you're absolutely right. Data. I can't
even believe that I'm talking to you.
In fact,
when we walk in public or is there any
way that you could kind of walk like 40
feet behind me so people don't know that
we're together? You can, I don't mean,
I don't know if your dad gets physical
and you starts fucking slapping you
around like some lifetime movie. But,
uh, I've used this technique on, uh,
a number of people after wow.
When you just get sick,
you ever get somebody they just get,
they just get, I don't know. They,
they get,
they get pissed cause they know you're
going to go out and possibly enjoy life
more than they have. You know,
like I had a couple people,
uh, you know, when I moved down in New
York I had friends given me shit like a,
you know, hey I got a new apartment.
Hey but it's not New York City.
And then I'd always find myself having
to knock living in New York City,
like tone down my shit so they could feel
better about where the hell they lived
in. After a while I was just like, yeah,
I just started agreeing with them. Yeah,
you're right. It isn't New York. New
York is shit. It's the Paris of America.
You know. It's too bad you
don't live there cause it's
fucking awesome. You just,
you just agree with the,
Oh you think you're the shit now.
Could you live down there?
Yeah, I know. It's unbelievable.
My Ego is completely out of
control and you know, just,
I don't know. I don't know what
to tell you, dude, that that's,
that's a really tough one
because no matter what,
you're always going to want
your dad's approval. Um,
but just watch out for the anger that's
building up in you and just make sure
that you don't start making spiteful
decisions towards Sam about your own life
and the path you want to go
down because, uh, then you get,
you're going to end up in some
miserable plate. Yeah, you'll start,
you'll literally start dating
someone just to piss him off.
I'm not saying you might, you'll do.
Maybe you will. I don't know. Um,
okay.
Uh, I dunno. Do that. There's, there's a
lot of shit going on there, but you know,
I'm glad you brought all of this stuff
up because you remember that bit I was
doing that.
Get out of the pool,
making fun of those movies where
they show like racist white people.
And this right here is
the point of that bit,
which is they've made 80 million
movies about white people being racist.
And I was laughing that,
that started off with slavery.
One of the most horrific things that's
ever happened in this country other than
then I guess the straight
up genocide or the Indians.
Native Americans are the fuck you supposed
to call them and there's been so many
movies made about that shit that now
it's all the way down to like swimming.
That was the joke and I know I like,
I stopped doing the jokes once they were
on TV, but I know I said at some point,
are white people the only
ones who think evil shit,
I can't remember the joke wins.
Isn't there some a Mexican guy making
fun of an Asian dude or whatever.
This is what the fuck I'm talking about.
This is what I'm talking about.
And it just gets annoying after a while
that you take a movie like guess who's
coming to dinner when it's, when it's the
white girl, bring it home, the Black Guy,
the original movie.
Then it's this drama and it's just really
serious fucking thing that needs to be
addressed. But when you flip it and it's
a black girl, bring an Ashton Kutcher,
all of a sudden now, now it's a
comedy. And, and what's his face?
The Dad there, you know, not wanting
her to bring home a white dude.
Now it's fucking hilarious.
I mean, I guess I get it
because of a, on some level,
because it's not like black
people and slave white people.
So though the rules are fucking different,
but you know what I'm saying?
So I'm not just saying, I'm just, I
don't fucking know. I don't want him,
you know what I mean? You
know what the fuck. I mean,
I'm just saying it's like I
got it. I understand. You know,
there's 80,000 fucking movies
about white people being racist.
How about we switch it up every once in
awhile and make a movie about Mexicans
stabbing Puerto Ricans after a boxing
match. How about that? You know,
we ever see that like whenever a Mexican
fire fights a Puerto Rican fighter,
guaranteed somebody getting stabbed
in the Bronx, that's all I'm saying.
I mean, maybe that's not a movie. Maybe
that's more of a, uh, a short, but a,
you know, he could have the
hackey characters in there. Right.
And what the fuck I'm talking
about. Anyways, let's move on here.
Let's recommend some are youtube
videos for the week. Um, here we go.
Here's one that you guys can search.
I don't have time to fucking look.
I watch all of these,
but this is just becoming way too big
to try to watch all of these and try to
come up with the greatest
one ever. My, my,
my youtube video of the year is tough
call a tough talk in college, Girl.
That one. Um, here's some other ones
that people are also suggesting.
If you're at work and you
don't want to work, um,
go on Youtube and search killer dwarf,
midget Muey Thai fighting.
MMM.
You don't have to watch that and
you want something a little cuter.
Watch a search Charlie bit my finger,
which it literally has 90 million views.
So if you haven't seen it yet,
um,
you're one of those people who
not only does not watch TV,
but you don't have a computer. Uh,
this is a weird one. Dog Malfunction.
I went to show that to my
girlfriend and she was just like,
is he going to shit himself? Like shit
all over the place? It's like, no,
it's something different.
A guy with gun confront skateboarder,
I can't remember if I told you that
one last week, but that's a decent,
that's actually a really good one.
And here's a really good one.
A boxer beats up two guys.
I love this video because the boxer dude
is basically what every man wants to be
in this video.
Basically two guys do something fucked
up to his girl and without even without
even a moment's hesitation, he fucks
up these two guys. Guy Is like,
you know who all those guys and like
the action movies pretend to be.
This guy's the guy in
real life. Um, all right,
well getting up here in time,
aren't we? 37 minutes. Okay,
we got to start winding down here.
MMM.
All right. Here's something
sneaky corporations. All right.
And I know I keep saying that I'm done
trying to tell people not to use those
automated machines at the grocery store.
I had another guy telling me
how much easy there. Oh yeah.
I'm in and out of there in two minutes.
Really?
You scan a week's worth of groceries
and you have them in a bag and you're in
and out of there in two minutes.
Oh yeah. I'm sure. I'm sure it's,
I'm sure it's way easier than having
someone who's trained to do it.
Do it for you and stick it in a bag
as you sit there rubbing your balls,
doing nothing. I'm sure
it's way fucking easier. Ah,
idiots. Idiots who want to
work for free. Have Fun. Um,
anyways, there's another one
sneaky corporation thing. Um, Bill,
I share your and Bubba Bubba.
Yeah.
MMM.
Here's an article you should check out.
I'll sum up the basic idea of the
article. Essentially, here's one for you.
Starbucks opened a coffee shop in Seattle
called 15th Avenue Coffee and tea.
They have nothing blatant to
indicate that they are a Starbucks.
They've gone out of their way to disguise
their company as an independent coffee
shop. They even send scouts to check
out independently owned coffee shop.
I'm assuming to better emulate them.
15th Avenue Coffee and tea
will serve beers and wines.
It will have cheese platters
and entertainment at night.
I think this is a new direction that
corporations go into these days.
They create new brands and new images
to trick people into supporting their
company.
And you can't tell who owns what anymore.
So for overrated,
underrated, I say overrated.
The 50th Avenue Coffee and tea,
Aka Starbucks in disguise.
How fucking creepy is that?
You know what?
I Bet I've gone in and spent
money at a place like that.
I was go out there and as
long as it's not a, uh,
as long as it's not like a, uh,
a chain name that I recognize,
I know some of this shit, like I know
like, uh, but this is a chain anyway,
so I wouldn't eat,
there was the,
that chipotle Lei is
actually owned by Mcdonald's,
but anyways, they, I fucking hate your
pote lay. I don't know if you've noticed,
you have a note to say,
always open right across the
street from like a really good,
a Mexican food restaurant.
That's how they didn't just fucking put
those guys out of business. I tried to,
I tried to stay away from those,
but I'll have to, I'll have to, uh,
I gotta be honest with you. I didn't
even read the article. You know,
that's what I do.
Somebody just tell something that's all
you gotta do is just tell me something
and it becomes fact here because
I'm not going to look at it.
I'm on bullshit and I'm actually going
to read it. All right. Um, horror films.
Bill, after hearing your story
about the movie curtains,
it brought back memories of a
movie that I saw when I was young.
It was called the unseen. All right,
you guys got to hear the description,
this movie, and just to let
you know, he ruins the ending,
but I still have to see this. This
is a fucking classic. He goes,
I haven't seen it since I was a kid
back in the 80s but being six and seeing
this one did a number on me for a while.
Pretty much.
The movie is about three chicks
who can't find a hotel to stay in,
so they end up at a bed and
breakfast type place. Jesus.
This and original beginning to our
horror movie. Um, so there's some quote,
there's some quote unquote thing that
attacks these people that stay there.
The part that screwed me up is
that the thing that attack them,
um, would attack through the oversized
air vents in the walls and floors,
pulling them through and killing them.
So after watching it,
I was terrified to go into the bathroom
because all of our bathrooms in our
house had vents right behind me as
I took a piss for the longest time,
I would have to use the bathroom with
the door open in case something would try
to get me. I look back at it now and think
to myself, what a pussy I was. But Hey,
I guess that's why six year olds
shouldn't watch horror flicks.
Here's to four months of pissing
with the door open. All right,
now here's the spoiler alert. Everybody
here's a, if you're gonna rent curtains,
you don't want to hear, uh, you don't
want to hear this last part. Um,
and of course, okay. By the way,
the thing in the movie turns
out to be a retarded kid,
that the parents kept locked in the
basement and all he wanted to do was play
with people.
Apparently his play was a little rough.
How many of those horror
movies are basically,
it always comes down to some, somebody
being shunned as a kid. I swear to God.
I think most of those,
most of those horror movies have something
to do with the person who wrote the
movie, their childhood. A lot of
writers, they're fucking nerds.
So they had these awful childhoods
and then they had like these fucking
fantasies of what the,
what they wanted to do to people and then
they just move it a little to the left
and they turn it rather from,
you know,
just some kid having
some murderous fantasy.
They turned it into a fucking monster
and then you've got a goddamn movie.
Does that make any sense?
That I just say that retarded
people are writing movie scripts.
I think I did. I think that's how
the math works out on that one. Wow.
Let's blow by that. All right,
bill question. I love your calm.
This is the questions for the
week and then I'm done. Ah,
let me hype what I got going on this week.
I'm going to be at the comedy
connection in Providence,
Rhode Island on Friday
and Saturday of this week.
That would be a,
what's today?
The third Friday is four days a
seventh and eighth. All right,
I'm going to be back there doing two shows
both nights. You can go on my website,
uh, Bill bird.com and just click
to the link. Please show up and uh,
watch my new hour of hilarity and the
following week I'm going to be at the
punchline in um, Atlanta, Georgia
and I believe I have the dates wrong.
I'm going to be there Thursday, Friday,
Saturday. I have it down as Friday,
Saturday,
Sunday.
I have to change that and hopefully
by the time you listen to this I have,
um, and other than that I'm
going to be in Stockholm,
Sweden at the end of the month and that's
going to be ended my summer and I'll
be enjoying being in Stockholm,
Sweden.
Cause I'm not going to be missing
baseball. I will not because I am done.
I'm fucking, I don't know
if I'm done forever, but I'm
taking a break. I've had it.
I don't give a fuck anymore. I think
what that guy in the white sox said,
the coach there was true. He's just
like for the love of God, just release,
just release the list, you know, so
you can just get on with it. You know,
I don't understand about these guys.
They get on roids and then they get off
roads and now they're clean and they're
still the same size that they
were. The only guy. Like I said,
the only tag I ever saw it get
smaller was uh, Jason Giambi.
That's the only fucking guy. All the
rest of them, they look the exact same.
So I dunno, I have, fuck it.
I feel like a dope getting all excited
the last 10 years, boy. Oh boy.
Did you see that home run?
All boil. It's all bullshit.
All right. Questions. Hey Bill.
Uh, let's call me podcasts.
I read recently started working at a
retail store and during the hiring process
they gave me a choice between
direct deposit or a debit
card that they provided.
Yeah.
Basically saying,
um,
I wouldn't be getting a
physical check every other week.
I asked why they did that. And The lady
said, that's just the way we, they do it.
Isn't that how you, isn't that the
response you always get from corporations?
You know what, why, why do I have to do
it? Oh, that's they just, they make us.
That's just, that's just
how they do it. So anyways,
like every other person
I said, oh, all right.
And even though that's the way they do it,
didn't answer my question.
So I guess my question to you is,
do you think that this is just a way for
paper money to be turned into numbers
on a computer?
Is it really easier to have my money
directly deposited in a bank or say,
or on some debit card rather than me going
to the bank and physically getting my
money? If I may use your
reference about it, um,
about if your iPod crashes
and all your songs are gone,
but if you physically had
the cds back to back it up,
then you will be okay. Uh,
did any of that makes sense?
Not The way I'm reading it now.
I'm just saying I would rather get the
physical checks than to be doing things
online, but I guess that's just the way
they do it. Yeah, dude, that's brutal.
That's fucking brutal.
See what they're doing is they're
forcing the herd into a direction.
So when guys like me don't play
ball with that, just out of,
I'm going to have to play ball the
same way with those automated machines.
Everyone's going to start using them
and then there aren't going to be any
cashier people and then I'm
going to be fucked, you know?
So, um, yeah, that,
that's what they're doing
is they're phasing out cash.
So anybody who has any cash hidden in
their walls are in their bed or any of
that type of shit.
Um,
that stuff eventually will become obsolete
unless you take it out and then you
give it to them and then there'll be like,
well, where the fuck did you get this?
And then they'll tax the shit out of you.
Um,
and I know a lot of you right now going,
well,
you should have fucking reported the
money anyways and all this type of stuff.
And if you really read about the Federal
Reserve and all and how fucking corrupt
it is,
there's a link on the Internet right now
where it's where some guy used to work
at the Federal Reserve just called
it a Ponzi scheme on television,
on CNBC said it's basically
nothing more than a Ponzi scheme.
I don't know if the guy, actually, let me,
let me get, let me get that link for you.
Um, if you really want to
check this shit out, go, uh,
it's called the daily bail.com
and oh,
this is, this is when they have the, oh,
that's a woman testifying
for the Federal Reserve.
When they've asked if they have any, you
know, they put it, give them $1 trillion.
And there was no record of where it
went or who took it and they just keep
talking in circles while we have a
person that is looking into that,
but right now I can't give
you an answer on that.
Like that's the way they
answered everything.
Do the whole thing's a fucking scam.
It's all a scam and what
they're trying to do is
they're trying to phase out cash so
there'll be no way for you to every like
everything you do will
have to be reported.
They'll know where all your money is
at all times and then not only that,
they're going to have all
your money at all times. It's,
I don't know how I do you know how to,
it's so fucking huge.
I never know where to begin
to try to explain what,
how little that I understand
about this is just,
just let me put it this way. The amount
of money that you've made in your life,
how much of it have you
actually held in your hand?
How many times have you gone out and you
work all week and then they just type
some numbers on a piece of paper and
then you the check and then you just go
down to the bank and then it just
becomes this number on a computer screen.
The amount of number,
that's money,
money that's out there versus the amount
of money that's actually printed first.
The amount of money that actually has
gold behind it, it's fucking terrifying.
It's a,
it's the biggest fucking scam
I think in the history of the world.
It's the biggest fucking scam.
And when you get a mortgage like I have,
and I'm sitting here to
figure out how to get
out from underneath that debt and meet,
realizing that me getting
out from underneath the debt
will actually cost me an
extra four grand a year in taxes,
if not even more. I think on the way I
worked it out, yeah, it would cost me,
I pay about 24 grand a year in
taxes or something like that
and we'd go up to 28 I
can't even remember. I,
I tried to work all of this shit out,
but basically my best move was
to Jess
take 30 years to pay off a mortgage
to basically pay 200% interest on six
figures.
I Dunno. You know what?
I can't even explain it.
I'm probably sounding like a more
on right now. Just [inaudible] just,
I dunno. Read up on this stuff.
It's fucked. It's brutal.
It's just fucking brutal. I
can't even, I don't know. I'm,
I'm coming off like a moron.
I wasn't prepared to discuss this
and what little I knew about it.
Now you guys are probably gone.
This guy, it's just a fucking idiot.
I don't know where the fuck do
you begin to try to explain?
This is actually funny. Like,
I'm really stammering right now.
I feel like I committed a murder right
now and I'm trying to say that I didn't,
and I didn't take time to fucking
come up with a, with an alibi.
Um, I don't think that you should
put your money in the bank is basic.
What I'm saying, you know,
these guys fucking you,
you take your money. Okay. He
put it in a bank, all right?
They give you like fucking 0.5% interest
on it and then they take your money and
then they turn around and they loan it
back to you with everybody else's money
at some ridiculous fucking interest rate.
And then on top of that,
they come up with these fucking loans
that make homeless people qualified to get
homes,
which drives the price,
artificially drives the
prices of houses up hip.
It comes like Superbowl tickets. Everybody
wants to go. So now a fourth thing,
something that's worth $400 face
value now becomes worth four grand.
It's not fucking worth four grand.
So then you go out and you pay like a
couple of hundred grand more than your
fucking places actually worth and
you're paying interest on it. And who?
Who drove the price up?
The bank.
And how does a bank make money
on interest? So they dig,
just basically create a loan so they
can make houses more fucking expenses.
So it's expensive so they
can make even more money.
The whole thing was was bullshit.
It was completely criminal actually.
You know what? It wasn't criminal. That
was a great thing. It was actually legal,
what they were doing.
That's how much fucking power they have.
And then when the whole thing fucking
topples, they make us fucking pay for it.
We pay for it,
and they keep the fucking money.
They're beyond fucking corrupt.
It's the most corrupt bullshit
on the planet.
I think it's worse.
Yeah.
It's worse than, than anything that's
going on in the planet right now.
It's right up there with genocide.
What
the fuck they're doing is
because basically they're in
slaving the entire planet.
And right now they rather, you know it
or not. You are financially enslaved.
You're fucking indentured. So I really
sound like I'm fucking crazy. I'm serious.
You're, you're fucked. You're in a dent.
Might my own guy who invest my money when
I was trying to figure out how to get
out of this bullshit,
he said it to me.
This is a guy who actually could probably
obviously and a much more intelligent
way explain this fucking
game. He said, Bill, face it.
We're all indentured servants
to the banks. Um, I don't know,
Dude. I don't know what the fuck happened
back in the day when you moved to town,
we went from having a house raising party
to having a 30 year fucking mortgage.
Will you pay 200% interest on the
fucking money that you were loaned?
And by the time you pay it off,
you're in a fucking wheelchair.
There has to be a happy medium.
I don't want to live in a log cabin.
I don't want to live in a cave. But, um,
if you think that the
government is above the banks,
you're out of your fucking mind.
And a great example is when the president
tells bankers after they fucked up the
economy not to take a bonus.
And they basically say, hey,
go fuck yourself with taking a bonus
anyways. And then he just says, oh, okay.
I think that should basically tell you,
you know who the fuck is running stuff?
So I know that came off
as completely ignorant,
but read up on it. Okay, I can't,
I'm just a fucking comedian.
I really shouldn't get
into this type of shit.
But that fucking question
really set me off. It's a,
I dunno.
It's frightening.
Frightening is why I'm trying to pay
off my apartment as quickly as I can.
I don't think I'm going to make
it because of the end of it.
I want to have something of some sort of
fucking value that I can go out and get
a sandwich with.
You know?
Maybe I can rent out a part
of my apartment because I
don't think money is going
to be worth anything if they just keep
printing it. They're phasing the shit out.
It's, it's bad. Bad people don't do that.
Don't get direct deposit.
Don't do that.
Don't do your fucking
banking on the Internet.
It's the level of faith you,
you're, you're, you're an
idiot. If you're doing that,
you think you're the only
guy looking at that shit.
I'll tell you what pisses me off
with someone sent me an email said,
even if you don't do banking on,
on the Internet,
all your information is up there anyways,
just in case.
Just in case you want to go online now.
I don't think that they should have
the right to do it. It's my money.
I should be the one who tells them,
listen,
I don't want my information
out there like that,
but they can do whatever the fuck
they wanted. It's just, it's all,
it's not your money,
everybody. It's not your money.
They give you money and your job is to
go out and get into as much debt as you
possibly can sustain.
And if you don't,
then they just take it from you so you
can never become rich and they keep
getting fucking richer.
That's what the fuck is going on.
And this has nothing to do
with Republican or Democrat.
That's just has to do with a select few
group of evil people at the fucking top
who are running everything.
I know I sound like a motto,
my fucking mind and I probably am.
Um,
but I welcome the debate.
Anybody whose in economics or whatever,
who majored in that Shit and you want to,
you want to email me and
you want to explain to me,
I mean,
am I wrong thinking that the Federal
Reserve is a private corporation that does
not have to answer to the u s government
that has never been audited. Am I wrong?
Aren't they in charge? I know the
treasury physically prints the money.
Am I wrong?
I'm just asking am I wrong when I say
that they are the ones that are in charge
of how much gets printed and when and
that the u s government or the banks then
take that money and have
to pay interest on it.
And that creates this debt that
we can never fucking get out of.
And isn't that what happened over in
Europe and isn't that why they are now on
the fucking euro and are we
now moving towards the Amera?
Huh?
This is me just regurgitating
all my Wikipedia youtube shit.
That even sounded dumb to me,
but I dunno. That's the general,
you know what I mean?
Um,
you know what I'm like right now
I'm a guy who just started watching,
like it'd be like me trying to
intelligently talk about the x games.
Then when I went to the x games
once and I'm like, do the backside.
Fakey all right, whatever. Let's
plow ahead. Hey, bill, I love the,
uh, the podcast here. Okay. Bill Harris.
Bill, have you ever been offered to do,
to be on the show, last
comic standing, um,
offered to be on it? No, I did. I
could've auditioned for it, but I didn't.
Um,
I just thought it was,
I thought it was good for Comedians
at a certain level and I thought I was
beyond the level where it was good and I
would have just looked cheesy on there.
You know what I mean? Plus
I want to, I knew myself,
I wouldn't have done any of the
competitions. I just would been like, no,
I'm not fucking doing that.
Just challenged me and I'll go up and
I'll do three minutes. And if you beat me,
then I don't have to live in a
house with seven other comedians,
which would be kind of enjoyable.
In other words,
I wouldn't have been good on the show.
So No, I never, uh, I never got offered,
but I, I could've auditioned
and I, I didn't think it
was for me. All right, Bill.
Hey, love your comedy a on the podcast.
Thank you. I have a question for you.
I need your advice. My brother passed
away two weeks ago at 34 years old.
All right. This is kind of a fucked
up one to end on, but I'm gonna um,
needless to say, I'm crushed. Sorry to
hear that, man. That's really a brutal.
So my condolences. I'm, here's the issue.
My inlaws haven't said anything to me.
No phone call, no cards,
nothing. I'm devastated.
You would think that them
being parents themselves, um,
that they may care about me since
I am married to their daughter. Um,
they will, they would have said
something. They didn't say anything.
I don't really want anything
to do with them now.
I relationship was fine before this
as good as you can be within laws.
I'm just not feeling
much like seeing them.
It hasn't come up yet with my wife,
but she is really close with them
and likes for us to go over, um,
likes to go over there to hang out.
What should I do?
Should I just drop it and
pretend like they, uh,
couldn't have cared less that my brother
died or do I stand my ground and fuse
to go over to any functions
until I hear something?
Obviously the latter choice
would cause friction at home.
I'm the first choice would kill me
inside the one being to go over there.
What do you think? Uh, you
know what this podcast is?
This should just be,
Bill just talks about shit that he's not
qualified to talk about. Okay. And uh,
that includes all that banking stuff.
Even though I know on my gut level,
somewhere in there, I'm
right. Um, all right.
My Gut is telling me, uh,
you're obviously you're,
you're angry right now and uh,
you have to go through that stuff.
I think the move here is it's a bad move
to, um, you know,
basically you're gonna be married to
your wife for the rest of your life.
You don't need the fucking not getting
along with the in laws to make it a
miserable situation. Um, I don't
know anything about your in laws.
I Dunno if they're not good with our
emotions. I don't know if they like, he,
I don't know what to say. I mean, I
don't know how old they are. I mean,
a lot of these people who come from
the pre Oprah fucking Winfrey show,
especially guys and a lot of
women, they don't, you know,
they don't know how to express shit.
Like when stuff like this comes up,
they don't know what to do.
So the move is right now is you have to
talk to your wife and you have to tell
her how devastated you are that your
in laws haven't expressed any sort of
condolences.
And you have to tell her that it's making
you not want to do anything with them
ever again.
And just say that you're putting into,
you really have to
communicate that to your wife.
Because what you're doing right now is
you're already going through something
devastating and you, you could
possibly, through your grief,
make your own personal life, which I'm
guessing was happy up to this point.
Even worse because you're gonna,
you're gonna push away your in laws and
then push away your wife at the same
time. So what you have to do, you
have to go to her and in a calm way,
just tell how hurt you are that they
didn't, that they didn't. Um, they didn't,
you know, send a car to flowers or
anything like that. Um, some of these,
I know I asked somebody about this and
they actually brought up a great point
that they had some,
a friend of theirs pass away and there
was so many flowers at the funeral and
people were coming up going,
hey, did you get the flowers?
Did you get the flowers I sent? And it's
like, you know, they're dealing with,
you know, the, the funeral stuff
that they got to take care of,
picking out the coffin and all that
awful stuff so they don't get a chance to
look at all the flowers. So for all you
know, they might have sent some flowers.
So the first, Oh, there you go.
Do this, you jump off point.
You have to say to your wife that, listen,
I need to talk to you about something.
And you just say, obviously you know
what happened. And as far as I know,
uh,
you know,
as you have your parents sent a card
or any flowers that I didn't get,
let her answer that.
And if she says she doesn't know,
then that's when you go
and say, look, you know,
obviously this is a big thing to me and
they haven't expressed any condolences
and this is making me want to do
x, y, and z. That's how you do it.
So just use the jump off point,
you know,
with that question. That's something
I've learned in my life was shit,
a lot less devastating,
which is basically the first thing you
do is you have to find out if what you're
thinking is correct before you go off
on somebody. Going off is step two.
All right? I can't tell you how many times
in my life someone comes up and says,
hey,
so and so says this,
and then I just take that as law rather
than going up to the person going, hey,
you know,
I'm not saying
you did this, but somebody, somebody
saying that you said this shit,
and then you're supposed to do it that
way rather than just flipping out.
Because if you flip out and they
actually sent flowers, you're, you're,
you're really going to look bad. And then
you made already a, a brutal situation.
Even worse. All right, there you go.
I'm done. Babylon for a week. Dude,
I'm sorry to hear about your
loss. I hope, uh, you know,
I hope,
I hope shit works out for you with your
in laws and all that type of stuff.
All right. Uh, it's a devastating way to
end this podcast and it's over an hour.
These things are getting
way too fucking long.
And I apologize for all my babble on
this weekend. Yes, I know. I am a moron.
So I would love to hear from all
you economic majors out there, um,
or someone who is even in banking.
Please. Somebody for love of God.
If you're in banking, please defend
it because I got to tell you,
I'm not one of these psycho conspiracy
theorists who thinks he's 100% right.
I want to be fucking
wrong on all of this shit.
I want to be wrong on the
automated cashier things.
I want to be wrong and all I want to
say that they're actually sitting there
going,
how can we make less money and pass
savings onto the fucking customer?
How come I yet be smaller?
All right, that's it. Um,
I should like, I should have lost
a lot of credibility on that one.
I really stammered my way through that
banking thing and I'd be lying to you if
I wasn't embarrassed. All right? And then
hit. That is the podcast for this week.
Thanks for listening,
everybody.
I'm going to try and get the
bandwidth up so more people can enjoy
my completely uninformed opinions
every week. All right? God bless you.
[inaudible]
[inaudible].