Hey, what's going on it's Bill Burr
is time for the Thursday afternoon,
just before Friday. Monday
morning podcast. What's going on?
How I yeah,
I am once again,
this is like all of a sudden I never
have fucking guests and then all of a
sudden they all come out of the
woodwork almost at the same time on all
musicians. And once again,
we have a very special guest,
a Ms Tal Wilkenfeld how are you? I'm
good. You got a new album coming out. Yup.
Right. It just can't, you know, I
didn't even want to start with that.
Cause I know you've fucking been talking
about all kinds of music I had asked
you, cause we were over your place right
now. Well, how are you liking the Vitamix?
I love the Vitamix because I got
into like the, I'm an old man now.
I don't know if he can tell.
I use a lot of lotion, right?
They can still in my twenties but I'm
about to turn 51 here in June. And uh, I,
I've started to do like for breakfast. I
like to just have like a smoothie. Yeah.
His phone. He's, that sounds
to everybody doesn't live in,
it's the fucking greatest thing ever.
Right? You just drink it. You full. Yeah.
You know, rather than doing the
Denny's grand slam breakfast,
you feel like a tub of shit,
which makes you eat something else bad.
So people been telling me about the
Vitamix and this is where I am in my life
where I'm like,
like that was the thing.
You have all these amazing
instruments and shit.
And the thing that stuck
out was like, Ooh, Vitamix.
I wonder if that one mashes up the fucking
spinach and Kale a little bit better.
The best recipe to you do cause I got it.
I got two really good ones that I
stand by. What are they trade? Uh,
I got one that uh, I substituted the
Kale for spinach. Spinach tastes better.
All it is, it's just that.
So if a Dandelion Greens,
just Fyi you with,
I need the landline Greens now.
What do you do to sweeten that
up so it's not bitter as shit?
I used some honey just a little
bit. Just a little bit. Yeah, man.
One time my wife took
me to some restaurant.
We ended up eating like Dan the lines
like a damn light. We both trying it,
not like, hey man, let's be healthy. We
both looked at each other. It's like, oh,
it was one of the worst things I ever
tasted it. So when you grind that up,
what do you have almond milk in there too?
Or Center?
It's actually a juice really. It's not
like a smoothie. Um, but it's quite thick,
which is why I still call it a smoothie,
but mine has dandelion Greens, Cilantro,
a little bit of black pepper.
Oh my God.
Tumeric and ginger. Like fresh
ginger, which Richard, call me.
What you stand by that it's this sounds,
it sounds.
What else do I put it in their water?
There's obviously water and then I
get hungry. An hour and a half later.
Where do you buy?
Danny was go in your backyard and
yanked them out of the fucking grass.
What do you, what do you get your
dental, ENT. Any health food store?
Wholefoods or I've never said,
I gotta be honest with you.
And I've been to a few of those
little health food places. I've never,
I've never seen that. But uh, all
right. Mine. Mine is just simple.
It's just a almond.
It's a almond milk with some almonds
just in case there's not enough almond in
there that some spinach,
uh, to fuck is a banana.
A little bit of ice.
And I know I'm forgetting something
says cinnamon blueberries ever use
blueberries? No, I gotta get
a couple of goals cause I,
I basically have to go to smoothies
and I'm getting sick of them.
And then I have like this Greek yogurt
parfait and I just sort of rotate that on
a three thing. I'm just,
I've had it, you know,
you don't like when you've been jamming
with people too long, you're like,
we need some new blood or something.
That's where I am assuming you're trying
to steer it back to the music here.
So let's at least say the name of your
incredible album that I only heard three
tracks of, cause I couldn't
figure out how to download it. Um,
for those of you not
familiar with Tal, she's, uh,
she's basically played with everybody and
I promised her I wasn't going to bring
up all the past like, hey man, what
was it like playing with this person?
But she's,
you know,
I MDB or she's played with literally
everybody and you've basically been known
as this monster Bass player that
can just play with anybody. And, uh,
your hidden talent of an unbelievable
singing voice is finally displayed.
That that's what killed
me when I listened to you.
Just played those three
tracks for me. Aside from, of
course, how upfront, you know,
the basis and all the mics,
which I'm loving. Um, I, yeah,
I had no idea you could sing like that.
I kind of, um, I, I've
kept it quiet for awhile.
Like I started as a singer songwriter
when I first picked up guitar and then,
um,
sort of started focusing just on guitar
when I moved to America because I left
home when I was 16,
and I moved to America and I went to
this music school for a little while and,
uh,
I went from like,
I hope you went to a nice place,
all this crap about the
Michael Jackson documentary,
which I refuse to fucking watch.
Why would you do that?
Why would you put all those that those
horrible stories in your head? It's like,
I get it. All right. The guy was
a creep, but now he's dead. So
what are we doing? I guess
you got list. Somebody going,
someone was telling me going, you, how
will you have to watch it? So then you,
you as a parent,
it's like,
I'm not going to let some fucking guy
sleep with my kid behind nine doors anyway
, so you've got this album
coming out. So I went to, um,
I went to this,
this school and I went from being allowed
to play like half an hour a day to
wanting to practice for like six hours
day. Was that torture for you considering
the way you took? I remember hearing,
I watched that interview, you said the
first time you actually played a chord,
you got emotional, you cried. Yeah.
So you love something that much and
then all of a sudden you go into,
you're going to school in Australia.
So they were teaching about Columbus and
all the great stuff that happened here
in America of course. Right.
Whatever it was, how you guys,
you got dropped off by the
English and so what happened?
Something like that where a
bunch of convicts apparently.
Yeah, exactly. Exactly.
So then all of a sudden,
was that torture for you in school?
It was just, it was hard
because, um, you know,
academia was the focus. Especially like,
um, where I, with who I grew up with,
you know, um, my mom just like
really wanted me to, uh, you know,
do all my head. Yeah. I do all
my schoolwork and stuff. I mean,
she's probably just being
a responsible parent,
but like I just was not into
geography and history I was into.
So did you ever just like to pick up the
bass and be like, mom, listen to this.
I mean, listen to this and then look at
my grades in math and you tell me which
direction I'm supposed to go in.
I mean, uh, I was just, I was
a guitarist at that point.
Like I only switched
to bass when I was 17,
which I already moved to America
at that point. But yeah, I mean,
she hugged me play. I just, I
think that like, you know, uh,
the music business is a tough place and
she probably just thought like, ah, maybe,
maybe that's not the best thing for
you to do, to be in the music industry.
It's so uncertain. Um, so,
but I wasn't going to listen to
what anyone was going to say.
Like that's all I knew that I had to be
a musician and I didn't care if I was
going to be homeless and,
and be a musician. I just,
I knew that that's what I had to do.
So
I ever wonder how many this,
how many musicians are out there?
Because that story is like,
you had that inner drive and
like I always wondered like,
how many like Jimi Hendrix or like working
at home depot because their parents
or, or some something, you know, they just
didn't have that thing to be like, no, no,
no, fuck that. I'm doing it. Right. Um,
really important people that basically
taught you how to walk and talk and all
of that stuff start telling you, you
know, you shouldn't go in that direction.
That's just something that you, is,
was that something that developed?
Was it the love that you had when you
started playing guitar that you will like,
no, I literally have to do this? Or do you
feel you always had sort of that, that,
uh,
that drive?
Well, I actually think, um, as a kid,
especially as a teenager, like if your
parents tell you not to do something,
you're gonna want to do it more.
Like 99% of teenagers.
I dread those days when my daughter.
Okay. Yeah. So it probably worked, uh,
out in the right way that she didn't
really want me to focus on music because
that just made me want to do it more. Oh,
okay. Yeah. I mean I'm kind of, I mean,
I wouldn't even say I was
necessarily rebellious,
but if you want something in that bad and
someone's telling you no, you're like,
well,
I'll prove to you that,
that I really deserve this and I'm
gonna work my ass off. And I did, like,
I was so focused,
like my rebellion as a teenager
was to succeed as a musician.
It wasn't like to go off and
do drugs or whatever else.
Like that was my rebellion was,
was success.
You know, I went to, I was
looking at schools to see
which one to take, you know,
put my daughter and you know, all the
public schools are shit out here, I guess.
So you're going to send them to private
school and spend like a zillion dollars
by the time I'm like eight.
It's so fucking stupid.
So he went to this one and it was
like a French speaking one. Right.
So all the kids, it was amazing. The kids
were super smart as a great school and,
and, but the lady given like the tour,
right? She goes, uh, the hell did she say?
I asked her, I said, hey, you know, uh,
to the parents kind of learned French
along the way. She's like, no, we,
we encourage you to speak
the perfect English at home
and blah, blah. I said, well,
what if I want to learn it
too? When she looked at me,
she goes, yes, it's too late.
I was just like, God damn, I actually
respected it, but you know what?
I'm so happy she said that to me because
now I've got this thing like, God,
I'll show you. Yeah. And I got flashcards.
I would have flash cards
and I'm like looking at,
I'm trying to put together phrases and
stuff. I listened to the back of my head.
I know she's probably right and I love
the school and I'm actually excited that
the potential to go there. But like
I do relate to that as far as, um,
when somebody says that,
but there was a period of my life
where I wasn't that guy. Oh yeah.
Like if somebody said that to me, I'd be
like, okay, forget it. Oh really? So yeah,
I've probably had that since
I was really young, like, uh,
like just determination to
do whatever I want to do.
Cause like I remember
being super focused on, um,
running before I was a guitar player and
I was like obsessed with long distance
running. Like, and, and in my head
I'm like, I have to be the best,
I have to be the best
runner gold from Australia.
One girl that was better than
me and it pissed me off so much.
And I remember like, there was
this one race that was, I dunno,
it was like a 10 mile race. It
was really long and, and I just,
I just had to beat this, go.
And I did beat the girl you did.
But I did this like,
um,
like still a Vittori dance afterwards
because I was so excited and I threw my
back out and know. Yeah. So then I,
I kind of was like hobbling around for
a little while and couldn't run like a
couple of weeks.
And then that's actually when I walked
past that guitar and started playing get
this out. Right. Yeah. Wow. She
got mad when you did that dance.
I mean, I don't think she saw it.
She was that far behind me. Wow.
That's like a feel good movie except they
always run credits before you blow out
your back. Then you became like
a musician. So you know, the,
the few tracks that I heard that through,
the three that I listened
to was definitely, you know,
this is really like a very personal
album as far as like, you know,
talking to yourself though,
that one you just played.
What was the name of the haunted heart?
Love haunted love.
The one that's just the base and
voice with the orchestra. Yeah.
That was some pretty,
uh,
heavy lyrics that may be sort
start thinking about my parents.
I went on a little trip there.
One of those. Yeah. Yeah.
Thinking about my whole life and um,
I fo people listening here,
I can't recommend like the level of
quality of, of the music that you've,
you've done with other
people now to actually hear,
hey these are my ideas with
your voice on top of it. Uh,
the second I heard you a few of these,
I was like, oh this is one of these,
these albums I'm just going to put
in back in the day when you had a CD,
just stick it in there until the thing
just uh, started skipping on you. But um,
you mean how your iTunes that
skipping on you right now,
he like had money second.
I know I am the worst.
I'm the worst before
all you can download it.
You got Spotify is like I
don't have Spotify. I, I'm,
I'm this idiot who I still buy music and
then it fills up your computer and now
cause right now I need a new,
I need a new laptop.
I need a new phone and I need
new iPod, iPad, the whole thing.
Shit in the bet on me at the
same time. And uh, yeah, I
can I buy it on vinyl? I yeah,
I have a record player. Yes.
I'll even give it to you on vine.
They don't need to do that.
You already got me a Burrito here
from coming over so I'll, I'll, I'll,
I'll throw some money towards
that. But um, what was I gonna say?
So you also mentioned that you're
actually going to be doing a whole tour in
this thing too, Huh? Yeah. Now headline
in tour, you open and what are you doing?
Headlining headline in. Nice.
I'm excited. And I got to Boston.
Is this your first like
big headlining tour?
Cause you've always been like
the hired gun as far as I know,
this is your first like,
um,
well I I actually I was opening for
the who with my band and we played the
Boston Garden and some really cool,
is it called the bus and garden?
They called the TD bank.
North side guiding Qi. How'd
you like that? That was fine.
And you do that recently?
Yeah,
I did some stand up there and I did
jam before with my brothers. So cool.
Uh, we had a good, yeah, we definitely had
a, you know what's so funny is we a ever,
no one was paying attention at all and
we were playing or whatever they thought
was kind of funny that we were doing it.
And this is comedian Jim Brewer who
does this amazing bit on slayer fans,
like how dedicated and crazy they are.
Well we actually play it,
I forget what song we played.
We played a slayer song and literally
it was like no one was reacting to
anything we were doing. We suck. Right.
The second we started playing slayer,
some fucking security
guide, like, you know,
halfway up the renewed just goes slayer.
Hilarious. So, um,
now your style of music like going no,
you're gonna ask me something
was going to say like,
like what does playing before
a standup set do for you?
It makes the, the venue
not as intimidating. I've
only done it at like what?
Because you know, it stand up in a
place that big doesn't make sense.
You like highlight, you know, I,
I had all these feelings of like,
why am I a, like how did I get
here? What am I doing here?
What the fuck do I have to say that
justifies all these people showing up,
you know, the normal, if you're any sort
of like human being, that's what you have.
If you're a psychopath,
you just like, yeah,
well how come I'm not playing the
football stadium or whatever. You know,
I've ever played in the Roman Coliseum.
But I, yeah, I was sitting there and uh,
that's that what was, what was
going through my head. But, um,
the first time I ever did one I did for
the New York comedy festival and I did
Madison Square Garden and, uh, we
got together and jammed in there.
And I just did that because
I love led Zeppelin.
And they did song remains the same.
If I could just play some drums
there and make a little bit of noise.
And what happened was we were having so
much fun and I invited so many people
down there, they, I, you know, I
didn't ever fully forget where I was,
but next thing you know, you
know I was yelling, Hey Josh,
John is at that Motley
crew thing and you just,
you just yelling and you just
kind of made it yours. Yeah.
So that night it just
didn't, it didn't feel, um,
I was able to kind of just like,
I had already made a bunch of noise in
there and nothing bad happened, you know,
enough the roof collapse. So I think that
that's kind of like what it did for me.
Although I fucked up at the form
cause I played it like three hours.
I almost fucked up cause I was just like,
I got off stage and I was like wiped
out. I was just like, oh no. Oh No.
But then like the adrenaline is like,
oh my God,
what if I bombing from all
these fucking people? You know,
that that'll get you through
a good 90 [inaudible]
but why do you not like play on stage for
your audience? Because I respect them.
Ah, you're a great drama. I
didn't know why you say that.
Uh, I'm good for a comedian. I'll give
you that. But I am not a, you know what I,
I like,
uh,
like one of my favorite things to do
is to watch a pro play cause it's just,
you know, when they're just
doing like a sound check,
a lot of times there'll be physically
playing something that I could play,
but I could never make it sound like that.
And there's always like a personnel,
you know,
if you listen to a really good drama,
you can hear like you can hear
them in the plane, which, um,
you know, took me a while to be able to
hear that. But, uh, now I'm able to do,
and I've, I've, I've seen, I don't know,
there's just something cool about it.
It's like watching a professional hockey
player, like taping up this stick.
There's just something,
when you see a pro doing something,
um, it's an your into it. Especially if
it's your hobby. It's fucking mesmerizing.
So that's, that's why when a
few times I've come over here,
like I'm always in there cause I'm like
sitting back and just watching all of
you guys play.
And um,
my favorite thing about watching a live
band is watching a band that doesn't
play it the same way every night and you,
and even if you've never seen the band,
you can tell cause they like looking
at each other and everything.
So that's when I get into like, aw
man, they're in the moment right now.
This is like watching a comic riff.
And so he's going to do something to
make somebody smile and then he adds
something else tonight.
And just as an audience member and a
fan of music trying to pick up like that
thing going on and um, and like my, I,
it turned like I'm the bands
I listened to growing up.
Like I remember Stevie Ray Vaughan,
whenever he was playing a solo,
it was like Chris Layton and Tommy Shannon
and Reese will always looking right
at him. Like, is he going
to go back in again?
Oh are we going to be going back to the,
you know,
him singing and he just would fucking
be wailing and he had this little thing,
you just look at him, he gives, give him
a little nod and how they all were like,
okay. And, and, and they
wouldn't fuck that up.
I'm just having attempted to Gino get
together with friends and play and
everything. I just, I've, I have
such an admiration for it. So, um,
I mean that's how I feel about comedy
and great comedy and that's why I like
watching you perform. Oh yeah. When
I do a great shit joke and I, okay.
I not over to somebody who just did
a dick joke gem and it's amazing.
It's right on the same level. No, but
like, cause I just started as, you know,
like getting really heavily into
comedy the past like year or so. Yeah.
And like the reason that appeals to me
so much is because it like speaks to both
parts of me as a
musician. There's the, uh,
the jazz musician in me, which is like
the improvisational musician, which like,
like really enjoys watching you ref like,
and, and just, and then there's like,
then there's like the composer, like
the, the person that's like, you know,
into writing songs and like,
and then watching you create
this amazing materials.
So it's, it's very sad cause that a
requirement for people in your band.
Cause I mean, when you work, when
you go and do this tour, like, uh,
I just know it's doing the same
jokes over and over and over again.
It's like you have to like, do something
to break out of it. Do you, um,
on this tour, I mean, you sell on the
album, you got to go out and, and, and,
you know, play it and sell the
music to them. Like how, uh,
how much like messing around do you do?
I do a lot and then is a requirement and
that's why it's been really tricky to
find band members. And I have
found like the perfect, um,
guitarist and drummer to play
with me because, you know,
my music is a composition. Lee. Um,
like lyrically for instance,
very influenced by folk music
or just songwriter music.
But then musically it's um,
it's influenced from anything from
rock to folk to jazz to whatever.
It just goes all over the place.
That's what I was loving. But this,
this is some sort of through line.
Maybe it's you,
I don't know what it is on and because
I was just listening to that song was so
great and then I really started listening
to the mix of it. I'm like, wow,
she's the whole bottom end of this song.
And then it felt like,
I don't know how to say technically,
but it felt like the guitars
and keys were like up here and,
but you are the sort of the meat and
potatoes of the whole thing driving the
whole song. But like the uh, the
different tones and stuff. Um,
there was wide I'm, I'm, I'm the worst.
I don't know the names of the, yeah,
when you went into that bridge,
that was all our is up
though with sections called
at Middlesex was just like,
what the fuck is that? And then you go
right back to that part that really rocks.
Cos when I looked at you,
I was just like,
that's when the crowd's going to go nuts.
Cause you taking them on this ride where
you coming out and you just, you know,
blowing their wig back in the beginning
and then it goes to this other places
like, Whoa, what the fuck is
this? This is this mood thing.
Well that's where it's like,
hey, if people start taking
the drugs in the crowd,
I would feel and look, and I went,
I went, what you'll be doing?
That's what I do. I grew up going to
heavy metal concerts. That was a time,
all of a sudden somebody like sparked up
a fucking J is we used to say. And uh,
and then all of a sudden
like out of nowhere,
you just punched him in the face again
and then the fucking song is over.
It's just like, yeah. Um, I
think that the cohesiveness, um,
on the record comes from like having
the same band play all of these songs,
even though they've, they're very
different. Like, some are, you know,
just vocal and base and some of our
acoustic guitar and, and very, uh,
little, uh, behind me.
And then there's like these full rockers
but it's the same band and I just think
that that's really important.
Like for how long does it take
you to put that together? Well,
it took me a few years to sort of search
for the sound of the record and like
figure out who was going to play on
it and who, who like what was the,
the best sound for these songs.
And then I finally went
into the studio with
the Blake Mills and Jeremy and Paul
Stacy and uh, we cut corner painter,
which is the first song I played you in.
It's the first song on the record.
And that when I heard that back on
the speakers, and this was no base,
it was just,
I was playing acoustic baritone guitar.
Blake was playing guitar and Jeremy was
playing drums and the sound was so full,
I didn't even want to play bass on it.
There's no bass on that song at all.
I just played it on an organ. And then
Belmont tench overdubbed a organ as well,
like a pump organ.
But I heard that song was like,
this is the lynch pin for the record.
And so then I went home and I like
wrote a bunch of other songs that I felt
would fit with that vibe or compliment it.
And then once I'd done that,
we went back in the studio for,
it was like anywhere from like eight to
10 days and cut the whole thing at once.
And so I think that that's part of
the cohesiveness is that we just,
we cut it all together.
Or when you've put together a band,
if you ever had been like, okay,
I know these two people are right,
and then a third person comes in and
so it takes it into another direction.
You got to fire one of those other two
people that just cause, but the other,
cause the other person's such a beast.
I mean it's all, it's all about Canada.
Sorry, pointed out the drums
when I said that. Right.
Chemistry take casting
for a movie to like some,
sometimes it's the most important
thing is the casting. All right.
How do you like your life by
the way? I Miss Australia. Um,
I don't Miss Australia. Um, some
of my best friends are there.
I definitely miss them, you
know, but, and I miss the beach.
I don't really think that the beach
in La is that cool? No, I gotta be,
I'm terrified of the ocean and every
time I go to Australia, it's like I,
if I was ever, you know, there's
a place to get eaten by a shark.
It is definitely the coasts of
your country. It's so beautiful.
You'd beat me as well. At least I was,
you know, at least you dive beautifully.
I remember we were there in like a,
I don't know when we were, was your,
your weird winter down there, which is
just the different time. And it was too,
it was too cold and
windy. Um, it's not weird.
It's just weird to me cause I'm
in the northern hemisphere, but,
so we were down there and I was expecting
it to be fucking hot and all of a
sudden I was like freezing.
And, uh, but even then I was
looking at, and I was like,
if it wasn't so rough
and it wasn't so cold,
I think I would add maybe I did actually
go into the water when I was in Perth
because I just wanted to say
that I stood in the Indian Ocean.
I literally went up to my ankles and I
got back in and then I got in the car and
I was listening to the radio and there
was a helicopter following in like an 18
foot tiger shark along the beach just to
let the surfers and everybody know that
the thing was there and you guys had
the creepiest terminology ever for when
someone gets eaten by a shark, you
say he was taken. That's what I heard.
Oh yeah, it was something, blah, blah.
He got taken. I'm like, Oh my God,
I'd rather be eaten than taken,
eaten to muse. It's over. I mean,
it's fucking horrific.
And then you bleed out and it's
over. Taken means I, I you, you,
you took me somewhere.
I just start thinking of chainsaw massacre
when that fucking guy just grabbed
that woman a yanked her in,
slammed the door.
Hey. Taken. Almost on. Slightly
more polite though. No,
no. Well I guess what the next
word is taken to the movies. Right,
exactly.
Taken into the fucking, I been taken
to the movies by some sharks. Oh yeah,
I was going to say, you know, it
seems a, you know what I liked?
It's this fair play on this album.
Yeah.
As far as a, there was a few where it
was the other person. That was a few.
That was you. All right,
so that's a a, that's a,
that's an important milestone
in your life when you the,
at least for me it was when I was
able to be like, all right, you know,
I was going through that dude
chicks if fucking Psychos, you know,
I did that till I was about 35 and I
was just like, all right Phil, you know,
at what point are you going to fucking is,
it may be you maybe who you're picking
maybe what you're bringing to the table.
And then once I was able to do that,
I am finally ended up meeting Nia.
I,
that's kind of why I called the album
love remains because love remains as in
the remnants of love.
Like the aftermath of,
of a love gone bad or love remains.
I like love still exists.
Oh it's true. It is.
Oh I thought you went,
there was still pieces of other
relationships in you. It's, it's both.
It's like the remnants and then
love still, you know, continues.
There's always love.
Well this is theory among my guy friends
that women are able to cry it out cause
you're allowed to cry,
that you're able to get passionate
and then it's just like fucking gone.
Where guys like hang on to shit.
I mean I was reading
this book on Bob Cousy,
he's one of the Great Celtics
and Bill Russell, right.
And one of the greatest players
of all time. And Bob Cousy,
his wife passed away and he still has a
picture on the wall and he still talks
to, well I guess they didn't break up.
So maybe it was that. But like, you know,
I used to always joke with my wife going,
you know, if I died within three weeks,
you'd have all my clothes
down at goodwill. Hey,
keep me a DVD in a back of a fucking
closet. Where's she's like, no,
I would never do that. But I just
feel like women are better at, uh,
either e how you're wired. And then
I also think it's more, it's, uh,
one of the great emotions crying when
the great healing emotions is not
acceptable for guys and
you just shut it off.
So not only do you not get to heal,
you actually make yourself,
I think worse by fucking, uh, holding
it in. It's bad enough. You know,
I dunno, it's, it's a really
a weird thing. So, uh, that's
a, that's actually, I don't,
I don't know what the word is, but to hear
you say that, that, that you actually,
uh,
some of it stays in there.
I don't know what that makes
me feel not as fucked up.
Well also like I feel like when when
you're in love or when you love someone
like it,
people often like projected outwards as
if it's the other person that's making
you in love.
Whereas like love is actually just
always in you and that that person is,
is maybe igniting it or oh,
was showing you that it's there,
but it is always there.
And knowing that keeps me centered.
Yeah, it's, it's, it's, that's
not something that you can,
it's hard to remember that, you know,
I would say I would say, I don't know,
I'm actually literally getting
uncomfortable just even talking about it.
It helps.
I was walled off for a long
fucking time and then I,
I had like this massive amount of love
in me and it would just come out in these
weird ways like about like,
like animals being abused or
any sort of person being hurt.
I could feel it,
but like if I was just with somebody
and we're going to the movies,
like I didn't even know
what the fuck to do.
I just be sitting there like this
fucking robot. Like, did you enjoy that?
Now we're getting on the subway and it was
just like, and I was meeting people, I,
I just, Oh, I know you,
I, I'm embarrassed at the,
where the kind of person I was back in
the day as far as like trying to get
through stuff like that.
But how did you break through that?
I met somebody I couldn't break up with.
I would in my head fantasize during tough
times of breaking up with my now wife
and in my head we were living
in this place where there was,
there was the first
place was an elevating,
they'll place had stairs and when
she was going to get on the elevator,
even in the fantasy of being single
again before the door closed,
I would run out and go get her.
Or when she would walk down the stairs
at Iri and I come back in like I couldn't
eat.
I couldn't even.
And for years I did that
and it never dawned on me.
Like I've always been so fucking like,
not in touched with like, hey bill,
you know, this is the 20,000 fucking
signal. Like I used to ride around.
I had a paper back in the day and I used
to ride around in the morning and I had
memorized comedy routines of my favorite
comedians and I would fantasize that I
was doing them in front of the school
and it didn't dawn on me at that point.
They hit bill. Maybe you want to be
a comedian. It didn't, it was just,
I had no connection to it
whatsoever. Huh. It was just me.
I think at that point it was all about,
you know,
getting people to like me so I wouldn't
get the shit kicked out of me or I
wouldn't have to deal with some, you
know, you know, was, you know, it was,
it was before all this carrying on social
media is just like the whole everyday
at school.
It's just like,
am I going to get it today or is or how
can I get it off of me and get it onto
the next weakest kid who was
a very weird, um, I dunno,
some of it was good but a lot
of it wasn't a necessarily,
probably the way kids should grow up
now we're probably like overly doing it.
I Dunno.
You don't make me feel good when you
came when I came into your place here and
you were like, oh there's my phone,
I lose my phone all the time.
Oh my gosh.
You have massive ADHD.
I also unfortunately get phone anxiety,
which I hate. Like oh you
don't have it right? Yeah.
If I don't have it I start to like
feel like oh shit, where's the phone?
Or like if I don't look at
it for, for, for too long,
I start to feel that and so I have to
work really hard at like disciplining
myself so that I can like keep it away
from me for a certain amount of hours to
be like creative and productive.
Cause it's just PR.
Like I feel so sorry for like for kids
that are like teenagers right now.
Like they just like so attached to their
phones and I see what it does to my
brain. Teenager I am.
That was brutal. Yeah.
Not like gives you the shortest
attention span it like everything's just
immediate.
And so I'm just so glad that like,
uh,
it kind of came a little bit later.
You realize we're like lab rats cause
we're like sort of the first wave of like,
well let's see what this does. The
people I actually saw, you know,
I went and I got gas today and I
saw this up to the Burrito or no,
well that's going to be later.
That's what,
this podcast will not be a full hour
whenever you're know what's hitting me,
what the fuck is on the microphones
that are here and dropping nuts.
Piece of Fuzz. Um, so I
went up to that still there.
See this is the podcast. People
are used to good though. Um,
so I pulled up to get,
I was getting pumping gas and you know,
this la couple pulls up
la meaning beautiful.
I'm not judging them like
they're assholes. They're
fucking beautiful. Right?
So they pull up and the guy
gets out to pump the ghost.
The woman's driving the second
she barely prost park, you know,
the immediately the phone and was just
sitting there and I was watching her and
I was just like, that's
me. That is literally me.
I do that when I'm driving like a lot.
I know. Fucking terrible. It's, yeah,
I called a friend up one time,
this is maybe about three months ago.
I was trying to do like an intense
period of writing and I said, hey,
could you just cause I'm,
you know, it takes like,
I think apparently 28 days to break a
habit. I said, can you come over for,
you know, 28 days
apparently, I think, can you,
can I give you my phone and then just go
away and then I'll meet you back here?
And I did that for a few days and actually
like helped me like reprogram myself.
Oh yeah, yeah. And like once
you do that, then it's like, ah,
you feel like you can finally relax.
It's weird.
This is something that I learned going
overseas and I can't get texts from
anybody. This is what happens if you
don't text anybody. Nobody texted you.
Like I would come back thinking,
oh my God,
I haven't checked my
text messages in 10 days.
I'm going to have 5 million fucking texts.
And I had like maybe six,
seven. Yeah. I don't, what am I a loser?
Nobody. Like if I don't text people,
you're like, no, I come back to a zillion
of them now. I feel like an asshole. No,
I came back and it's just like you, uh,
it's, it's like, you know, like once,
do you want something in
your life not to happen
and you don't realize how much of it
you're creating? Yeah. Okay. Well,
so much of the phone shit,
I realize I am creating all of the texting
that I'm doing. Like, I'm in traffic.
Traffic sucks. I just start calling
people, right? I'm just like, hey man,
what's going on?
I'm stuck on the fuck.
I literally have a friend of mine that
we like we our friendship cause she's
married with kids and I'm married,
didn't have a kid.
It was just like our whole relationship.
I don't think I've seen her in a year
and a half hour relationship that we have
the deal,
the,
an unwritten deal is that we call each
other when we're stuck in traffic. Yeah.
And the big joke is,
hey, I'm on the one 35,
hey I'm on the one on one or the other
person picks up. All right, where are you?
How long a drive do you have?
And it's just like you're sort of almost
like a suicide hotline talking them to
get home.
I do like all of my phone
calls in the car to or um,
really, really late at night. Like
while I'm getting ready for bed, like,
like my friends in Australia just know
that I'm going to call it like 3:00 AM my
time. Like facetiming them while
I'm like brushing my teeth and shit.
And now it's like a ritual. Like, oh,
are you ready for teeth brushing
time and what is it like
seven the next day? They're right. A seven
at night. 14 year olds or even slightly.
Yeah, something like that. Yeah, around,
around about then it's great that guy,
I always call Australia at that time
when I'm getting ready for bed time.
What was the last time you heard
some music that that made you? Uh,
like whenever I listened
to like amazing music,
I always fantasize that it's me doing
it. Oh yeah, yeah, I do that. No,
and all the way through the song. If the
drums are awesome, I'm playing drums,
someone singing great,
then all of a sudden I'm doing that.
I'm very self involved.
One was the last time you as a musician
listened to something and you were just
like, ah, fuck. I wish that was me.
Does that happen? I don't
know. It doesn't happen.
But strike too with the texting
and now fantasy, the fantasizing.
I don't do that.
But I listened and admire a lot of people.
Who'd you to listen to it coming up?
I didn't want to ask you
any of these questions.
I know you've been asked this fuck,
I listen to miles Davis and then
of course there was the bgs,
jazz disco.
I just,
you know what I'm really obsessed
with is his Indian classical music.
Do you remember that time?
We were like driving back from one of
your shows and I played you some Indian
Indian classical music. I've played
you. I remember we were meeting,
me and Josh were singing some
Song Bob Dylan Song to you,
which you really didn't like
or you are making fun of.
But Bob Dylan is like one of my favorites
of all time. I love Bob doing okay.
But like you were like joking around
my changing the lyrics and stuff.
I was just being an asshole.
I with media,
if we do that all the time that you made
me laugh so much and then I played you
in Indian classical piece,
but maybe you don't remember that.
But what I remember you played
me that Blues Song. Yeah.
That was blind Willie Johnson. Yes.
Also one of my faves. Yes. Okay. Yeah,
that I remember. Yeah. I love old
blues. Like it's so raw and real. Right.
And I also like, like as if you,
you'll notice like on my album,
like I switch in and out of
like time signatures a lot and,
but it doesn't sound like I'm
switching time secrets. She has.
At least that's what I do tell
them the things that I, yeah,
I didn't really notice it, but that's
what I'm saying. Like, because I kind of,
I let the music,
um,
like the melody or the story guide the
time as opposed to like the other way
around.
Like sometimes people will write the
music first and then that lay the melody
and stuff on top. Oh, I saw
an interview with somebody,
so they'd said every time
I come home with a riff,
it's in a weird time signature
and then the drummer fixes it.
And I remember thinking like,
this should've fucking kept
it. Right. Getting that,
yeah, but like fuck do I know. But
I'm just saying that's, that's what I,
that's what I would think. Yeah. Like
I was joking around like with, uh,
with Bob Weir because like basically he,
he played with Lightening Hopkins.
Bob, we're here shooting
grateful dead right now.
He played with Lightening Hopkins is
one of my favorite like blues players.
And um, and when he started,
like those guys were all
like in their forties, right?
Yeah.
And lose guys on me.
And he was joking around like saying that
like lightening played like the 12 and
a half bar blues because you know,
if he has to add a beat
to finish the story,
he's telling me he's going to add a beat.
Like it's not about like just
this rigid thing and like I was,
I've been composing like that too.
Like if the melody wants to go on
a few beats longer or you know,
then make it a buyer or seven like,
and it will feel natural
if it goes with the melody.
But if you try to fit a melody over the
top of the time signature than sometimes
it can feel a little bit more, um,
choppy. Yeah, I get that. Yeah,
because then it's the
cause to the lay person.
They're not listening what time it's in.
No,
they're just following
the melody and the story.
And it's the same with like
all that old folk music too.
Like you listen to some of the old folk
like you hear like bars of five and
seven cause it just adding
beats to like finish the phrase.
I know I never noticed and that's
sometimes why like you know,
there won't be drums on it.
Like if there was drums it,
it probably would sound kind of strange,
but it's just like an
acoustic guitar and a voice.
Like that song I played for you,
that Bob Dylan Song it's called,
it's all right mom.
And any bleeding,
like there's some bars have
like five and shit in that.
He just like add some
beets and as you were,
you wouldn't know it if you counted it.
It's odd because he's just trying to fit
the lyric in. Ah, yeah. It's, it's genius.
I love it. How, how, oh,
you're so talented in that
area. Like when, when did,
when did you notice that shit?
Like I would just be like,
I'm just psyched if I listen to a song,
I know all the words. I wouldn't be like,
oh that was just in seven
when I first moved to America
and I was playing guitar.
I, and I was like starting to play like
six hours a day and I like gave myself a
tendonitis and I had to stop playing
for a minute. And then I started like,
like messing around like with drums with
one hand or like base with one hand.
And people started coming up to me being
like, yeah, mini Vinny, Vinny, Vinny.
And I'm like, what the fuck is mini
Vinney you know, of any color Uda. Uh,
okay. So I went and like
listened to Vinnie Khalida,
this is me at I guess like 17 now and uh,
and everyone was passing around tapes of,
of Vinny color you'd like or like
the stuff with charisma and um,
just a bunch of other stuff.
And uh,
and actually Vinnie was then one
of the first people I met when,
when I moved to America because he came
to my school and I'd been playing for
two and a half months at the
time. And like one of the, the,
these drum clinicians was
friends with him. Wait a minute,
you don't even play in two and a half
months if somebody told you to move to no
base space. Cause I'd been playing
guitar for a couple of years. Yeah. Yeah.
And what was that like? And he was like,
oh we should play some time. I said yeah.
And I was so shy like, because I listened
to all this stuff and obviously his,
he's one of the best in the world and I
was, but I kept it in my head. I'm like,
okay, okay. But then I moved
to New York and I was like,
I just want to be a jazz musician.
I want to like play in clubs
like five times a night.
And like Charlie Parker and
monk and all the guys did.
And I did that for a few years
and then that's when like I,
I played with the Allman brothers and
like made a record and played with the
almond brothers. That was my first Gig
when I was a teenager. Jesus. Yeah. Yeah.
Like that's where it all started.
And then I came back to La
and I like played Vinnie,
this stuff with the Allman brothers
and my, um, my solo project. And, uh,
and then the weeks later he got the
call from Jeff Beck that like, Oh,
hit Jeff Beck's management that they
needed a bass player. And then he,
he told them about me and then they called
me and they asked me to send in tapes,
I sending the tapes and the next thing
I knew I was flying to England to
audition for Jeff. So, and then everything
like, you know, prince and her whole, you,
um, I think I was 21 when I started
playing with Jeff. Yeah, he's as correct.
That's the first time I saw
you live at Ronnie Scott's,
which I've still never been in there the
couple of times I've gone to London I
received, it's always like
packed. I'm like, Oh fuck,
I want to go in there and just,
yeah,
I have a drink and actually listen to
some music for like two sites the first
time I saw you. So were you nervous when
you went into the audition? Um, well,
I was food poisoned.
I just got enough a plane,
like where me and Vinnie went to the
airport and I ate some barbecue chicken
pizza and I got on the plane and Vinny
is a grieving on about politics because
he's obsessed with politics and I'm like,
hey Vinny, I'm feeling kind of sick.
And uh, he's like, yeah, yeah. Um, so
then this happened and that he, you know,
I mean he kind of reminds me of you and
you're writing me and him. He was from,
uh, he's from like Pennsylvania. Oh, is
he? Yeah. Oh No. Yeah, Pittsburgh. Oh,
he's from Pittsburgh. Pittsburgh
guy. Oh, he went to Berkeley.
That's why I knew there was some sort
of Massachusetts from there. Yeah.
But anyway,
he's going on about politics.
And then meanwhile I just like throw
up in a bag and I'm like, there it is.
He's like that. What is, I'm
like, I'll see you in 10.
And I was so sick that like,
then I had to let get rushed
to the hospital and we
landed and like be on a drip.
And then the next day
I auditioned for Jeff.
And so I was feeling really weird but um,
talk about the worst fucking place
to get food poisoning. Oh my God.
But the audition went well because at
that point I was so like woozy that I was
just like, okay, let's
get through this. Yeah.
And then that was the point where like
Jeff pointed to me and said Solo on,
cause we've ended as lovers and like
he ended up loving that so much that he
like kept it in the set and that's how
he was like featuring me every night.
Oh Wow.
Like
a cool of him totally sharing who he
is and all of that stuff too to like,
uh, I love, um, when
people do stuff like that,
there's a lot of comedians that I,
you know, um, that I'm a fan of.
But what really makes me,
you know,
over the top is when I see them
like encouraging and helping out,
you know, pick comics that are coming up.
Cause I, I hate that fucking thing of, uh,
you know, that behavior people
will get to a certain level,
then they start treating, you know, I
don't know, I'm here and you're there.
It's all stupid. It's just like, it's,
you know, you're great like that.
Like the way that you kind of mentor
younger comedians by, I mean I,
I try not to be in it.
I mean I remember most people were nice,
but I definitely remember who the people
who weren't necessarily the names,
but I just remember how that may be feel.
So it's,
it's sort of the same thing too,
um,
with being like a parent and stuff.
I remember the good days at
school and I remember the bad day,
so I'm about how much fun it was
playing with the other kids at school.
And then I also remember
how bad it was if, you know,
you wore the wrong shirt
or whatever and it's just,
it was just your day to take the
pounding and just like how you could just
literally beginning that was
literally like your world.
And that's something that I'm hoping
I'm going to be able to remember. Um,
which I think I will as, as Mike, my
kids going through school as far as, uh,
knowing that though, I
mean those days, I mean,
who the hell knows with all the fucking
cameras out there, I don't even get it.
If anything, my buddy was just telling
me, you know, some key told this story.
There was some kid everybody
picked on that day.
And then the kids who picked on him,
they found out who all of them were
and they had to go see the fucking
psychologists and shit. And I was really
thinking about that. It's just like, wow,
man. Like nobody, like there
was none of that at all.
Like the guidance counselor was just some
Weirdo down the hall and he would just,
he just would talk to,
he would only really talk to kids who
had no hope of going to college. Right.
And he'd just be down. They're like,
well, hey man, you know, like maybe a,
you get into construction, you know. I
mean, I never even talked to him. I just,
I don't know what he talked to them
about maybe their home lives and shit.
Maybe it was like a therapy thing,
but like, only the fucked up kids,
God guidance. Right. Always
weird. Everybody else was
just like, all right, you're,
you're following the cattle right
over the fucking cliff. Go to school,
two years of language, get
into college, pick a major,
decide what the fuck you want
to do at 18. And then it, yeah,
it was one of those things.
And um,
I remember when I was 15,
um,
there was like this like woman that came
to the school that was supposedly like
a career counselor and she came up with
this huge book that looked like yellow
pages or something, right? And everyone
had to have an appointment and,
and you'd go in and she'd be like,
okay, so now what do you want to do?
And like someone to be like,
I want to be a dock guy,
open up the book. And she'd looked under
doctor. And so I walked in, she's like,
so what do you want to do? I'm like, that
wouldn't be a musician. And she's like,
sorry, there's no musician here.
What else would you like to do?
I just walked out. Oh, you walked
out. What did she do? I don't know.
That was it. I would have been, yeah, I
want to have like an epiphany being like,
wow,
I made,
how many of these fucking kids wanted
to do something that's not in this book?
Right? Yeah. But then
you have to look at her.
It's just like there's no way
that was her dream in life.
To have a yellow book and talk to people
half your age. What do you want to do?
I want to be a zookeeper. All right,
let's get to disease. All right.
Do you have any khaki shorts?
So you literally have somebody didn't
follow a dream talking you out of yours
and you had the strength to fucking
walk away from that. That's very,
very commendable. So
that's the, those are the
moments in life there to haunt me that
I think back into my life when somebody
said something negative
and thank God, you know, I,
I didn't latch onto a totally and
somebody else like, cause I have like,
I have like this like three Mike
moments in my life, you know,
like climbing up a fucking cliff that if
I went to go this way I would have fell
back down and, and just the luck of it
sometimes when I think of it like, God,
what if I didn't meet this person?
You know, and why reading my,
I worked with this guy in a warehouse and
I finally found somebody that was into
comedy the way I was and he
understood that you could become it.
You know what I mean? Like
he was going like, dude,
these guys on TV and not funny man,
one of these days I'm going to take a
shot of Jack Daniels and just go on stage
and do it. And all of a sudden
like, cause it just, you know,
it was on TV that was
like a million miles away.
There was no fucking internet or anything.
And uh,
we had nobody had video cameras, nothing.
So it just seemed impossible to me.
It was so impossible. It didn't
even seem impossible. Didn't even,
I didn't even enter my brain and be like,
fucking going to the moon and all of
a sudden he was just next to me going,
I'm going to fucking do it. And I
was just thinking like, well shit,
if he can try it, I'm
going to try it. So, uh,
if I don't run into him and if he doesn't
have the balls to say I'm going to try
it,
then I'm just fucking hanging out with
other knuckleheads like me drinking,
then then all of a sudden I'm 30 and
where the fuck am I? You know? So, yeah.
Do you believe like in like a destiny,
like do you believe that if
that wouldn't have happened,
someone else would have
happened or do you believe
like, I don't believe in destiny
because of tragedy, right?
I don't think that anybody's
destiny is there. The, Hey,
thank God you're not this person. I
just think you get lucky. You get lucky.
It's like a half court shot,
I would say in a lot of ways.
Well maybe it's not that it's,
it's don't you think it's like
partly luck and partly manifestation.
Like if you really want something,
you're going to create the
path forward and it can,
and it can go in many directions.
Yeah. But I also feel like,
and there's also tragedy,
which is unavoidable and, um,
unpredictable, the tragedy of where
you're born, right? What you'll look like,
what race you are,
we're part of the world you're in.
Like how lucky I was to be a white guy
born in USA, you know what I mean? And it,
and how lucky I was to be born
outside of Boston had this crazy,
insane seeing this like a lot of like,
you know, hurdles that were like
this big. And even then, even then,
because of all the bullshit,
uh,
that even just,
even if you get that much of a head start,
all of this other shit that can
emotionally fuck you up can,
um, you know, I mean, I think
by the time I was like nine, uh,
I, I, I had already just sort
of like, I had that. Yeah,
I don't give a fuck. I don't
give a fuck. I don't, yeah,
I just didn't give a shit like, but,
and, but I did, you know what I mean?
And then that's all your work to get
back to that person who did care and did
want stuff. You just, as a defense
mechanism, you just like, yeah,
I don't give a fuck. Oh, really?
Is that going to happen? No.
And then when that's supposed to,
what make me cry. Fuck you. Like I,
I became that person, which is, uh, it's,
it works is far as to
get through that shit.
But as far as getting anything
you fucking want in life,
we have to be open and warm and
attract stuff to you that you want.
And you're over there with you. Oh yeah.
I don't give a fuck. Fuck you really,
400 pounds on my chest. Put 500. I don't
give a fuck doing that dumb guy. Shit.
Um, yeah, there's like, yeah,
it's just, yeah, that's the,
that's the thing when you're sitting
there and it fucking Boston garden going,
how to fuck if I didn't meet this guy,
if that guy didn't say that,
if I went out that night and went
with those people and did that,
he just think of all of that fucking what
if shit and this somebody who went out
that night and went with those people and
then they fucking sitting in a cubicle
or a jail cell or in a fucking
loveless marriage or something.
And then just like,
why the F that that's somebody's
destiny to be in a loveless marriage.
It's like I just, I don't, um, yeah, and
commas and other one I don't buy into,
I think calmer works if you, if you,
if you believe in it, but what do you,
how do you define Karma? That
basically, if you're a good person,
good things happen to you.
But if you're a bad person,
that's not what comment is though.
But in my world it is.
But comment like if you like comma
simply means cause and effect.
So, okay, well if you do good things
then no, it's not a bad, good or bad.
It's just you feel like I'm
in school again. No, no, no,
but you do it. You do it.
Can you just give me the F and
I'll go to summer school? This f
not like you, you, you, you do an
action and it causes a result. Right?
It's as simple as that.
That's all Karma means.
That's like being a satanist.
People thinks that you believe in the
devil and people were just like, ah,
satanism or whatever. They don't even
believe in a heaven or hell or devil.
It's just they just living for
themselves and everybody said, oh,
they render the devil.
So I always thought Karma was like,
if you're a fucking nurse or
the bed should help us here.
And then in my business,
I'd watch these fucking people stealing
and doing all this shit and just look at
them and be like, well,
you know, good. You know,
nothing's bad's happened to them
and I've done a bunch of bad shit.
And like overall my life
is good. But I, you know,
I've heard a lot of people and shit
so and so what is it that it just,
it just simply means that you do
an action and it creates a result.
So all these people are using
that term incorrectly. Yes.
I just put it in a script incorrectly.
Well,
episode eight F F is for family.
it's correct in that because like a lot
of people think that that's what it,
what it is. But like when you go
to the root of what comment is,
it just simply means like you do an
action and it's cause and effect.
I saw somebody, uh, somebody
I follow on Instagram,
they had a picture of a boomerang
and it said Karma on it.
So that's actually wrong.
Oh my God,
I wish I knew the real definition than I
could have been that pompous ass on the
Internet feeding like
actually none of you guys.
That's like one time I saw this guy
talking about how he didn't have white
privilege and his idea that he didn't
have white privileges because he wasn't
born rich and he had to work
for the things that he had.
So his idea is that white privileges
means you're born on a yacht and all of
this fucking shit. It's like,
no, that's not what that means.
That means that no point where you with
because of your seat and just get pulled
over for being white, get the shit
kicked out of you, you know, and all,
all of these other things that would
have happened to you. You just,
you basically because you had to work for
things. You feel you're not privileged.
So literally his
definition was privileged.
It was,
I can't give you any more details of it,
I'll tell you afterwards because it's,
I mean, how do you deal with like, um,
Internet trolley type people?
Like,
have you ever struggled with that or
wanted to interact with people like that?
Early on I did, but now I just, it
has nothing to do with me. Yeah. Yeah.
It has nothing to do.
The amount of shit that I hate that
really just has to do with me and my day
that I do. And other people do that
too. I don't think, um, you know,
any different than they
are. But like, um, yeah,
I don't give a fuck.
I don't even have to be a specific thing
that I did and I thought it was bad too.
And then everybody said you shouldn't have
done that, blah, blah, blah, blah. Like,
I dunno. I Dunno what I, but if it's
just like a, you know, you know,
so much of whatever you post
isn't about what you posted.
It's about what's in the background so
you to be, so you could do some gravy.
Oh my God,
that's fucking great.
But what's up with that fucking picture
on the wall? Yeah. Laughing my ass off.
Like that's like what I
learned after a while.
It's like that's their moment
right on the thread, right?
Like I'm going to be the guy that
notices the thing that starts and then
everybody's talking about
what I wanted to talk about.
And then it's this weird thing
where you feel good, but like I, I,
I do the same thing if I send out a
tweet and it gets a bunch of retweets and
likes, I'm like, all right,
people thought that was funny.
So I'm just on the other end of it.
So I just learned like I can't get upset
that somebody is noticing something in
this and now they're doing their little
show. Like who the fuck am I? It's like,
you don't want someone to do that.
Don't post something on there.
And I just look at like,
listen,
you don't want people saying
a bunch of bad shit about,
you don't put your face on the Internet.
It's like you're literally asking for it.
You're sticking your chin out and they're
winding up and punching you and then
you're acting like a victim. It's
like, well you fucking don't post shit.
Just sit there like this or you know,
post it.
Take a few shots and uh,
continue on.
I guess as a musician like I'm a
little firstly like as an instrumental
musician,
there's nothing anybody can
say about like what I'm saying,
I'm not expressing an opinion,
I'm just playing notes. Right.
But then now I've just put out an album
of songs with lyrics and there's only
been out there for right know.
What I'm saying is that in
the context of the song,
and I'm very much expressing like stories
that are personal but like to go out
there as a comedian and like
express really strong opinions.
Like I can't imagine like the difference
in like the kind of feedback that you
get.
And
I guess I'm curious what people do is
you have to understand that what they do
is they don't,
like I've always said,
he's like you can do 80 jokes in a row
and someone will sit there laughing and
enjoying your set and then the 81st
one has to do something about them.
If it's a fat joke in their fat,
right.
If it's about women and they are a woman
or it's about this state and there from
there and then all of a sudden, yeah,
it's funny you say that, then they go,
that statement you made about fucking
Arkansas and it's just like, no,
no, no. They were all so they all,
all jokes except for the one. Right.
You know what I mean? So this, this, this,
that, um, you know, there's just that,
that thing,
I just,
I don't pay it any mind and um,
yeah,
yeah. If there was ever any sort of
big dust up about something, I said,
if I actually looked at it and thought
I said something wrong, I'd be like,
all right, well maybe I'll phrase
it a different way. But like, I,
I do think it's absolutely ridiculous
that people get offended about a joke that
was told at a show that they weren't at
and how has it taken so out of context
and no, you want it to show. Yeah.
And you chose to click that thing
and the tears. And another thing too,
if the comedian didn't film it and posted,
yeah.
If just some fucking asshole in the
crowd, they'd get mad at them. Yeah.
And it's just like,
well,
what the fuck are you doing if you're
this easily offended about standup comedy,
what are you doing watching,
watching standup comedy?
The whole thing is, so like,
I just saw,
I think it was in Australia,
like the first mammal went extinct due
to human global warming and barely,
barely a word about it. But like all
of this shit, uh, you know, fucking,
you know, it's more difficult to
be a comedian if you're a woman.
A fucking me too.
Uh,
it's all about us and what we're going
through and Llama, Llama, blonde,
all of this shit.
And just meanwhile,
all of that pales in
comparison to, you know, if,
if this fucking places in here,
you're not going to have to
worry about any of that. Right.
That's why I think that the cell
phones a super destructive, like,
because they are making everything
about me, me, me, look what I'm doing,
look like where I am, look
what I'm eating. And so, and,
and were on it constantly. And it's
like, well, the Jesse Kristala you fall.
Did you see his thing that he did
the, the unfollowing? No. Oh my God.
It's one of my favorite things ever.
He's talking about,
it's just making fun of Instagram models.
Uh,
I mean I can do it.
I don't feel like I'm doing
this joke because he put it
out there. He goes, look,
he goes, if you're on Instagram,
it goes in your posts and stuff.
You've just taken a picture of your
booty and your titties. He goes,
make no mistake.
You Hook in.
And he just starts calling them
hookers and then, you know,
and then he just starts
really like something.
Some of these people I didn't even know
fucking exist that I guess this thing
that pretty girl still with a bite into
a sandwich and they kind of look up like
that saying like, yeah, that I'm going to
start this thing called the unfollowing.
And what I love about it is,
first of all I'm seeing him turning
the corner as a comedian because he was
always just, he just had that this guy is
a club like a fucking closer, you know,
and now he's getting,
he's like fine in his like like this razor
because he was always kind of fun and
energetic and stuff and,
but now it's, it's like,
it's like it's becoming this, you seeing
this force going in this direction.
Like I was fucking cry and laugh for
like I'm not afraid to do things along
those lines make me laugh and it's just
really fucking was making me laugh.
But the funniest thing about that is that
would really bother somebody like that
where like cause cause they're living,
not that I would want to hurt those
people cause it's very easy to hate
beautiful people. You know
what I mean? It's just, it's,
they're very hateable as you're staring
at them because you hate yourself.
Like why am I this fucking of just with
like this beauty in all of this stuff.
Like, like look at that. You've got like,
I got to fucking do nine hours of fucking
specials to get half as many followers
as you do because you were a fucking
half shirt, you know? So I just,
there was just something
funny to just finally see a,
a movement to make their numbers go down.
I don't know.
The more I'm saying this out loud,
I'm actually realizing that it's kind
of says more about me than about those
people that take those pictures. But I
don't know. I just thought it was at,
that shit is funny. So I'm actually
watching that girl at the gas station.
I'm going to try to take, uh, like this
morning I didn't have my phone, you know,
when I spent the entire,
like two and a half hours I have
with my daughter this morning,
chased her around, we play with
the puzzles, I read the books. Uh,
what else did we do?
Was teaching how to play catch and uh,
I think she's going to throw at the
left hand, which would be really cool,
although she's really big.
But the Darryl Dawkins over the
top sort of two handed slam.
I know you're not going to
know that reference he played
for the 76 years before
you were born.
Um,
so I'm trying to get her not to,
uh,
be into stuff like that.
But the weird thing is,
is because they're so hyper with their
energy and all you want to do is just
hold them and hug them.
The best way to do that is if you put
on their favorite cartoon and then they
stay just totally snuggle up next to you,
but then there's no interaction other
than the physical because then you just
literally say like, Hey, hey, hey,
hey, give me a kiss. Give me kiss.
And they'll go like, we'll just sort of
lean into you and not even look at you.
Just give you the chicken. They just
sorta lasered into that. And I'm like, uh,
I dunno. I Dunno. I watched a lot of TV.
I did all right in life.
The fuck are you going to do
so and allowed to watch TV and,
and look at you look fucking talented.
You are. And I'm up there just screaming,
yelling like a lunatic. Um, where can
people get this album? Um, anyway. Yeah,
listen to music. Um, can they
download it on iTunes? Yeah. Spotify.
I don't think it's true to things going
to be said on this podcast than that.
Yeah,
I can't because my fucking computers
filled up and I forget my password all the
time.
Well I just want to uh,
congratulate you because I know you worked
so hard on this. It just assembling,
abandon,
all of that type of stuff.
Like there's so much more work
to this where I just like,
I need an order to new hour.
I don't have to find a Mike
stand guy and all of this shit.
I just have to go out and
just go do it. But um, uh,
whatever you did the three songs that
I listened to, I mean it is just,
it's on such a high level
creativity and everything.
Um, I'm, I'm really happy for you and uh,
everybody watching listening cause there
was going to be some clips of this on
video. Please download and it is
called love Romaine. Love remains.
All right. Thank you for coming
on. I was going to ask you, um,
how do you stop doing ums and uhs
and you knows and shit like that?
How do I, yeah. No, I don't, I do
it all the time. All the time. Why?
Because I get something that will
cause you do it. I do it so much. Oh,
I do it to how you do and you're in care.
Not,
I didn't know if I don't give
a fuck. He, you listen to a
Keith Richards Jagger, people can't
understand him. He doesn't give a shit.
But like what about when
you're doing material?
I guess because you've written the
material that's going to be less of that
because you know what you're about to say,
as opposed to if you're
just doing a podcast.
If I was to actually try to
work on something like that,
then I would be up here,
which is not where I want to
write. Yeah. I want to be,
it's just calming down the rain spout
and out my fucking considered technique
for a comedian to like at some
point work on that. Yes, it would.
Whereas like with like, um,
I learned, I started, uh,
taken from lessons from Dee de
village. Um, how many, like,
how much,
you know,
of the way I was playing was getting in
the way of me getting to where I wanted
to be with whatever,
because my, my technique,
I was like sitting like this and I was
grabbing the sticks like that was getting
blisters and,
and uh,
like I wasn't making gravity at anything
that had to do with physics work for
me.
So I was literally fighting the drum
kit and then he taught me all of this
stuff. I haven't seen him in a couple of
months and I'm going back to my bad old
habits. But, um, there is that thing,
I think that like a while we'll say
with like a musician, it's like,
I don't want to learn how to read,
man. I just want to, you know,
I just want to fucking be this, you
know, free fucking thing. Right.
And just there is merit in that because
you do have those people who only can
play if there's sheet
music in front of him.
But if you can somehow marry both of those
where you actually have technique but
you can still play from
here and not be up there.
I think that that's like the promise
land and I always kind of felt is a
comedian,
if you could somehow combine Richard Pryor
that specially did live in concert on
long beach, if you could
combine that with George Carlin,
um, where his stuff was
just like, I feel like he,
he knew every fucking word that he
was going to say and it was like,
yes, like pop up, up, up, up, up, up.
The whole time where prior, you know,
on that special came walking out,
it was like a hell Gig.
There was people walking around and
shit and he just started making fun of
people. And I think the way
he was wired that helped him,
that helped him better than if everyone
was just sitting there staring at him
like, okay, begin your,
your standup special.
I think that he came out and
sit your ass down, you know,
sit your fucking ugliest.
I what?
All that stuff that he was saying and
everyone was just walking around and he's
riffing and then he just
just got in a zone. And
what's amazing, you know,
is if he can to his own,
usually that lasts for like six minutes
because what happens up to six minutes
of that is you're like,
you start worrying going,
well what happens when this ends
and I have to go into my act,
I'm going to be fucked.
And you,
you can't think that because it's
almost like when you haven't tried like
meditating. Yeah. So you know,
like when you start to feel like you're
floating and like leaving your body,
if you start thinking,
oh my God, this is great,
I'm leaving and then you'll
just go right back down.
So that's the same way with like,
like catching his own.
So like what I've learned a little,
I know about technique with like drums,
he should just practice
a little bit every day.
And then when it starts to become this
thing, you don't have to think about,
then all those skills you learned about
sort of leaving your body and just like,
just like, I mean your
body's there, but you're,
you're listening to what you're playing
that's making you do that next thing.
If you can exist,
you can go back there with all this
technique now he not going to get hurt,
you're not going to get tired and
eventually will. But like, um,
so I think what the comedian, if, if
I was to try to do that, like okay,
maybe I won't curse as much
or something like that.
Like I that would definitely
be a few steps backwards. Um,
by that man, maybe it would
help me. I don't know. I don't,
I honestly don't think,
I don't think. Okay.
Cause if I go up there
and I start doing that,
I said it's all about not being
here. Um, I mean I sell them.
I'm obviously thinking like, okay, I'm
going to, it's more like, okay, you
like I just walk out,
I just start talking and then this Joe
comes out and then I said this joke,
which made me think, oh yeah, I have
this joke and look at this fucking guy.
And then it just sorta just, oh now
we're over here and it just, you're just,
but do you have like a set list of jokes?
Like you want to do it in this
order or this order? Yeah,
but that is all out the fucking window.
The second I go up there and sell,
some nights it goes like that.
And then other nights I like,
I definitely have like sections,
but this,
some nights I just go out there and all
of a sudden I tell the last choke first
and I'm switching everything around. And
then the guy I talked with is this like,
you know, waiting to go
on stage going like, dude,
I didn't know what the fuck was going on.
Or You did,
you close a bit in the middle. I was
like, wait, he's only doing 35 minutes.
And then you went on, you did
like another, you know, whatever,
another 25 after that or something.
Um,
I have like the main setlist you know,
so that's the, you know, this is
the plan, the general fucking plan.
And then you go out there and shit
happens. You're in a weird mood.
Somebody says something is you look at
something in the back of the room that
makes you think of something and then
it go, it goes in that direction.
And um,
and I am a full believer of doing that
because then it doesn't become this grind
cause I used to,
I used to have,
I start with this and then that leads to
this and I have my segways in blah blah
blah blah blah. And it just became
like, you know, it's rigid. Yeah.
And then I would be on stage and my
mouth would be talking and I would find
myself thinking about going like,
well the second show if the
or lets me not close it out,
I could probably be home by,
and then I was just like, yeah.
And then I was just like,
wait,
I'm talking right now and people laughing
and I'm thinking about other shit,
what the fuck am I doing right
now? And um, I uh, it's weird.
I learned how to free myself up through
y more through watching musicians.
I've always equated it to music because
that's something that I sort of started
with.
So I always thought,
I remember talking to a long time ago
late great Patrice O'Neil and I said,
I was telling him, I was like, you know,
I always wished I could see someone cause
you couldn't gauge how good you were,
you know,
you can't see how good you are or how
might your improving because you're, you,
you know what I mean? You're
just in there. So I always
said I always wanted this.
I wish I could just have somebody sit
down and play guitar at the level of comic
that I am right now. It's
like, could they change chords?
Could they play without looking?
Could they solo?
Like where am I on that trajectory?
And it's one of the few times he didn't
give me any shit. He was just like, hi.
He goes,
that's actually interesting.
Then probably I reacted to that and
then he probably trashed me cause he
actually opened up for half a second.
So yeah. Fascinating. Fascinating.
Nuts and bolts of how
to tell Dick and shit.
Jokes will continue after these messages
from stamps.com and now for bill burrs
theme song. Oh, I get a
theme song out of this.
I would've thought it would've
been all like a Ukulele,
some sort of Irish Jig song. Did they
play Ukuleles out there? I don't know.
You have to play though.
Seriously? I have to play. Yeah.
Why do I have to play this?
I'm going to sing the theme song.
Well then you have to tell a joke.
I have to tell a joke or why
do I have to do my hobby? Oh,
do you know what I mean?
What am I playing Dan
to crack? I don't have any earplugs.
My years are fucking junk. Okay,
so play it really softly. Play it
really softly. Is that piano or 14
hey, can you just, can you just make sure
you do the retard, Huh? The retard. Yeah.
I learned. How were you going to retard
in the end? All right. You Ready? Yeah.
All right,
Bill.
Hell,
Bill Bell,
Bert.
That's all I get. No, no, no. I was
going to keep, oh, I didn't know. Okay.
You're the one that
why it sounded so simple.
I didn't pick you and keeps you
bill.
Bill.
Let me see. I think it needs more. What
if you went petted the Dah, Dah, Dah, Dah,
Dah, Dah, Dah, Dah. Yeah.
It'd be like,
welcome to build better Monday morning
podcast on a Thursday afternoon.
You're
welcome.
The bill Bez Monday morning podcast on a
Thursday afternoon. Oh, I gotta do that.
Yeah, I can. I can see. I can. It'd be
like, it's like, it's like triplets.
Yeah. Dah, Dah, Dah, Dah, Dah.
That's how your brain works.
My brain doesn't do the Kasia
only it'll do that, but not really
that bad. Bad, bad, bad. Yeah. See,
this is why I became a Canadian
Bell Bell
Bell Bell.
Welcome to bill burst
Monday morning podcast.
That's how it has to end.
That's the retard
[inaudible]
[inaudible] to
cod
and no knees
for
[inaudible]
shoes to
bitcoin.