Hey,
what's going on is bill burn?
It's time for the Monday
morning podcast for Monday,
December 19th,
2016 what's going on out?
Um,
oh Jesus Christ, my fucking
computer. Every five seconds.
Do you want to download this?
Do you want to do this now?
Do you want to do it in an hour? Should
I remind you later on tonight? Lay.
Give me some fucking space.
Jesus Christ.
He's fucking God. Damn. I Dunno man.
I'm not going to do this shit at all.
Just the level with which that sits
fucking, I guess because of technology,
I am able to do this. You know,
if it was back in the day,
I would not be able to do this. What is
this you, you ask, maybe you didn't ask.
Maybe I'm doing that thing where
I'm putting words in your mouth,
but if you did ask, you know,
but doing a podcast, you know,
I guess there's always a price
to pay and I think that the,
I think that that's one to grow on.
Maybe that's the lesson.
I swear to God, I want to start
a fucking church. I got to do it.
You guys been watching that?
Uh, that woman from a king
of Queens, she played, uh,
the beautiful wife, you know,
to the guy who drives the truck.
Did you know that? Well, how they've
always done comps. The honeymooners. Hey,
I fucking drive a bus and you know,
I'm,
I'm the wise crack can be
pretty wife. Well, Ralph,
maybe if you weren't a fucking eight,
Yay.
One of these days. Alice power, right?
The baby maker right now what they did
sound like that little fucking ice box in
the corner, you know? And then
you get into the 60s, right?
Sixties was like the Blue Ball era of,
uh,
of sitcoms.
You know what I mean?
Yet I dream of Jeannie and the fucking
guy would teach us, wouldn't banger.
I've talked about this shit before.
I remember watching as a kid.
It's like you've got, why don't you like
rubbing up against her or something?
You know? I didn't even know
what sex was. You know why?
Because it was no internet.
Now if there was internet back when I
was watching that show and I was like
seven or eight, uh, you know, I would
have been like, why does any, well, hey,
you're fucking prefers jockey style
over the fucking genie lamp. You know,
I would know all this extra shit.
That's what the fuck is wrong with
kids nowadays. It's like they just,
they take care of Alamo. I'm
going on. An old man ran,
they get on these fucking computers,
right? That parents are like me.
They don't know how to work them. They're
not even interested in them. You know,
we're in the fucking corner
making homemade apple side
of getting ready for the
holidays.
You know,
wearing a Christmas sweater that
we think actually looks good.
We're not wearing it.
Ironically. Well like got, this
is my Christmas sweater, Joe.
My fucking mother's sell this together
for me when I was in high school still
fits. You know, sweaters always
still fits because they stretch.
They like the sweatpants for just your
torso. You know that it takes a while.
Like, if you have a homemade sweater,
you know, one of those lobster fishermen,
ones that your mom would make,
you know,
and she just give it to you in the bag
that she bought the yarn and you know,
then one day you look at it and some
fucking moths started eating at it and you
just like,
is it the 18 hundreds really a
fucking caterpillar learn God,
it's fucking pilots license
and now as eating my sweater,
this is like so fucking 1826 how is
this happening right now for the love of
God? Mom, can you go to
the Ray on store? You know,
can you make me a fucking polyester?
Did his sweater.
How about why don't you do that?
Why can't you do that? I mean,
Jesus Christ is fucking children doing it.
Sweatshops around the world.
You got to come and meet with yard.
That's the problem with all the
mothers nowadays. You know what I mean?
That did them in the fucking yard.
They just won't let go of it.
I'm just fucking with you. What kind of
woman knows how to knit anymore? You know,
trying to find a woman that knows how to
knit is like trying to find a guy that
knows, still knows how to
hunt. You know what I mean?
And that even goes for
the fucking rednecks.
You're not doing it the way
you fucking, you're, you're,
you're way less fucking,
I don't know what four wheeler
fucking ancestors hunted,
almost talk myself into a
corner and I was like, God,
I don't want to do the Hacky,
you know,
saying your grandfather who first had
sex with the fucking relative, you know,
I didn't want to say that.
I don't, I didn't, I didn't
want to go down that road.
I don't even know if that's true,
but how the fuck did that start?
You know what I mean?
One fucking guy bangs his sister and
then all of a sudden everybody out there
that has a four wheeler, it's
still on it. You know what I mean?
Okay.
They can just take like,
they don't have Facebook.
You don't have to be lonely.
I like,
have they gotten more aggressive on that
farmers only where they've really just
started shitting on fucking city folk.
You know what I mean?
City folk just don't get it
and they still make
themselves look stupid.
City folk just don't get it.
They could go with global warming,
they could go with overpopulation,
they could go with quality of air,
quality of life space.
There's so many different
directions that hey,
you want to come back to my place and
you'd go there and it's like some fucking
city apartment. You know what I mean?
With like the kitchen is in the bedroom,
you know in the bed.
Folds down from the wall that you
could fucking attack them that way.
You know what I mean? Someone true
to try to come through their window.
May City folks just don't get it and
then they go to this spread, right?
Yeah.
Fucker.
Get your own parking space.
You're not driving around the block
like fucking nine hours trying to find
alternative side of the street. Fucking
parking. There's all these things.
Water levels rising.
You know,
I saw this one of these man in the street
things I've been watching that debt
channel Vice, you guys watched the vice
channel. It's a fucking great channel.
Reminds me a lot of ways,
a little bit of, um,
MTV during the early days were like,
they had a lot of funny promo commercials.
I don't know why more fucking networks
don't do that. Cause you know,
he usually fast forward, I turned the
channel when there's a commercial,
but they got like,
they have funny fucking commercials.
Like there's some talk show on there,
these two black dudes right now,
at least one black dude and one
guy sort of Puerto Rican maybe. Um,
maybe he's light skinned. I don't know.
I'm too white to understand. Right.
So that they do a talk show.
So they're hyping it and they're showing
like the New York City, you know,
skyline like they always do
before talk show. And it was a,
I'm going to fuck up the joke. It was
something like, no big guests, no band,
no audience, no white dudes.
And then they cut to the Promo.
Somebody comes out, you know, and I can't
know what the fuck was. I was watching,
I was like,
this is funny.
This looks like way back in the
day when I would see like Randy,
the redwoods agenda, taxi driver, you
know, they would have like funny promos.
I Dunno why they ever got away
from that. But, um, anyways,
Oh, speaking of that,
speaking of [inaudible],
um,
I saw a fucking front man this weekend
in a band that was fucking unbelievable,
right? I went down, um, uh,
the other day I did, uh,
the dark matter podcast, um,
which is Dave Navarro's podcast.
And um,
had a great time on that.
And afterwards they were like, yeah, hey,
Dave's doing his show down at the Roxy.
You want to come down Friday, Saturday
night, I guess. I mean, I'm on,
I'm in the dark here.
Literally, no pun intended.
I didn't know he did the
Christmas show every year. Um,
and it was like an all star lineup.
You don't know who the
fuck's coming out and um,
you just go to the show and then they
just start bringing people out. And, um,
so I went down there to go
see the show and I mean,
I knew it was going to be good.
Dude was fucking ridiculous,
the amount of people
that they had coming out,
which of course I'm going to fucking
forget the names and everything, but uh,
you just, you know, some will
come out, this guy could,
they sang Stuart's saying the
immigrant song and something else.
It fucking murdered it.
I never even heard of the guy fucking
murdered at the band was unbelievable.
The viral was killing it.
And then they,
then they brought out Macy
gray and then she sang, uh,
the fuck did she sing?
She sang the pretenders brass in pocket,
and then she's saying Radiohead
creep. I was just like, Jesus Christ,
what the fuck?
And then they brought out Cypress Hill
and Nolan was doing like their own style
of music to everybody would like switch
it up. So then they bring out this,
they get this fucking intro,
which no performer wants to get,
right? The guy goes to do the
intro and he just goes, uh, yeah,
Billy Morrison was there. Just
fucking everybody. Right goes, um,
by this next guy, you know, people
suggested him for this show. Uh,
you know, first few like
gay, you know, we don't know.
We don't know if he's right for this show.
And then we saw him and he
absolutely blew us away.
Our jaws were on the ground. I'm telling
you, this fucking guy is unbelievable,
Yada Yada. And I'm thinking, I was
in the crowd going, oh no, not that.
That intro was to fucking war. You can't
follow it. It's, I can stand up comedy.
This guy he's wanting to on
a bachelor in commerce today,
he reinvented the Mike Stand.
Eddie Murphy was still doing stand up.
He for this guy to write from it.
You know,
they start giving you a
fucking intro like that.
You're just in the back like guy,
hey, tone it down, tone it down.
Right to this guy came out and
totally fucking lived up to it.
It's, this guy's a rapper. I man,
I don't know shit about hip hop or
anything like this Guy Post Malone.
So the guy on stage for whatever reason
said this guy's responsible for Justin
Bieber's career.
Right?
Which I don't know why you would say
that in front of a bunch of fucking 40 to
50 something year old white people,
right.
So this dude comes walking out and
there's a few people bowing like Ba,
you know, like five people because
of the Justin Bieber thing.
I love people in their forties and 50s
who fucking talk about how bad Justin
Bieber's music is. It's like, really? It
doesn't speak to you. You fucking dope.
It's not for you. You know what I mean?
That's like getting mad at the fucking,
I don't insult the guy, but you
know what I mean? It's, it's for,
it's for younger people. You know
what I mean? I think hat like,
I don't understand people getting in
their forties and 50s and they just, they,
they don't understand that,
um,
somebody perspective as a 20 something
year old is not going to seem like the
same as theirs.
And we sitting there going like,
what the fuck is he talking about?
I'm like, that's bullshit. That's a,
that's a stupid blah, blah, blah,
blah, blah. And it's like, yeah, yeah.
That's what you did when you
were there that age and somebody,
he'll be in his forties and look
back at himself at 2123 going,
what the fuck was I thinking?
Right. Somehow like four
or five people don't get,
and they're literally Boeing,
you know Justin Bieber at a show.
Justin Bieber isn't that.
So this guy comes fucking walking out and
he just walks up to the microphone and
he goes, what's up la?
I'm drunk as fuck. Right?
So immediately the crowd just starts
cheering and he goes, I, you know,
I'm usually,
you know,
I'm a rapper and everybody I was
assuming in the crowd was like,
we're going like, yeah, I'm
completely unfamiliar with you.
I am a white guy pushing 50 I
have no idea who you are. Right?
So they start playing
rage against the machine,
killing in the name of, and I'm like
going, Oh God, uh, rappers gonna sink.
Do they got the auto tune on? You
know, is this gonna be like a,
is he going to have too much
deodorant under his arms?
Like fucking ll cool j when he did the
Unplug, what's going to happen here?
Do this guy,
this guy fucking murdered the son,
fucking murdered this song.
Tell,
just took the whole thing to another
level and it never came back down again.
Everybody else matched this guy.
This fucking dude was unbelievable.
He sang that song and then he's saying
Alison chains would and fucking murdered
both of them. Um, and you
literally felt it in the crowd.
Everybody on their phones go like,
who the fuck is this guy?
I gotta download some of his shit.
Um,
oh,
he's hilarious thing.
So later on that weekend I'm watching
vice and there's another funny promo.
He's sitting there, that
Guy Post Malone, right?
And I was sitting there with near gone.
That's the fucking guy I saw that
the guy that murdered that song,
those two songs. Right. So, um,
he was talking about conspiracy theory.
I don't even know what
the commercial was about.
It was just him talking to another guy.
I'm telling you,
very like early days of MTV.
He was just talking about
conspiracy theory and, uh,
being able to teleport.
And he was just going
like say is area 51 right?
Which of course he picks that rather
than saying San Diego, okay, he goes,
here's area 51 right here.
Here's Australia.
If you want to fly from area
51 to Australia, you've got
to fly all the way here.
You know,
and he draws the arc too.
We just didn't draw straight lines like
someone actually understands aviation,
right?
Cause this is what creeped me out.
Cause if you just do a straight line
and be like, all right, this guy's,
this guy's out of his mind. But the
second he drew the arc, I'm like, Oh fuck,
I'm buying into this theory. Right?
And he goes, um, and he goes,
well with teleportation,
they just do stuff like this and he just
takes the paper and the x were area 51
was in the x for Australia is he just
takes the paper and he just folds and he
pushes them together. He
goes, it's like that. He goes,
I know you guys think I'm out of my mind,
but I know this shit is true.
And I was like, this guy's brain.
That's what my brain tells me, you know,
so I, I don't know anything about
any of his, uh, and he was, uh,
any of his music, but I'm definitely
gonna Watch, download some of his shit.
If anybody knows what is best
album is or whatever, you know,
a good jump off point for
that guy. Um, it would be,
it would be a be tremendous.
Um, so anyways, oh by the way,
Navarro fucking killed the
guitar solo in that too.
I was wondering how the
hell he was going to do it.
Now I don't know if they came up with a,
a,
an effects pedal that made
the noise that the dude from a
yeah.
You know, fucking rage against
the machine. You know, cause he,
when he came out of here that will, those
weird sounds that he made. I don't know.
You know, I was in over my head
musically about fucking 15 minutes ago,
but whatever. And I want to thank
everybody at dark matter for, uh,
for hooking me up, um,
to see that show. Uh,
it was fucking great, man. Just a
great God damn show. So, of course,
I talked to Dean del Rey
who sees everything. He
goes, oh yeah, man. He goes,
I went to that show at like the fifth
anniversary and it was like fucking Ozzie,
Lemmy and Steven Tyler. And I
was just like, Oh fuck you man.
Fucking, you never going to beat
Dean del Ray with the fucking, uh,
I went to a concert story, fucking
guy seen everything. So anyways,
so I'm watching this vice channel.
I know I'm just plowing through this
shit fucking all over the place. Um,
and my wife just kept, you know,
recording this shit. They recruit,
she recorded something
about, um, like Dj's,
uh, she recorded something about
these, the fucking kids of those,
you know, oil barons or whatever,
oil money in Saudi Arabia.
So watching both of these,
right, the Dj thing, you know,
it's just something I'd seen before the
show and how much money that they're
making in I'm in Vegas. And, uh,
it was funny though actually actually
actually asking a couple of them what the
future was and a few of them understood
it in a few of them are just like, yeah,
it's never going to end. It's like, dude,
at some point you're going to be the
bgs in January of 1980 it happens to all
genres of music and the in the,
yeah,
so few bands figure out how to do it,
how to age gracefully
from one era to another.
Um, and like I was saying like, yeah,
I think I was talking about that and I
can't remember what fucking podcast is.
You have to, I don't know how to do
it, but somehow you have to, like,
your music has to age with you so you
don't look like a fucking moron. Um,
like Justin Bieber has got to write some
fucking middle aged shit when he's in
his middle age, you know, cause he
can't be singing about whatever the,
whatever the fuck he sings about. You
know what I mean? It looks stupid at 40,
you know, and it makes every people,
everybody in the crowd feels old.
Then you start on, my God,
we're gonna die. You know,
you just see your mortality
when they come out.
The first time that I saw that was when,
uh,
okay,
like 10 years ago when David Lee Roth
came back with van Halen and I went to go
see van Halen, I was like, oh my God,
this is going to be fucking great, right?
I can't believe he's back.
I saw a diamond,
Dave went on the Itam and smile
tours can be easily thrown, you know,
just thinking can be throwing fucking
kicks and jumping off the stage to the
fucking split. Right. And a dude,
he came walking out on stage and I
sweated within two other guy, God.
And like within five seconds
like, ah, fuck, he's all Damo old,
we're going to die.
Like this wave of fucking depression
just hit me, you know, until I've really
realized like, wait a minute, like,
you know, guitarists and
drummers don't get old. I mean
they do, but like, you know,
they can still fucking, you know, if
they have a technique or whatever,
they can still fucking
still fucking shred.
And I forgot that Eddie and Alex had
been playing again for like 50 fucking
years and they were unbelievable.
The singer has it the worst
because your voice naturally drops.
And of course everyone from my era
actually fucking sang, you know,
not to shit on Justin Bieber born.
I was watching that Dj thing on
the vice channel. They fucking, um,
okay.
He shows up at some, some pool party,
you know, where everybody's fucking,
you know,
turning the cameras around,
doing selfies and the peace sign
and the duck lips and all that shit.
And he shows up to sing his song and
he's just clearly fucking lip sinking.
He's not even trying to do a good
job and everybody's freaking out.
There was a few times,
like he took the mic away from his mouth,
pointed at the crowd. He could still
hear him singing and nobody gave a shit.
There was no band,
there was nothing.
And all these Yolo do, we're going fucking
nuts. It's like, how is that acceptable?
I don't know that, that shit makes
me feel old. Like back in the day,
if you ever got caught Milli Vanilli oh,
the whole fucking,
he milli Vanilli Milli add vanilla lead
his whole fucking way through that.
Nobody gave a shit 20, 20, 30
fucking years earlier. You know,
I guess it's cause those guys
tactically never even sang on the track.
I dunno, everybody's doing
fucking commercials now.
I mean, it's just back in.
It's the whole thing is just changed.
He just do whatever you want.
You don't have to sing. You
can fucking hear, you know,
you can lip sync you away with yours,
your hit song through a commercial
for fucking under roofs. And uh,
it actually equates to more
album downloads. Evidently
I should just be sitting
on a porch right now,
watching young people
walking by yelling at them.
That's what this podcast is just
slowly becoming. Um, so anyways,
I'm watching that channel and uh,
the next thing near recorded
was a, this thing about the, uh,
it looked like those same guys that
I saw when I was in London. The, uh,
Middle Eastern do to fly on a cargo plane,
fly in all their fucking cars
with this same ridiculous rap,
you know, or maybe it's a paid job. I
think it's a wrap that they put on there.
You know what I mean? They got like the
fucking a, it's like that marriage finish.
Like those three people in
Shanna now with the gold suits,
they'll do that to like
Mercedes and all that. Well,
when they're back in the country,
another status symbol is to own a,
uh,
like endangered species or a exotic
animals is they call them in these fucking
guys.
They owned like a cheetahs
and Lions and tigers.
It was the most disturbing fucking thing.
And I don't even be coming at
this and like a Peter Away,
I just sat there going like,
dude, that is a fucking lion.
You've got it on a leash. And
these things kept, you know,
they have their friends and they'd sort
of lunge at him and then the friends
would jump out of the way and be
like, Whoa, Whoa, Whoa, like laughing.
It's just like you saw how big these
fucking things where it's just like
they could like sorta like
at the 30% like bitch,
slap a refrigerator and the thing
would tip over and go flying across the
fucking room.
You know what I mean?
Okay.
And these guys are fucking with DC,
so this fucking lay goes over there.
This white lady making white people look,
look fucking stupid as shit. She's like,
she fucking goes over to
this guy's goddamn house.
He's got a giant fucking lion. All
right? And he goes, well, we'll get,
or a tiger Isam Shit.
And he goes, all right,
we'll get you comfortable with let
you play with some smaller ones first.
So she's playing with these
little ones in immediately I say,
I wouldn't fuck with that.
A long time ago I was on Opie and Anthony.
They brought in a fucking
baby tiger and little worlds,
little white ones or some shit.
And they asked me if they wanted a whole,
if I wanted to hold it. I was
like, no. The thing was upset.
It didn't want to fucking be there.
And I've been scratched by a house
cat fucking killed right now.
All it got me with one goddamn
cloth when write down my forearm,
I had to put all this shit on it so I
wouldn't get some sort of goddamn disease.
And I'm looking at this,
this cute little baby tiger or a lion,
whatever the fuck it was.
A little sick. Freedom.
Roy wants the Mariah Carey one where
it's all fucking white, you know?
And uh, I'm just looking at the
size of its fucking pause. I'm like,
that things pause already.
A like four times the size of a house cat.
I've got scratched by a house cat.
This thing's in a bad mood. I don't,
I don't want to fuck, I don't want
to deal with the thing. You know,
it's funny because actually scratched
Anthony, if I remember correctly,
and he had to get like a tetanus shot
or something,
some sort of ointment and to be put
on his fucking neck. So anyways,
so this lady goes in there, right? And
she's playing with them. She's like,
oh my God,
this is so durable and um,
was really not impressed with the
intellect of the woman that I thought they
could have got somebody
alive fucking smarter. Right.
So then she goes outside
to meet this lion.
Yeah.
Okay.
This lioness,
and there's no way to describe
to you how big a fucking line is.
It's not very often that you get to see
a person standing next to a God damn
line.
She walks up to the t in the general area,
this thing and the things
immediately looking at,
or the way a fucking wild animal
looks at you. You know what I mean?
It's the same way.
I've always said this is the same way,
like a fucking hooker looks at you
where there's no bullshit. You know,
you don't know bar. Some
woman looks at you, you know,
should we get fall, you know,
she's just trying to get a fucking drink.
They'll hook it looks at you. It's,
it's the real deal. Like, yeah,
I will fuck you. Okay. You
have to. Circumstances are,
are, you know, if you've got the
money, I will fuck you. Right.
It's the same thing with like lions.
They looking at you like,
if the opportunity arises I will kill you.
You know, dogs don't look at you like
that fucking lines looking, you know,
cats attempted housecats,
you know,
you turn around and he'd catch
them stock in you and shit,
but then you look at them and then
they fucking run away. All right,
picture a cat doing that.
A house cat.
But you turn around and it's a line and
it doesn't run away if fucking lunges at
you or maybe it gives you that
refrigerator bitch slap, right?
So this fucking thing is looking at her
and he's the owner who has no training
whatsoever. Brings his fucking
thing. I'll do, my palms were sweaty.
I, I had to get, well, when I was watching
it in bed, I literally stood up going,
what the fuck are you doing?
So the thing comes over,
immediately starts crawling on top of her,
it's on top of her.
And then she puts her hands on the side
of the thing and starts like, like,
you know,
rubbing it like it's a giant dog.
And all I remember was that does that
youtube video of that stunt men who worked
with bears and he had brought us some
sort of relative in there who wanted to
learn how to work with bears. And he told
him to keep his hands down by his side.
And the bear came up in like
stood up on its back legs,
put its paws on the dude's shoulder.
And he instinctively put his
hands on either side of the bear,
which the bear took as like an aggressive
move and one of the fight and it
fucking killed this guy. So she puts
her hands down and I see that I go,
oh fuck is this thing like a bear? I
don't fucking know. And all of a sudden,
um,
she got just a little bit scared and
then the thing like collapsed down on her
and it got weird really quick.
And then the guy stood up with this rope
fucking leash and like quickly tries to
pull the lion away, what she does and
this woman gets up like, ha ha, that was,
that was I.
And I feel like that was like a spiritual
experience of what it's like, bitch,
you almost got fucking killed.
And then the guy goes, yeah,
you got scared and it senses
your fear and then Oh God,
thank God she didn't make any high pitch
noise like the sound of an animal like
suffering. You know what I mean?
Do you have any like a dog toy?
You know when they bite on it and
it makes that high pitch noise,
it excites the Predator in them.
And um,
so I say the Nia,
I go how far into this show before they
show as somebody who got killed. I go,
I say about 17 minutes.
They didn't,
it was at the end of the show and they
were just like two weeks after we left.
Um, so this fucking woman,
basically the housekeeper comes in,
all right,
she didn't fucking do anything.
She's not like these fucking guys
who for some reason like it's,
it's just total like male ego shit trying
to outdo the other fucking rich guy
down the street that
they get these things,
they don't know anything about
the animals. They fucking,
at least that's the way it was presented.
They didn't know shit about the fucking
animals. And then they were like, no,
that thing has a better life.
Live in here. It's walking
around in a fucking cage.
You know, it's like, dude, what do you
want to walk around in a cage? I mean,
you could always get knifed. You could
get killed the way an animal couldn't in
the wild.
Okay?
It's a fucking lion who's killing a
lion other than another human being.
Um, so anyways, uh,
this fucking housekeeper came in and uh,
she got mauled by these fucking lines
and they bring the woman in and the guy
tried to say a dog did it.
And they were like, ah,
these injuries are a little more than
a dog. And then the owner is like,
well, whatever, do you
mean? It's like, well,
she's missing her left arm and the claw
marks on this f so you know what the
fucking asshole did? He had
three lions. He went home,
he shot all of them, and then burn
their bodies out in the desert. So we,
you know, so nothing would fucking happen
to them. And, uh, it was just like, yeah.
It's like, yeah, there you go.
They go fucking inevitable.
They had like cheetahs disguise riding
in a fucking six wheeled Mercedes with a
fucking Cheetah.
Yeah.
And that woman's getting in
the car going, oh, it's, it's,
it's acting just like a dog. It's
padding. It's looking out the window.
Maybe they had to get somebody, I'm
not saying she was not as smart person,
she just wasn't very aware
of the situation I feel. And
I just kept hearing like,
it was back in the day,
like 50 def jam comics did bits about
how white people fuck with wild animals.
And so in a way I'm like,
oh, this is good for once.
It's not white people being idiots with
wild animals, you know, now it's Arabs.
Let's, let's, uh, you know,
take a little heat off of Whitey and
then they bring this white lady in there
and she fucking does everything that,
you know,
every one of those bits says that we do.
So anyways, um, let's get to some of the,
uh, some of the reads here for the week.
If I can,
if my fucking
okay.
Computer isn't gonna tell me to
fucking, I dunno. Update something. Um,
oh Jesus. Here we go. Here we
go. Oh wait, I have to promote
this thing real quick. All right. I was
supposed to promote this regular hero,
um,
year in review.
You can donate now and be irregular
hero to change your life today.
These people work around the world
to help the disadvantaged. They, uh,
they are a not another
yet another nonprofit.
And I'm assuming that because
it's on my podcast that this is a,
uh,
this is actually a legit one.
You know,
they help out with hurricane Matthew,
skid row at risk youth.
Um, oh, regularly heroes
show [inaudible] oh fuck.
I've done one of these. Oh, this is,
what's this Steve Simone thing, right.
The regular heroes show has been a
great fun and awareness raiser thanks to
comedians. Bill Berg, Gabriel
Iglesias, Dane Cook, Daniel Tosh.
Chris had WIC.
Chris Delea the world at the world
famous comedy store and the Improv. Yeah.
This is actually legit one in a,
in a world where so many of
these nonprofits are, um,
I'll complete horse shit.
This is actually a legit one,
which is a very nice thing. Um, because
everything is a fucking nonprofit.
Like you remember that,
that that lady from a couple months back,
she,
uh,
she lost her job at that
nonprofit yet another nonprofit.
Uh, when she said that horrible
shit about Michelle Obama, you know,
and of course wrote it like a
dope. She said something like, uh,
it will be so refreshing to have a classy,
beautiful,
dignified first lady in the White House.
You mean that trophy wife?
Well, cause she wears a red blouse. All
of a sudden she's fucking, uh, you know,
a better person. She wrote, I'm
tired of seeing a ape in heels,
not Ann a n a ape in heels.
And ape is capitalized.
Like it's a, I don't know somebody's
name or some shit like that.
And so of course she gets fucking,
she gets bounced out of this nonprofit.
She gets fired because everybody knows
that makes you less racist. You're racist,
and then you lose your job.
And then you go, oh, wait a
minute, what was I thinking?
Everybody is equal. Um,
so anyways, then the, uh,
the fucking mayor from this town,
Clay County is something Virginia,
Virginia,
West Virginia I guess
backed up her Goddamn, uh,
why you would do that. You know,
even if you were raised as,
you'd think you'd be smart enough
to keep your fucking mouth shut,
this person co-signed or
what the other person said.
And then the mayor had to fucking
resigned. So anyways, they actually,
so they fired the first lady who said
it from the Clay County Development
Corporation, nonprofit. There a
corporation that develops shit and,
but it's not for profit.
Well, let me ask you this.
How is this woman not homeless?
I don't get how you work for a
nonprofit and you're not homeless.
If there is no profit, how do they pay
you? This is what all corporations do.
I'm in business.
I'm in business with a certain corporation
that claims in 90 to $180 million
loss a year. And the people I work
with are buying mansions out here,
redoing them.
I don't know how that works.
That's actually a different thing because
they're not considered a nonprofit.
They're considered a business entity.
And if he,
if you don't show that
you've earned any money,
then you don't have to pay any taxes.
Um, so the corporation doesn't,
but then everybody draws a salary.
Now you have to pay taxes on,
um, on the salary that you drew.
But however, if you just say,
and you're not making a profit,
you don't have to pay any taxes.
And I would think that all that extra
money that you didn't pay taxes on,
you then use disperse amongst
your employees. Right?
So rather than making a million a year,
you make 2 million a year and
then you pay taxes on that. Right.
I Dunno how it works.
I don't know. You know,
I'm too stupid to figure out
how that shit works. But, um,
for the life of me,
I looked up this nonprofit
trying to figure out what
the fuck they do. I cannot,
I can't figure it out. So anyways,
they fired this fucking lady and um,
okay.
Then like a month later, they just
reinstated her. They just reinstated or,
and uh, I don't know. To me
that is the Trump influence.
I think that that's what
everybody learned from Trump.
It's just like you just say, Hey, you
know, that's locker room talk or a,
you know, [inaudible] he's fired.
And because back back. Yeah.
You know, I left, I left for six
weeks in our back. Uh, you know,
and what I love with media is there
is no follow up after the first story.
The first story has done this, this,
there's the whole fucking everybody
flipping out. Let's go burn the witch.
And then once it dies down, then you
just bring the person back and nobody,
they've moved on to something else.
Um, I don't know. It's really bizarre.
I just don't know how somebody could
fucking be in business with somebody like
that. It's fucking nuts. Anyways,
all right, me on these, uh, oh Jesus.
Bateau both bought me undies. Me On
these rubbing up on your card. We do do,
do me undies. Me On ds. It's
like a sheepskin fucking suck.
It's so fucking soft up
against your taped. You know,
you fucking love it. Um, your Dick,
you will pay two with a pair of fucking
me undies. Why would you paint your deck?
I don't know. How many fucking
times can I sing this picture?
A world in a world we're putting on a
new pair of underwear isn't just fresh.
You're stepping into a better day,
you know, I bet. Where's me undies?
Who lives in me undies? Lifestyle
is Mariah Carey. I know.
It's the second time I brought her up,
but that fucking channel,
Nia keeps watching on one of these reality
shows that's following Mariah Carey
around. Dude, she's fucking
hilarious. Every fucking shot.
She's like laying in a bed in an evening
gown with heels on full makeup and
everything with a glass of wine.
It's like in the 1950s what people thought
rich people did all day just laying
around with like, you know, some fucking
$300,000 diamond necklace. It's like,
we get it. You're a diva. Jesus Christ.
You never wear sweatpants, you know?
Does he have a fucking white
Zinfandel over there? Um,
anyways, it says, think about it.
Underwear is the first thing you put on
in the last thing you take off unless
you weird. You know what if you
don't like your torso, what have you,
one of those guys that fucks with his
shirt on, you know, you sweaty tee shirt.
Right. You know what I mean?
It's still like a tee shirt off.
Yeah.
You know,
ladies,
if you're fucking a guy wears man titch
that's when you know he's really letting
you win is when he takes the t shirt off
to of Jesus. But why would you say that?
All right. Think about it.
Underwear. It's very blah, blah blah.
Why would you settle anything less than
the best feeling underwear on the planet?
Me undies focuses solely on producing the
most comfortable underwear you've ever
experienced.
Um,
my friends at me and he sent me a few
pairs a while back and now I can't imagine
wearing anything else.
Why do you keep putting out in the copy?
You sent me two pairs.
I warm one.
I liked the other with a Greg Louganis
cut and I don't, I wasn't in that shape.
You know, you send me the Olympic
diver fucking Skippy's there. You know
Jesus Christ. I went from muffin top to
like, I dunno what the fuck croissant.
What's the next one up the pastry ladder.
Um,
it really makes each day that much
better for the price of two cocktails.
Mian he's,
we'll deliver your new favorite pair
of underwear right to your doorstep.
Better Day guarantee you try them on.
And if they aren't the most comfortable,
best feeling underwear you've ever had,
the refund you and let you keep your
first pair for free. We'll obviously,
what are you going to take it back?
Like that fucking mattress company.
These Uber Cozy undies are sold
exclusively on the me undies website where
you'll enjoy free shipping in the US
and Canada. And for a limited time,
everyone in my audience gets
20% off their first order,
but you have to order our,
go to our special URL,
[inaudible] dot com slash burr
to get 20% off. That's me.
[inaudible] DOT com slash burn. All
right, give me loot crate everybody.
Hey nerds, wake the fuck up. If we go, uh,
be the envy of your friends and get
your 100% exclusive crates that Luke
craig.com/burr and enter my code birth
to save $3 off any new subscription.
What the fuck is a loot
crate? Oh, here we go.
Wait until I t oh wait until I tell you
I'm subsidy. Supposed to be excited here.
Wait. Aw, wait until I tell
you about December's crate.
It'll have you fight the power man.
Luke crate offers an epic range of pop
culture items for less than $20 a month.
If you're more of a fanatical fashioned
Isa needs to then try loop where?
Monthly wearables and accessories
with coke classics and your favorite
franchises.
If you wanted to get fancy,
get a bigger box and even
bigger loop with loot crate DX.
Want to geek out a your pet.
Try Luke pets offer expires
December 19th at 9:00 PM pathetic.
Get ready for December's rebellious theme
revolution. They're always watching.
I have no idea what any of this shit is,
but I know nerds a loving this.
They designed a system to keep you down
in their meddlesome. Hello friends.
It's time for a revolution.
December's Craig features exclusive
items from assassin's creed. No way,
Mr. Robot, Holy Shit. Firefly.
What the fuck is that?
Our monthly tee shirt and pin and
more including an exclusive Funko pop.
I'm telling you, I say this every week.
That sounds like a fucking dad. Gene Band.
Funko pop. You take
elements of Funk, you know,
you're like really into tower of power.
It's like a James Brown kind of thing.
And we met, we mash it, we do a, one
of the,
one of the kids call it oh,
a fucking combining their of Tucson's
with the same tempo of more contemporary
things. Our kids love it. Uh, do not wait.
You have until the 19th
at 9:00 PM Pacific. Hey,
maybe next year when Nevara does he show,
maybe I'll have some members
of Funko pop. C'Mon, um,
Pacific to subscribe to for December's
crate. When is, when it's over.
It's over.
No more crates.
Go to Luke craig.com/ [inaudible] and
enter my code birth to save $3 off any new
subscription today. How many more
fucking things that are there.
Uh, I don't know. Real. All right guys,
can you handle one more?
Let me just do one more just to fucking
plow through this shit. All right.
Now that you know how to dress like a
nerd, now that your balls a nice and soft,
you know at some point you're
going to want a sandwich, right?
Blue Apron. Everybody. Not to be confused
with Red Apron. This is blue apron.
This is for the Democrats
only. All right. And that old,
not if you want to cry into your
meal after Trump gets sworn in,
you got to go to blue apron. Not all
ingredients are created equal. Fresh,
high quality ingredients
make a real difference.
So it's important to know
where your food comes from. Um,
talk about how blue, fuck you. I'll
talk about what I want to talk about.
Affordable for less than $10
per person. Per meal. Yeah.
Blue Apron delivers seasonal recipes
along with proportion agreements to make
delicious home cooked meal for Righty,
we got you covered.
Choose from a variety of new recipes
each week or let blue apron culinary team
surprise you. Holy Shit,
is that corn flakes.
Recipes are not repeated within a year,
so you'll never get bored or you like
Mariah Carey with all their fucking
evening counts every fucking time.
She's got a different one. Flexible.
Customize your recipes each
week based on your preferences.
Blue Apron has several delivery options
so you can choose what fits your needs
and there's no weekly commitment. So you
only get deliveries when you want them.
Easy. You want it easy. You don't want
to thank you. Fucking dope. Here we go.
Each meal comes from with a step by step,
easy to follow recipe card,
card and proportion ingredients and
can be prepared in 40 minutes or less.
Just like Rachel Ray over there.
Um, guaranteed blue aprons,
fresh obstructionist guarantees,
promises that every ingredient
you deliberately arrives
ready to cook or they'll
make it right.
Check out this week's menu and get the
first three meals for free with free
shipping by going to blue apron.com/
[inaudible] you'll love how good it feels
and tastes to create incredible
home cooked meals with
blue apron, so don't wait.
That's blue apron.com/bar blue apron.
A better way to cook.
Why do they write so much fucking
copy? It's like, yeah, I get it.
I get it. Okay. I get all
these aren't all cool.
Some of these are reads I fucked
up. I only have one left. Oh my God.
This is great. There's
only one left. Everybody.
Then I get into the questions
for the week. Perfect. All right.
Seatgeek everyone buying tickets online
for sports and concert has been a
confusing process for a
long time. Yes, it has.
It's always been hard to find the best
deal for that game or show you want to go
to and none of those older
tickets sites want to change that,
but [inaudible] is different.
They've come along and created an amazing
APP and website that makes it easier
for every fan to bind,
sell tickets.
Everything about seek is designed to make
life easier for sports and music fans.
See Keke does all the price comparisons
for you by searching multiple tickets
sites and ensuring that you
get the best possible deal.
See does all the work and you
save time and money. Best of all,
my listeners get $20 a $20 rebate
off their first SeatGeek purchase.
To get your $20 rebate on tickets,
download the SeatGeek APP,
go to the settings tab and
click on the add a promo code.
Allow them to access all
your photos into track.
You long after you've bought the seats,
enter Promo Cobra side. This is an Uber.
Enter Promo Code [inaudible] [inaudible]
we'll send you $20 after you've made
your first ticket purchase.
Download the [inaudible] APP and
enter the Promo Code bird today.
All righty then. All right,
so according to the emails,
somebody wanted me to look at this
fucking thing and it's simply says crazy
Asian sport. Saw this on reddit. Neat. Uh,
and needed you to see a merry Christmas.
Twinkle lies.
All right,
let's see what this is.
Oh my God. All right. Let me hit pause
here. This is basically, this is,
I want to go to this.
Yeah.
All right.
There's this whole group of fucking dudes.
They're all dressed in white.
Oh my God.
They're all huddled around a pole and
there's a guy sitting on top of the
fucking pole and then another group of
dudes come in wearing orange shirts and
the fucking,
they all have on like Olympic
boxing headgear and that when,
when the fucking orange dudes come in,
they tried to knock the guy off the Paul.
This is like fucking
ads fighting each other.
Yeah,
dude,
you fucking asshole.
How can you show me this and
not tell me what sport this is?
They tried to knock the guy off the
fucking pole. What is this called?
And what happens is,
is basically everybody gets piled on.
Once the orange crew comes in,
oh, there's a weak guy. He turned,
he ran the other fucking way. They
start jumping up on top of each other.
Oh my God.
That would be so fucking claustrophobic.
It's basically like a rugby scrum.
If you could throw fucking punches and
you climb and just imagine a rugby scrum
and rather than the ball,
one of the rugby dudes was sitting up on
a pole and they tried to fucking knock
them off.
Wow,
dude.
They're just kicking each other in
the face. I swear to God, you know,
how the fuck did I get so lucky to
be born in this goddamn country?
Where do they at least pretend to
give a shit about your wellbeing?
And you like that is a fucking
hardcore sport. You know what?
Hat's off the fucking Asia right there.
I would love to see them and try to get,
this is barbaric.
Tried to do it in our country.
Like is everybody's listening
from America? My country,
I should say this is barbaric.
This is,
this is promoting violence against
people at different kinds of shirts on.
Let me, I don't even understand what is,
what is, what is the purpose of this? Um,
can you please tell me
the name of that sport?
Am I ever gonna get
over this fucking cough?
Haven't smoked a cigar and forever I'm
getting eight hours sleep. Not really.
You know, Nias tossing and turning on
every fucking minute. Now I literally,
you know, I, I,
I sleep in bed for like half the night
and then after awhile I just ended up
going upstairs and it fall asleep.
You know, I want to do the same thing.
Like when the baby comes, I'm just going
to be one of the baby cries too much.
I'm just going to be like,
you know what,
I can't deal with either one of you and
I'm going to go upstairs and I'm going
to put it on an evening
gown like Mariah Carey and
in lay here with my fucking diamonds on.
I Dunno, maybe it's just for
the show, but I just look at it,
it's like this person is out of their,
at some point it's just completely
lost touch of reality. Um,
there's something about that when you
get like backup dancers and they're all
hanging on your every word and they,
and they literally want to be you.
Like there's no way to keep,
keep yourself tethered to any sort
of fucking reality. Um, alright.
Advice, age, different
story. First of all,
did I talk about everything I wanted to
fucking talk about this week? Um, oh,
let's talk about how you guys don't want
your up. If you'd like to the podcast,
you can still start right now,
man.
I've been trying to do a half hour cardio
every single day cause this, you know,
between Thanksgiving and, um, new year's,
she eat all of this fucking shit.
You put on weight and then you've got it.
You just start the year behind the
eight ball by the eight ball. Right.
I was like,
I'm not fucking doing that.
So as of December 1st I've
been trying to do a cardio,
a half hour of cardio every
single fucking day. And um,
of course I fucked up. Right? I, um,
what did I do?
I,
I made it through the first 11 days and
then December 12th I had a busy morning
and you really got to knock it out in
the morning, which I didn't. And uh,
the day got longer and longer.
And then I came home and he was watching
some fucking TV and she was just like,
I need comfort. And I was just like, all
right, acting like I was a good husband,
rather than like, I don't want to
get on that fucking elliptical again.
So I missed a half hour. On the
12th, 13th, I did my half hour.
So I had 12 out of 13 days.
14th I missed.
Then I was like, fuck, this is becoming a
trend now. I owe that machine down there.
60 minutes plus the 30 foot today.
That was Friday, December 15th.
So I got on that elliptical,
blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
The Dodo, no baby baby red cakes. Um,
I got on the thing that I did,
um, an hour and 11 minutes,
71 minutes out of the 90 minutes.
I just looked at it like it
was a basketball game or a
sporting event and I was
down by 90 points.
And so the next day I started my day,
I was down 19 points plus the 30 I had
to do and I ended up doing an hour on the
elliptical.
So now I was up 11 minutes
and then I liked it.
I liked the results of doing a
fucking hour. So then, uh, on,
say I did a an hour and four minutes.
So then now I'm up. I was down
90 minutes now I was up, uh,
an hour and 15,
also known as 75 minutes.
And then yesterday I did
an hour and 15 minutes. Uh,
so I don't even know what I'm up at
this point. 45 minutes plus an extra 45.
I'm actually up 90 minutes, something like
that. I don't know what the fuck it is.
I can't really remember,
but all I wanted to do,
I was going to do a half hour every
day and that was going to be a seal.
31 days there'll be 15 and a
half hours of cardio, but, uh,
now I think I'm just going to do hours
every day for the rest of the fucking
year. I weighed myself the
other day. I was one 77.
Now when I came back from fucking Europe,
I was a buck 90,
so I've taken 13 pounds off since,
um,
okay.
Since that trip. So I dunno, it's
all about the fucking cardio. Um,
I would love to do that. You know,
if I, if you don't, the reality is,
is if you've got an elliptical every
day and did fucking 60 minutes,
if he just did that, you know,
and, and when you do that,
when you put together a playlist,
that's when you gotta love. I tell you,
you got to love like bands like
iron maiden or they have six,
seven minutes songs, you know, at least
the songs, or at least four minutes,
which is a huge fucking chunk,
you know?
And I just put my sweatshirt
over the clock and I'm just like,
I just peek at the clock after
every song's done. All right,
so if you just do want
to half hour of cardio,
you gotta listen to rhyme of the ancient
mariner. It's a 13 minute song, you know?
Yeah.
Hey there, right buddy? Hey chip.
Marriner the whole fucking thing there.
You got to change
by, by the De de de, De, De, De, De, De,
De, De, De, De, de, De, de. [inaudible].
He listened to the whole fucking
thing. The courtesy, the party,
right?
Yeah.
You're going to go from fucking
27 minutes down to 14 minutes.
He like this a fucking joke.
I always try to put it on.
You don't have it come on time.
It was like 21 minutes, you know,
and then I just covered up
because the next time I look,
I'm going to be in single digits. I'll
be down to like eight or nine minutes.
It's fucking tremendous.
But, um, anyways, I, uh,
a buddy of mine,
my drum teacher was showing me
this fucking song this week and uh,
I dunno how I slept in this one.
I've always been a big Soundgarden fan
to somehow I never heard that song rhino
sore and a, as always, Matt came
on with the sickest fucking drums.
Uh, I become obsessed with that
song in that fucking album.
And uh, and I saw it, I thought
it said 2016 I was like,
oh, they got back together.
This is their latest shit.
And then I looked again and said in 1996
every fucking thing that I listened to,
I don't know what happened,
but I think part of it,
cause I got old and then I was also like
trying to fucking get somewhere as a
comedian.
I just completely missed out on like 20
years of music and like half the shit
people show me. I'm like, oh,
that sounds fucking, you know,
it always sounds like it's brand new to
me when that come out. And they're like,
yeah, like 2002. I'm like, ah, I just,
I just can't get contemporary.
I got 20 years of Shit I got
to fucking sift through. Um,
so if there's any other drugs out there,
you know,
part of my lessons is
they'll play shit at the end,
like ear training, Shit. Like you gotta
try to figure out the groove you got. Oh,
you got to figure out what
time signature was in.
And this was to figure out
what time signature was in.
And of course I was fucking it
up and a few drummers out there,
it's in six.
But if you count the eighth notes,
you just count up to 12 in the
phrasing is seven and five.
Um, and I would play it for you on
here, but I always just feel like,
because I do advertising,
if I play any music, um,
that all of a sudden somebody's
going to come after me and be like,
you owe us money cause you
made money off of me on these,
why you played our fucking
song or whatever. Um, anyways,
but do you guys think of
the Patriots yesterday?
Everybody's flipping out about our
defense. Like I don't know what the big,
you know, we beat the Ravens and
the Ravens, they, you know, there's,
they got that subs guy,
but back in the day add Suggs they
had ray Lewis and they had ed reed.
So they're big three is basically
down to one dude and you know,
they're not who the fuck they were.
And then we beat the Broncos in mile
high where we never fucking went,
but they basically navigating got
a rookie quarterback. I Dunno,
I get so frustrated with the Patriots
because it seems like they only protect
their offensive players. They've been,
I know I've been bitching about this,
but they just, you know, that fucking
cornerback, whatever the fuck his name is,
Taylor Lib, whatever the fuck his
name is. He, when he was with us,
that whole side of his whole squadron
section of the field was just shut down.
What didn't we like about that?
Why didn't we just keep that guy?
You know, we always, we got fucking wide
receivers. We got fucking a quarterback.
That's where we keep all our fuck
them. You know what, this is my theory.
Bill Belicheck is such a defensive genius.
I think he just thinks like,
you know what? I don't fucking
need, uh, you know, I don't,
I don't look at it as my fucking computer
just decided, you know, I said, act,
do you know, contact me in
an hour. Now it's like, all
right, an hour's gone by now.
It's just sinking with my fucking
phone. Like, who's doing this?
So weird. Just like all these fucking
satellites just fucking pointed at yet.
I don't know. Anyways. Um,
I think he just is convinced that he
can take any second round draft pick,
train this person into being a n NFL
quality player at that position slash
borderline all pro view.
And if you become an all pro,
Danny just fucking gets ready
at the second you want money.
Okay.
Just fucking been doing it forever.
But back in the day, you know,
we'd keep McGuinness, we kept Grable. So
our defense, I felt like had an identity.
Now it's like every three years it's like
a whole new fucking defense drives me
up the fucking wall.
Okay.
I Dunno, we'll see. Cause I
watched the giants, you know,
and you know like all patriots fans, every
year when the giants go on their run,
you get this sickening feeling
in your stomach going like,
oh fuck yet you want to play him again?
Cause we got to beat him one time,
you know? And I was sitting
there going like, all right,
well they lost Tom [inaudible]. This
is going to be huge. And Lo and behold,
they're doing it again. They're on
another fucking run. All right. Yeah,
the defense looks fucking amazing.
You know,
I'm not saying a defense
doesn't look good, but it
does not look as good as this.
And um, I dunno, that's the giants thing.
Like the only thing about the giants as
they don't score any fucking points for
whatever fucking reason they got eli who's
a goddamn beast. They got the fucking,
uh, they got the diva there.
What's his name? Uh, uh, how do I,
I don't,
my short term memory's for shit.
I just thought why it,
I can't fucking remember his last name
is the same name as the fucking soccer
player with all the tattoos
is married to the spice girl
backup bend it like Beckham, Odell
Beckham. There you go. See that?
I'm learning how my fucking old brainworks
now I've got to go on one of those
brain exercise websites that try to help
you with your short term memory. Um,
I dunno, I'm fascinated how they can
have him at wide receiver. You know,
I don't know if they play in that
Cruz guy a bunch of fucking money,
but they got eli,
they're able to keep him.
But then on the other side of the ball,
they got JPP and if he didn't
fucking mess up his hand like they,
they seem to be,
they're more balanced.
Okay.
You know? So what if Chandler Jones
wanted money? Fucking earned it.
Sometimes I just feel like we're getting,
I don't know.
What the fuck do you build?
How many Superbowls do they have to
win before you realize bill Belichick's
knows what he's doing. I know, I know.
I'm just looking at the NFC west and
they just seems like they're stronger.
I'll tell you right now, the Dallas
cowboys, you buy it, sell it. I'm selling.
I don't believe in him.
I don't believe in the Dallas cowboys.
I don't believe in that coach.
I Dunno about, you know,
this is just totally based on, I
look at that guy and I go, I don't,
I don't believe in that guy.
I just don't.
Uh, Pete Carroll is a fucking beast.
Eli is an animal and their coach,
who
I swear to God,
looks like he wants
some radio contest is a,
is a, is a wolf in sheep's
clothing, is a wolf and upper deck.
Fucking eating a pretzel and get
mustard all over his face clothing. Um,
I think one of those teams, and this
is really isn't going out on a limb,
I think one of those two
teams goes to the, uh,
to the Superbowl and having watched
both teams, I think I would rather play,
um, I rather play Seattle. And that's only
because Seattle, you know, once you went,
a couple of you went to win a Superbowl,
you go to back to back. You know,
they lost too many guys.
Um,
not to say that they could beat the
patriots every fucking beat us this year.
But uh, we'll see. We'll see. I
never fucking believe in my team,
you know what I mean? I don't know why.
I always just see the fucking, you know,
why are we doing this?
Why are we doing that? Um,
so anyways, we shall see. But uh,
be nice to play the giants
again and finally fucking win.
We'd actually would have to win that
game or else Tom Brady would forever just
get ripped on sports, talk radio,
buy all his mouth breathing dopes.
They will be like,
don't,
don't do it man.
Like it was this one on
one game like Tom Brady.
Every Superbowl has not let his team
down the field for the winning score.
He's had to do that. Every super
bowl that he's been in, you know,
and four out of six times the defense
went out and did their job and two times
they did not.
Um,
and I'm not taking it away from fucking
Eli because two times Eli beat our
defense, but he beat our defense.
He did not be Tom Brady. However,
when you're the quarterback, you
take all the blame, you know,
all you gotta do is look at Dan Marino
and the ridiculous level of Shit that
that guy takes, despite the fact,
all the records that that guy,
I've never run a study. It's just
did he have to tackle people too?
Was he supposed to run the ball up the
gut to fucking eat up some of the clock?
MMM.
I Dunno. It's just so fucking, uh, the
shit that Dan Marino gets is the dumbest.
It's the dumbest ever. This is how much
the game has changed. By the way. Uh,
I looked this up the other day just
because all they do is fucking throw the
ball and I looked up all time,
you know,
running backs, just rushing all time for
your career and I'll tell you right now,
what's his face?
Emmitt Smith.
No one's going to break that
fucking record the way, the way,
they just don't run the
fucking ball anymore.
No one's going to get anywhere near that
thing. Uh, let me look this shit up.
Like I looked it up yesterday
and um,
not now. I don't know. Install
these fucking things. Fuck off
Christ.
It's like a
fucking kid tugging at you,
Mommy. Mommy, Mommy. Um,
where we go all time NFL rushers.
Um, all right. Where the fuck
is it? Pro Football reference.
This is the best thing ever.
So I look this shit up. Okay.
And in the top 20, top 20, all like,
as of right now, there's only
three active players in the top 20.
The first seven are all retired.
Okay. The, the, the, the highest ranking
one is Frank Gore who has 12,000,
931 yards. All right. Then you
got to go all the way down to 16.
You got Adrian Peterson who granted took
a year off because he beat his kids up
with something fun in the
woods. Uh, Adrian Peterson,
and then he got Steven Jackson at 18.
All right, you go to the all time.
Uh, where the fuck is it
passing? What the hell is it?
Passing yards? How hard is it to
find that passing yards? All right,
so there's only, there's
only, there's only a
three active players. Top 20 rushing,
right? Starts at eight and ends at 18.
All right.
Passing all time.
There's in the top 14,
there's six active players,
six active players in the top 14 all time.
There's only eight of the qbs in the
history of the NFL that is thrown as many
or more yards than six current fucking
players and the top two all time.
Or Peyton manning and Brett Farve,
Peyton manning just retired last year.
Brett Farve retired six years ago.
It's fucking unbelievable.
Like how much this game has changed.
And there's only two really
old school names, uh,
in the top 20 is Johnny Unitas.
Where's the other one in
Fran Tarkington and uh, once,
what's his face like a
John Elway Warren Moon. That class? Uh,
Dan Fouts, Joe Montana, they
came in, they did their damage
to Kerry Collins is in the fucking,
he's 16th all time. So here you go.
So you got Peyton Manning's one.
Brett Farve is to drew.
Brees is three was 65,462 yards.
He's,
he's less than 7,000 yards.
Let's, uh, about six,
6,500 yards away from owning the record.
Dan Marino's fourth, then
it's Tom Brady, John Elway,
Warren Moon than Eli Manning is eight.
Then Fran target attendant.
Ben Roethlisberger, Vinny
Testaverde, Philip Rivers,
drew Bledsoe, Carson Palmer, Dan
Fouts. I've seen like everybody,
all of these people play in my lifetime.
I catch the end of for integrity.
Dan Fouts, Kerry Collins, Joe Montana,
Johnny United site didn't see Dave
Craig boomers size and Donovan McNabb.
All right, done. Move.
Natalie's is 21st all time. Um,
that's how much the fucking game has
changed. It's, it's unbelievable.
And what it is, is that these guys are
like throwing for four yards, five,
six yards. That's shit used to give to
the running back. So I think Emmitt Smith,
Walter Payton, those guys, no
one's going to touch them. I don't,
I don't know how you'd get enough
fucking attempts to even do it. Um,
was there a point to that bill? I'm,
yeah, just say they throw the ball a lot.
I guess that's what I'm saying,
Jim or say completely changed.
And then another thing too is just
the way that they protect the fucking
quarterback. You know, when
they call it the Tom Brady rule,
because at time he turned around and
looked at the referee, said, Hey,
somebody touched my jersey.
And the referee was like, Oh,
I'm sorry he fucking
threw the flag. Um, yeah,
everybody calls it to Tom Brady rule,
which I love.
I love that they call it the Tom
Brady rule. Cause it is, you know,
you gotta protect your
quarterbacks. That's your money.
Everybody realizes that a,
you know, when, when the best, you know,
everybody knows the fucking quarterback.
That guy gets knocked out.
No one's going to watch the games.
So they protect the hell out of him and
they're like, yeah, fuck everybody else.
And uh, people who not into
sports, they're into offense.
They want to see some action.
So they just stay, you know,
now it's like a legal to cover fucker,
cover a fucking receiver, you know,
to Dan Marino. I'm the shit you could
do during that guy's fucking career.
And he's still through for like
60,000 fucking yards. I don't know.
I always talk about steroids.
Right.
And then they put an asterisk next
to your name. You know, they don't,
you don't have the same way they
don't give Barry bonds is just do,
it's just like a, you're going to
sit there and tell me, you know,
all of these fucking guys were
as good as Dan Marino with the,
so putting up fuck out of
here. All right. Um, advice,
age difference and history. Ah, dear bill,
I'm just a bill. Yes. I'm only a
bill. Um, I'm a big fan of yours.
I really enjoy your podcast. You'll
thank you very much. I appreciate it.
I am 28 years old and in a relationship
with my girlfriend who's seven years
younger than me and who I plan on
marrying were really great together.
I love her. Well congratulations.
The thing is, is as our
relationship has gone on,
we've slashed, I've been getting some
static from people about our relationship.
Well who gives a fuck what they think?
Like I said,
she's seven years younger than me,
but we've known each other for awhile.
We've met,
when I was working at my first job as a
counselor at a camp when she was one of
the kids. Oh Jesus. When we first
met, I was 17 and she was 10
yeah, Yep, Yep. Man. That,
that's that creepy thing.
That's that creepy thing.
Cause some point you were like,
oh look at that little kid. That's the
woody Allen moment where you go, oh,
isn't she adorable? And then at some
point the switch flips to being like, Hey,
think I want to fuck that.
You know, there's, there's
no way to get around that,
sir. You'd have to understand
that. So anyways, he says,
nothing happened between us at
that point. Will, I would hope so.
It wasn't until we reconnected years
later when we were older that we started
talking again and really getting
to know each other. All right,
well I guess that's fair, but people are
going to say some shit. Right. Anyway,
I'm getting shit from some family
and friends because of our history.
Just from an outside source.
I'd like to know what you think.
Do you think it's strange or weird?
I know there's people out there 15 to 20
years apart. It's just with our history,
it throws people off again.
What do you think from an
unbiased perspective perspective?
Thanks and go fuck yourself.
Yeah.
The thing is is that you were 17 and
she was 10 when you first met her. Um,
that's what makes it weird.
MMM,
okay.
Like my wife is 10 years younger than me,
but I didn't meet her until I was like,
you know,
35 and she was 25.
MMM.
Hey Nia, come in. Here is a question.
Somebody, uh, somebody, uh, 28,
what do you say they are? Wendy,
what do you still out of breath for?
Come here. Give me a place
to sit here, you know, Jesus.
So this guy, he's dating
this woman, right? He wants
to marry, he's 28. She's 21.
He said, the thing is that I
met her when I was a counselor.
I was 17 she was only 10. He
goes obviously nothing. Yeah.
What happened then?
He goes,
obviously nothing happened then,
but now that we're together
people are given a shit. And
uh, I was saying how there was a 10 year
difference between us, but I, you know,
I was 35. You were 25. Right. So Phil,
come on. So they're looking at you like,
uh, you've been grooming her since
she was like seven years old.
Yeah.
But he like met her,
but then it didn't seem like
you didn't see her for awhile.
Then they reconnected and
had all the choirs, which
happens, don't worry about it.
Have, you know, everything's on the up
and up. Just just do your thing. Yeah.
Is there family cool with it, you know,
is her family given him the side eye?
Like he was grooming her or
seems to just be friends.
What do you mean? His friends?
People that he knows it just like,
this is what I would do.
I would just,
whatever those Pete runs are giving
him shit about it. I wouldn't,
if you meet new people, I wouldn't tell
them that that's how you first met him.
Probably not.
I'm not.
Everybody needs to know your entire
history and that way just because people
will misinterpret it. But yeah. Have you
guys are fine. Your families are fine.
Like don't worry about it.
Yeah.
As long as nothing happened when
you were a counselor. Exactly.
As long as you're sure nothing happened
when you were at council there,
which I'm sure they didn't. He always
wants to push her on the swing. Oh God.
I know.
It's bad.
All right, well let's see.
I did it to you, sir. You're
gonna, you're gonna have to,
you know, there's a certain level of shit
you're going to have to deal with. Um,
where you going?
I'm going, I'm going out to have a
little, a little breakfast with a friend.
Well, I didn't like the vagueness of
that. Having a little with a friend.
Yes. I'm going to have smoothies
with Chelsea Peretti. Oh,
he didn't have to say that.
Smoothies. Chelsea Peretti.
Yeah. Sacramento zone. Chelsea
Peretti from Sacramento or, yeah,
she, she's from Sacramento. Oakland. No.
Helis Sacramento soccer. She
does say hello. Um, yeah,
she's white trash from a PLC.
Is she is,
she's white trash from
northern California. She is,
she's also a Republican. Um, anyway.
All right. Where the fuck am I? Um, yeah
dude. Just, you know who gives a fuck?
This is the deal. Once you get married,
you have a fucking kids and shit.
You're never going to see anybody anyways.
So who gives a fuck?
Who gives a fuck what people think?
Go out and do what makes you happy.
Okay. As long as you're not hurting
anybody and you're not breaking a lot,
please go out and do it before.
Just being happy becomes
illegal because, uh, you know,
just the level that the
population is going in, you know,
I'm thinking by the end of my life,
I don't know what it's
going to be like over here.
I hope we don't end up like China with
China. It's so fucking over populated.
They got to like peep. Nobody drive
cars for like five fucking days.
And just the shit that they're dealing
with is a, it's brutal over there.
The white one. What are you doing? Yeah,
take the priests, take the priests.
I still have the Prius everybody up.
I'm going to be selling the car.
I just can't find the title.
So I sent,
I sent in all the forms to the DMV.
Bye.
Enjoy your smoothies in
big Hollywood phony. Bye.
All right. Um, so I send it in
to the local one and I fucked up.
Not only did I send it to the wrong DMV,
I wrote for some reason 2017 on the
checks and they thought I was trying to be
pull a fast one. So then, uh,
I ended up having to send
it up to fucking Sacramento,
some waiting for that thing so I can
finally get rid of that other fucking car.
Um, all right, here we go.
Girlfriend texts. Okay.
Hey Bill, I'm in in a bit of a
tough situation. I think you are,
you wrote in twice and we'd love
to hear your take on it. Uh,
I'm 24 years old and was recently
seeing a 33 year old girl. Whoa.
I love it.
Bought a Doodoo Doodoo do
common rub my fucking balls.
You a fucking nine years older.
Um,
for about six months, uh, within the
time span, I cheated on her twice.
I told her about it and
although she was upset,
we agreed to get back together
and start over a new, uh,
everything was relatively
fine until last week.
I went to her house before she got off
of work to do some work on a computer.
When I noticed her text messages opened.
Oh,
mac computers are usually
linked to a person's phone.
So I was able to see of her texts.
I'm sure you know by now where
this is going. Oh, Jay. Jay's,
um,
since she has gone through my text before,
I figured I would take the
same evasive liberty. Well,
you've fucked around on a twice. I would
think that she would be doing that. Uh,
I found a particularly strange thread
from someone named Lauren who am I found
out was actually her ex boyfriend and she
had it in her phone in a woman's name.
Oh God. They were sexting back and forth,
talking dirty and exchanging pictures.
I also found out she was sending
him videos of us having sex.
What the fuck?
Whoa,
dude. That's, I don't think that's legal.
Is that legal weight? Did you can
see, oh wait, how does that work?
If you could essentially let somebody,
yeah,
if you didn't know you will be in film,
but I don't think that that's legal.
This is what I do know. I'm not a
lawyer and I have no idea what the lies.
All right,
let's continue.
I confronted her on it and at first she
minimized the entire situation saying it
wasn't really that big of a deal.
Since then, we've been going back
and forth arguing, you know what,
you guys are both like not ready to be
in relationships remotely and thank God
you both found this out before
you got married and had kids.
She sends apologize,
but I'm not sure really sure what to do.
I did cheat on her.
So does that even the playing field
or is the whole thing just rooted in
disfunction and chaos? There
you go. Walk towards the light.
I can't tell if I'm just lonely and
want her in my life again or if I should
just walk away. Please help me here. I am
emotionally involved in this situation,
so it's hard to make a clear objective
call to just walk away, walk away,
and you need to do some work
on yourself because, uh,
I think you're a fucked up dude. Um,
and I'm, I'm saying this with empathy.
Uh,
you are fucked up dude who's actually
relationship guy and probably would have
just gotten married and fucking had
your own little fucking fruit stand or
whatever, but something fucked
up happened to you as a kid.
You got weird boundaries.
So you get into relationships with
dysfunctional fucking people and then you
could consider continue to fuck around
on the side and all that, that it's, um,
it's actually a very common
thing. So I would say, uh,
what you need is you need
to be single and, uh,
you need to do some work on yourself.
I may would go to therapy,
figure out what your deal is,
really figure out what the fuck it is
that you want in life and what it is that
you looking for. And then just take a
baby step everyday walking towards it.
That's what I would do, but I would
get out of this relationship. Um,
and I would give her the same advice
to, um, [inaudible]. There you go. Yeah.
Get out of it. And uh, and just know
that you're going to be fucking lonely.
But did all it takes is like, do you
know, two to three months you'll be fine.
You know what I mean?
Just make yourself go to the gym.
What you got to do is you're breaking
a routine and you fucking use to this
person being in your life.
But like the further you go
without seeing that person,
the more objective you can be.
And you can look back and then one
day you're just going to be like,
what the fuck was I thinking?
MMM.
And it can actually be funny to you or
you can really just see like, like, uh,
like what the fuck is wrong with me?
That I would do that to a person and what
is wrong with me that someone would do
that to me and I would consider staying.
Uh, you need some self esteem. Have Buddy.
Um, all right, girl with
pet rat. Oh, Jesus Christ.
Dear Billy Christmas toes.
I don't know what that means.
I've been listening to the
podcast for a long time.
I recently came into a situation that
resulted in me having to make a decision
instead of writing into you and
asking what to do in this situation.
I decided to do what I thought you would
want me to do and right in with the
results
do don't base your life on what the
fuck you'd think I would want to do.
But this is already interesting.
Last month a girl I'd
been dating got a pet rat.
Boy got a pet fucking rat.
Okay.
Is it Angelina Jolie?
Did she have a rat or if she has
Billy Bob's blood around her neck.
We had been dating for about four
months and it was going well.
I would say that if we were
together about six months,
I would have moved in with them.
We really clicked well.
She got a pet rat and I
wasn't down with that.
Not because I had a problem
with a rat in a cage,
but her taking the rat out of the cage
and holding it while we watched a movie
bill, I can barely even stand a cat
on a lap because I don't trust them.
So I voiced my concern and she laughed
them off and ended up being a bigger
argument and eventually came
back around to the wreck.
I told her it was me or the rat.
She said she'd rather me, Oh, you missed
a word here. She'd rather have me,
I guess, except it was a long
pause and some serious thought.
I really liked this girl.
And honestly,
if my devotion ever came down to choosing
between her and anything short of
family or friends, uh, would
she, are any girl ever,
except that dude you so emotional,
you skipping words here? Probably not.
They'd say bail on the guy who's not
sure if he choose you or something that
potentially spreads diseases.
Anyways, that's what happened.
Merry Christmas to the burrs.
Um,
okay.
Yeah.
But what you're doing is she loves that
rat and you're making her get rid of
something that she loves.
So there's going to be I guess a pause.
MMM.
I Dunno.
I think that it was really bugging you.
I think it was really fucking bothering
you and you let it simmer and then you
just fucking hit her with,
you know,
you are ready to talk about this for days,
weeks,
I don't know how long.
And then you just fucking caught her off
guard and she's been bonding with this
thing and you made or make a Sophie's
choice between you or the rat,
which, um, I gotta tell you,
I don't know about that move.
I Dunno about that move.
You could have easily just said,
listen,
I respect the fact that you like a rat.
Okay.
You know what the first thing I would do
is I would look up life expectancy of a
rat. All right? And I don't
mean someone that snitches,
cause I think everybody even I
know at this age is white as I am,
that snitches get stitches.
No kidding. Um, all right.
Life expectancy. What
do you guys think? Huh?
What's the overrun here?
How long can a fucking Ratliff,
I'm going to say they
live six to eight years.
You know, if those are the prices, right.
And I was the last person to fucking,
I would say six, but I'm going
to say eight, eight years.
Life expectancy of a rat.
Uh, two years, dude. It only lives
for fucking two years. All right?
This is what you say to her.
If she hasn't gotten rid of the rat,
come back and say, listen, I know
he loved that. Fucking rolling.
Um, here's the deal. The
things only live two years.
All right? I plan on being with you
in two years. Can you do me a favor?
Make this be the only rat he
ever have. All right. Okay.
She agrees to that thing and
then just put parameters.
When I come over and we're
watching sleepless in Seattle,
I don't want to have a threesome,
if you know what I mean.
Just keep it in the fucking
cage when I'm not here.
You want to roll around the floor, get
yellow fever, whatever the fuck you want,
whatever. Fuck rats. Do you want to do
that? That's fine. I just, you know,
I don't want to fucking deal
with the thing. You could've
done that, but you know,
you kind of made her like, what's
she going to do with the rat now?
Like how do you get rid of a rat?
Is there like a fucking adoption agencies
is make me feel bad about my dog again,
which is of course been brutal. I'm
not gonna talk about it. All right. Um,
yeah. You just let the fucking
thing go. Do you know those lines?
Do you know when the twins,
those people have those fucking
lions and tigers and cheetahs,
fern long enough time.
They can't release them back into the
wild because they don't even know how to
fucking hunt anymore. You know what
I mean? That really blew my mind.
They don't have to hunt anymore,
but they can murder a fucking housekeeper.
I mean, it's just, how the fuck
do you have that in the house?
There's no fucking,
this
was in Kuwait, by the way. I don't
know why I said Saudi Arabia. Kuwait.
Exotic
pet deaths.
Let's see what we got here.
Lions. Tigers to come. Problems.
Pets in golf.
MMM.
Big Cat killings. Modelings.
Big Cats escape, right?
Here we go. This is 2014 this
is a website you want to go to?
Big Cat. Big Cat rescue.
All right. Big Cat killings.
Molly's and escapes.
2000 tens before a lion.
Attacks on humans. Here's a video
I had to do. I want to watch this.
And is it weird that I root for the
fucking animals? Oh, Jesus Christ.
All right. To look at
those things. We will.
I was talking to [inaudible] and we were
talking about these big cats like those
big cats.
They literally,
the Lamborghinis and
Ferraris of fucking of cats,
you know of animals.
Oh my God.
Okay.
It's fucking,
it's got his fucking arm.
It's got his fucking arm and
he's trying to slap at it.
Oh my God.
Jesus fucking you fucking idiot.
This guy is trying to remain calm.
This is too,
there's one guy,
he's dealing with this lion
attacking him and then the fucking,
there's another guy slapping at the
fucking lion and it's got his fucking leg.
It's just sort of holding him.
He's almost away.
Oh my God. He's bucking.
Got Him again. Dude.
You should've got the fuck out of there.
Get the fuck out of there. And this guy,
he's still staying in the fucking cage.
Oh, there you go. You're fucking dope.
Oh, this is like the top 10 all right,
you got to go to this big cat rescue.org
and this is another guy. He's getting
fucking bit by this goddamn thing.
It's weird, man. When they decide
that they're going after somebody,
like the other guy can just
totally be like, get the F,
you'll the other guys like the
friend and the bark on, come on, man,
you don't need this.
You don't need this.
This thing is just going
after this one fucking dude.
Lion attack number rate. All right. Pet
in the back of the thing. He's patented.
You know, it's a fucking line. And
then boom, oh, it's got his arm.
I've seen this one.
It's got his fucking arm.
Ah.
Now his friends,
his friends are pulling.
It's a tug of war with this guy right now.
And the other guy is funny.
He tries to hit the line,
but he's too afraid to go near it.
So he keeps hitting his friend
who has it in his mouth.
Wow. Lion attacks hunter.
I've seen this one.
I don't like that one because they killed
the fucking light. Uh, Jesus Christ.
You know what I gotta be honest with you.
What you don't see in any of these
fucking videos is women that own fucking
these things. You know, guys is just such
fucking dopes. Um, anyways. All right.
That's the podcast for this week. And if
you guys miss last Thursday's podcasts,
um, you gotta tune into
rich shied. Man, Amanda,
this guy gives you basically a
standup comedy history class.
He's one of my favorite guests
I've ever had on the podcast.
I could have talked to him for like two
hours. You have to get his book. Um,
you know,
it's about his life as a standup comedian
was at walking through the ashes of
standup. My life is a stand up comedian.
You gotta get the book because, you know,
he started to tell me those Johnny the
first time he did the tonight show,
he had cocaine bag, a little Baggie
of cocaine in his fucking pocket.
He said the next time he did it,
um,
he did a joke about heart attacks and
Johnny was really nervous about having a
heart attack because he
smoked and hated them. And uh,
they made sure that he stayed in the
fucking dressing room. They're like,
you never do in the show again, and
blah, blah, blah. And all this type of,
it's fucking, the book is amazing.
Um, but you've got to listen.
Listen to the podcast. I have the links
and everything. It was last Thursday.
Pull if you're really a fan of stand
up. Um, it was just effortless.
It was one of the fastest hours
I've ever done in the podcast.
Totally fascinating. Please check it out.
It was from, uh, what's Today's date?
I don't fucking know. It was last
Thursday. Damn Bill. Let's see.
Thursday, the, uh, let's see. 11, 12, 13,
14 at the 15th. That Jesus,
Bill, come on. Can you,
can you get your shit together here? All
right. 2016. Yeah. Thursday the 15th.
Check that one out, right?
That's podcast. Go Fuck Yourself.
I'll check in on you on Thursday.