Hey, what's going on? It's bill burn.
It's time for the Monday morning
podcast for Monday, September 4th,
2017 how's it going? How? Why
you happy fucking Labor Day.
Happy Labor Day. Happy Labor Day.
You don't have to go to
fucking work unless you're
the guy that owns the fucking
business then you never
get to sleep, do ya?
You should have stuck
with your first wife,
but you threw her out and now you got a
fucking 20 something fucking car and she
wants to spend all your money.
Alright, sorry. Anyways,
how you know something you
worked hard all year. God dammit.
It's nice that you got a
fucking a Monday off, isn't it?
Don't you wish it was
the way it is in Europe?
Okay.
I don't know how they do it over there.
You know they all got
fucking health insurance.
They get like 53 weeks off a year.
Then have like the whole fucking
continent shuts down in August.
Everybody just says fuck
it. We're not working.
And somehow it keeps going.
Is it because their countries are so
small doll? Look at the little country.
Is that what it is?
Okay.
Over here is so fucking
big. You know, just a mow.
Your yard takes half the God damn summer
over here. All of us fat Fox wall,
Elon around a giant pieces of property
rad in a four wheeler shooting a guns.
You fucking live over there in
Europe, man. You get, you got nothing.
You got to flat, you know,
you and five other guys
fucking addicted to heroin.
When some baby drowns in a toilet
or whatever that fucking movie was,
you know you got nothing.
Or maybe maybe you got a house
and it's got like the fucking,
it's got that roof that looks like a
bale of hay that someone braided in.
It looks like a weave but with like,
hey, I don't know what it is over there,
but all I know is they still have castles.
Some of them still have kings and queens
and they get, they get like August off,
just off. You know when
they get free health care,
they pay a bunch of fucking
taxes. But I gotta be honest,
you pay a bunch of taxes here too. I
think it's just because we're bigger.
Got The wide open fucking roads.
I'm going to go with that.
I'm going to go with that and I'm never
going to read up about it and that's
what I'm going to say. If that topics
ever brought up like, Hey, I'll come back,
come they get all this vacation time
and if a woman as a kid over there, Raj,
she doesn't have to be backward
to work on Monday, I'll come.
That is because there are
little tiny countries, you know,
they have little tiny hospitals, you know,
a little tiny teeth that they don't
brush. You know, it's, it's, it's Europe.
What do you mean? What do you do? That's
why their cars go better into corners.
They have a little tiny streets and
they gotta they gotta zigzag around some
shit. You know that, that's basically
what it is. It's not like America.
Some woman gives birth on Friday,
the eight gene makes sure you're
fucking here on Monday, pumped that kid
out, do whatever it is you got to do.
Yeah. Have you gotten a stick?
A weed wacker of ROR a fucking reverse
blower up there and suck the kid out and
be back to work. We'll give you Monday
off. Then you gotta be here on Tuesday.
That's how it works here in America
now.
Everybody wanted his why was so fat
has nothing to do with our poison food.
We're just stressed. You know,
if you guys didn't have a whole month
to August off over there in Europe,
I'd love to see if you guys actually
had to fucking work over there and worry
about, you know, I need a new pancreas.
How am I going to afford that?
Right. Which is easily the cost
of at least three flat screen TVs.
That's the going rate for a pancreas,
if I remember correctly. All right.
If you are dealing with that stress,
I'd like to see how many fucking
doughnuts you be eating, you know, uh,
speaking of which, uh,
Billy, no fun. Billy,
no fun. His on his 18th day of not Busan,
18 days, not Booz and I
barely even remember what it
tastes like at this point.
You know, I'm dropping weight. This
is the time of night when it sucks.
Um, you know, in the morning
it's great. I wake up,
my stomach's flatter than it
was the day before. I feel good,
but it's like at night,
I mean, Sunday night,
I don't have to go to work on Monday.
I have tomorrow off like all of you
guys while you're listening to it today,
you know, you can't tell me, you know. Um,
I mean as, as a fucking human being, I
have to go out and get fucking hammered.
Right. I mean
kind of. I mean, I, if I don't die, I
mean if I was running the CIA I'd be, oh,
there's this guy in Isis, see
some sort of religious fanatic.
Oh, Billy red cakes. Oh, Billy red velvet.
I'm staying away from the
sugar. I'm being an angel.
I'm being an angel cause I
might have some act and work in,
um, in October.
So, uh, I got to make sure I'm down to
my fighting weight of my fighting weight.
A buck 72. That's what I need to
be at. Whenever I shoot something,
you know all these fucking actresses
out here talk about how it's so hard for
them is if a guy can go on and be a
bloated fat fucking nut, get shit for it.
Okay? That's not how it works.
They can get to you through social media.
They go right at you and they tell
you that you're a bloated fed.
Fuck what happened to you. You got
old, which a hair go, all of that shit.
You know what I mean? But you know,
you know what it is about people.
They look out their own
fucking heads. All right?
They look at the world
in a two dimensional way.
They look out their heads,
they observe something and then they put
it their head and they process it with
their previous experience and
then to them that is the truth.
That is what's going on in the world.
They look at it from their fucking
angle and they don't realize it.
That is 360 degrees,
which is why South Park is the greatest
fucking show of all time as far as I'm
concerned, because the matter
what problem they attack,
they hit it from all sides. The red side,
the blue side from the north to South
East, west. You know what I'm saying?
You're like dead. That was, that was
the longest fucking compliment ever. Ah,
Josh Adam Meyers from
the God damn comedy gym.
Josh Adam Meyers, Bill Barr. I'm
taping my Monday morning podcast.
You're one of our first
callers. How are you?
Good, good. I'm just curious.
I could get your opinion on the
Kyrie Irving at dad's on the street.
I wasn't aware that that happened.
Was that a big news story
in the world of sports?
Good. The little bit. Yeah. It's,
it's a few people know about it.
Uh, you know, as a, as a fucking lover
of the Celtics, as a Celtics lover.
I hated the fucking trade because I loved
Isaiah. He was like a mini big PAPI.
He was on his way. He was going to
have a street named after him. But, uh,
that it's, it's a business
now and this all goes back,
I think to the Miami Heat, all
those pile on teams back to
the Coby Shack Lakers when whenever
it stopped being bird bird, Celtics,
magic Lakers, Isaiah fucking, uh,
Pistons Jordan with the
Bulls and everybody just
jumped around. Now it's over.
I thought you wouldn't
ask about the cigar.
I am. That's what I
was saying. I was like,
do you want me to give you some time
so you can finish this up and then,
no, I don't give a shit.
Just ring the doorbell and I'll
stop and I'll finish it later.
All right. Costing a little bit.
Alright. Don't, I don't ring the doorbell.
My daughter's sleeping. Just text me.
All right. See Ya. Um, anyways,
the most roundabout compliment
ever for South Park.
I had no idea it was going to say
that. So a, I am, as of this morning,
I bought 179 pounds in
six ounces, one 79.6.
So I'm trying to lose three weeks and
next week on Friday, I need to be, uh,
I need to be one 77. I right.
Just said he hit pause him in the fucking
dog house. I just woke up my daughter.
Oh my God, my wife is
fucking pissed at me, boy.
[inaudible] all right.
This is the Monday morning podcast
and I'm gonna be fucking whisper.
And for the rest of this God damn
thing, um, that was, I talked to my,
yes.
So next week I want to be 177 pounds by
a Friday and then one 74 the next week,
and then I'll be one 71 and
then if I get this acting Gig,
I'll be where I need to be. Um,
so I was going to take a month off from
boozy, but if I get this acting Gig,
then I'm just not going to booze like
right on through to the end of the fucking
shoot. And then when
that's over, okay. Uh,
I'm gonna get like one of those kegerators
and I'm gonna fill it up with fucking
whiskey
and I'm going to be underneath it
and it's gonna be glorious. Um,
I dunno. I Dunno what
my fucking problem is.
I should go to a meeting and
just see what that's like.
I went to a meeting a long time ago and
I got arrested for drinking and driving
and one of the requirements was you
had to go to a, uh, an AA meeting,
two of them or something like that. Um,
all I remember, I was just like,
these guys are fucking drunks.
I mean I drink, I don't,
I don't fucking drink.
These guys had like lunacy stories.
Yeah.
Talking about like fucking bleeding out
their ass and going right to the liquor
store and the next day, you know what
I mean? Like not eating food for Mike.
Just crazy.
Yeah.
Crazy, crazy fucking stories. So I
just was sitting there going, I am
okay.
I'm just a drunk. These
people got a fucking problem.
I'm telling you right now, if you
ever just want to see, you know,
some of the most fucked up people on
the planet, just go to an AA meeting.
These fucking people, man. You know,
if fingers are like stuck together
from like cigarette smoke,
you know what I mean? They got
like, they just, you know, I can be,
I'm just being an asshole. I have no
idea what a fucking AA meetings like.
And it looks like you get like a little
trinket if you'd do it for awhile,
you know, get six days, you know,
he Shah flagging, you know,
you know, addictive people.
They're, they're fucking, they can never
stop talking about themselves. Right.
So I think it's got to
go up there. Oh my God,
I'm gonna get so much shit
for this. I don't give a fuck.
I think it's about time. Somebody
fucking put a in its place, right?
Once you grow up in white
knuckle it, like the rest of us,
you've got to go join a fucking group
and everybody sits down and fucking makes
an Afghan together. Um, you know,
it's funny that I actually
would love to be part of a group
when I went golfing up the,
this past week, you know,
and I went with a buddy of mine and he
was like a member of a country club and
like, this is fucking cool.
It's really cool. You know,
bunch of guys could fucking
talk shit, having a great time.
All that shit that everybody fucking
gives you a rough time for, you know,
they always make fun of guys hanging out.
Now if they all hang out
together like they do,
there has to be like mocked for
some fucking reason. It's fun.
You just sit around
breaking each other's balls.
That's all it was. I
went there and it was,
everybody was fucking cool and everybody
was just busting chops the whole
fucking time.
And then you go out and
golf and everybody's just
giving each other shit and
you're laughing and you smoking cigars
and you're gambling and shit. It's,
it's fun for whatever fucking reason.
I don't know if he, if you do that now,
I don't know for some reason
that that's attacked. You know,
I don't, I don't know what
the, I don't know what it is.
I don't know what the fuck
is you supposed to be doing,
but I can tell you I did enjoy it.
Um, and speaking of enjoying shit,
I know I'm all over the map.
Um,
I found I got caught up with the last,
do you know today's Formula One
race and uh, the previous one,
like a week ago or two weeks ago,
I missed it and I have to tell you,
I loved the force India team before I
watched the previous race and now I,
I will fucking love that team forever.
I will love that fucking team forever.
It at the very least,
Esteban O'Connor and Sergio
Perez, everybody else was fucking,
was racing to not lose, you
know, didn't want to fuck up.
These fucking guys went in
there. You know what I mean?
You ever watch a hockey fight
and the guys is so good at it.
They barely even punch each other.
The best ones is where you just,
you grabbed my shoulder,
I grabbed your shoulder.
We just fucking beat the shit
out of each other. You know,
that's what these guys did. They went
old time hockey with like racing.
They're on the same team. They
slammed into each other twice.
They don't even give a
fuck that it's a teammate.
This was like some sort of bloodsport
that they were doing everybody else's out
there. Like, oh my God,
that's my teammate. I need to,
I'm really literally making fun of the
other teams for actually doing the smart
thing. I love that they did it.
I love last year when Hamilton
and a fucking a Nicki Minaj,
whatever his fucking name was, I
can't remember this fucking name.
What the hell's guy's name.
Okay,
Nikki, I want it now. I'm
taking my toys and going home.
I'm getting married now. Rosberg right,
Nico Rosberg that's what it was
when they slammed into each other.
They did that a couple
of times. I liked that.
And I love how these fucking drivers,
there's all of these shit where they
don't like each other. This, you know,
like Sebastian Vettel
doesn't like Lewis Hamilton.
Kimi Raikkonen doesn't
like Valtteri Botox. It's,
it literally is fucking days a
thunder. It's tremendous. And a,
this past week's race was
great. Uh, yesterday as far
as watching a lance straw,
getting, uh, 18 years old.
These lined up in the front
row next to Lewis Hamilton,
who's just the fucking greatest
driver. He just is. He is.
I know Mercedes has the best fucking
cars right now, but you know,
give me a fucking break. It's not like
Ferrari's and he's sort of a slouch.
Right? I Dunno. You could argue
that Daniel Ricardo's just as good.
He's just not riding. Driving a car was
good. Maybe that's what the fuck it is.
I don't know what it is,
but I really enjoyed yesterday's
race and the previous one. Um,
how do you not love force India
out there with the pink cars?
The few Chicago slamming into each other.
It looked like me and my
brother had a fucking carnival
that we'd be like, those two guys are
related. Like you would know. We would,
if we got into bumper cars, we
would, no, I didn't give a fuck
about anybody else out there other
than slamming into my own fucking
family member. What was the
point of hitting somebody else?
I couldn't laugh at them in the car
ride home. I'd never see him again. Um,
so anyways, I guess they go to
Singapore next one of these years.
I'm going to line up a stand up
date with that race over there. Um,
I'm going to try and go to a couple
a year cause I'm a fucking lunatic.
So I went to Montreal this year and I'm
also going to the race in, um, Austin,
Texas, um, provided
there's not another, uh,
you know, fucking hurricane like that
one that hit Houston. Jesus Christ.
Um, anyways, I actually, you know,
I want to show to tweet
out something you guys,
there was actually something we could
send like fucking diapers and that type of
stuff for our kids.
Can't imagine it about that as babies
and everything you got to take care of.
Um, that seemed like a really
cool thing to do. The very least.
At least you could fucking
dope. So, uh, anyways,
I'm behind with my MotoGP racing.
I gotta get caught up on that. Um,
but I have to be, I
have to be honest, this,
this race in Italy was one of my favorite
races just because of what was going
on in like position four, five, and
six fucking lunatic racing. And, uh,
I just wish they could somehow
do something to the cars that,
that happened in the first and
second position because once again,
Lewis Hamilton, you know,
he gets to the first corner first he comes
out in first place and then that's it
. He's in the front of the race
for the rest of the fucking race.
And then that's just it. It's
over. He's driving in clean air.
His car's too fucking fast.
Now you've got to hope that the
car breaks down or he fucks up,
which isn't going to happen. And, um,
but I did enjoy all that other stuff.
But uh, congratulations to Lewis
Hamilton for winning another one.
He now is the head of Sebastian Vettel
and I believe the Mercedes team as a team
is ahead of everybody else too. So
they're fucking crushing it. And a,
I think it's going to be
all downhill from here.
So I'm hoping the fucking
Ferrari team, cause they,
the closest ones can step it up. And a,
I like both those guys. I like Kimmy,
Kimmy Raycon now he seems fucking pissed
off getting penalties and shit. Um,
I relate to the angry guys.
That's why I like force India.
They're going to fucking slam
into each other. It's tremendous.
It's tremendous. You know,
it's childish. It's stupid.
I love when that guy who the
former race car fucking champion,
I don't know what his name is. The
commentary just goes, Oh da boys boys.
What are you doing a buy baby? Every
gets all like fucking parental with them.
I wanted to see, I watched the
qualifying to, I love when it rains out
to all,
I forgot the greatest quote I've heard
since I started watching formula racing
after the fucking four Sindia
cars hit for the second time.
I think it was that old card
guy. He, she says over his radio,
he goes to his fucking
crew chief for whatever. He
goes, what the fuck? Seriously,
what the fuck? Like flipping and meanwhile
he's going like 180 miles an hour.
He sounds like me when I drive to work
and he's doing like, you know, 180,
200 miles an hour and he's, they fucking
flip each other off. They never flip.
He jets, you know, the
European and shit, they,
they give the a little
blue with the fucking hand.
Somebody's got to flip somebody
off. You know what I mean?
Or if they write on their ass, slam on
the brakes like you do on the highway.
Stop fucking tailgating. I wasn't
tailgating. I was drafting. All right,
enough of this shit. I know a lot of
you guys don't even watch this shit,
but I'm all right, let's
plow ahead here. I, uh,
I was, um, did it casino, I
already forget the name of it.
Um, I was in a casino, uh,
right outside of San Diego and I did it
two years ago and I flew down in our 44
and today, oh, yesterday I flew in a, uh,
I don't even know what the fuck
it was to be honest with Ya.
Let me see if I can look up
the name of this helicopter.
This helicopter was turbine engine,
which is a jet engine. And uh,
it was fucking on. The
whole thing was hydraulic.
I fucking gives a fuck
with what helicopter was.
So basically I trained on the [inaudible].
Our 22 is like driving a car
that has drum berry, drum brakes,
no power steering. You know what I mean?
And you have to like fucking control
the wipers yourself. You know,
like the 1920s, like Laurel and hardy,
you got to like move it side to side.
Um, which is also why I love that
thing because you're really flying.
If you hold in a hover your fucking
doing it, then you move up to the RF 44.
And this is kind of weird
where it's like the, uh,
the collective and the cyclic
of both hydraulic. Okay.
That's your power and then how you
steer the shit you hold with your hands
basically. And then if for whatever
reason your foot pedals are,
are not hydraulic, they just
manually your own precious.
So you're dealing with
like really finessing it,
barely having to touch it up top and
then your drum breaks down the bottom.
It's just, it's a very odd feeling.
And I fly out of Burbank
and there's always a fucking
tailwind when you're going
into set it down. It's so
fucking annoying. Like right
behind you. Full blast.
I don't know where it comes from. Um,
every time. In fact, I saw this
student that was learning over there.
What he would do once he, when he
would go to set it down, he would just,
he would just face the wind and set
it down and then go inside and get the
wheels and then put 'em on the thing and
then just turn the helicopter around.
As much as it was funny, I was
like, that's a great fucking idea.
I would rather do that, you know, cause
you're landed next to other helicopters.
I don't want to fuck anybody else's shit
up. Sweaty was this thing was like a,
was like a six and a, I've
got a picture, you know,
Dean del Ray, go look him up on Twitter.
He's teed, tweeted out a picture,
I'll fucking, I'll retweet it.
And it's like, the word is,
I'm standing in front of the
coolest helicopter I ever flew in.
I'm talking when somebody, whoever took
the picture. So I looked like a fucking,
I may look like an asshole
anyways. Whose kid? No. Um,
but it was,
I would say the most
amazing machine I've ever
gotten the chance to
operate. And it was like,
it was like a sports car in the
air with like, like the tightest,
most responsive fucking suspension you
could possibly think of without the rough
ride because you're not on the ground,
you just go in through the air.
It didn't feel any turbulence
whatsoever. And um,
I just know when you take off in the
year 22 and you push the stick forward,
right? I mean, I don't know how
long it is. It's a good eight,
nine seconds until you want to get
up to 53 knots. That's the optimal,
you know,
speed to get out to get the most rate
of climb and it takes you a good,
I feels like forever eight, nine
seconds, this fucking thing.
It was like maybe two and a half
seconds and it was up to speed.
You just pulled the stick back and
you fucking shot up in the air.
I've never been, it was really
intimidating. But once I just sort of,
I watched my instructor
and I've two times do that,
the start and startup and shutdown of it
and it's like, it's, it's not that bad.
It's just intimidating at first. And then
you get, once you know where to look,
which is basically your manifold pressure,
your altitude and how fast you're going,
and then also your trim once you know
where those are all the other shit.
It's just like, well, you know,
a fucking horn is going to go off if
there's a problem anywhere else. Right.
Anyways, it was fun as shit and
went down and we did the Gig and um,
I think I'm going to start
doing that. Like, um,
I'm doing a podcast festival for the
all things comedy network in the end of
October. And if I don't get
this acting Gig and I'm in La,
I'm going to fly out in a
helicopter. I got a Vegas Gig,
I'm going to do that one in the
helicopter too. And that way I can get my,
keep my hours up, stay current and
a while going out, making money.
So I'm renting the helicopter,
but I'm earning money, right?
And in a way I get to fly private without
having to blow all this money on a
fucking stupid ass jet,
which is stupid, right?
Those fucking private jets is fucking
stupid as hell you in and you can't even
stand up. It's the dumbest
thing ever. You're way better.
You could spend one 90th the money on a
first-class fucking ticket and you are
in a a, you're on like a fucking
cruise ship. You can stand,
you can stand up when you take a piss.
You don't have to bend over
at the fucking neck, you know?
I know they make bigger jets, but
those things are like, you know,
you're going to fly from Boston to Rhode.
It's going to cost you like a fucking
$300,000. I don't know how people,
I don't know anybody flies
private to be honest with you.
I have no fucking idea. I'm
just go to a mom and pop airport,
get on jet blue or virgin.
That's the way to do it. Use some miles,
bump yourself up to a bigger seat.
You're going to get a pilot who's psyched?
He's making a ton of fucking money.
You get on those little ones, those
[inaudible] people and I'm making shit.
Yeah,
right. I don't know. That's been, that's
been my experience. They're trying to,
they're trying to get a gig flying one
of the bigger ones so they can actually
make money instead of flying
some little fucking six cedar.
Okay.
But you know what it is. I'm
out of my fucking element.
I don't know anything about that shit.
I just have heard about how much it
fucking costs. All right, let me, uh,
let me read the, um, let
me read the fucking, uh,
advertising here for this week. Uh,
all right, what do we got here? Oh,
draft kings. Everybody Gay. Do
you like to gamble on sports?
You want to make some fucking
money? These are the guys.
It's not too late to get closer to the
game you love with draft kings one week
fantasy football. This Sunday
draft kings is hosting a
$100,000 pick contest that is
totally free to enter. Alright?
Pick them as the newest way to
play. One week fantasy football.
Drafting your team is faster than ever.
Draftkings has organized
players into eight tiers.
All you have to do is select
one player from each tier.
Choose between public contests,
choose between public contest with big
cash prizes or private contests where con
private contest, sorry, where you can
compete against a group of your friends.
Dr King's also has the beginner and
casual contest where you can play against
people of a similar skill level.
The best part is you get to draft a new
team each week without any commitment.
So get to draftkings.com now and use
Promo code bird to play in draftkings free
contests with a hundred thousand dollars
dollars in total prices this Sunday.
Use My Promo Code [inaudible] you
are to play for free this Sunday.
That's Promo Code bar@draftkings.com
eligibility restriction supply.
See draftkings.com for details. Speaking
of which the New England patriots,
the five times Superbowl
defending champions,
um,
the they offer the often criticized
for absolutely no fucking reason.
You know,
all the time I had another guy
bring up fucking deflate gate.
I always tell them, it's like they did
not get convicted of deflating balls.
You fucking moron.
That was laughed at at court
for the 90 million at the time.
And then the suspension
was, was, was canceled.
Remember that he was supposed to be
suspended and they took it to court and it
was laughed out of court and
the judge said, you're wasted.
Why did you waste my fucking time
with this? That's what happened.
And then you know, the
United States of America,
you can not get tried
twice for the same offense.
That's a hearsay
something or other, right? You can't be,
you can't be fucking double jeopardy.
You can't fucking do that.
So the NFL found a loophole,
they just went back to court and
said, uh, is the NFL and corporation.
And the judge was like,
yes. And then they said,
does a corporation have the
right to suspend its employee?
And the judge said yes. And they
said, fine, where corporation,
Tom Brady is our employee and he is
suspended. And that's what they did.
Yeah.
That's why he got suspended, not
because they proved anything.
You fucking dopes. And by the way, the
guy who caught the, the, the alleged,
by the way, under inflated
fucking ball, by the way,
the cults also allegedly had 200
flighty balls. But who gives a fuck?
Then I went in all the
championships, right?
The guy who caught the ball
tested positive for steroids
this past season. Ah,
nobody gives a shit. All right,
Luke crate everybody. Luke Craig,
be the envy of your friends
and get 100% exclusive
crates@lukecrate.com slash x
x x and enter my code x x, X.
Well, I guess I got the
wrong fucking copy, didn't I?
Uh, I don't know what to do
with this exactly. What is this?
I never know what this fucking gobble.
I'm just going to read it and get x, x,
x amount of dollars off
any new subscription.
September's loot crate theme is
robotic on a quest for epic gear,
housewares and collectables
loot crate has it.
Luke crate offers an epic range of pop
culture items for less than $20 a month.
If you're more of a fanatical
fashion Easter than try loot where?
Monthly wearable and accessories
with cult classics and your favorite
franchises.
If you want to get fancy getting bigger
box and an even bigger loop with Luke
Craig DX, want to geek out
your pet. Try loop pets.
Offer expires September
19th at 9:00 PM Pacific,
whether they be per speak.
Many of your favorite characters are
robotic and September's Luke. Great.
You'll find items from star wars,
Star Trek, aliens and blade runner.
Let me see only of those robots. I
can name. C three p. O r Two d two
r five d four. That's
a, that's a good one.
That's like naming an
offensive lineman. Uh,
there was that one on fucking buck
Rogers Smith, that stupid thing.
Bidi Bidi Bidi Bidi remember that before?
Talk to go Bidi Bidi Bidi Bidi
and then it would say something
that I'd never understood it.
Somebody sat in a writers
room and pitched that.
What if the robot said Bidi Bidi Bidi
Bidi and then said what he was going to
say. It somehow there wasn't like
a deafening amount of silence.
It'd be like, what the fuck did you just
say? Get out of this room. All right.
One lucky subscriber will also win
a mega crate of seriously epic.
You have until the 19th September 19th
at 9:00 PM Pacific to subscribe and
receive that month's crate. And when
the cutoff happens that it's, that's it,
it's over.
Go to [inaudible] dot com slash burn enter
my code bur bur to save $3 off on any
new subscription today. I wish I had more
information on that, but I don't. Um,
all right, here we go. What do we got? Ah,
[inaudible] me on days. Who remembers
our five d four [inaudible] do,
do me on these me on days.
They even make them for the whores
nice and soft up against your Twat.
You know, you fucking love it.
Don't say it's not nice and
comfy up against your snatch
and they make them even
for your ball bag. They'll take
out the wrinkles. I'm all right.
Me. DCE you want to look good in your
underwear and be comfortable, right?
Right. But that perfect
balance is hard to find.
Don't sacrifice style or comfort.
Checkout me undies.com and find the
best pair of underwear in the world.
Talk about why me on these is the
best underwear you will ever own.
Feel free to improvise a Jesus cry.
I don't fucking know because it feels
good up against your under carriage.
You know what I mean? You know when you
go to buy a car and then they go, hey,
you want to, you want to get the fucking
undercoating. This is the undercoating.
You know you bite a pair of pants, right?
What are you going to have you going to
have you fucking Levis chafing and up
against your junk? He can't have that.
It'd be great if there was some fucking
soft velvety Greg Louganis speedo type
of underwear out there with thank God
there is with me undies for the Fellas,
me undies, diamond seen
pouch, a ran stone ball bag,
cradles your jewels and gives you stuff
to support it needs without feeling too
tight. You know, I love about
that song rhinestone cowboy.
I love when he goes, uh, what does it
ever has? Tall Cowboy Dah, Dah, Dah, Dah,
Dah, Dah, Dah, Dah. Total. Oh yeah.
And he goes and offers coming over the
phone offers coming over the phone.
You only have the,
you have to be in fucking show business
or be self employed to know how great
that line is. Offers come in over the
phone after years of having your hat,
your hand begging the fucking do anything
to finally get to that level where
people actually want you and you
get to stand there and be like,
you like me to really like me. All right,
so you got diamond and
crusted balls, right?
A ladies will love the
soft ecofriendly fabric.
What did my screen go?
So soft and touchable.
Gross 100% satisfaction guarantee.
I don't know why they talk about their
fucking pussies and they have so soft and
touchables. It makes me feel like a creep.
100% satisfaction guarantee sells off
the touch upon the guarantee you will
love. We guarantee. They guarantee
that you'll love your, uh,
your undies or your money back. Right now,
Mandy's has an exclusive offer for
just my listeners and anybody else.
They advertise with the fucking horse.
Get 20% off your first and free shipping
and the undies is so sure you will love
your their underwear. They even offer
100% satisfaction. Guarantee your order,
you order a pair. And if you don't love
your first pair, get a full refund.
This is a no brainer to try 20% off free
shipping in our percent satisfaction
guarantee. What fuck are you waiting
for? Fuck. Could you wait for buddy a,
you want to have soft nuts under your
fucking overalls when you got your bunk
shotgun, that little front pocket,
is that what that front
pockets for and overalls,
that little thing there is that
where they put their buckshot. Um,
it's great. It's nice and snug doesn't
fall out when a mom a four way look a,
this is limited. This
is a limited time offer.
So what the fuck are you waiting for?
Start wearing the best goddamn
underwear of your life.
It changed my life evidently
according to the copy.
It's time to let me unease change yours.
Go to [inaudible] dot com slash
burn right fucking now. All right.
Dollar Shave Club, dude. Oh my God.
They never proved that the
balls were underinflated,
um, every which they
didn't. By the way, uh,
everyone knows dollar shave club
ship's amazing raises for a few bucks.
What you might not know is that dollar
shave club also has products to pretty
much, uh, for pretty much everything
else you need in the bathroom. Body Wash,
shampoo, Hair Gel, lip balm,
everything at the store.
There are too many options and you
can't tell the difference between any of
them. It's overwhelming. You feel like
Robin Williams and Moscow on the Hudson,
right when he walks into the grocery
store and he fucking faints and he sticks
his head up that girl's dress. You
remember that, um, at the store,
the too many options. You can't tell
exactly where he said that. All right.
Then if you have any questions,
that clerk usually doesn't know the
difference and usually can't fucking find
them cause they got a skeleton crew
at nine in the morning. Now, um,
they're not implicit, not
experts on the products.
A dollar shave clubs makes it easy and
convenient for you to upgrade your shave
and your bathroom.
Now you don't have to step foot in a
store to get high quality shave and
grooming products. Deloach Shave Club
delivers them right to your door. Uh,
if you're sick of the
nonsense at the store,
now's the time to try dollar
Shave Club for limited time.
Dollar Shave Club is basically
giving away their shit.
Shower shave started set to new members.
This is why I Love Dollar Shave Club.
They just put curses in there.
They've got a shit shower,
shave started set for
new members for only $5.
This start a set features their
executive razor. This is just brilliant.
This is just for all single guys
shit, shower, shave. There you go.
Pack it all up and three
trial size versions of their
most popular products that
help you stay fresh and clean
and clean, so fresh and so clean.
And your first box you received the
fuckin shave butter body wash and one wipe
Challies, one wipe challis butt wipes.
You will also receive
their executive razor,
which includes their
premium weighted hand,
weighty handle and full
cassette of cartridges.
After the first box replacement
cartridges are sent for only a few bucks a
month. This offer is exclusively
available@dollarshaveclub.com slash burr.
That's dollar shave
club.com. Dollar Shave clubs,
high quality products will have you
covered from phase to cheek to butt cheeks
from face, cheeks to buttcheek.
Sorry. There is no better time
to fucking try the club now.
My God, there's still one
more. Sorry. Pro Flowers,
pro flowers with the, you can get
somebody flowers for Labor Day.
Talk about the last time you spontaneously
surprised someone was something
completely unexpected and how it felt. Um,
I remember I stuck this gun in this
little kid's face one time and I was like,
I'm gonna fucking kill you.
And his parents were freaking
out and uh, oh my God.
Did I laugh?
Talk about what the Rose Bouquet recently
sent to you by profile was look like
in o your overall impression of
it. Well, I didn't get one and uh,
so I have no impression of
it. Sounds Nice. Maybe Andrew.
Got It. Do you have any more requests
than can I just read this shit?
Pro Flowers wants to help you
surprise someone for no reason at all,
while also surprising you with this
special deal. For my listeners, know,
pro flowers wants to sell flowers during
months when you don't have to sell
them. You don't have to. You
know what the fuck by him.
That's why they want you. We want you
to buy our shit. Just say, listen,
we got a ton of fucking flowers
left over from mother's Day.
Can you buy these things before they die?
We got a great fucking deal for you and
if you fucking give them to your wife
for no goddamn reason at all, she's
probably gonna blow you. Okay?
This is what should be in
the copy. Instead of this,
get 20% off any of their unique summer
rose bouquets or any other boot K for $29
their colorful rainbow
roses are always a hit.
And if you aren't sure what to
send someone profiles, boot cares,
you are guaranteed to last
at least seven days. Guys,
just fucking do this for your
wife. It's easy. All right.
Go to proflowers.com use my code name
bar. Do you want to get a blow job?
I may be a little handy at the fucking,
I hop onto the table to make the table
a little more sticky. Gross. Sorry.
This is what you need to do. All the
dopes. Buy Flowers on mother's Day.
They buy them on fucking, you know,
birthdays and they buy them on, on,
on fucking Valentine's Day. All right.
If you want to up your blow jobs,
if you want to stay up in
the pros and hit 300. Okay?
You got to spray it all
over the field. All right,
so one of these times you just, you just
can't, it's August. Is it September?
Yes. Who gets their fucking wife
or girlfriend flowers in September?
Nobody be the person that fucking does
it and get your Dick sucked today.
All right, there you go. All
right. Booze lineup. Oh, beautiful.
I was hoping people gonna send
these in. All right. I um,
I talked last week on, you know, I
get back into baseball and a Yankees,
red sox things heating up again.
We'd better meet in the playoffs.
It's has to happen. It's
been too fucking long. Um,
I ended up fucking Yankees
took three out of four,
so I broke even all this shit-talking
all of this fucking shit talking and it
just, we ended up just being
even, um, but I was talking about,
you know, just watching baseball. I
did my booze lineup of like whiskeys,
scotches, and bourbons. All right.
I don't just do scotches. Okay.
This isn't like the fucking, this isn't
MLB when Babe Ruth played. All right,
this is any, anybody can
show up as long as you brown.
Now Tequila is also welcome. Um,
so this would be my lineup. Uh,
I always change the lineup.
I would say this week, uh,
Johnnie Walker blue was leading off.
You got to start with some strong shit,
right? Pappy van Winkle is in second,
and then I would put a
angel's envy at third.
MacCallum rare cass. Rare cask
is baton cleanup. All right?
Then I'd have Yippy Kai, Yay.
Fifth.
And then once she gets in the middle
of this is just when I just want to get
fucked up. Right. Those
other ones. Angels.
Entities also want a good one just
to get fucked up on, you know,
it's not that expensive either. Then
you get to the middle of the order,
but it's like I'm staying at home
and I'm getting drunk by myself,
or I'm getting drunk with a friend of
mine that it appreciates good whiskey,
bourbon or whatever. When I get in the
middle, then it's like [inaudible],
patroned silver. Maybe I put grand
patrol where I put angel's envy.
That's why I got that. Okay. Grant
patrol it fucking the third spot.
Then I got [inaudible],
then I got fucking angel's envy
and then Johnny Walker Black.
Okay. Those are the next three.
So then you've got eight and
nine and that's when you know,
you just have fucking, yeah,
just people coming over and they just
want to get shit faced and you just got to
go maker's Mark Fucking, uh, Jack Daniels,
you know? And then if you just
have a complete fucking shit at,
do you just give him Red Label?
Fucking Johnny Walker. All right,
so here's this person's Booz
lineup. All right. He goes,
I love your idea about doing a
booze alcohol battling lineup.
Here's my submission leading off
Kentucky Tavern. I'd never heard of this.
This is what I love. It's going to
give me new shit to try. Dependable,
a little rough around the edges,
but you know this guy's going to get
on base at a 400 clip even if he has to
lean into one every now and then.
I love that this person broke it all down
and give me a scouting reports to when
you send these in [inaudible] second
core nitos. What the fuck is that?
Juanito's a can be streaky at times,
but still has a little bit of a pop if
you mix it with grapefruits. Soda, Dude,
Jersey and your second guy, you're
already mixing it with something.
Okay.
Alright. Oh Shit. Hang on
a second. Speaking of that,
some Josh just asked me if
I had soda. No, I don't.
I got to do a voice text here.
Get the Phanta orange
with the Mexican sugar.
There you go. All right.
Okay.
That's right. When I'm fucking not booze
and I actually drink Fanta Orange Soda.
It's kind of nice cause it's really sweet.
And then you got the smoke. You know,
it's not redundant.
Remember big night when that lady got the
pasta and then she also ordered mashed
potatoes and the guy wouldn't do it
cause it was two starches. You know,
why would you have a cigar and
then drink something really PD.
It's like fucking redundant. You want
some, a sweet kind of alcohol, um,
fucking with you. I'm not actually,
I do. Okay. So batting third,
this guy has bullet. This
is your franchise player.
He makes everyone around
him a little better.
Plus he's going to give
you a team friendly,
longterm contract that won't
have you paying luxury taxes.
Do this guy's great. You know, we took
a funny idea. Now he's taken it to,
he didn't even funnier
level. All I did was just,
I got to break down each player now.
All right. Batting Cleanup Knob Creek.
He goes, can you tell I'm a bourbon
drinker. I can never keep them straight.
Egos. Bottom line is if there's
any ducks left on the pond,
this guy is there to deliver
it. And the knockout punch.
I gotta tell you the way
he's describing this lineup,
he's definitely making the playoffs.
If not fucking winning the pennant.
I'm batting fifth Smirnoff vodka. Okay?
Definitely nothing to write home about,
but when surrounded with
the right personnel,
there's always potential for magic. You
know what my vodka is? My goto vodka.
I like Belvedere. Oh,
Belvedere, come here, boy.
I like that better than grey
goose. Grey goose is just like,
that's like soft rock, like easy
listening. You know what I mean?
I like Belvedere. It's got a little
more of a fucking bite to it,
but I don't know much about vodka is
either a batting six Johnny Walker black.
Now you might be now. Might
be a good time dimension.
I'm in my early thirties thank goodness
this guy is a September call up.
You're not quite ready to add them
to your 40 man roster just yet.
Buddies for a cup of,
but he's up for a cup of coffee because
you know he's going to be an important
part of your future. Yeah. Maybe you
can get on base and steal second.
All right. Batting seventh. Oh
Jesus do this is unforgivable.
If you're in your thirties,
this is unforgivable and I respect you
that you can still drink this Yeager
meister. Wow. Wow.
You often find yourself wondering why
this guy is even still around and yet you
feel you can Burma you
wait and yet you can,
you feel like you can remember a time
when he was actually pretty good. Yeah.
He's like the fucking, uh, one
of those guys. We had just like,
you know, like Vince Carter still plan.
It's not fair to Vince Carter because
Vince Carter was one of the greatest
fucking, you know, I think the
best dunker of all fucking time.
High of certainly the
highest jumper. I Apologize,
I shouldn't have said Vince Carter was
the first guy I thought of. He is like a,
uh, uh, up. Do you have moon?
Do you ever one like Giobbie was
playing on the Colorado Rockies.
It's like one of those deals. All
right. Captain Morgan Batting Eighth,
definitely a role player. This,
this I, that's like your catcher.
This guy could be a superstar,
but he's got a bit of a sweet tooth
and always shows up to spring training,
20 pounds overweight. Now he's
the panda still. You know,
he's good for a sac flying
a key situation. Yeah. One
of these guys just has to,
you're out there for defense, you know,
he's not hitting for average. Alright.
Batting ninth, wild
Turkey, American honey,
and he writes old ggs a,
you ask him to lay down a bunt and you
just know he's going to hit into an
inning ending double play every
damn time. Uh, by the way, if it's,
if it's a close one,
I'm putting in buffalo trace in place
of Jaeger as a defensive substitution
through this guy's brilliant. So
that's my lineup. Thanks for the idea.
I enjoyed putting this together.
Even if you don't read it now, Dude,
I love that you broke it all down. All
right, here's another guy's lineup.
All right. His whiskey
lineup. Bullet, Eagle,
rare batting third macallan 12
batting fourth angel's envy,
cask strength. I never had that.
D h a I might fuck up some
of the names of these. Uh,
Bell Bell. Vinny, 12 years, single malt.
Glen Levitt, French Oak. I can't deal
with the florals. I don't like the floors.
I like more that PD thing.
Like the Glen Levitz.
I'd never been able to a quite
handle this, but I, I respect them.
They are definitely in the
hall of fame of booze. Um,
oh fuck. He's going to stop by a Taco. Oh,
Jesus Christ. What is he
talking about? No, fuck.
He's gonna stop by Taco truck to get the
fucking booze. No, no, no, no, no, no.
The soda I made. Hang on, let me
hit pause and straighten this up.
All right, I'm back. So anyways,
uh, Glen Levitt, French oak,
six number seven, Willie pots. Still
Reserve. Never heard of that one.
Number eight, Jefferson's
ocean aged at. See Jesus.
Sounds like low tide
shit to me. Number nine,
Hudson Bay starting pitcher is blends.
I've got to do a starting
pitcher. Middle Reliever, uh,
giving you a re a reliable
couple innings makers.
46 closer is Alijah
Craig barrel proof. Dude,
I love everybody going
with the starting pitchers.
Then you got to have your
middle Raliegh. Eylea yeah,
actually actually had middle relief. Oh
my God, Dude. This is, this is endless.
And then you don't see, you're
gonna get some real big time.
Booz hounds that nine, you know,
positions in the batting lineup,
but not going to be enough. They're
going to have to go thick enough to like,
I dunno, do like a a football
team. 11 offensive players.
This isn't fair to people
over in Europe. Go ahead,
give me your fucking lineups and use
all the fucking soccer terminology.
Maybe I'll learn something. All right
is another not last booze line up here.
Dear Billy, no fun. No fuss, no Muss,
no brainer in answer to your requests
for our batting lineups of booze.
I'm not much of a drinker anymore,
so I'll go the other way and
do my recreational drug lineup.
I love it. I love it. You guys have
taken this idea and running with it.
This is tremendous. All right. Number one,
weed number two, black hash,
preferably from Nepal. Number
three, magic mushrooms.
Batting cleanup, LSD, preferably purple.
Owsley never tried it, but
according to Ken Casey,
it was the best number five,
ecstasy, pure and uncut.
Number six, ketamine. I don't
want this number seven, cocaine,
pure and uncut cocaine. Pure on
up unconscious should be fucking,
that sounds like a speedster, man. Get
him on base. He fucking still second.
You have LSD. Fucking bring them
home with a single door, right?
I don't know. Running on a full count.
You're not going to catch that guy.
He might score from first.
All right, number eight,
peyote pot number nine,
masculine, pure and uncut.
Hey Bill, on Thursday you were talking
about the sound of drums in the 70s.
I watched this recently and thought
it would be informative to you over
overhead, Mike with a compressor on
it. Um, you guys have to watch this.
If you're in, are there
any type of music? I actually
watched this thing and it's,
do you know that sound
of a Phil Collins Drums,
the famous drum fill from in the air
tonight that Gaga go, go, go, go good.
Don't, don't dumb. And it was,
you got to watch this video,
how they came up with that drum sound was
an accident and then everybody used it
and it literally became the sound
of the 80s. And now it's back.
I guess Taylor swift used it in
some song called 1989 and all that.
But if you just, if you're
into that nerdy audio stuff,
like I found this out great. My
fucking drum teacher, Davy Lich is,
I was tuning up my drums, you know,
I got some back east and says old
Slingerland kit and it's a a third,
a 12. Wait, no, a nine
by 13, 14, and an 18.
It was 13, 14,
Tom's and then an 18 inch
floor and a 24 inch kick.
And I ended up adding another, I've
found a, uh, from the same era,
a 16 inch floor Tom. And then
I added another base drum.
So I got to 20 fours. All right.
This is my first attempt to get,
to try and get away from just aping and
doing a bad job of everything John Bonam
did. I was getting into
Primus and my, my brothers,
they were playing like speed metal and
shit and they would try and I always try
to get me into Metallica,
slayer and all them and I just,
I just was too much of a fucking idiot
to realize how great that music was.
And I could have seen all those bands
on their first tours and I didn't do it.
Um, so anyways, uh,
I went home and I was tuning
up the bass drum and um,
I just couldn't get a good fucking sound
and it was this weird like vibrating
fucking sound or whatever.
And I text my teacher, I said, yeah,
I'm getting this weird like
a buzzer rat on. He said,
is there a hole in the
front head? I was like,
this guy's a fucking genius.
Could genius because what happened is
there wasn't a hole in the front head,
but where they were or something fell
on it and puncture just a little list of
hole. I said it was a
tiny little, it goes,
that would be enough to fuck it up cause
I couldn't get that boom sound. And,
um, so now I'm like obsessing
about it. I gotta get,
I gotta get back east again. I want
to try tuning them up again. And um,
I've now become obsessed
with like different heads
and I used to be so afraid to
try and tune my drums.
I'd have somebody else do it and
then I just wouldn't touch them.
And I play them until they sucked again.
And then I hope I could find somebody
else rather than just biting the bullet
and being like,
just take out your drum key and start
fucking with it and ask people who know
how to do it, to teach you how to do it
and keep fucking doing it. You asshole.
But you know, part of me, I mean, an
asshole is you don't do shit like that.
All right. Apocalypse.
Hey there, dilly dilly.
Hey there, Billy death bell. Uh,
the Internet keeps talking about the
end of times as if things today are far
worse than they've ever
been. I'm only 31 years old,
but I seem to remember plenty of
bad weather and shitty presidents.
Um,
there's this need to make everything
sound worse than it is these days because
everyone loves to be the bearer of
bad news and they get a thrill off the
excitement that shit may
be going south real quick.
I saw a quote by John Mayer on Twitter.
Someone asked him what annoys him?
And he says, spacious argument.
It's everywhere. I can't stand
it. Is that, as I say that right?
The Fed has a,
the fetishization of defense
attorney logic gone mainstream.
Ugh. Well,
he's obviously a smarter person than me
because I don't want any of that means
spacious argument. It's everywhere.
I can't stand at the fetishization of
defense attorney logic gone mainstream.
That right there is why he's a brilliant
guitars cause I don't know what the
fuck he just did, but I don't,
I don't know that anybody's ever
put words together like that.
I don't know what that
means. Uh, I totally agree.
Everyone thinks they're dropping the mic
and they're just pandering and reaching
for low hanging fruit. Now
that I agree with. Yes.
A P s keep the 90s music coming though
that Fiona Apple Song that Andrew used
last week reminded me of the summer.
I started jerking off save
the pet store manager from,
from last week. I don't know what that
means. Yeah. Andrew picks the music.
I wish I was could claim a that I was
as cool as to know all this shit that he
does. He knows a bunch
about music. Um, yeah,
there is a lot of that.
There's a lot of gloom and doom and all
that type of shit, but uh, you know,
it's not all it is. I, you know,
okay.
The Great Barrier Reef and all that
type of shit is pretty terrifying.
All of that shit is pretty fucking
terrifying. And uh, I mean,
I can't even focus on it if you actually
get passed all the dopes on social
media talking about things
and you actually listened
to scientists talking about
like whatever their predictions
are. Um, I know that there's,
I don't know, this sounds
like a, uh, you know,
I think it's going to be a
no, it should be interesting.
We'll see. I hope that wrong. You know,
who the fuck knows? I Dunno. All right.
The DNC, everybody dear Mr. Burn,
I'm appalled and disgusted that you had
the Addis audacity to speak poorly of
Debbie Schultz. Wasserman, a lifelong
servant of her country and the only party,
uh, that has moved this country forward.
I usually enjoy your brand of humor.
There's no way this
person's serious. I have C,
I have c parts of your comedy specials
and overheard a handful of episodes of
your podcast while in the
proxy of my brother in law,
a. You Sir,
I have a responsibility to tell the truth
and not just your uninformed opinions
on politics,
that the seat that you distribute is
going to aid in the dismantling of this
country. Oh God, no. God,
give me a fucking break.
You just happened to be walking by
and you heard that. Well, you know,
the whole part of this podcast
is that I am uninformed.
Um,
and I sent a link that you could watch
on Youtube and listened to that lawyer
discussing
the things that she did or didn't do.
So I don't know what you fucking problem
is. You know, I talk about politics.
The way I talk about sports is someone
who never did it at a professional level.
I met Schultz Wasserman a few years back
and I asked her what we could do every
day to change the nation for the
better. And she eloquently said,
do not let them tell
you how to feel. Oh God,
I'm not reading the rest
of this. This is fucking
sincerely a proud Democrat
who will not be discouraged.
You know what you sound like.
You sound like someone, you know,
when someone comes up to me and says, the
Patriots are cheaters, and then I say,
who's your team? And then I talk
about the shit that they've done.
And then they downplay that. Yet you
are, I've gotta be honest with you,
as uninformed as I am. Um,
people like you, I can't
even talk to because you're so lost in
your blue ties that you can't see that
it's this. You know what?
It's like everybody out here in Hollywood
loves to sit there and Trash Fox News
and talk about how there are
all these bullies and all that,
and I'm going to tell you, I'm
not gonna name any fucking names,
but the amount of performers,
comedians, actresses,
and all this type of shit,
like their level of zero
tolerance like they are,
they are literally what they're
fighting. They're bullies.
They tell people how they're supposed to
think the way they're supposed to think
and they feel that they are 100% right.
They feel that their view of the world
is the way that the world should be.
And anyone who doesn't think
that needs to be attacked,
needs to be dragged on stage and
humiliated needs to have their, their,
their ability to earn a living attacked.
It's no difference than when
you watched what Fox News did,
did the Dixie chicks, it's
the exact same fucking thing,
the exact same level of righteousness,
patting themselves on the back about how
fucking smart they are and how informed
they are. You know,
meanwhile as they fly around and fucking
private jets, give me a fucking break.
Give me a fucking break. Okay. You know,
the Patriots Cheat, your team cheats,
the Republican's a pieces of shit.
The Democrats are pieces of
shit. Alright, there you go.
There you go. So, and other
than anything other than that,
you're looking at shit through
fucking rose colored glasses. And, um,
I think it's, I think that that is a,
I don't know what to think. I just, I
can't have a conversation with that.
You know what I mean?
It's like if I listen to a red sox fan
back with Derek Jeter was playing and
they just say that he sucks and he's
fucking overrated and blah, blah.
And I would just sit there
and be like, no, he isn't.
He's fucking won one of the
greatest players of all time.
I'd love if he was on my team. You
know, I hate the Yankees, but I,
I'm not going to hate on greatness.
Marianne Rivera is the greatest
fucking closer of all time.
I still fucking hate the Yankees,
but I don't hate him to
a level that I can't see.
[inaudible]
I can't see that. You know what I mean?
I just don't, I just don't fucking
understand it. I don't understand it.
Like you want to talk about
spy, Geeky and the Patriots.
We're guilty of cheating. Deflate Gate
was bullshit. Spy Gate was true. However,
they were only guilty of,
of doing it for one game.
And I only clarify that because everybody
thinks well they should take away all
their titles because that's what they
were doing now. That was the first game.
It was illegal and they kept
fucking doing it. All right.
And they were 100% guilty or they deserve
to be fucking fine because they were
cheating then. Yes,
they were that one time.
All the other stuff was bullshit
though. However, if they,
cause I'm a one deflate gay came out, I
was like, if they did this shit again,
I'm done with this fucking
team. That's what I said.
And then I watched the whole fucking
thing unfold and I was like, oh,
this was just bullshit.
Okay,
so there you go.
Does that sound evenhanded you guys
probably think I'm too much of a patriots
fan, but I mean I did it. They spygate
was cheating and they were guilty.
They did it one game. Raymond.
Janie fucking ratted him out.
Okay, then that was it. They will
fucking guilty. What are you going to do?
Does that make them worse than anybody
else? No. Bill Walsh fucking cheated.
So there you go.
They should democrats and you Republicans
say the Patriots are Democrats.
I'm a patriots fan, so I am a democrat.
Okay. But I could see their fucking,
I can see that spygate was fucking
cheating and they were guilty of it.
And I could also see that Bill Walsh.
Okay.
Fuck it. Did the same thing when he
pretended his fucking headsets went out.
It's not that fucking heart. Um,
I don't understand what your
point is that the, Oh my God,
this person was used to fucking meeting
proves, you know, they said, would she,
we do easy. Don't let them
capitols tell you how to feel.
That is such like, that has
got to be the most vague.
I'm on my way to my town car
fucking horseshit response ever.
Hey Bill. Uh,
what's your secret to being as
successful standup comedian?
Uh, you just get out there
and keep doing it, man.
All right. Girlfriend won't
take racist last name.
All right, dear. Bills burry. Doughboy
Hey, fuck you man. I'm under one 80.
Okay. Go easy. Go easy.
You know. All right,
dear bill's very doughboy. Uh,
my girlfriend of three years has
made it very clear that if we,
if I were to propose to her that
she would not take my last name.
The reason being is that she
feels my last name is racist.
The name is Koons, spelled c. O. N. S.
I told her that I have never encountered
a problem having this last name and she
has nothing to worry about.
Thoughts. Yeah. Here's my thoughts.
I think you're making this
up and if you're not, um,
that woman is too dumb to
marry and reproduce with.
Yeah. Right.
If you call a black person
a coon that is racist.
If your last name is coons, it isn't,
you know, like I see if your last name
was the n word, then yeah. I mean,
maybe you want to, you know, yeah. I mean,
if it's, I don't know. I, yeah, I
mean if that's your fucking last name,
that's a believable last name, isn't it?
You know what I mean?
I Dunno. Anyways, my roommate is,
you know, like, I'm trying to think,
I'm trying to think of a fucking racial
group I can do here without getting in
trouble. Cause I want
to really do a fucking,
I guess I got to go against my own,
my own fucking racist.
What I do if there's no good ones,
there is no good ones with white people.
Cause like it doesn't have
an effect on us. Nah. Shit.
You know what I mean? I don't know.
Maybe in the future some other group
takes over and then we'll have that.
We'll have our, you know, you
can't call me cracker. Um,
I love crackers. I love putting cheese
on it. My roommate is a fucking Weirdo.
Dear Conti. McConn fuck. Uh, first of
all, a big fan of the fucking podcast,
the last fucking Netflix special
was phenomenal. So thanks. Okay.
Now needs is one of
these people that thinks,
because I swear that
now they have to swear.
You don't have to bring yourself
down to my level, sir. Anyways,
I just fucking moved into
college as a freshman.
My roommate is a hot
motherfucker. I mean I'm gay.
So right away I was into them,
but I kept to myself since I had
no way of knowing he was gay too.
I thought you guys had Gaydar
you couldn't sense it. Um,
so last week on Friday after
a fucking drunk at night out,
we returned to our room.
Oh Geez. Here we go.
And the fucking guy
offhandedly tells me he's gay.
Once the conversation started
getting more personal,
then I told them I'm also
gay and this guy says fag.
I don't think this is real.
After which we proceeded to fuck,
which was fucking amazing.
By the way. I find the term,
I find the fag term endearing. So
fuck all the political correctness.
Hysteria by gays and non gaze alike.
All right, I'm just going
to read this. Okay. Anyways,
this is when the shit started to hit
the fan. No Pun intended. Sorry Dude.
You loved it over the
fucking net. Um, once I came,
he expressed disappointment
at the volume of my comp.
Does anyone believe this is true? The
fucker literally said that's it. What?
Are you sick or something? I
felt fucking inadequate sense.
His load was considered
really bigger than mine.
Okay.
Oh Jesus Christ. So then the next
morning he says he wants to fuck again.
I go along with it like, he's so hot,
I'm not going to refuse halfway through
this motherfucker says, you know,
for a tall guy, you
sure have a small Dick.
Yeah.
And he writes like, what
the fuck? Yeah. Well Dude,
you came back from more abuse
here. So I'm all for two, right?
Inadequate Dick size check, lack
of Herculean come shot check.
Uh, is insulting the people.
He fucks part of his style.
Like I can't figure out why he
still wants to fuck. We have to,
to colossal fucking insults.
So what the fuck do I do next?
So stop fucking the guy. Ah,
fuck knows. But the next day
we're chugging peers in our room.
Okay.
You know, other than, than the gay
sexist sounds amazing that, sorry,
I'm looking at this as a straight guy. Um,
what the fuck am I? Uh,
okay. Well chugging beers,
a room and he suggest
something beyond weird. Oh God.
He's basically tells me He wants
me to pee in his mouth. You know,
even if this is fake, this
is tremendously Korean.
If you got to give this up a case since
it turns him on, since it turns a mom,
I'm eight beers deep and I'm a
lightweight, so I'm like, fuck it dude.
I swear to God,
if this is true and you piss in this guy's
mouth and he's like [inaudible] I set
a,
this motherfucker has a stream like a
God damn firehose and nearly broke my jaw
in the process. What?
I don't believe that Jesus Christ.
So I'm completely weirded out
by this colossal cont dude.
You let them piss in your mouth.
His only saving graces that he happens
to be the hottest guy I ever met.
So bill, what the fuck do
I do? Do I change room,
kick this con to the curb and sleep and
never sleep with the game or do I stick
stick in there so that I can
stick it in there. Thanks.
And Go fuck yourself. You
McGee Bitch. Uh, I don't know.
It sounds like you feel bad afterwards.
If I was with a woman and she was doing
this shit to me and she was really hot,
yeah, I'd probably keep going back,
but I would just get
myself mentally prepared.
You know what you might do just
telling me as a weird asshole.
Okay.
You got to get in his head. Tell him a,
his ass is too hairy. He needs
to braid the hair on his ass of,
so I don't know what the fuck did to,
I mean [inaudible] you're outside,
you know, this is still
basically human interaction.
So you're talking about feelings here.
So do you want to get childish
to say something mean to him
and uh, I don't know.
You know what's weird is Josh just
showed up and now I have to smoke a cigar
after reading that
shit. Yeah, dude, don't,
don't fucking go back. Don't
go back for more. Right.
Or if you're going to go back for
more, I'm sorry, I'm texting him. Hey,
hang on. All right. Uh, yeah, you
don't need to put up with that shit.
Everything's like a pun in this. Um,
the weird thing is that
you live with the guy.
It's never good to fuck your
roommate. You know, it's, that's,
that's never going to be a good thing.
But I don't know how it works with gay
guys cause you're both guys. Right.
Okay.
So I would think you'd be able to just
be like, yeah, we'll just fucking write.
Then we'll watch a game and fucking
drink some beers and I'll fucking piss in
your mouth. Evidently. I
guess that's how it goes down.
I don't know what the fuck
happens here. So I would just, uh,
if he sincerely is making
you feel bad, then I would,
I would try to find a better guy. Um,
but consider you live with them.
You obviously get to see kids. Nike,
you can just blow the guy off. So at some
point he's going to be like, hey man,
you want to fuck you gotta be like,
Nah, I don't. You'd be like, why not?
It'd be okay cause you're a dick. You
say mean shit to me and I don't like it.
All right,
so why don't you in there and go rub one
out and piss in your own fucking mouth.
You're fucking Dosha or you
just move up. All right,
that's the podcast. Everybody, God
bless each and every one of you.
Go fuck yourselves and I'll
check in on you on Thursday.