Hey, what's going on? It's bill burn.
It's time for the Thursday afternoon.
Just before Friday, Monday morning
podcast. And I'm just checking in on Ya.
That's right. I'm not yelling at,
I'm fucking up my voice doing that.
Every God damn week I'm
starting to drink, throw Coty.
I need to take care of
myself in these next,
this next chapter as they peel off another
layer of the onion or whatever stupid
artistry thing. I've just decided, you
know, few people in my life, you know,
I'm kind of seeing it. I'm seeing it.
I'm seeing what live in a certain
lifestyle leads to. And I'm like,
you know what? I need to clean up
my act a little bit. All right.
It's time to grow. And so one of
the first things I'm going to do,
I'm not cutting out the booze or
I'm just going to stop yelling.
I'm checking in on you. You
know, it's baby steps, you know,
and I'll gradually work towards
laying off the heroin. You know,
I like it. It helps me,
helps me go to sleep.
You know the amount of times that I always
want to take a nap when I'm standing
up outside in public and I just can't do
it because my mind just won't shut off.
You know, that's, that's
when the heroin comes in.
That's when it comes into play. You're
going to have to listen to my phone,
Ding Dong and cause I got a phone call
coming up and I don't want to miss it
here. Um, anyways, let me see here.
Uh, uh, Jesus. Now I'm going to be looking
at text messages, message messages,
messages, while I'm
trying to do this podcast.
This is really going to fuck with
my add here. How's your week going?
I'm going to tell you something, right?
Oh, but oh, Billy Booz bag. All right.
I had, I had family and flew back.
Sched some of you guys guessed
the movie by the way. Um,
it's something you do with a car.
Can't figure it out now
I can't help you. Uh,
what I love is now everybody
knows what the movie is,
but there's still going to tech treat
me like, you know, the long, long,
long trailer starring Lucille Ball. Um,
why don't you guys ask me if it's every
other movie that you can do with the car
other than the one you
notice. How about that?
How about switching it up a little bit?
Is it Herbie goes to Monte-Carlo you
don't even realize all these years I've
been using that as a reference. Like,
cause it's the f one of the
first or second movie I saw,
I saw for the love of Benji.
Then I saw Herbie goes to Monte-Carlo
and my mother was just like,
my mother told me, you know, they're
just, those kids movies were stupid.
I wasn't going to take it
any more of those, you know,
basically there wasn't anything there for
her. And she just was looking at like,
you know, there's really
nothing here for these kids.
It's a fucking talking car.
It's a talking dog. You know.
How long are we going to
keep the lie going? Alright,
the fat fuck doesn't come down.
The chimney. Dogs don't talk.
And the fee w beetle, it's a, it's a,
it's an economical car. But you know,
at the end of the day it's not respect
itself. That's it. Let's go see stripes.
Um, anyways, uh, completely forgot
what the fuck I was gonna say there
out of fuck. Did I get to that? I have
no idea. Do I need to go on Brian?
I need to play some brain games.
Several years. What the fuck was out?
Eat more healthy. I don't know what
it is. Oh yes. Oh Wow. Agamemnon.
The family back east. I got it.
I got it. We're back. Right.
He'll be those outtakes on Casey Casey
when he flips out screaming, yell.
Now God damn it. I'm not fucking reading
about a fucking dog died. You know,
this is basically like those outtakes,
except I don't edit them up and I
also don't have his iconic success.
Yeah. Other than that, I think it
seeks act. Same thing. But anyways,
I had family come and fee and we'd kill
me in palm bakeys twice in this past
month. And, um, I had to
take them out to the spots.
We had to drink a little toast
for the little one, a little Nini.
Dude, she's laughing her ass off
now. It's the greatest thing.
It's the greatest thing ever. Um,
could not be in a joint more in a first.
And for the first time in my life I'm,
someone can actually look at me
and say happy father's Day. Right.
And I don't have to be like, oh my
God. In what Comedy Club did you work?
How old is it? Um, anyways, now I
was never like that on the road.
I was a good boy, sort of. I had my
moments anyways, plowing ahead here.
Um, so because they came in,
I kind of got off my diet.
I was still doing the cardio every day,
so I stepped on the scale and the
unacceptable second number in my world is
eight. Okay. If it's ever a
nine, I'm telling you right now,
I am going to jump off
a fucking building. Um,
I won't do that. I'll just
buy really comfortable.
I'll keep wearing the golf clothes that
I wear that just get bigger. You know,
I was getting to the
John Daily Line. Um, so,
uh, I'm, I'm back on it. I'm back on
it. Jumped on the scale today. One 78.8.
Still unacceptable.
I haven't been having the worst fucking
time trying to get down to my fighting
weight. I wanted to be one
72 by my birthday, my 49th,
the end of the forties. Wrapping it
up. If I was a professional athlete,
I would be 10 years for tired unless I
was Tom Brady with my senior we muscles
or whatever the fuck he's doing
with his spongy muscles. Um,
I don't know what he's doing. Sorry,
I'm drinking the throat coat. Oh, Jesus.
Bill, you're just annoying on so many
different levels today. I apologize. Um,
so anyways, I'm just,
I'm going to try to just lay off
the booze for a little bit. Um,
I'm going to San Francisco, uh,
this weekend and, uh,
I'm working with fucking my dean
off my Dean Martin. Joe De Rosa.
Okay. So that's going to be, that's
going to be a Mulligan that night.
Joe.
My friendship with Joe to Rosa in his
friendship with me is one of the great
friendships in show business
history and it's all,
it's all alcohol fueled. You know,
I don't think we've ever hung around
each other sober and I don't think that I
got to get him on the podcast.
I really got to get all fucking Joe to
rose or whatever. His background is,
Egyptian, Italian.
He doesn't know that man was left at
a doorstep of a funny bone way back in
1977. I believe he showed up on a knower,
a baby nobody wanted,
he came out of the womb already
wearing those dark frame glasses.
Um, it's sad, but said I'm
anyways plowing ahead. Okay.
I'm sure I'm going to hear
about that from old Joey. Um,
I'm guessing two drinks in, they do.
There was something I want
to talk to you about. It's,
I know you were just joking, but you
know, to bring that up, it's just really,
um, fuck him. He trashed
my dog on stage. Oh,
that's coming out fourth drinking.
I'm trying to guess where the
argument's gonna come from this weekend.
Why drink with Joe? We really don't
argue anymore. Once I discovered,
fair enough, you know,
I grew up a little bit,
he grew up a little bit
and that's all we do.
We start to argue and then one of
us just goes, hey, fee, fair enough.
And we laugh and it just
diffuses everything. Fair enough.
Fair enough. Can Stop
Wars. You know what I mean?
This is our borderline now we think it
said, hey, fair enough. Fair enough.
I understand why you would take that,
but I mean, you know, fair enough.
Well are going to give it to us
law. Yeah, I didn't say that.
Well then I'm going to fucking start
shooting. I think. Fair enough. Yeah.
That's what you feel you need to do.
Okay.
It just diffuses the other guy and then
the other guy stayed in there going
like, no, you're supposed
to, you supposed to get mad.
Then you get mad and then I get mad and
then I lie to my people and you lie to
your people. We dehumanize each
other. Now, don't we start shooting?
Okay,
fair enough. All right, fair enough. Um,
anyways. Did Anybody Watch the, uh, the
penguin's wrist of fucking predators?
I'll tell you something about these teeth.
These penguins from Pittsburgh is they
know how to fucking win a goddamn series.
Jesus Christ,
the predators in an oh two hole for
those of you bad at math when it's best,
four out of seven, you're down oh two.
That means you have to win
four of the next five. Oh,
the coach isn't going to tell you that.
What's he going to say? All right guys.
All right boys. We've got to take
it one game at a time. Okay. Hey,
these crossed the hall
in that Locker Room Bay.
They put their escape to on
one one, one boot at a time.
Okay, we've got to
start winning the batch.
[inaudible]
take it one period of time.
Do they are beating the shit out of
Sidney Crosby, this playoff series.
This plaintiff is just this,
this, this playoff run.
I don't know what he did to the refs,
but they had done protecting that guy
this slash and I'm there hooking them.
They're fucking hitting him in the
head. Anything that they could do. Um,
I dunno. I think that they, uh, they,
they should have brought
a goon up or something.
Somebody to do something.
I don't know. But anyways,
how about fucking Malkin's goal?
Absolute fucking s you know,
and I know that they, uh,
pulled out peto today or whatever his
fucking name is for some reason I can't
remember his Goddamn name.
Pekka Rina. Dale's his name.
Uh, Jesus, I can't cock sock. I can't
remember some about it. Dick is the,
is the Predator.
I fucking watched every game and
I still can't remember his name.
The focus is new. Is it Pecorino?
Was that the guy from San Jose?
Was He on San Jose? And then he
went to Nashville. You don't,
once I stopped collecting cards,
you know, and I turned to scotch.
I just never been able to, I've never
been able to handle the names anymore.
But anyways, I don't give a
fuck who you are, Ken Dryden.
Patrick wa Terry Sawchuck.
Nobody stops that fucking puck.
That was an absolute
filthy, filthy fucking goal.
Um, so my prediction way back
in the day, what did I say?
What did I say before I flip flopped and
said Otto was gonna was gonna win game
seven before I did that, I
said the penguins were going
to win the whole thing.
So when it happens,
I'm going to ignore the fact that I
thought Ottawa was going to come back and
win game seven cause I was questioning
the goaltending in Pittsburgh.
I'm going to ignore all of that and I'm
going to pull up Paul version and say,
dude, what did I say
dude? I called it, um,
just out of a, you know,
jealousy. I want to, uh,
I want to see the predators tie
up the series. Not Jealousy,
just out of like selfishness.
I want to see the, um,
the NHL season goes as many
games as possible. But uh,
though I tell you right now the
way the tournaments and playing a,
I mean I don't even see this
called back to Pittsburgh. Uh,
we'll see something incredible
has to, how about the WHO?
I don't know who the fuck shot the
goal. That baby face kid there.
I mean I've,
that was like the puck had I said like
there was one little fucking just puck
sized space for a split second.
Yeah.
Between old, uh, a penis
there, whatever his name is.
It just opened up for half a second.
The puck literally turned sideways like
some Matrix Shit and went in the guy,
I remember when I, when I saw it
labs, I kind of fuck did that go in?
Okay.
I Dunno man.
I'll tell you the hockey gods are
smiling down in Pittsburgh right now. Um,
who knows. We'll see what sort of home
home ice advantage they have. But a,
and also the NBA playoffs not
play the, a final starts tonight.
Is it the NBA finals and the Stanley Cup
final or was it Stanley Cup finals in
the NBA final? I think
it's the NBA finals. Um,
every time I say something stupid, my
phone rings. That's it right there.
That's a little thing. All right.
I have a call here in fucking,
uh, let's see. 10 minutes, 10 minutes.
So I'm gonna have to hit pause here.
It's not gonna matter to you guys
cause I'll just pick it up. You know,
I'll give me 10 minutes of silence.
Like I'm trying to do something artsy.
Um, that starts tonight. Um,
okay.
I Dunno, I don't have a feeling on this
one. I want the Cavaliers to win. Um,
okay.
I want the capitalist doing cause I
still feel like they don't get their
respect.
People aren't talking about them like
did the defending like they are the
defending NBA champions and it's,
it's cause Doran went to the warriors.
I think that that's why nobody
seems to be able to talk about it.
You know what I mean? Just to be able
to see like, hey not for nothing.
These guys beat those
other guys last year.
So I hope they keep disrespecting them
cause I always root against the pylon
team. You know, I even did
it with the red sox in 2007.
I just, I don't even think
I watched the world series.
I mean obviously I was happy that we won.
Obviously I'd rather see us win
than the fucking Colorado Rockies.
But I, I was just like, ah,
this is, that's not competition.
You know, having said that,
having said that, when the, uh,
when the bass, when the basketball
and hockey season ends, okay,
I'm getting the,
the MLB package and I'm watching my
$210 million Red Sox who are in second
place,
three games behind the evil empire that
has nothing but their own homegrown
talent.
And I'm going to watch that collision
course and see how that goes. Um, I,
I've learned this is what you have to do
if you're a sports fan with some fairly
big east is the baseball
is such a great sport,
but the problem is, is the first,
almost the first half of the season is
the most exciting time in basketball and
hockey. And your emotions
as a fan are so heightened,
even if your team is out of
it, just to watch, you know,
there's always something great happens
in the f in the final, unless, you know,
the fucking ref called 38 files on one
team at 15 on the other, then it sucks.
Okay.
Letting it go. Um,
and then all of a sudden it's
over and then you settle.
Ah, just a bit outside a
billable day. Pro Ball game.
Okay.
I'll tell you his on base
percentage is six 45. And uh,
he's really seeing the ball right
now. I kept you played the game.
What was it like when you just,
when you hit a zone like this? Oh,
I'll tell you, you know, when you
hit a all like, just to me that ball,
I mean your eyes are as big as
Christmas. You know, Jermaine, it just,
it's like you can't,
you just stick in the bat out there and
the balls going away and wants to go,
but you know, and uh, what do you want?
How do you tell you to try to, uh,
how do you try to stay in that zone? How
you try to do I try to keep it go well,
you know, it's one of those things
you can't control it. You just,
you learn is you,
as you mature as a player to just try
to enjoy those moments in a while.
You know, you hope it goes, as
long as it can put a Veggie,
it is going to swing back to the other's
way. And you just hope that that's is,
uh, you know, that the slop doesn't last
as long. So, uh, you know, you could,
uh,
keep your house in that gold digging
whore that you met in a Tulsa when you're
coming up and triple a that you
knocked up and you don't really love,
but you like her, you're
hanging in there for the kid.
Um, you know, you gotta settle into
that. So what you need to do is, uh,
what do you, you gotta just immediately,
you gotta slow everything the fuck down.
And what you have to do is
you gotta watch a day game.
You gotta keep score while
you smoke a cigar. You know,
you get you lineup, you
get it all ready to go.
You just fucking sit there and you
like the cigar about the third day,
you know, and you just sit there and
you fucking maybe even on the radio,
listen to it on the radio and
you just, it's like sports yoga.
He just have to totally
just calm your mind,
fucking relax and then slide
into the dog days of baseball,
right?
And then you ride that out for about six
weeks and then all of a sudden it's NFL
preseason. All right. And
it's a preseason comes along.
You're excited about football.
Cause every week's exciting because
they only play 16 games, right?
But baseball is also ramping up.
So then when September comes along,
it's like April, May, June
with basketball and hockey,
because now it's like you're so
excited. How fuck NFL football,
college football, it's coming back.
I have a reason to live. Right?
And the baseball race is heating up
before you go in with Joe Buck and all the
great October baseball.
That's how you do it. Alright,
so these next six weeks after the finals
are over, you know, I'm telling you,
I'll walk you through it
on the podcast. You know,
you pick a couple of alternative
sports. Maybe you watch a little
Roland Garris Little Wimbledon, you
get into Formula One, maybe a little,
a moto GP, right?
I don't know what the
fuck you got. [inaudible]
it's not my business. It's none of my
business. What time is it? Nine 55.
Let's see. I can read advertising in
five minutes. I don't think I can do it.
Especially when I've got to
type in my goddamn password.
The family bag. He sched kidding.
Um, all right. What do we got here?
Oh, love supreme. All right, worry.
Uh, Indocin don't cheat. Uh,
talk about how every man looks
better in a suit. You know,
when I'm checking out of Fella, I love
boys shorts, just like the next guy.
But what really turns me on is a
nice sharp look and fellow in a suit.
You know what I mean? Grab
him by his tie. All right.
Indochino is making it easy to get a
perfectly tailored suit at an incredible
price.
You can choose from hundreds of top
quality fabrics and personalize your suits
and your fucking initials on the
pocket. Uh, just the way you want it.
Don't use pills shoe, whether it
works, uh, whether it's for work,
a wedding or another special
occasion. Indochino, um,
has suited up hundreds of thousands
of men and are now the largest made to
measure men's wear brand in the
world world world world. Uh,
here's how it works.
Visit a showroom or shop
online@indochinoindochino.com.
Um, like the indigo girls, if
they went to China Indochino uh,
pick your fabric.
Where do the warehouse.
I picked out a bucket to
our warehouse with three PS.
I taught two way, man.
Um,
choose your customers' customizations
from lapels to pleats to jacket linings
and more. Submit. Submit
your measurements,
place your order and wait for it to
arrive. And just a few weeks this week,
my listeners can get any premium
Indochino suit for just 379
dollars@indochino.com when
entering bur at checkout,
that's 50% off the regular price for
a made to measure premium suit plus
shipping is free. Uh,
that's indochino.com promo code bar
for any premium suit for $379 and free
shipping.
Incredible deal for a suit that will fit
you better than anything off the rack
ever could. Nine 57 how many more
do I got? I got two more to go.
Five. Four club. Yo,
you like a short pitch.
This is the five four club.
I'm kidding. I'm looking good.
Doesn't need to cost a fortune five
four club is revolutionizing the way men
stop at five fold club. They
found a way to make a great look.
Great looking clothes
affordable for everyone.
Five folk club also understands that
your time is extremely valuable.
Why?
Why wasted at the mall or wandering around
in stores each month they send you a
crow, a curated box of two to three items.
That just means somebody else picked it
out. I hate that fucking word curated.
You know like somebody gives a shit
the fuck does this guy want tank tops?
The idea fucking tank tops. Why waste it?
Like what the fuck am I handpicked match
the current season and your style? Oh,
they're crawling early. Oh God.
This is from Montreal, Quebec.
I'll get right back.
All right, I'm back. I'm
in between interviews.
I'm in between fucking interviews here.
I got on the wrong fucking headphones.
All right, here we go. Back back.
I got another interview in four
minutes with The v [inaudible].
Um, narrate,
let's put the fuck was I talking about
trying to type in my password and this is
a mess. Why would I do this before I
hit fucking set it? Yeah, there we go.
There we go. Oh, five four club.
Did I finish five four club. Um,
they've been helping men with fashion
for over 15 years and shipped over a
hundred thousand men every
month. Chris Paul and
Mike Walberg use fivefold club.
If fat folk club is featured in GQ vice
and in style among other publications,
they know what they're doing. So
if you don't think that's okay,
five four club will help you.
What? They know what they're doing.
So if you don't also, if
you don't, that's okay.
Thought they were getting
a little chip on itself.
So you don't think that's
okay, that fuck you get,
you got damn suit somewhere else.
Five folk club will help you build
your wardrobe one month at a time.
Because when you look good, you
feel good. Brother [inaudible],
he knows she's on her
knees. It's a fact of life.
You get $120 worth of clothes
for just $60 a month. You can.
That doesn't make sense. 80% of
the time it works 100% of the time.
You can pause or cancel
anytime, no commitments.
And as a fivefold club member,
you'll receive up to 50% off your items
in their online shop and access to
exclusive members only items. You know,
members only jacket for 30 bucks,
free shipping and sys exchanges.
Go to five folk club.com right now and
enter your Promo code birth and they'll
give you 50% off your first month's
package plus a free pair of sunglasses.
That's 50% off your first
package at Five-o club,
spelled f, I. V. E. F. O.
No you are club.com Promo Code
[inaudible] club.com Promo Code Park.
All CSO. Everybody see?
So you know I've had funny
feelings. I've gotten funny looks,
I've eaten, I've even eaten funny
smelling Sushi. But let me tell you,
none of those are as funny as CSOs
streaming's library of stand up television
and original content,
especially not the Sushi.
Why would they try to write comedy for
us? Let me do a quick rewrite this.
You know, I've had a
funny feeling in my gut.
I've gone down on a funny smell and Twat,
you know,
I've been in a parking lot late at
night and felt funny like, you know,
is someone going to fucking cut me up?
But nothing compares to watch and a
fucking six feet under run on CSO.
All right, maybe I should've
gone with this shit.
Next please mention the talking points
below. I'm going to mention all of them.
If you fucking give them to me,
you can dam cans over the um,
with CSO you get unlimited access
to CSO original series next day,
late night, hilarious.
Standup sketch specials,
binge worthy classics including
42 seasons of Saturday night.
Live the entire money
pond, python catalog,
the it crowd in more. I don't understand
why more people aren't watching. So,
I mean, they've got some fucking,
every episode of Saturday
night live is on there.
The entire Monty python cannon. I don't
know what the fucking ed crowd is,
but shit, it's following those
two. It's gotta be good with CSO.
You get binge worthy classics,
British cult comedy original series
like harmonquest and bajillion dollar
properties. Not to mention the entire
SNL library. I just fucking said that.
I'm supposed to pick one of these or
what's your favorite sets from comedians
like Louis C, k a me fucking shit.
And Hannibal Buress access CSO content
from anywhere at anytime using Ios,
android, Roku, apple TV, Amazon Fire TV,
stealing cable from your
neighbor windows or x-box one.
Ready for the punchline. CSO is
just three 99 per month. No joke.
Three 99 per month for all
the comedy. Want anytime,
anywhere add fucking free. Go to CSO,
s e s o.com right now to sign up for
one month for free with the Promo Code
[inaudible] at checkout.
That's seeso.com spelled s
e e s o.com Promo code burn.
All right. What else did I
want to talk about? Um, oh,
by the way, tiger woods, who is arrested,
everybody said was arrested for,
for drinking and driving blue is 0.0
point fucking Xero at Jesus Christ is
another one. Hang on a second. Hello.
Okay.
Oh Man, those are two fun interviews. I
just talked to a guy who goes by lights.
Camera Jackson.
How do you not love that guy?
That is old school showbiz.
How do you ever forget that name?
Lights. Camera Jackson. All right,
let me type this in
here. Your family, Becky,
my fucking password. Why
won't you work for me?
Why won't you work for
me? You know, it's funny.
Somebody has enough time at some point
to fucking splice together every time.
I'm trying to fucking put together
my password yet by the way,
tiger woods, Tiger Woo, uh,
blue and 0.0 the dude was on
pills. You know what I mean? The,
the level of shit that, that guys get,
that guy sacrificed his fucking
body to become great. Okay?
Now his body's breaking down and
everybody's blaming it on the fact that he
cheated on his lady. Right.
And that's what did him in
his laser focus. He couldn't block out
the fat I the first two years. Yeah,
I'm sure it bugged him, but I mean
at some point you move on, right?
His body blade set at the front from the
very beginning they said the way swings
the club, his body's going to break
down at some point. So now look at him.
Now look at him. You know,
he's trying to come back.
He's on all these painkillers.
He wants to win another one probably
before he hangs it up and goes to the uh,
the senior tour. He's
doing what he has to do.
These fucking drugs that you can get
nowadays are completely out of control.
When I was a kid, when a drug came
out, bear or any of this shit,
they didn't have 9,000 side effects.
What happened was people used to
be in the pharmaceutical industry,
got into the fucking FDA and they're
the ones who police to pharmaceutical
companies.
And those cons just waved everything
around like the third base coast that lost
his vision, right? So then they
let opiates into the fucking world.
Now you've got a goddamn
heroin epidemic. Okay.
And now tiger woods is taken too many of
those fucking things and he pulls over
to the side of the road and everybody's
saying it's because he did the fucking
blonde haired blue eyed woman
who evidently is a saint
who took his fucking his,
his master's money, bought a giant house,
not the fucking thing down
to buy something else.
Where did all that material go?
Where did all those fucking
gold plated toilets go?
They went right into the fucking ocean.
Well, you know, but she's a victim. Oh,
give me a break. That's it
for the podcast. Signing off.
Not fucking with the arm.
I'm just trying to energy my way
through the last bit of this a,
what else do I have here to talk about?
Oh, you know what has a great new bits,
a new bit I brought, his name is Charlie,
Charlie Watts drummer for the rolling
stones as a great new book out.
That is just a drummers
that influenced him.
And if you're a drummer and you're
into that shit because he's a,
I guess a jazz drummer at heart.
He talked about all these
fucking great drummers that I've,
I've heard most of the names and didn't
know enough about him and the fact that
he could break down their styles
and what they did has made me a,
I was already listening to a lot of that
shit through some of my drum lessons,
but really just trying to listen
to the shit that he's saying.
It's a great book. Um, let
me, let me look it up here.
I'm going to fucking hype
his book here. You know,
we've been trying to get Charlie
Watson on this podcast for a long time.
I know he doesn't do a
lot of interviews and uh,
but I know he'd want to come on my
podcast. I'm joking. Charlie Watson Book.
Let's see what we got here. Jelly.
You know the fucking Internet works
in like two rooms in my fucking house.
I spent all this money like can you give
me the nuclear level fucking Internet
so I can send out, beat out
my neighbors. And you know,
it works for a little
while then that's it. Well,
we sound, Shelly watch 10 things
you didn't know about Charlie Watts.
Why no books about Charlie Watts?
You know, I'm usually good about fun.
Charlie watts books,
drummers influence book. You know,
I nailed the John Daily search the
last time. Come on for fuck sakes. Oh,
Charlie Watts. Favorite
drum. I, so it did come up,
dude can get it for 12
bucks, $12 and 37 cents. Um,
whiplash, the film that puts
the drummer in the limelight.
Did I have to tell you guys how
much I fucking hated that movie?
I just hated watching somebody getting
berated. It's just like fucking quit.
Go join another band.
Why would you sit there taking that level
of shit from the guy and then not to
mention the kids fucking technique. I,
you had to look away when he
was fucking playing real fast.
He was making those faces. You
could just feel the guy's forearms.
Tighten up this guy.
This guy's going to have carpal tunnel
trying to please this complete cut.
You know,
and I gotta tell you the best drums
from that year was not in that movie is
great as the drums were the best fucking
drums and some of the best drums I've
heard in a movie, a mainstream
moving along fucking time.
Was that Michael Keaton movie. Um,
what the fuck was that movie where he
was the to form a superhero. The bird.
Do you? Not Long.
I watched that movie before I realized
that was him in the costume talking to
himself. Spoiler alert.
All right, Michael Keaton.
I'm just going to write bird.
Fuck you spell his name.
I've only been watching this movies for
30 fucking years. Bill and Jesus Christ.
Michael Keaton, bird bird man.
Yo Birdman five. Oh. Um,
who the fuck is the drummer in that?
I know I talked about that before.
The drums in that movie
are fucking incredible.
It's like,
like that's what just a whole other level
of drumming would. That guy is like,
he's playing like moods.
Hey supposed to just play in 90
million miles an hour all over the kid.
That guy is, he sees, he's
creating peaks and valleys.
I mean that was like a [inaudible] that
was literally a movie score just done
with drums. I mean how many people
can have that level of talent?
I can tell you right now, I know, I don't,
I already knew I didn't in the for the
last three weeks cause I've been so damn
busy, I've just been playing like,
you know, not on a real drum kit,
you know, little practice pad kit that
I was playing on and I thought I was,
you know,
I thought I was doing something and
then I went down and I played on a real
fucking kitten. Jesus Christ.
Everything that you think you can,
you can do drops by
like 50 bpms. You know,
it'd be basically like if you would
just jogging on a treadmill being like,
wow man, I couldn't run
a seven minute mile.
Then you go out to run
down the street, you know,
and you forgot about hills and
shit and all of a sudden, you know,
you can't run a seven minute mile
anymore. Even if it was flat,
flat level. Okay. Maybe
if it was flat level,
all of a sudden you run like a fucking
11 minute mile. That's what it's like.
It was extremely fucking
disheartening. And um,
I'm doing the a,
the comedy jam this weekend up in
San Francisco for cluster fest,
which is just completely
like one of the biggest,
I don't know how they afforded to, to,
to get all of those comedians
and bands and all of that.
They must've had a lot of ad money.
Somebody who's doing something to
establish that comedy festival going,
we're going to go fucking, you know,
nine zillion dollars in the
hole to start it out. But uh,
you might want to go this year
because they're going big. Um,
oh, and I almost forgot before I sign off
your thank you to everybody who's been
watching season two of f is for family.
Um, got nothing but great reviews.
You know, there's always a couple of
country ones. What are you going to do?
But overall you guys not only like it
but you're saying you think it's even
better than the first season, which
for the amount of work that we put in,
um, to hear that kind of feedback,
you know, I know I'm a jerk a lot.
That really means a lot to me. So thank
you guys for not only watching it.
Thank you for the people that took the
time to let me know how much you enjoyed
it. Please let other people know about it.
The more the people people know about it,
the more people watch it and the better
chance we have a possibly getting a
third season. Um, and that's it.
That's the podcast for this week.
Have a great weekend.
You can sit there and a is a little bit
of a bit of music from Andrew thumbless
and then we'll play a little half hour,
some greatest hits from a Thursday or a
podcast or whatever from Thursday gone
by and maybe a Monday morning. I don't
know what we're doing here. All right.
That's not my part of the podcast.
All right, I'll talk to you on Monday.
Hmm.
All right. Hey,
this is the longest fucking revenge
story I think I've ever read.
Let me see if I can, uh, see if I
can fucking just, I'm going to blow.
I'm going to read that one next week
when I have the energy. All right.
Questions? All right, Bill.
Uh, I have a question for you.
I was hoping you might be able
to shine some insight on this.
I have this great friend
that that's a girl mistake.
Um, and we get along great and we have
never had any sort of sexual tension
or interest despite her being attractive.
All right, dude, right there.
You're either gay or you're, Oh,
you're an idiot and I'm gonna try,
I'm giving you some tough love here.
That's a fucking stupid situation
to be involved in. That's stupid.
All right.
Unless you're using her to attract
other females to get you fucking late.
Let's see if this is the
case. I will continue reading.
So she has this smoking hot
friend. Oh, there we go.
That met a few times
and always flirted with. But uh,
but it's just been overall friendly.
So this chicks calls me up one night
and I'm at the bar at like midnight and
asked if I want to stay up drinking
with her and she come pick me up.
So obviously I agree.
Things go very good and we have a few
drinks and flirt and when I make my move,
she gets all upset. Like
I should have known.
She just wants to be friends when she
calls me up at midnight to say to stay up
drinking with her alone
after the incident,
the bitch still has the balls
to sleep to ask to sleep over.
Uh,
since then I have noticed all our friends
are trying to be my friend when all I
want to do is rail the shit out of
them. Bill, I was hoping you could,
you should, you could shine some light
on the situation and help me out.
Yeah, dude, never have a
friend as a, as a female,
you know.
Okay.
You always gotta be fucking them. That's
the only reason to be around them,
you know? I know that's really
sexist, but you know, I, I just,
I'm speaking from me.
There's no fucking point
in hanging out with that level of
frustration if you're not having sex with
them. And if they're
actually like a good friend,
then that's the one that you should,
uh, I mean that's the ultimate,
if you're banging them and
they're also a great friend,
that's the one you marry because
you've got a connection there. Right.
But if you just, yeah, I mean the,
they using you as like a
live teddy bear and um,
yeah. The next time they call up,
just be like, no, I'm, I'm not,
I can't hang out tonight.
What are you doing?
I'm going to go out and try
to get some ass tonight.
I know I'm not getting any from you.
And it's frustrating because you're hot
and I want to bend you over every piece
of fucking furniture in my apartment.
Yay. I can't believe you said that. Yeah.
Well, I just did. Are you going
to come over here and fuck me?
Well then great. I have to go. Why are
you being so mean? I'm not being mean.
I'm being honest. Okay. Do you have
any times I've jerked off to you.
It's fucking, it's annoying.
Okay.
That you just, you just, I'm telling
you like that's a little aggressive,
but that's what you have to start doing.
You just have to be straightforward
and honest and don't do it.
Like I just said it do if do it,
how you can do it and pull it off and
you just say it like that. Just be like,
yeah, I want to go out. I want to
try and get laid tonight. All right.
And I go out with you and
you're not fucking me.
And then other girls see me with you
and they think that I am fucking you,
which I'm not. And I ended up going
home, a dry humping my futon, you know?
And it's really fucking
with my self esteem. Okay.
So that's it. So basically where you said,
you say that you've had how to stack
your cock, you know, I hang out with me.
Yes. That is what I'm saying.
That's what I'm saying.
Your conversations are awful, you know,
I'm sure they're interesting to
other females, but not to me.
I don't want it to, I don't
want to talk about that.
I can give a shit about the
hills, the o sea, the ocean,
or whatever the fuck I was stupid.
Show you what? I don't give a fuck.
I don't give a fuck. I
want to fuck you. Okay?
It's worlds every day in
orders. You have a seat.
We'll watch the world series of poker.
When you go all in, that's what you do.
Just say what the fuck you want
to do. You push all your chips in.
Then you stand up and
you start walking around.
You wait for that next car to drop.
You see what the fuck happens? Yeah,
dude, that's my advice. Get
out of that whole circle a VA.
He's like a big teddy bear.
Fuck debt. Fuck Dad. All right.
You're not a teddy bear
or you are one right now.
You've got to stop being that
guy. So fuck all of them. Go. Uh,
where are your guy friends? What are
they doing? Go hang out with them.
Go get a fucking wing man,
get yourself back in the game and
go out there and talk some shit.
Hit on some girl you
don't give a fuck about.
So you can practice not giving a fuck
and just say a bunch of shit that you
would never say to some girl
that you gave a shit about, eh,
because you don't give a fuck up. The
Girl Says No. Start with that. You know,
always wear a condom. And uh, and
that's it. That's what I would do.
That's what I should've done. I didn't,
I just have that knowledge
now cause I'm fucking a,
have I ever been the funeral
home? I was never the front,
but I was definitely the douchebag.
I was definitely the, the, uh,
not even pussy whipped was
even pussy. What does this,
I couldn't fucking speak up for myself.
I was afraid of having a confrontation
and then by the time I had the final
confrontation, I was like,
oh, I don't know. I was like,
fuck in a year with this
shit and we broke up. Um,
but that's a whole nother thing.
Stories. Hey, what's up
everybody? It's bill burner.
This is the Monday morning podcast that
I'm recording for the third time this
week.
Praying and hoping against hope that g
CAS will actually upload this one cause
I've already spent 90 minutes doing
podcasts this week. So anyways,
if you're hearing this, it means
I successfully uploaded it.
So there's no sense complaining unlike
the rest of the people in my fucking
life. You know you have it.
Just have one of those weeks where
everyone's just bitching at you.
That's what I got. You know,
that's what I'm dealing with right now.
Like today's my girlfriend's birthday
and she's, she was fucking pissed at me.
[inaudible] she went absolutely
psycho on me this morning. You know,
it had nothing to do with me. Had
nothing to fucking do with me. You know,
I gave her a piece of cake last
night, right at midnight Sanger,
happy birthday because
technically it was a birthday.
I gave her a pre birthday slice of cake
and then I gave her a bag of Fritos with
a little bow on it. Right.
Just being a silly jackass.
Like that's all you get in
for your birthday. Right?
And everything was going
great. I was a big sweetheart.
And then I woke up this morning and made
the mistake of telling her that I had
made a dinner reservation yet.
And then she starts flipping out acting
like I'm just throwing her goddamn
birthday together when I gave her a pre
birthday fucking slice of birthday cake,
you know, start flipping out.
Know I don't know why she was flipping
out. It's like, it's fucking Tuesday.
It's a Tuesday. It's not a holiday.
This who the fuck is going out tonight?
June 2nd. Oh Shit. Was it
Cinco de Mayo? You know,
is it a fuss? I'm fucking New Zealand
holiday that I don't know about.
There's going to be plenty of fucking
reservations and lo and behold,
after she flips out, you
know, screaming at me. Right?
So all my neighbors think that I'm
beating her. Women love doing that Shit.
They just put on this
big fucking show. Right?
And then afterwards they just gone thigh.
I got a little crazy. I don't know.
I think just, you don't hate
me, dare you. You forgive me.
They do that shit. Right.
Meanwhile, you know,
your neighbors don't hear that part.
They don't hear the part where they sort
of say really quietly that they flipped
out for no fucking reason. You know,
all they heard was to
screaming and yelling.
So now I'm going to get the looks today
I'm going to go down to the garage.
You know,
like it's the 1920s like I should become
walking out with like a fucking wife
beater. You know, as I
reattached the belt to my pants,
so this is what happens, right? I ended
up calling up this fucking restaurant,
this, this, Nah, one of the nicest
steak houses out here in la.
I call him up. I said, hey, I'd like a
reservation for two people. I go, okay,
sir, what time would you
like? I said, how about eight?
I can't do anything at aide.
How about eight 30 and I said,
you know what sweetheart, that
would be perfect. And she said,
okay, and that was it.
That's all I had to fucking
do. But for some reason,
because I didn't do that
before her birthday,
that means that I don't give a fuck.
That's how fucking nuts women are.
She absolutely, she
actually flipped out on me
at 10 o'clock in the
morning on her birthday.
She didn't give me a chance to fuck the
day up. She did a preemptive strike.
Even though I gave her a pre birthday
slice of cake, I sang happy birthday.
I made a shut arise. I put, I put out
the lights, I lit a candle. I came in,
I sang happy birthday and
I gave her a bag of Fritos,
which is fucking ridiculous
and silly. It was great.
And tonight she's getting a real
gift, if you know what I mean. Oh. Um,
you know,
so it's one of those deals
where I'm laying in bed and
then all of a sudden she,
ah, it's just fucking ridiculous,
you know? But I didn't back down.
I didn't back down. I, you know,
actually when she really got mad,
why she started flipping out is because
she, when she was screaming at me,
I was laughing. You know,
I don't know if any other guy out there
has that problem you ever had any like
when your girlfriend
starts yelling at you,
your first is just to start
laughing. I Dunno why.
Every time my girl yells at me,
I instantly feel like I'm in school
again and I'm like in in second grade and
I'm getting yelled at and it's just, and
my friends are laughing at me. That's,
that's what I feel like.
I feel ridiculous. Okay.
I guess that's what it is.
When when a woman yells at
me, I always feel ridiculous.
You don't want a guy yells at me.
I get mad because I think, oh fuck,
this guy's going to beat the shit out of
me. So you got to get into that energy.
But when a girl woman is
just sitting there, hey,
hey,
what are you supposed to do? You know,
I'm not going to yell back at you.
You're a woman. I don't
want to feel like a bully.
We're not going to get
physical. You're a woman.
You know it's stupid.
Stop yelling that fucking high pitch
voice. You sound like a fucking,
he's all like Mickey
Mouse. Sit Down, relax,
collect your thoughts, make a list. If
you have to tell me why you're upset,
you know,
but don't just sit there fucking yelling
at me like you just took a hit off a
helium balloon because
it just sounds hilarious.
Especially when I haven't done anything
wrong and I got a great fucking gift
this year. That's what was killing me.
That actually I actually had that
moment during the fight where I said,
you want your gift, fine. And
I went out and I pull it out.
It's already wrapped with
a bow on it. You know,
sitting there acting like
I'm not fucking prepared.
There's your fucking present. Bam
wrapped with a fucking bow on it.
Jesus. Everybody giving me shit.
I remember last week when I
called that woman a douchebag.
Remember the douchebag of the week last
week cause she was giving me shit once
again, a female surprise.
Surprise was giving me shit that when
I read the underrated over aids or the
questions people have, I
wouldn't say what sex they were.
And she somehow found out a
way to kind of, I don't know,
make me look like I was some chauvinist
that I guess she felt if it was a good
question, I credited a guy and uh,
you know, it's a free podcast. Alright,
stop being so fucking conti. So
she became douchebag of the week.
So evidently she didn't like
it. And what does she do?
She sends me an email, his
email, she sends me a bill.
It's nice that you named
me douchebag of the week.
I don't really give a shit because
I always mean what I write.
I didn't know what that means cause I
always mean what I write. Oh really?
What are the rest of us just faking it?
We're just joking around but not you
yourself fucking serious is anyways,
evidently this psycho. This is a
new segment. This is cy. I can't,
I can't figure it out.
This is a love letter of the week or
a psycho of the week. I don't know.
You guys name it. I don't give
a shit. So anyway, she goes,
I don't really give a shit because I
always mean what I write and it seems
you're just talking shit about two
things that I wrote that seemed bitchy.
Now I was talking about your entire
email. Don't try to knock it down.
All right, continuing here
she goes call me account.
But I really don't give a fuck.
You've read a lot of my
comments previously and
agreed with them or had a good
response to them.
I'm literally fixing her sentences because
she doesn't know how to write here.
But it's nice that you a will consider
telling the gender of the person who, uh,
who the comments are from.
And I know you have a shit load of
people who listen to your podcast,
but I got you some more since my friends
who heard the podcast thought it was
fucking hilarious and then
they started listening to you.
So you really should be thanking
me. Isn't this just typical,
this is just all going to
be woman bashing this week.
Isn't this just typical of a fucking
female? You know what I mean?
She's getting something every
week, every week that is free.
And she still found a way
to bitch about it. Okay.
And then when I call her
out for being a douchebag,
now she's actually trying to make
me feel guilty. Yeah, I just,
you know, you can call me a douchebag
now. Whatever. I mean he just even,
I got a whole bunch of
friends to listen to you.
I mean probably should be thanking me,
but you know, that's okay. Shut up.
Just shy. I swear to God. Why? Why
can't you slap women? You know,
back in the day, how great did that feel?
You know you have on the wife Beater, the
wind blowing through your armpit hair,
his you just crack. I know it's evil.
I don't give a fuck. Fuck all you guys.
I don't give a shit. This is
the rest of her email. Okay.
Before you think I'm an
asshole. This is what she wrote.
This is actually so psychotic. It's
hilarious. She writes and yeah,
I do know that the name shows up on
the email even if I don't sign it.
But you just make it seem like you
that much of a retard to notice.
That's literally what she wrote.
And then she wrote your over 40 and
have the vocabulary of a seventh grader.
Your is spelled y, o U. R. All right,
for all you morons out there,
your y o u r is possessive
meaning like that's your shirt.
Okay. If you're saying your
over 40 that's you are.
Okay. So that means if you're going
to say your, it's an apostrophe.
Y O u a pause to free our e.
So if you're a dumb fuck like this woman,
if you don't know the next time you go
to write your just stop and see if you
are would still fit. All right?
Like your over 40 you are
over 40 okay. Right there.
You know you got to use the apostrophe
as as opposed to saying your over 40 so
what is over do I own over you? Dumb fuck.
But I do have the vocabulary of a
seventh grade but you know something,
you have the fucking vocabulary
for third grader. All right,
your over 40 and you had the
vocabulary of a seventh grader,
you recognize real words.
How hilarious is this?
And she's misspelling stuff.
You started when you read and
I hope your dog outlives you
and you die lonely because of your
inability to commit and therefore never
achieve the comedic fame of the
Great George Carlin. So Simon says,
go fuck yourself sense,
it sounds like you have
major brain damage.
All right sweetheart, I'm really going
to try to help you out here. Okay?
If you hope that my dog
outlives me and then you say,
and then I die lonely. Okay. If
I'm going to die before my dog,
mathematically the fucking
dog is still gonna be there.
So how am I going to be lonely? You know,
the dog would have to die first or
run away. So what you should say is,
I hope you dog outlives you then runs
away and then you die by yourself as
opposed to saying, I hope your dog
outlives you when you die. Lonely.
Now I would die before my dog and be
sitting there licking my face and my last
few pathetic moments,
and then evidently because of my
inability to commit to a relationship,
I'll never achieve the comedic
fame of George Carlin. Oh,
that totally makes sense.
It has nothing to do with the fact that
I wasn't blessed with his gifts as a
comedian, you know,
all you have to do to be as good as
George Carlin is just commit to a
relationship to some psycho
fucking chick like you. All right,
lady. These are podcasts. These are
jokes. When I call somebody a Douchebag,
I'm just fucking around so I don't
take it seriously, but if you want to,
you and your friends can
go fuck yourselves and go
listen to another podcast.
All right. Stop trying to threaten me
like you're going to take podcasts.
Listen, there's listeners away. I
don't give a shit. This is free.
What are you guys going to take
away advertising dollars from me?
I don't give a fuck. Fuck
you and your friends.
I hope you're all listening it together.
Fuck all of you. Look around the room.
Look into each one of your eyes.
I'm saying fuck all of you.
You know what's funny is your friends
are probably laughing at you right now
going, you know what she has?
She has kind of a comment.
She really is like that.
She does have a tendency,
I know I shouldn't use that
word, but I'm serious. She has,
she can be real cunty sometimes and she
has a tendency to exaggerate things that
aren't really happening in
fact in here. Okay. All right.
So that's the first hate mail.
So I figured, you know what,
why don't I seek out, I'll try
to find some other hate mail.
Here's one that I got on
youtube. This is a nice one. Um,
basically I, uh, there's a clip on there
from me from about eight years ago,
which he'll obviously notice cause I'm
skinnier and have a full head of hair.
And I'm doing this bit about joining
the military, saying how, you know,
when you watch the commercials for the
military, it makes you want to join.
You know, they make it look like
everybody gets their own jet.
Everybody's driving a tank.
Everyone's doing some top gun shit.
Everyone's having a, you know,
you're a fucking navy seal.
You get your face painted and you're
clinging to that raft and you comment up
out of the water, like fucking
Rambo into the mud and shit.
That's what they make
you look like. Right.
But what they don't show is all
the other jobs that, you know,
you go in there and you think you're
going to be like, you know, Tom Cruise,
oh my God, my dog just
farted. Jesus Christ, Cleo.
You know? Could you at least like,
you don't kills me about
this dog when it farts is it,
it doesn't even have the decency that
fucking kind of make a face like, yeah,
that was me. Sorry about
that. She doesn't lays here.
Good Lord. At least it's silent. You know?
It's the worst is when you have a dog
that farts like a person ever been over
somebody's house and the dogs
and a corner, they just go like,
it is like, really. Anyways,
so that was the bit,
so the bit is yeah, you, you, you, you
see the commercial and you sign up,
you thinking, yeah,
I'm going to be like Tom Cruise in top
gun and then you show up and you ended up
being that guy. You know
when the jet takes off,
you just like point in the same direction
that the jet's going or they give you
those, those orange glow sticks from a
rave. You know when the plane comes in,
you're that guy, you put the air
in the tires on the jet, you know,
you joined and next thing you know you're
standing there with like a camouflage
weed whacker. Wait, wait, gay
man. Yeah, that was a joke. Okay.
Simple joke.
I actually did the joke at a military
base and I also did it at one of the VA
hospitals and if fucking
killed, you know what I mean?
So this guy of course has to go all
Fox News on Youtube and this is what he
writes is actually kind of funny.
He writes you on grateful bitch.
And then he puts in quotes, if you're
dumb enough to join the military. Dot.
Dot. Dot,
which is classic of somebody who wants
to take a joke seriously as they don't
write. The whole joke is they
just take not even a sentence.
They just take a part of a
sentence. Okay. So he writes,
if you're dumb enough to join
the military dot, dot. Dot.
And then he writes in capital
letters. Fact, fact is,
if it wasn't for the bravery
of the American servicemen
and the American spirit
throughout history, I
like the American spirit.
What do you mean chicks who go to
a fucking bake sale? Um, anyways,
you wouldn't even get,
you wouldn't even have the right to mock
those sacrifices which have been made
for you. And if you did,
you would probably be doing it in German.
So respect your American servicemen
because it is him in which you owe your
freedoms to take to that what people came,
you know, half the time
people think I'm a morons,
cause people can't even write a sentence
because it is him in which you owe your
freedoms to that you take so foolishly
for granted. That's word for word.
I appreciate the sacrifices
of other, you coward.
Uh, you know, at what point did I
make fun of servicemen? I didn't,
I was making fun of the how fucking
whatever. You know something.
If you guys want to take jokes
seriously, I don't give a fuck and I,
I'm really sick. That hacky thing
where someone goes, you know,
and they did it for you and if you didn't,
you'd be speaking German right now.
That's how dumb people are. You know,
they're just used to say that you'd be
speaking German right now is a hacky
fucking reference.
You're just saying that because you
heard someone else say it. You know,
why wouldn't I be speaking
like I was from England?
Why wouldn't I be speaking a
Spanish right now? You know,
we did fight other countries,
Mexican American war.
How come that one never gets brought up?
I can, I wouldn't be speaking Korean.
I mean, granted they weren't over
here, but you know what I'm saying?
I'm so sick of fucking idiots who speak
in sound bites like everyone who like
makes fun of France. Yeah,
we full conceived jurors.
[inaudible] read a history book.
We were paying them back for saving
our ass with England. You dumb fucks.
So now we're even all
right, whatever. Look at me.
I'm getting all upset here cause
people are morons. All right, let's,
let's move onto saline. Let's, let's get
to some information here for the week.
All right. Um, last week I
was at, Oh, here's going out.
Last week I was at teasing firefighters
and I was talking about how, uh,
you know, 20 trucks show up to
every fire. Why does that happen?
How much do those trucks cost? And
a volunteer firefighter wrote in,
he said a up it up. A De I. Yes.
How much a fire trucks cost fire
engines, which put the water out.
Uh Oh wait, put the water out.
Fire engines, which put water out.
I think I'm dyslexic. Um,
typically run between
300,000 and $600,000.
Fire trucks also called ladder trucks
run between 400,000 and 800,000.
The two main differences between the
low and high numbers is the make of the
truck and the equipment.
It comes with a fire engine with all
the hoses added on and the breathing
apparatus is more expensive
than without. All right.
Well here's a question I have with for
you. You saved the make of the truck.
So, uh, I guess what Mack
truck, that's a reputable bank.
Reputable law brand as opposed to what?
A High Hyundai fire firetruck.
I guess that that's what it is.
I don't even know what the fuck
they are. But anyways, you asked us,
you asked why so many pieces of
apparatus show up to a call a,
there are a few reasons for this.
Sometimes it's manpower. In my case,
we have three fire companies
consisting of six pieces of apparatus.
Since we volunteer, they may not be
enough volunteers in town at any one time.
So all three companies get
banged out, banged out,
equals called out in firefighting terms.
Typically at least four
pieces show up for a call.
This allows us to have all the
equipment we need at the scene.
Sometimes you just never know what you're
going to need. All right, fair enough.
Uh, but perhaps the best
reason this is great here,
but perhaps the best reason
is that sometimes we are
called for what amounts to
be in the end. Absolutely
nothing. About six months ago,
my pager went your pager,
Jesus Christ. Dude,
is your firetruck pulled
by a couple of horses?
Who the fuck still has a picture? I
know he's going to write back. Girl,
should we just special fucking nine 11
pager for firemen? I right. I'm a moron.
I get it. All right. How about six
months ago, my pager went off for,
for a working house fire at 2:00
AM I jumped awake and flew down,
uh, to the firehouse. We got on the
scene. We saw no smoke or flames in, uh,
in speaking with the residents,
they had just woke up and saw a reflection
in their mirror that they thought was
a fire.
So here's all six of our apparatus
showing up for absolutely nothing,
or the time we called for,
for lightning, hit lightning,
hitting a house on a clear summer night.
The woman heard something and thought
it was lightening hitting her house.
People are fucking idiots
all over. Hope that helps.
And even though I am a firefighter,
you're firefighter jokes were funny. See,
they as a cool guy. He
see their sweetheart. Even
though he's a firefighter,
he sees the joke. He realizes. I'm just
telling jokes out, right? There you go.
People how we learned
something this week. All right,
you want to learn something else then I'm
going to wrap up this fucking podcast.
I'm gonna know it's
really short this week,
but at w I don't understand what the
point of me keep babbling for fucking 50
minutes. If G Cass won't
upload, the files are right.
Here's some computer
tips for the week. Uh,
here's some computer tips on
web searching. All right, Bill,
when you want to find something that, uh,
that you are Google it, what? That makes
no sense. All right? When you Google,
use the plus and the minus
signs to find the shit you want.
So this is how it works. If you
want to search something with uh,
plus in front of it, then it
will have to contain the word.
And if you want to put a minus in front
of it that were removed the word from
the listing.
So basically put the plus in front
of the word that you're searching,
that you want to find an a minus in
front of the one that you don't want.
For example,
I want to see how many sites have bill
burr on it while limit while eliminating
bilber from, uh, from the search.
So you would Google the
plus sign plus my name bill,
then the plus sign,
and then you write bur minus bill
bird.com and the results will,
uh,
will show sites that can AV content with
bill burr on it and not include bill
bird.com. Huh? Isn't that interesting?
I didn't know that shit. And he said,
I'm listed on seven hundred thousand
seven hundred six thousand web pages,
not including my website.
706,000 websites have my name on it and
I still can't sell up the third show on
Saturday night. What the
fuck is going on? All right.
Unless you find some shit out, like uh,
if you want to find some
shit out like to do to you.
I can't read what you guys write.
If you want to find some shit out,
like to you do when you are on what?
I can't even paraphrase that.
If you want to find some shit out like
to you do now like you do when you're on
the podcast. All right? You had
an extra word in there, dude.
If you want to find some shit out like
you do when, uh, you're on the podcasts,
use the above option, the plus, minus or
or use quotes. All right?
You wanted to find the names of
female serial killers a few weeks ago.
Just put quotes around a phrase and it
will only show sites that contain all
phrases. Okay, I get it. You know,
like you guys ever go to search
something and you're like,
you'll just write female serial
killers and then a bunch of, uh,
hits will come out and you have a
bunch that just say female and a bunch,
several just say serial and other one
would just say killers or whatever. Yeah.
I guess if you put quotes around it,
that puts it all together. You know what?
That's very helpful. I know this part
of the s the podcast. Isn't that funny?
But God damn it, we, you know, we got
to learn something here. All right.
I should've got some water here. My
fucking mouth is dry as hell. All right,
let's wrap up the podcast here. Uh,
this is the Syrah killer topic. Bill,
if you want to be a serial killer, uh,
and use the best weapon
you have to use ice.
If you stab someone with an icicle
or beat someone to death with ice,
then it melts and you have no
murder weapon or fingerprints,
no DNA or fingerprint problems.
Oh yeah. That guy who, uh,
that talked about tracking you down with
the type of soil where it was located
and the type of wood used and all
that shit is exactly that bullshit.
They watch too many shows. CSI does
not do that shit. I know, Dude.
We all knew he was just fucking
around. He was making fun of how,
when you watch those shows. Um, all
right, what else do we got here?
Question. Uh, Bill, you say that you
play the drums. Um, if you could,
uh, play the drums in any band, living
or dead for one show, one night,
only in any city in the world,
who would you play and in what city?
Okay. Fuck. Um,
Jesus Christ, it would
either be led Zepplin
you know what's funny is I
think I would have a better,
better chance faking what John Bonam
does than what Phil Rudd does in ACDC.
Fulfill red does is so fucking difficult.
If you play drums to just sit
there going, boom, crack, boom,
crack for fucking two hours straight.
Um, yeah, I think I would play,
I would play with led Zeppelin. I do
it in England at Royal Albert Hall.
And I would, and I would play
on that, that the Ludwig, uh,
that maple drum kit that he played,
either that or his green sparco kit.
I don't like the Vista Vista
light kit he had, or the, uh,
the stainless steel one. I
liked the two ones that he had.
I play on either one of those and somehow
I would sound as good as can I, can I,
can I have that as part of the fantasy
that I would actually sound as good as he
would sound? You know,
that's what I would do.
Um, and then I'd get fucking some 1969
groupie pussy afterwards. All right,
next question, Bill. Um,
would you rather be respected,
be a respected comedian who never
makes it really big like so-and-so and
So-and-so, I'm not going
to name the names a,
he named two people who are
millionaires playing theaters,
but I guess who can still
walk down the street, he said,
or would you rather be a one trick
pony like a blah, blah, blah,
who has written, uh,
one catch phrase to fame and fortune and
has more cash than he can ever spend?
Oh No, I'd much rather be respected
by my peers without a fucking doubt.
Without a doubt. I would a, you know,
you can become a really big comedian
and not necessarily be super fun.
Like that's the great thing about
entertainment is you, it's easy to become,
I can't say it's easy, but you can become
a millionaire and still not be famous.
You know what I'm saying? And I
always use this, this example,
like that Sitcom Caroline in the city,
they actually made it to syndication.
And the entire cast could walk by me on
a walking down the street and I would
recognize any of them. So I would,
you know, Dude, you're a millionaire.
How much fucking money do you need?
And I also think the more I look
at these people being super,
super famous is I just doesn't
look like a good time to me.
You know, I think I would,
I want to be a millionaire
who has notoriety,
which means maybe two, three times
a month, somebody goes a year,
that comedian, I really like what
you do. And then Yay, thanks a lot.
Then I go back to eating my omelette.
I'd rather do that than fucking, uh,
I dunno. You know, I, I don't,
I don't ever want to fucking have to
step out of a limo with no panties on.
You know what I mean? Just so I can
maintain fame at that fucking level.
Do you think that would whinge, do you
think that that would be miserable?
I mean, other than when
you're at the, the,
the fucking Celtics game and you
have court side seats in that moment,
that's fucking awesome. You know what
I mean? I've always used this analogy,
but it's someday at some point you're
going to have to fucking blow out a
bathroom in public and you don't want
to be famous at that point. You know,
you just want to be like, dude,
you can have some fucking guy just blew.
You don't want a bill burns
just blew out the bathroom.
They literally put a fucking name
to it. It's brutal. Um, all right.
Overrated or underrated, really quickly.
Overrated beer with the
lime already in it. No joke.
It just tastes fucking gross. Um,
what else do I got here? I'm sorry,
this is really fucking unraveling here.
I just, I, I, I've done, I've done
this too many times this fucking week.
I don't mind. I lost my passion.
Like if Pau Gasol was
doing a fucking podcast,
this is what it would sound
like right now. You know,
and I'd be thumping my chest acting like
I'm giving you entertainment right now
and I'm not, you know, that's what
I'm going to end with this week.
What do we got here? I'm 28 minutes in.
Good. I'll keep it under 30 minutes.
I'm going to end with this prediction.
I think Orlando is going to beat
the Lakers and I think that they,
they're going to beat them
in six games because uh,
they don't have anybody to stop. Dwight
Howard and I think Turco Lou is a,
I dunno,
I think that guy's going to get enough
points and then they got that other guy,
the number two or is he the point guard?
I don't know shit about basketball.
I just fucking hate the Lakers.
So I'm going to go out on a limb
here with no money down or nothing.
I'm not going out on a limb. I just,
I just think I got a feeling I
got a fucking feeling. All right.
I think Van van Gundy
is going to out show.
He's going to out coach
Phil Jackson. Phil Jackson,
he's making home videos
with his girlfriend,
his new hot young girlfriend on the,
on his way to the staples center.
Every night. They're soft,
they're fucking soft.
All they have is Coby
Kobe's to shit. I love Coby,
but I think his teammates
are scared of them.
I think they're scared
to fuck up around them.
They're scared to disappoint them. Uh,
and they just get freaked out
and they just pass him the ball.
That's what I think is gonna happen.
Pago Saul gets the most quietest,
15 fucking rebounds and the quietest
20 points a game. I think he's gonna.
He's gonna take a fucking Dwight Howard
elbow to his bearded chops sometime in
game two and the Orlando's
gonna win game two.
They got three in a row in Orlando.
They're going to win two out of three
and then they're going to come back and
they're going to beat the heartless
Lakers in the staple center. Game Six.
What the fuck do you guys think
about that? Huh? You liked that one?
You know, what do you guys think about
the two, three, two play a format?
I think it's bullshit. I think the,
they give the advantage to the weaker
team because the Lakers should have home
court. Right? And I don't think
they do with a two, three,
two format because when it's two, three,
two the pressure is on the home
team for the first two games.
Right. If it was two, two, one, one,
one like they used to do back in back
in the day you open the first two games,
the pressure are on our Lando to
steal one. Now when it's two, three,
two the, the pressures on the Lakers,
they have to win both of those
fucking games. They can't go one,
one and then path to play three
fucking games in Orlando. Right.
My out of my mind, and this
is, is this all getting boring?
While I don't give a fuck cause this
is my third one this week. Listen,
my goddamn mouth is dry. Um, so anyways,
I might Abdu do another podcast this
week as I might have a very special
announcement of something that I might
be doing next week that might be on
television. How do you like that? I'm
leaving you with a little cliffhanger. Um,
and with that, I don't
have any gigs until, uh,
the third week in July when I'm going
to be at the comedy works in Denver. Um,
why is that? Um, I booked a
very small part in a very big,
and, um, I dunno, I'm shooting
like five, six days on it,
but they had to clear out my [inaudible]
my schedule because they're working
around famous people's schedules. So
I'm low man on the totem pole. So, uh,
I gladly cleared out my
Spec, my a schedule. So, uh,
I'll let you know what the name of the
movie is and all that type of shit,
when in fact, I know that I haven't been
cut out of it. How's that? All right.
And that's the, a very short, very
succinct Monday morning podcast this week.
The third fucking time I'm praying to
God that this thing is going to actually
get published. All right,
you guys have a good weekend.
Thanks to everybody who came out to the
Improv a couple of weekends ago out here
in Hollywood. All right, that's
it. Take it easy. Take it easy.