Hey, what's going on ? it's Bill Burr.
It's time for the Thursday afternoon.
Just before Friday. Monday morning
podcast and Ah, I'm just checking in on.
You can't yell. I can't yell.
I am in a Cologne, Germany.
Um, and it is, it is one 49 whoops.
Sorry.
One 49 in the fucking morning
and I'm fucking wide awake.
I'm still on fucking hell a time.
What time is it back there?
Nine hour difference. Saints.
To what? Claw Gates. About what?
Nine 30 in the morning.
I don't what the fuck it is.
It's about four 34 or five o'clock
or some shit. Anyways, I worry you.
How are you doing? I made it over
here. The flight was a fucking joke.
I literally watched like
I watched one full movie.
All right. It was a, I
watched Dr Strange love,
one of my favorite movies of
all time and favorite director,
Stanley Kubrick and Peter
Sellers. Everybody. That
movie is fucking brilliant.
I watched that and then I watched
a half hour of goodwill hunting.
I was like,
I have not literally not seen this movie
since I saw it in the movie theaters.
I've seen bits and pieces cause it's on,
but I never just sat down to watch it.
Um,
for those of you who've never seen it,
he's wicked smart. He cleans the floors,
but he's wicked smart.
Um,
so a little bit of that,
it was crazy because that will be,
doesn't seem that old to me. I was
like, wow man, that's fucking movies.
21 years old. And when I was just seeing
just the shot of the skyline of Boston,
how much it's changed, um, since then
and how much it's gentrified
and gentrifying is Boston,
is that the white people became
even wider for most of those, uh,
most of those areas.
And then I watched the beginning of pappy
on the original with Steve McQueen and
Dustin Hoffman, and then I fell asleep
and just fucking woke up in Germany.
Um, it's not that bad, man was not that
bad a fight, but here was the problem.
I landed in Munich and at a connecting
flight to Cologne and they gave me a
fucking one hour window to catch it.
An 11 hour flight.
And you're gonna give me a
one hour window. I was like,
before he even got on the plane,
I'm like,
there's no fucking way I'm going to
make that thing. Yeah. So much shit.
Just a context of a headwind for
11 hours and I'm going to miss it.
And I missed it.
So I to fucking sit there in Munich,
get the God damn airport for like
fucking three hours waiting for the last
little southwest flight I had to take.
It was like an hour flight, uh, up
to Cologne. Wasn't that bad though.
But I mean I was cracking me up.
It was making me think about
the way they play football now,
where before halftime
you score a touchdown,
you down by a point and rather than going
for the extra point, they do dumb shit.
Like they go for a two point
conversion and then they don't get it.
And rather than being tied up that
down by one and then the end, you know,
there's some county thing,
you know,
you're down by four points instead
of three negative score, a touchdown.
That was the travel version of that.
So anyways,
um, I gotta tell you, I don't,
I never think about World War
II until I come over here.
I watched that Ken Burns the war,
which was like a 90
fucking part one out each.
Each one was like one
hour long about the war.
And every time I fly over here,
it's not till I get over Great Britain
and you just think about those spits
foe fires and the blitzkrieg and all of
that shit.
Winston Churchill,
then you've come onto the mainland,
you start thinking about the
battle of the bulge Dresden,
all of this fucking shit.
And I was actually watching
this documentary here, uh,
and it was in German, so I couldn't
tell. I was like, wow, they fucking,
they're also talking about world war two.
I figured they'd want to shy away from it.
You know what I mean?
The same way I don't watch highlights
from last year's super bowl.
I don't want to see those
eagles win either. Right. Um,
but they were talking about,
I could tell what they were talking about,
cause I had heard about it before,
is this top secret now basically a jet
that they were just on the verge of like
developing, which just would
have been a fucking game changer.
Like how far ahead Germany was
with all of their technology.
I remember hearing,
I've talked about this shit before.
Like if you killed the
German soldier in American,
you dropped your machine
gun and picked up there.
It says with like fucking liquid
cooled or something like that. Um,
I remember hearing some German
tank commanders saying, uh,
one tiger was better than three Sherman's,
but the Americans always had
four. You know, typical us.
We just treated it like a food court.
We just piled on instead of the food.
It was a weaponry and were able to
get 'em but some historians, so I,
and look up this fucking jet
first German jet World War Two.
Yeah, this fucking thing. And it
looked just like the spitfire,
but it had like two jet engines on it.
So the only thing I could think like,
well what the fuck would you do? How
quickly that thing could get up on you?
What would you try to be like Tom Cruise
and that drug movie we just slowed down
in the feds got to keep going by you.
You know,
I think that's works if somebody is not
trying to fucking shoot you out of the
sky. So I think that that's probably
what they focus on over here.
They focus on how, how good their
weapons were rather than their, uh,
you know,
steps in society.
It was called the Schmitz.
Me Is two six to nickname the Schwabie.
Yeah,
I'm sure I'm saying this phone
is German for the swallow. Um,
was the world's first operational
jet powered fighter aircraft.
That's what it was like.
Basically a jet powered fucking two seat
or a design work started before World
War II began.
But problems with the engine,
which means people died test in
and out. Uh, Buh Buh Buh Buh Buh.
Yeah,
the me 62 62 is faster and more
heavily armed than any allied fighter,
including the British oh jet powered.
Gloster meteor.
Oh, at that big clunky hunk of shit. Uh,
well I mean I shouldn't talk.
The Americans didn't have one,
but Jesus is that an ugly ass fucking
playing? The German one doesn't look bad.
It just looks like they're, uh, what
they had the English had the spitfire.
I don't forget what the, we
had the Cadillac, I don't know.
I don't fucking know shit about this
stuff. But anyways, I was watching,
I found that,
that um,
that was definitely interesting and um,
you know what it is,
you know how they always make
fun of the ignorant American,
the fat American and all that Shit.
You know,
what is the through line of Conti
behavior is people getting off an
international flight and
doing that fast walk.
I mean, you see people cutting off
old people in all of this shit.
Just trying to not get in, you know,
trying to get as far up. Do, you know,
to get through customs is possible.
It's really fucking horrific.
Um, I always laugh thinking like,
where are you going? You know, where
the, where the fuck is anybody going?
It's already another flight in front of
you. You know we didn't, you're going to,
you're going to get there first and
you'll be first and fucking line. Um,
maybe it works. I don't know. I don't,
life's too short to run through a
fucking airport with your luggage.
If you're not trying to catch a plane,
you're already landed. What are you doing?
Just sit on your phone,
play a little fucking solitaire and
then talk to the guy up there. You know,
I didn't know what to say cause you
only landed where I landed in Munich.
I didn't know. Usually I have work papers
and I was sitting there thinking like,
ah, fuck man, I don't have any fucking
work papers and I get up there.
So I tried to look all chill and shit.
Right.
The lady doesn't ask me anything and the
guy behind her is like training of it
and he's like, oh, I just need some
describes him, desires, it's rising.
And I'm like,
he's just trained at a man.
He's just training and I'm working up
this lie in my head that I'm meeting my
wife and Cologne, Germany and she's
coming over from London. Could,
could it be any more convoluted?
Like really,
you guys are beginning of your
European vacation and Cologne. Jeremy,
do you have family there?
Did they just put up a new fucking
Ferris wheel with the eight Garner that
fucking giant there?
Which I didn't know existed.
I had no idea that fucking thing existed
until I fucking looked up things to do
in Cologne because I got
a whole day tomorrow.
I just want to go out and buy a pair of
fucking Adidas over here that they don't
have stateside. I'm not looking
for 20 floors a horse here.
Um, anyways, uh, so I make it through.
They stamped my passport,
I think I'm all good.
And then this fucking cop is just
like a guten tag. Hello. And I'm like,
Hey, what's up? He goes,
Oh, where you're going?
I want to be and what the fuck are you
going? Fuck you mean, what am I doing?
He already stamped the fucking thing.
So then I tell them to stupid shit
about my wife coming over. He goes, uh,
is this the only place you're going to
be in German? I was like, I made Cologne,
Munich, Berlin, where
else? And I'm like, Warsaw,
Prague hungry. And he goes, how long
are you going to be over here? I'm like,
until the 14th. He's like,
of January. I was like, yeah.
Then I'm like, and he starts
walking towards this door
with my passport. I'm like,
Jesus fucking Christ. Here we go. Right.
And then he just turns around and gives
it to me and I was just like, all right.
So then I text my fucking tour guy over
here. I was like, do I need work papers?
And he's like, no, you're all good. So
I went through that whole fucking, uh,
what was that movie there?
Okay.
Well that fucking guy,
he has the drugs tape to him.
I can't remember fucking anything.
I ended up having that moment.
I didn't even need to.
MMM.
So anyways, so I'm here. Um, uh,
um, obviously jet lag, but, uh,
my hours ready to go and I plan on kicking
the shit out of people right through
Europe.
And this is going to be a thrash.
So my only thing I need to do is I
need to get my Kiddo some shell toes,
get my wife some sneakers and get myself
some sneakers. And other than that,
all I do when I go to new countries cause
I don't like clutter is I, you know,
that little flag you buy that
people selling their coat.
I just buy that thing and I've
never sold them on to anything.
I just keep them in a little plastic bag.
MMM.
Which by the way,
I saw this thing where people try to
break the record to see all of the content
go to every country in the fucking
world. Um, first of all, I,
it's like what country do you come from
where your country doesn't have beef
with any other nation?
You know what I mean?
Jesus Christ the way that they're
fucking whack and people nowadays.
Um,
but anyways,
so like some people have done it by the
time they're like in their twenties.
Then I read this one guy, we say, sorry,
daddy started to do it.
But then after he got up to 127
countries and he realized that he wasn't
traveling, he wasn't seeing anything, he
was just going there and just, you know,
you know, flying all the way to China
and getting like a fucking, you know,
some fucking shrimp fried rice and then
just flying on to fucking Thailand and
doing whatever the fuck he did there.
You know,
stand next to an elephant
and take a picture.
So it's like not traveling is what
the guy was saying. So I don't know.
Am I babbling right now? I'd probably
have fucking jet lag too. Um,
oh my God.
Did you guys see I'm going to try to
get more into like pop culture to expand
the reach of my podcast. Oh my
God. Madonna went up at this,
this legendary gay club and showed off
what some people were staying with a
brand new ass.
It's trying to say she got acid plants.
All right.
And I'm like, okay, you know,
why the fuck would you get a
brand new ass in your sixties?
Why would you get a new ass anyways?
I don't understand that one.
You know what I mean? I, I don't
really understand the tits.
I don't understand taking anything
and putting it in your body,
uh, that you can't kind of get rid of.
You know what I mean? Shit it out. I mean,
you got fucking,
what do you know?
I gotta see what those fucking
things look like. But anyway,
so I'm just going like, oh my
God, she's lost her fucking mind.
And then I find out that she has a new
album coming out and nobody's really been
talking about her. It was fucking
brilliant. I bet it wasn't even real.
I bet she just went down to a joke shop.
You know, they're phony British accent.
Roy you to put this fake as in the
back of me pads, promote me new album.
MMM.
What's her new album's? What's his new
album called? Huh? Songs about coming,
something about the summit.
About something about sex.
Um, anyways, let's see.
Fake ass implants.
Let's see what these things look like.
Are these like, oh my fucking God.
Oh my God, what enough. All those attempts
thought that was somebody ass. I'm like,
why is this so much space in the bud?
Crec was cleavage. Um, all right,
this is just all calling out
people with butt implants.
This is something that guys get blamed
for it. You know, this is chicks.
Just this is classic check on chick
hate and they're gonna fucking,
they're gonna fucking trash. It's,
I want to see what it looks like.
Oh my God. Oh my God. What the fuck?
That can't be fucking real.
I don't understand why.
Why do people do shit like
this to themselves because
of the pressure if fucking
me or puts it? Is that the pressure
you gave into it? All right.
There's a lot of pressure out there to
have a full head of fucking wavy here.
You know, this transparent fucking
jackass doesn't give into it.
Why the fuck are you fucking
blame society? All right.
What do ass implants look like?
Yeah.
Google must be like, oh
my God, this guy's dumb.
I want to know what they look like,
people feel but implants.
Oh my God. That just like those
giant silicone fucking things.
He's fucking lazy assholes.
Just go do some squats,
go do some squats and just admit that
you're not fucking Jennifer Lopez.
Whoever the fuck has the
best ass right now. Um,
anyways, dude, I should do that.
I've been threatening to get hair
plugs right out here in eastern Europe,
eastern Europe yet,
but what I consider eastern Europe,
anything that was behind
the communist block,
when I go to fucking the other side
of Berlin, the east side of Berlin,
I'm going to get some fucking take stem
cells shut in my head and I'm gonna come
back with this ridiculous fucking
lion's mane of ginger hair.
And you guys are all going to be like, oh
my God, what the fuck did you guys see?
Bill's fucking hair plugs. And
eventually we'll be like, hey man,
he's got a new special coming out
and I'm gonna, I'm gonna fucking,
I mean Madonna's the master at it,
you know,
I'd be lucky to stick around for
half as long as she has. So, I mean,
if that's what you got to do, maybe
I should do it. You know what guys?
I don't watch fight club
because it triggers me.
It makes me not like my body and I
just feel like Brad Pitt is just,
he's just, he's, what do they say?
He's just setting the bar too high.
I can't like,
I just don't understand why
nobody calls these women out.
Like how fucking self involved are you
that you're looking at a movie star and
you start thinking like, Oh God,
I have to compete with that. No,
no,
just appreciate compete with that.
You're not even in the same fucking solar
system is that I can throw a football,
but I don't look at an NFL
quarterback and be like,
why does he have to throw it so hard?
What is there to be so accurate?
Um, anyways, um,
Jesus Christ, the Internet, my gut
comedians from a fellow comedian,
please stop attacking other comedians.
What are we doing?
We need to circle the wagons here.
Jesus fucking Christ.
Don't comedians get enough shit.
We're going to sit here and
fucking attack each other.
The fuck are we doing?
I feel like this is like at
the end of the Blair witch.
When those kids kept them,
ended up in the same place in woods and
they were losing their fucking minds.
This is what's going on. Well, I
don't, I, I, for the life of me, I,
I just don't understand how a
comedian could trash another comedian.
Um, publicly like that. I mean, amongst
your friends, you guys guys a hack,
this guy stinks, blah, blah, blah, blah,
blah, blah. I like this guy. You know,
everybody does that.
And every fucking but the to go on there
and then to actually talk about what
subjects should or shouldn't be discussed.
I mean,
there's like comedians out there.
They sound like Tipper Gore back in the
80s when she was freaking out about hair
metal.
Um,
I think there's bigger problems in the
world than someone going on stage trying
out new jokes that he's not putting out
to the world. He's just working on them.
That's all that was happening.
Jesus Christ.
I think some of the fucking Shit I've
said on stage just fucking around.
And it leads to something.
It's, it's part of it.
So that's like somebody
saying like listening to the
first version of a hit song.
God, Oh my God, that fucking sucks. It's
like, yeah, well we're working on it.
How the fuck could somebody fucking blow?
Everybody's acting like not everybody,
but there's people out there.
They're acting like fucking my God,
they were acting like soccer moms.
It's just a,
it's just a fucking weird goddamn time.
And any ways it's hard enough.
Ah, right now to try to avoid a fucking
scandal. It you're not even looking for.
We don't need to be attacking each other,
right?
So God bless all the comedians out there.
God bless [inaudible] whatever the
fuck it is they're trying to do that.
Try to be funny,
you know?
And let these fucking non
comedians say what you shouldn't.
You shouldn't joke about. Let them sounds
stupid like that. Jesus fucking Christ.
You Remember Tipper Gore?
Remember that lady way back in the day?
Poor al.
You imagine that?
I bet he listened to all that,
but he listened to motley crew
at all of them back in the day.
Wish I could do a fucking Al
Gore impression. It's sync.
Fucking kickstart my heart,
the Al Gore voice. Um,
all right, let me, um, I just set
the other night at the comedy store
late night
and I was just in a stupid mood and the
piano player was laughing and I just
started playing to him and I said like
two or three fucking things that I would
never, I would never put in a special,
I would never ever, it was just,
and it wouldn't, it wouldn't even have
worked in that room at like eight,
nine o'clock at night, nine, 10 o'clock.
But once you go on the
other side of midnight,
it just becomes like a different
fucking thing now. All right.
If anyone were to film that,
whatever the fuck it is,
I was talking, what the fuck did
I talk about? Oh, don't say it.
Don't say I fucking say it.
Right. One of those sets,
if all of a sudden now somebody at eight
in the morning is eating their toast
and then somebody says it,
you know what I mean?
It's like for as much as a dick is,
I am, you know, if I go to church,
if I ever go to church, go like
once a fucking year when I go there.
I don't act the way I act at the
fucking comedy store, nor would I,
and I wouldn't feel like if,
if what I said at the comedy store,
I then said in a church,
if people got offended,
I wouldn't then feel like I was having
a Lenny Bruce moment and I was fucking
being censored.
Okay.
Yeah. There's a time and a place for
things and it's just like, you know,
to just fucking
take somebody.
They working on this shit,
doing what they're supposed to be doing
and then you take it and fucking throw
it in everybody's face at nine in the
morning on Twitter, every z, he said,
Whoa, no fucking, it's
like Jesus fucking Christ.
Okay.
I Dunno. It's a really,
people, just to let you know,
making jokes about really dark things a
lot of times is a way to avoid the pain.
It doesn't mean you don't care about it.
That's really the way it is.
Such like page one of comedy.
And if you don't understand that,
then you don't know what you're talking
about and you really need to stand down,
I think anyway, there's my little fucking
too sensitive. Jesus fucking Christ.
I cannot,
I can't fucking imagine.
I can't ever fucking imagine telling a
comic what the fuck they should be saying
on stage.
Um,
yet let alone trying to incite other
people who aren't Comedians to fucking
share that point of view.
MMM.
If I did that, evidently nowadays
I would be a progressive liberal.
It used to be the hardcore, right? What
is going on? The world has gone mad.
Down is up, up is down, black
is white. What the fuck? All
right. Dollar Shave Club.
And I'm not trashing anybody.
I'm just fucking say it guys.
Don't fucking pick on each other.
We're going to get enough
shit out there evidently.
MMM.
From butthurt alley over there.
All right. Dollar Shave Club.
Everybody Dollar Shave Club has
everything you need to look, feel,
and smell your best.
You never have to go to this store.
If you're ever pushing a mop,
it fucking MIT and you
fucking buddy itches and you
can't fucking solve the math
problem. It's because you
didn't use a one wipe Charlie,
a little goodwill hunting little dollar
shave club there. That's called a Mashup.
I believe the kids call it a Mashup.
That's because they deliver everything
you need right to your door and they keep
you fully stocked on what you use. So
you don't run out. Here's how it works.
Dollar Shave Club has everything
you need to get ready.
No matter what you're getting ready for.
They have you covered.
Head to toe for your
hair, your skin if, okay.
Just say your hair and just assume that
people aren't bald who are reading this
really triggers.
And I really feel that everybody
at dollar shave club could use,
should lose their jobs so I
can feel better. Um, your face,
you name it,
they have it.
MMM.
And they, what do you mean? You name it?
They have it. Even child pornography.
I'm triggered again.
I need Gillette to oto apologize just
because they make shapes stuff too.
And when I see that reminds
me of this read, um, sorry,
that was my impression
of 2020 around September.
If this continues and they have this new
program where they automatically keep
you stocked up on the products you use,
you determine what you
want and when you want it.
And it shows up right at your
deal with, uh, from what,
once a month to once every six months
plus with their handsome discount.
The more you buy, the more
you save. And right now do,
I only shave club has a bunch of
status sets. You can try for just $5,
like their oral care kit.
After that,
the restock box ships regular
sized products at a regular price.
Get your start, start a set, uh,
for just $5 right
now@dollarshaveclub.com slash burr.
That's dollar shave club.com/bar.
This is how dumb I am and how bad I
wasn't math when I was watching goodwill.
Hunting they have is amazing.
Establishing shot, um,
of MIT, some sort of giant dome and
I didn't even recognize what it was.
I thought they were in Rome.
I thought it was some old building and
then all of a sudden he was inside mouth
the floor and it's like, oh, I
guess that's what MIT looks like.
I mean, I'd seen it. You'd drive
by, if I remember correctly,
you could go buy it over a bridge,
isn't it? Right off Kenmore Square.
You go over that bridge. But there was
always trees sort of obstructing it.
You know,
I dunno.
Math triggers me butcher box everybody.
What's your box?
Delivers healthy 100% grass fed
and grass finished beef free range.
Organic chicken at heritage bread,
pork.
The incredible quality of butcher box
meat starts with the commitment to raising
animals humanely and free
of antibiotics and hormones.
Cook with piece of mind knowing you
are eating healthy, high quality meat.
Each box comes with at least
eight to 11 pounds of meat,
which is enough for 24
individual size meals.
Unless you're a fucking binge
eat fat, fuck, then you know,
it's probably an overnight snack,
right?
To have me 12 pork chops
before I go to bed. Uh,
you can choose from five different
box types. All beef, beef and chicken.
Beef and pork mixed box custom box,
which lets you choose your own cuts.
And now announcing our
new brand of protein,
wild Alaskan Salmon.
This isn't just Alaskan Salmon.
This is wild Alaskan Salmon.
That right. You get this. You
give this fish a couple of
shots. It's shown as tits.
I don't, I'm sorry. What's
your box? What's your buck?
They're pure sustainably harvested
salmon from Bristol Bay, Alaska.
Unlike any salmon you'll
find in your local stores,
how do you know it's from there? They
got a certain style, certain swagger,
the way they move their tail.
Literally,
its red color means that this salmon is
as fresh as nutrient a nutrient rich as
it gets. Oh yeah. Uh,
for $20 off your first box
in two pounds of free salmon,
go to butcher box.com/burn enter bur bur
that's butcher box.com and enter Burr B
u. R. R. Um, all right.
What am I up to? 27 minutes.
Oh Jesus. It flies by Liverpool.
Got Their first loss of the year.
I missed the game.
I couldn't find it here.
I was watching some sort of soccer over
here where they had this really small
net.
What does that indoor soccer looked like?
It was outside and there was some sort
of basketball going on and they were all
they were doing with speaking in German.
Everybody was talking in German and
then the crowd was chanting defense in
English. It's weird. Where are
the words that come? You know,
I mean, I don't know. I guess I use what
screen do I, I don't think I do. Um,
anyways. Yeah. So I've just been, I
couldn't find the fucking game. Uh,
congratulations to man city.
I didn't realize,
I know it was like a huge deal
when they want an understatement.
A few years ago that came out of fucking
nowhere and won the whole God damn
thing.
MMM.
And I guess they handled
Liverpool pretty nicely.
Some sort of controversial fucking goal.
I don't know what happened,
but the way my brain works is like,
fuck, when do we play these guys again?
And we got to figure out how to beat him
or are we going to lose in the playoffs?
And then it's just like, oh
wait, they don't have playoffs.
It's just the end of the year,
whoever has the most points,
whatever the fuck they call it,
which I can't quite,
do you get three points for
a win and one for a decision.
I don't fucking know dude.
I'm so fucking jet lag.
I just was on youtube and I think
I just learned how to play snooker.
Um, but anyways, then they know
they don't want to fucking play.
They could like lose to them
every time they fucking play him.
But still when the whole thing makes
no sense, it makes no fucking sense.
Anyways, I gotta I gotta kill a day
tomorrow here in Cologne, Germany. Uh,
what is there to do here? Um, is
there a good sneaker store here?
I don't want to go to
like the Adidas store.
Is there a place where they have like,
you know,
a bunch of different, like, you know,
Adidas that you wouldn't get at the
Adidas store, you know, like a, um,
a undefeated type store,
you know what I mean?
One of those types of stores, you know
what I mean? The ones with a super,
super fucking crazy sneaker
head type fucking people go to.
That's what I want to go to. Cause I have
to come back with some original shit.
I can't just come back with a pair of
run DMC looking fucking shell toes that,
you know, my wife and kid could've got
down the fucking street at the mall.
You know what I mean? So help me out if
you can. Uh, send me a tweet. All right.
And, uh, all right, I think
that's it. Uh, God bless you all.
Thank you to everybody who's coming
out to my show tomorrow night.
I'm so psyched to be over here.
What am I great friends in the world,
Paul Versey Club Soda Kenny.
We're going to have a great time over
here and thank you to everybody that's
coming out to the shows. Um, yeah,
that's it. Uh, I'm really
looking forward to this and uh,
I don't know, it feels weird
to end on something positive,
but I think I'm going to, all right, so
have a great weekend and I'll check in.
I'll, I'll talk to you on
Monday. Enjoy the music.
And there'll be another half hour,
great,
greatest hits from a Thursday afternoon
podcasts from a, I don't know,
some fucking Thursday earlier this year,
four years ago. I have no idea. All right.
Hey,
what's going on?
It's built par and it is the
Monday morning podcast from Monday,
January 3rd,
2011 did you guys have a nice new years?
Hope you had a nice holiday.
Seriously before I,
uh,
before I say con for the first time
on a podcast this year, officially,
that one wasn't official. That was just
me stating it like in a court of law.
As in,
I asked the defendant where he was coming
from and he told me quote to go fuck
myself.
See,
now that lawyer is not saying
is saying the f word, but it's,
it's not that example. Make no
goddamn sense whatsoever. Um,
anyways,
I'll hope you guys all have
a merry Christmas and a
happy new year and all that.
Now that you're back at work, you know,
is this a way, this is a weird week.
This is another weird week.
Last week was the weird depressing week,
unless you're ray. Uh, a college
student or something or, or, you know,
a kid you live in at home or some shit,
then it's great because you got time
off from school. Everything's awesome.
You going sledding, right?
You make an ice balls,
you throwing them at the fat kid
down the street, right? The ice ball,
fucking snowball, right? Put
a nice chunk of ice in there.
You pack it with some pottery
stuff and you say, hey, fatty,
you want to have a snowball fight,
right? You can't. Oh my God,
they're finally including me.
Geez.
It's been so rough since July
when they laughed at my man
down at the town pool and he
thinks he's included, right?
I love all the mean fuck's who
are laughing at this right now.
And then what do you do?
Bring them all variety. Throws a couple
of fucking Colorado snow balls now,
that powdery shed at you and then you
fucking set them up like Pat Patterson
when he took out the fucking brass
knuckles when he beat Ted DBRC for the
Intercontinental Championship in 1980.
But you knew that maybe it was 81.
I don't fucking remember.
Right,
and you fucking nailed that fatty right
in the side of his head. It goes down,
he cries half his face goes numb.
He gets bell palsy from laying in that
half frozen puddle and all your friends
laugh.
You don't even help him up.
And he's laying there and his dirty
orange fucking puffy coat that he just got
fixed
Christmas.
And
where does he go?
He goes back inside.
It sits down a place fucking video games
until he's 36 and that's the first time
he discovers craigslist,
you know,
with a quivering voice
and trembling fingers.
He picks up the old rotary phone.
I don't know where I'm going with this.
I think initially I was going to make fun.
The kids don't even do this shit anymore
because they're too busy being inside
playing video games and then just sort of
spun off to a Vignette of my childhood.
You know what's funny is that that
whole thing never really happened.
I was on both sides of that
snowball. Jesus, that was pathetic.
You know,
I think it's important in life to
remember that at some point you are on the
wrong side of an ice snowball.
Um,
am I really just going to do the mock
gave voice to just get out of every
difficult comedy moment?
I think I'm going to,
I've been doing it for the first
three years of this podcast. People,
do you understand that?
I am basically about a year and a half
away from being five years into this
podcast and actually getting to do a
reunion show with myself, you know,
thicker head of hair,
five pounds lighter,
just as much as a Douche.
Um, just as much of a Douche.
That's something in 2011. I would like
to have more sentences. That makes sense.
Do you guys make any new year's
resolutions? Well, I can't hear him.
So shut up. Are you an idiot? You
can sit there and rattle them off.
Look at that Goddamn cubicle.
You're really going to sit in that
fucking thing for another year are, yeah,
that's right.
Look down in shame at your belt buckle.
That's snazzy little belt buckle that
you bought that you thought which set off
your suit,
you know,
make people see at the gas station
standing there thinking that you actually
have some sort of a fucking desk.
Well you can look across at somebody else.
Will you wield the little bit of power?
Is it actually creeped me out? I don't
want to make somebody do something crazy.
It's okay.
A a cubicle is just a stepping stone to a,
a cubicle that's even larger.
Um,
and then one day being the final three
people to get the corner office and then
you realize that you've been replaced
by a fucking robot. Speaking of which,
I got to find this email
that somebody sent me. Um,
if I was organized, I would've heard
it blue. Now, uh, in the meantime,
my goals this year is I'm finally going
to rehab the fucking torn abdomen muscle
that I, that I fucked up
at a pirates game. Uh,
I'm going on three fucking years.
Three years ago I tried to show that I
could go into the pike position at 40
years of age.
Okay.
Goddamn it, I did it, but
I didn't stretch. And uh,
I think I talked to you guys about
this right after I did it. God Damn it.
I've been doing the podcast long enough.
Go back to like July of 2008,
somewhere in there.
I went to a pirates game when I was
working the Pittsburgh Improv and I wanted
to show off what great shape I was in.
And here I am three years later,
still dealing with two and a half years
later still dealing with that. Um,
what the hell is it? Oh,
they are watching. Yeah.
So anyways, let me, let me,
before I get into the conspiracy theory,
um,
which I took a break from in 2010 because
I wanted to actually enjoy my life.
Um, yeah, I want to Rehab it.
Anybody can give me some
web MD free advice. Come on.
There's gotta be a
personal trainer out there.
I know when you tear an abdomen muscle,
you supposed to rest it and then after
you rest it from one to four weeks
in court, according to my stomach
hurts and I don't know why.
Dot Com is supposed to rest it for a one
to four weeks and then begin doing some
sort of Rehab, which uh, you
know, I don't know how to do it.
I found just sitting there in
the plank position helps for you.
Yoga people out there. It's sorta
like the pushup position, but you're,
you're on your forearms. Um, that
seemed to have helped it, but I, uh,
I don't, I fucked it up the other
day and it's really frustrating.
It's frustrating. So anyways,
um, yeah, I want to rehab that.
I wouldn't want to eat better this year
and I want to continue to not
drink for as long as I can.
I'm going for a hundred days.
I'm going for 100 days.
In fact, listen to this. Fuck goes.
I went to a,
I went to the rose bowl this year
and I did not drink. I did not drink.
And I know there's a lot of you who are
disappointed that I didn't drink because
you want me to fill up your life with a
hilarious story of me making an ass of
myself once again to kick off a new
year. Well, God damn it, I didn't,
but I stood around and watched
enough other people. Fuck it, do it.
And I still have plenty of stories and
I got the brain cells to remember them.
Um,
so fucking awesome game.
It was Wisconsin versus Tcu at uh,
how was like most people are like,
who the fuck is Tcu?
And then you look on the program.
Let me go grab the Rosebowl program.
Hang on one second. Just you
guys sit tight. Just relaxes.
I walk across the road,
drive to find the Rosebowl program.
Oh, here it is. Look at this.
I found it.
I really need to get in with an assistant
on this podcast. All right, I'm back.
So here's the Rosebowl
program and basically
the rose bowl this year, if you
were going to turn it into an awful,
you're going to turn it into
an awful made for TV movie.
This was a s I guess it
was a story about respect.
All right. In that, you know,
people barely respect Wisconsin
because they never go to the rose bowl.
I can't remember the last time
they won the big 10 championship,
but they finally won it.
They want it and they beat the
likes of, uh, let's, let's see you,
let's see who they'd be.
All right,
let's go through their whole
fucking season here really quickly.
Stop Rolling your eyes. You fucking
commy non sports fan cunt. All right.
Start off the year they beat Unl v. These
are the cupcake games early in the end.
And they beat San Jose State,
Arizona State. There is a
PAC 10 team. Austin Peay.
Who is that somebody somebody's
name. Did they play like one guy? Uh,
then they beat Michigan state, then they
beat Minnesota. They beat Ohio state,
right? Big 10 Iowa. Purdue. You've
heard of these teams? Indiana, Michigan,
one of those teams. They actually
lost two, but I went by too quickly.
Northwestern, you know, they
played some fucking teams
take, see you on the other
hand, didn't play shit.
Okay. Shit down there. Know,
outside of Dallas, Texas, Texas,
Christian, Oh, Jeesh is university.
And you wonder why no one gives a
fuck about the mountain west program.
I want you to write me and tell me
just exactly. Okay. Oregon state too.
That's PAC 10. That's Tennessee tech.
This is, they're undefeated season.
They'd beat Oregon State,
Tennessee tech, Baylor, Smu,
Colorado state, Wyoming, Byu, air force,
UNL, V, Utah, San Diego State,
New Mexico.
That was,
they're undefeated season and they're
sitting there scratching the top of their
fucking heads,
wondering why there didn't that
people are questioning their record.
All right, so here's the deal. I'm
sitting there going, all right,
I like this big 10 even though the big
10 isn't what it used to be considering,
they went, oh, and five on
fucking new years day. Um,
who doesn't like an underdog?
So I'm going, well, fuck it man.
I'm going to roof a Tcu even
though they have Christian. Oh Gee.
He's in the middle of their fucking
name, which, you know what that means?
They automatically think they're
better than everybody else.
And Jesus loves us best,
despite the fact that they're preaching
that everybody needs to be more
understanding like Jesus.
Somehow they missed the irony of the fact
that they feel like they're the chosen
ones. Like all stupid
fucking religions do, right?
Jewish people think
they're the chosen ones.
Christians think they are the chosen ones.
Muslim thinks that the, you know what?
You guys are all a bunch of Douche
bags. All right? None of you matter.
That's why there's so many of us.
If we were special,
that only be like nine of us once
there's 7 billion of anything. I mean,
we're about why we're not special anymore.
Okay? Do you understand that? Well,
like socks,
you know,
actually some poor
people can afford socks.
The socks is still important
to some people. You know,
I don't what the fuck
I'm saying it's a Tcu.
They got a fucking bay in their bonnet
about how nobody's respecting them.
So I'm sitting there, this is before I
talked to anybody from Tcu. I just saw I,
you know, purple and black does a decent
colors. Man, I liked those. Wisconsin.
I'm looking at all these fatties
from Wisconsin, you know,
walking around just horrible, horrible
shape. I think when, you know,
when Europeans look at America and they
think of of the Fat Fox, you know, I,
I think, I dunno, I think they,
they send away for a Wisconsin broche
university brochure every year.
I don't know what, because Jesus Christ,
those were some healthy fucking people.
All right?
Evidently the recession has not hit
Wisconsin yet because those people have
plenty of money for extra food. So
anyway, so I'm sitting there and uh,
we start to walk into the game,
right?
Me and three of my buddies were all good
and I don't name names on this fucking
thing. We go to walk into
this goddamn thing and I start
looking around after, oh,
after a wonderful tailgate.
We really did it up this year.
Plenty of booze
and which I did not partake in.
I brought a 12 pack of water. Go
ahead, email me, call me a fag.
I don't give a fuck. I feel
great. You fucking cunts. Look,
I'm still defensive about it, you know?
At least I'm one of those, those, those,
I'm not a preachy, sober person. I'm not
going like, you know, why do you do that?
What are you,
what are you running from?
I know why you're doing it because it's
fucking fun. And I'd still be doing,
if my head didn't get three times
the size of its usual enormous size,
you know my head when I'm not boozing,
looks like one of the moons of
Jupiter. Okay. I don't need,
I don't need to continue adding to it,
you know,
and then have it be like Pluto and then
scientists can fucking debate on whether
or not it's a fucking planet. All right.
Fucking fucking fucking, there you go.
See I needed the help there.
The F word for me is, is my,
my, uh, uh, w what are those things?
The Hgh of my fucking comedy.
All right.
And I'll continue to use it and I don't
give a shit cause they're not banned in
my industry. Um, anyways, so
what was I saying? Alright,
so we had a great tailgate. We show up.
I became in the back way this, this,
this year. All right. We
parked right along the fence.
We were right near the clubhouse on
the golf course. And then you can,
I could literally see one of the lights,
you know that lights up the stadium.
So we were right there. There was no
way we were getting lost this year.
Actually brought a frying pan,
brought some eggs. We had burgers,
hotdogs, steak. We had shit to
throw in the omelettes. Cheese,
everything you want. We had a spatula,
we brought tongs, we had napkins.
We had a fucking garbage bag.
We had a grill bag of charcoal,
four bags of fucking ice to cool.
We had every tick,
we had fucking core chips.
We had salsa,
we had two bottles of mustard.
Ho Jara fucking pickles catch up.
We had everything we had.
We had,
we had real forks and steak
knives for the stakes.
We had everything except
for a fucking table.
Yeah.
God, next year is going to be the per
every year two bottles of crown royal.
A case of fucking beer. We,
we will, we will ready to go.
We even had orange juice
for the fucking eggs.
We will ready to go.
And we forgot a God damn table.
It's one of the ways we start the day off
with one of the best fucking omelettes
. You ever got to have new year's Day
sitting on a golf course on a Sunny Day,
knowing the rest of the
Goddamn country snowed in,
screaming at some ticket agent that they
got to get back to Albuquerque before
they yak, you know, shits the bed, right?
Okay.
You forgot a God damn table,
which isn't bad when you eat an almond,
but when you're eating a fucking stake
that's an inch and a half thick that's
been cooked at best rare,
it's supposed to be
medium rare. Okay? It was,
it was just medium rare.
What happens is you got it on a paper
plate and as you use pressure to cut into
that, it creases in the middle
and you see this puddle of,
of, of grease. It just starts coming.
It comes close to your
balls and then goes away.
Just like the tide coming in and
you sitting there going, you know,
I really should a just drip the rest
of this grease down into the grass,
kill a couple of lady bugs and then
continue on with the eating process.
But it tastes so fucking good.
You going, you know what?
I think I can do it one more
time and then you do it.
What happens if fucking rolls right off
onto your jeans and you haven't noticed?
I don't give a fuck what you spill,
where you spell it.
You could have your arms outstretched
if you spill any sort of liquid.
It not only does it land in your crotch
at lands right at the head of your Dick,
so it always looks like he pissed you
pants. So that's what I look like.
I had grease on the front of my pants.
Um,
I mean while I'm sitting here watching
all these Wisconsin fans walking around
and they got these candy
striped fucking overalls,
they look like Richard Simmons shorts.
If you fucking mugged him and cleaned
out his closet of early eighties fucking
gay, his running shorts ever, and you
somehow turn them into overalls, you,
it'd be one thing of women were wearing
them that be kind of hot, right?
But there was a bunch of
guys wearing them too. They,
they all look like they look like it
looked like a jugglers convention is the
best way to put it. So I'm sitting
there going, man, I liked the big 10,
I want to root for Wisconsin.
Then every once in a while,
because it seemed to be like 80%,
75%,
maybe 70 a at the smallest Wisconsin
fans. And then Tcu, so you know,
who doesn't like an underdog? So I start
walking towards the stadium, right?
And, uh, I'm thinking I want to go for
Tcu. Fuck this. I helped this little,
uh, mountain west, whatever. Fucking, I
didn't know what conference if from, Huh,
um, I hope these guys win. And, uh,
I start going up to the stadium and,
uh,
one of my buddies elbows me and he turned
around and he points to these Tcu fans
in.
This guy is wearing Brown loafers,
these light purple,
uh,
like corduroys Docker's with the Tcu
emblem and then like a v Neck sweater
and like these ray bond fucking
risky business sunglasses on.
And He,
I like if you,
if you were casting a movie,
did you guys see Facebook,
that Facebook social network? Do you
know how like the Harvard guys wear it?
This is what this guy looked like. And
I was like, oh my, are you serious?
Is this guy an anomaly or is this
really what Tcu was all about?
My buddy literally goes to me, he goes,
that's it. I'm rooting for Wisconsin.
You know, I look at this fucking guy
and I, and I was sitting there going,
you know what? I think he's right. No, no,
no. Maybe it's just this one fucking guy.
And then I see another guy he has on a
purple fucking blazer with gold buttons.
Oh,
white shirt,
some polluted slugs and
low first to the game.
Then all of a sudden I started looking
at these. There's not all of them,
but a good 15% of them
are dressed this way,
looking like those rich kids who
fucking, you know, uh, air quote,
accidentally kill their date,
you know,
and then they say it was consensual
because she wanted rough sex too.
And their daddy has enough fucking
money to get them out of it.
That's what they started looking
like. So I'm like, Holy Shit.
Fuck this. I'm, I'm,
I'm rooting for Wisconsin now we're
in the crush to get in the game.
And I look in front of me and
there's this pasty fat fuck Wisconsin
fan in front of me with the Wisconsin
had turned around and I dunno if it was
dry skin or Eczema,
he had a perfect band of it going
around the back of his, you know,
his hairline at the back of
his head and the flakes of it,
we're on the back of his sweatshirt.
I know. I hope you're not eating.
Okay. So I'm looking at
him going, oh, horrified.
Absolutely horrified.
And then I'm turning around.
I'm looking at these fucking slack.
In a sport coat wearing douchebags.
And at that point I didn't know who I was.
Four, I was actually hoping
that during the flyover,
one of the jets would go into the crowd
and they could just start all over again.
It was, it was horrific. Worst Group
of fans I've seen. And in three years,
granted I was sober this time and
I could actually remember this.
So I go into the stadium,
right. And, uh, Lo and behold,
I'm in the TCU section,
right? And I'm like,
okay,
uh,
I dunno if I liked this and
I just, and I'll sign it to
here. Start here. Take, see
this girl like three rows
back, Jay. Yeah. Come on.
Come on. Frogs. And I go, frogs.
They're the fucking, I didn't know what
they were. We got to give it to Wisconsin.
Badger is a Badass.
Fucking m TCU horned frogs.
Okay. And that their mascot, look,
I don't need it looks like something
I'd like to that star wars bar scene,
you know, and against
go frau come, I'll tasty
tasty you. And I'm looking at the girls
and they, uh, they, they have their jeans
tucked into their cowboy
boots, like they're in that
band, great white, you know,
and then on top they have like these
dime store Dolly Parton cowboy hats on.
And I was like, oh my God, I fucking
hate these people. And at that point,
and I was sitting right in the middle
of them and I immediately just became a
Wisconsin Fan. Now, in defense of Tcu,
I think if I was hanging in the
Wisconsin section, I would route,
I would have rooted for Tcu.
I would have ruled for Tcu in the middle
of me just screaming that tacy Gee,
who come out frogs.
I can't tell if Nia just laughed or
the guy downstairs yelled at me, oh,
that's a dog. Okay, my
fault. Or it's Mel Blanc.
Um, good. Anybody imitate a dog barking
better than that guy. Um, anyways,
let's plow ahead here. Uh, so
then I just sat there and, uh,
just was rooting for Wisconsin and
I just want it and I, and I, I just,
another thing too that it's really
fucking annoying about TCU fence.
Okay is no matter what's
going on during the game,
they have a reason to fucking
put their hands in the air. See,
can't see the fucking game.
Anytime it was third down,
they had this gay little thing where you
know,
you make the a Amo k sign,
they would do that signifying third down
and then they would just sort of shake
their hands like you just in case you
don't know what town and everybody,
so it's like third down and anybody who
watches football knows third down is a
really important fucking
down as a fan who played,
have paid a fuckload for the ticket.
You want to see what happened and these
fucking idiots is so busy going to the
loo. You couldn't see anything. Then,
not to mention there's fat whore in
front of me who from the size of her
should've been a Wisconsin fan. But then
again, I've been to Houston, Texas. Okay.
Those people like their barbecue to the,
these are the people that
really make America look bad.
It's the fucking middle of the country.
You got damn people.
I don't know what your problem
is because you're landlocked.
Don't they have swimming pools where you
people could do a couple of laps people
on the coasts or in shape. All right.
Seattle. All the way down to San Diego.
These mother fuckers are
in shape. Go ahead. Yeah.
San Diego grew right up the
coast. Los Angeles, San Francisco,
or a Portland, Oregon. They're in shape.
A Seattle. They're in shape. Vancouver.
I even leave the country and
they're fucking had shape.
You start getting out there in Nebraska.
Our Wisconsin.
Huh? Fucking people are, are,
are horrific other than Florida.
Florida doesn't count. All right.
Florida is a, I don't know what it is.
It's like the ball bag, but he
says, it looks like a dick to me.
It looks like a fucking 56 year old.
Scroll them. Just hang in there.
Um,
after the Dick got lopped off anyways,
so they handed out the like, like them
doing that third down thing wasn't enough.
They handed out these fucking
little purple like rags.
Okay. First of all, stealing from the
Pittsburgh Steelers, the terrible towel.
They steal that.
And then on them it said fear of the frog,
which they stole from a
Maryland fear the turtle,
right?
The first school to actually
admit that they have a bad name,
a bad mascot fucking name.
So then what they would this fucking fat
whore in front of me. I swear to God.
Every God damn play.
Okay.
Her fucking team would be,
we had ends on seats were was in the
other end zone at Wisconsin's 10 yard line
trying to drive in for a score.
Okay. They're, they're 90 yards away.
If you're standing on the goal line,
forget about being 40 50 fucking rose
up in the Goddamn Stan and she would be
sitting there as she's talking to a
friend too. That's what killed me.
Classic brought it again. She sitting
there shooting the shit. You know,
she probably went there for the tournament
of fucking roses and she just kept
and I finally,
I tapped her on her fleshy shoulder
and she immediately took it. As I
was saying, put it down. I said,
can you just wave the, can you wave
it more in your like in front of you?
Which this is the funniest thing ever.
She does.
And immediately realizes that when she
does it, she can't see the fucking game.
Welcome to my world,
you fat whore.
That's what I've been dealing with
for the last three fucking quarters.
So then what she did was she then
switched into her left hand. Okay.
Because not only is she a fat
whore, she's a dumb fat whore. Okay.
And the first moment when I
tapped her, she was like, oh,
this guy must be a Wisconsin fan,
you know,
because he's telling me to put it down.
Then she realizes, oh, it's in his way.
Then she waves it in front of her face
and realizes, oh, now I can't see.
And you would think at that point light
would dawn on our fucking fat head.
And she'd be like, oh, I get
it. If I waved this thing,
people behind me can see the fucking
game. Not this fat whore, not this one.
She fucking puts it in the left hand
and starts waving like that. Like,
that's the solution.
Like she doesn't notice that there's
another fucking 80,000 fans to her fucking
left. It was the worst. And it's
times like those where I just a
times like, those were made for
taster's choice. Remember that coffee,
which is brew up a Nice Hot Pot and you
just dump it right over a fucking head.
That's what I would've liked in a
perfect world. And as she screamed
from the scalding Burns, um,
she would collapse afterwards.
So maybe pass out either way, she would
be out of my wife and I gotta tell you,
that would be the equivalent of three
normal Americans who live on the coasts,
who lived near the ocean.
Hey, you know what? I just realized that's
how I'm gonna make my million dollars,
my multimillion dollars,
so I can parachute out of this goddamn
business I've been trying to come up with.
Yeah.
Um, some bullshit that I could
sell for 1995 late at night.
And I think I just did,
you know,
I'm going to sell, I'm going to sell, uh,
ocean water and little
salt shakers for 1995.
That's what I'm going to do and
I'm just going to go, you know,
have you ever noticed how,
you know,
people who live on the coasts of
this country are in shape? You know,
and now I'm now just show a bunch of good
looking people running down the street
with their knees nice and high,
like the Wisconsin fucking marching band,
which was the shit,
um,
just running down the fucking street,
you know, high stepping it and then, uh,
the white version of high stepping,
which is basically bring our knees up
to our waist as opposed to the Grambling
black version where you basically,
you know, you're, you're, you,
you couldn't do it in a dome stadium
because you would break your fucking toes.
Okay. Whatever. Black
people were trying what?
Try It anyways. So, uh,
yeah, I would, I would sell it and I would
just say, and then you get, if you know,
are you tired of being fat
in the middle of the country?
And just so somebody who sit in a bunk,
taking a bite out of it and then just
look into the camera, like, you know,
throwing their arms up like, Ooh, yeah,
I am sick of being a fat fuck, you know,
you know, they have sent a bunch on the
east coast, why are on the west coast?
Why aren't they fat fucks?
And I'll just, I just spin it.
It's because they live
near the ocean and it,
they're smelling that salt water in the
air and I just make up a bunch of shit.
I'll pay off some fucking
people in the FDA. Uh,
it doesn't seem like a hard thing to
do considering half the drugs that get
approved nowadays, and I'll just say
it's because of smelling salt water,
air that you're able to eat Cinnabon and
shut off those fucking pounds. And A,
I'll sell it like little
bottles of fucking colognes,
every fatty in the fucking
Midwest and I'll make my money
and then I'm going to move to Denmark
and I'm going to pay 90% taxes yet have
free health insurance.
And, uh, you know, when a little vesper,
I'm going to go around
those little fucking, a
little streets out there. I'm trying
to put together a Scandinavian tour,
by the way, this year. I'm really looking
forward to that. Um, so there you go.
You know, something like you, I also
lost interest halfway through that.
So that was the rose bowl for me
this year. I didn't drink. I had a,
uh, I had a fucking awesome
time. I remember the game.
Congratulations to tasty
you. Let's go. Proulx.
Congratulations to you.
A horribly horribly dressed human
beings just horribly dressed.
Trash, white trash is the only way
to describe what I saw out there.
You guys really looked like you
never left the Greater Dallas area.
Um, you're not going to go out
on limb here. And I would say,
I'm never going to get an opportunity
to perform at that school.
And if I ever get an offer,
I'm going to be really suspect of it,
thinking that they actually listened to
this podcast. Oh my God, the dime store.
Fucking, oh, every, the woman,
women all dressed like the Dolly Parton
movie. Best little whorehouse in Texas,
except they were serious. They probably
put out my best hat for this one.
I saw a guy actually took a picture
of him. What did I zoom into them?
I have some video. I got to give
it to my web guy, um, of this guy.
He was dressed in a suit with a big
black Stetson looking like fucking a JR
Ewing standing. You know, if it was
the early eighties, I went, well,
he would've looked good, you know,
but it's fucking 2011, dude, it's,
it's time to let that go.
You're fucking oil man slash coke dealer.
Look from fucking 1981 30 years later,
you're still rocking.
That look like dead serious,
dead serious.
These are the kinds of people that think
like there's, you can cure homosexuals,
you know, and uh, you know,
like one of those countries,
singers like need a hit.
So they just write a song about
how great America is and that too.
And the fans are too dumb to see through
the fact that they're just trying to
make money. You know, I lock American.
If you don't lock,
get the fuck out
cause it's the best goddamn nation,
even though the schools are
going down the shitter. Um,
and just ignoring everything speech.
Speaking of which, I got a great
underrated overrated here this week
that somebody sent in and you know,
you guys know I'm a moron, so I couldn't
put it any better than this guy.
Um, this guy says overrated. The
New Year on TV, every fucking year.
All these celebrities come on and
say how amazing the New Year is.
How is it?
How is it any more amazing than the last?
The population is still rising and people
are just getting more fucking stupid
and fat. You know, for comedic
purposes, you sort of said more fat,
more fucking fat and stupid. See the
alliteration, but fucking stupid if fat,
you know, that's just like, you know,
after you've gone down the roller coaster,
you've gone down ticking the big drop
that you get those little ones that don't
even scare you,
those little bunny hills.
But if you say more fucking fat
and stupid fucking fat, fuck,
you get two of those in a row.
That's like,
that's like going right down the big
one. Um, anyways, I'll help you out here.
The population is still rising and
people are getting more fucking fat and
stupid.
The banks are still stealing our money.
Our money spelled are our money. And
uh, and the politicians still lie.
I don't see how it is anything
more than depressing and pathetic.
Loved your special. Thank you.
Um, yeah, I agree with you.
100% agree with you. Um, to the point.
It's so fucking depressing that I just
got a dog a couple of years ago because
no one else seems to give a shit.
Um, and in that, the line of that,
uh, here's some, here's some
conspiracy theory for you.
Somebody said bill that they uh,
he wrote,
they are watching and um,
I got trashed for talking
about conspiracy theory.
I've been trashed for talking about
those automated checkout lines in the
grocery store and saying that I'm paranoid
and I'm afraid of technology and all
this technology's just going to help
my life and make my life more easier.
And why don't you trust these big fucking
corporations basically is to shit.
The people who have given me the same
way people gave me shit for trashing the
jets saying that the jets,
you know,
haven't done anything so I don't know
why they're fucking Superbowl favorites.
What? Because the coach said they're going
to win every fucking game. Not this is,
this is the best way I can
sum up. Rex Riley, rex, Ryan,
Rex Ryan is the Tila
Tequila of NFL head coaches.
Famous for nothing in particular.
He's never won anything yet.
Everybody knows who he is and is hanging
on his words like he has something to
fucking say.
What?
Cause he dropped 9,000 f bombs
on Hbo is famous for that.
He wore a wig and a press conference
and we found out he has a foot fetish.
Oh yeah.
Toss some right in there with chuck Noll.
Yeah.
Fucking ridiculous. By the way.
Speaking of that, the fuck,
did you know the Steelers
finally looked like the Steelers?
I thought that they were going to look
like when ruthless burger came back.
That is a scary ass team. And I know
they were just playing the browns,
but when a Polamalu comes in,
the is playing,
it's an entirely different team.
So all you jet fans out there who
are excited that you beat that team.
I'm telling you, that's a
different fucking team. Um,
I'm not even excited that
the Patriots beat them.
Um, because, uh, I just
don't think that this,
the Steelers are now
starting to click and a,
they remind me of a certain giant team
from a few years ago that no one was
really paying attention to and all of
a sudden got hot in December and Lo and
behold, beat the 18 and
oh patriots. So, uh,
oh. And speaking of that, my season
long bet with Paul [inaudible],
um, I want it. I'm psyched. I want it. Uh,
I basically rattled off six victories
in a row against the spread and put Paul
versary Paul Versey out of his misery.
You know,
the poor bastard the entire year really
felt like he was gonna beat me just
because I had never,
I,
I never really gambled cause I did it
like fucking in 1989 that's the one.
And only time I did it,
I had season tickets to the patriots.
We made the playoffs the year before and
all of a sudden we were five and 11 and
I was like, fuck this. I'm getting
some of my money back for, you know,
shelling out 250 bucks for season.
Yeah.
Tickets. That's what you could
get back in the day before ESPN.
Overhyped every sport and people who
don't even like sports or going to games
now. So, uh,
uh, yeah, I want to get
some of my money back.
And I remember the buffalo bills right
before they became the buffalo bills.
They had all those guys,
they were a year away from
going to their first Superbowl.
MMM.
You know, four in a row when in
for AFC championships in a row.
One of the most underrated accomplishments
ever. You know, basically cause it got,
because he lost four super bowls in
a row. So I mean, what do you expect?
But anyways, I decided to bet the
fucking buffalo bills that year.
This is off on memory.
This is what gambling does.
And I remember that was the one fucking
week to Goddamn patriots showed up at
one the game.
So I couldn't even enjoy it
and I lost like 50 bucks,
which when you're only making
125 a week is a tremendous blow.
So I never bet again,
I never gambled against the spread for
like until this year I had Paul Versey
who you know, has been
doing it for years. Go
Dude. I called it, I did this. I did
that. You got beat by a guide. Yeah.
Damn nerd. I'm just breaking your balls
park cause I know you're listening.
I know you'll
listen. All right, so they would go,
I almost went 500 for the
year against the spread,
which from what I've been told is,
is, is pretty goddamn decent. So yeah,
I'm patting myself on the back. Um,
anyways, let's plow ahead here. Um,
so I have to get in trash for all,
you know,
talking shit about all these corporations
and actually having the audacity to
think that bankers, we're all trying to
team up and have one World Bank, you know,
to become the loan sharks for not for
not only individual but actual countries.
Okay.
Which is something that I was thinking
about when I was at the Rose Bowl stone
sober and I was sitting there on the
golf course and I was looking at these
houses up on up on the ridge of this
hill that actually looked down on,
on the Rose Bowl,
the granddaddy of them,
all of these people have a
house that looks down on it
and I was actually envisioning that
those were all bankers up there.
And while the game was going
on in 104,000 people or 96,000,
whoever showed up for that game,
we're sitting there going fucking crazy.
One of those pieces of Shit bankers up
there could put his hand on his son's
shoulder and be like, see all those people
down there, they all, all of us money,
they all owe me money,
son.
I'm getting a piece of all of their
fucking paychecks and they don't even know
it. They don't even know that their
daddy is looking down on him right now.
Now,
had I been drinking
that thought would have probably
caused me to, uh, you know,
entertain the thought of climbing up that
hill and thrown a rock through one of
the windows, which of course I wouldn't
have done because even my drunkest I am,
I am aware that I don't want to go to jail
and get raped. And secondly, I really,
I'm not going to go all the
way up that fucking help.
So what I would've done is I probably
would have yelled at that kid with the
light purple slacks. I would've commented
really loud about that dude's fucking,
uh, Eczema flaking off into the
back of his goddamn sweatshirt.
Um, so anyways, this guy sends
me this email and he says,
build the days in this blog. When I
say they are watching our big business,
not the Illuminati, but they are just
as evil as any bank or secret society.
They don't even need your signature.
Listen to this shit.
They don't even need your signature for
these information gathering trader where
programs to monitor everything from where
the device is to what your heart rate
is. Thanks for giving me something
to look forward to on Mondays. Also,
I like your Christmas tree.
You should turn it into a walking stick.
Now that the holidays are over, you guys
are so dumb. You guys are buying shrubs.
Do you realize that?
Look out your window and look at trees.
You can see the trunk he had dumped Fox.
It's like, you know, you're morons. Look
at a shrub. Can you see the d, The d?
You can't. You're buying shrubs that are
pruned into the shape of Christmas tree.
I had information from an
actual fucking guy last week. All
right? I bought a Christmas tree.
You brought a Christmas shrub.
She go fuck yourselves.
But I liked this guy because he
sends me his, what his trader where.
That's the question I had.
Um,
you digital camera may embed metadata
into photographs with cameras,
serial number or your location.
Your printer may be incorporating a
secret code on every page at prince,
which could be used to
identify the printer and
potentially the person who used
it. Now, now the fucking morons, the
sheep out there, it'd be like, yeah,
that's in case she
threatened the president.
They're just doing it for
the good of all people. Um,
if apple puts a
particularly creepy patent,
I guess Apple's applying for this as
a recently applied for the use, um,
for,
um,
you can look forward to a day when
your iPhone may record your voice.
Take a picture of your location,
record your heartbeat,
and send that information
back to the mothership.
This is trade aware devices that
act behind your back and portray,
portray your privacy. Now this is what
the moron sheep are going to be to say,
well, if he ain't doing nothing
wrong, what's the problem?
That's,
that's the philosophy.
That was the philosophy behind why
they can record your phone calls. Now,
if he ain't doing nothing,
we're tacy you come on frogs
gate doing nothing wrong.
Do you realize how fucking
dumb that mindset is?
So basically,
as long as you do what the people
in power tell you what to do,
you won't have a problem.
Do you understand how dangerous that is?
Do you understand how fucking stupid it
is to have that level of faith in the
people who rule you?
You know what I mean?
Eh, you haven't noticed how much
power can fuck somebody over.
Like for some reason we only seem to
focus on when celebrities get famous and
then they wig out and start
becoming these fucking mini tyrants.
For some reason people don't feel they
just have like this because they waved
the flag and they and they play those
songs that make you choked up that they
never feel like that they'll have
any sort of ulterior motive for this.
This is the type of technology that allows
a small group of people to take over
the world.
Something that's sociopath's have been
trying to do since the beginning of time
and they were never able to do it
because at some point your army would be
stretched too thin,
right?
Germans the fuck at Roman empire,
all that shit.
At some point the fucking Japanese,
all of them,
everybody who's ever
tried to fucking do it,
at some point it gets stretched too thin.
So America,
what we've done,
yeah,
is we then we, we've, we've done the,
we're putting this base here to protect
you thing, that brilliant thing.
That's how we got our world empire.
So we just have a base.
Then also we have these insane
weapons where we can nuke everybody.
So we were able to kind of do it that way.
But the problem is,
is when you really get into sociopathic
thought and just like those people who
are so into power that it makes
their dick hard is they want to know,
they want to be able to see everybody,
know what they're thinking and know what
they're doing at all times because not
only they psychos,
but with that level of power becomes
this unbelievable level of paranoia.
Like those people with those houses
sitting on the ridge looking down into the
Roosevelt, there's a fear. Like we sit
there looking up at it, go look at,
they got the fucking world.
There was a fear of when you attain that
level of wealth, of losing all of it,
and you've,
you begin on this,
this quest to quiet your mind,
you want,
you want to get a level of wealth
and control in your life that you are
guaranteed that it will never go away in
your lifetime or your kids' lifetime or
your kids' kids.
So basically everybody that you know and
love will be okay and you will be okay.
You get into that psychotic
fucking mindset and uh,
you give those kinds of people this level
of fucking technology and you're going
to have a problem. I think that's
unbelievable, but that, this shit is,
so they have this, this website here, uh,
the eff electronic frontier
foundation that is trying to fight
these things being put into, into
the, the tech, you know, the cameras,
the cell phones and all that shit.
Like the fact that there's a
tracking device in your cell phone.
Like how come we didn't
get to vote on that?
How come we don't get to
vote on that type of stuff?
I don't want people knowing where the
fuck I am at all God damn times. Okay?
And I don't need you to show me, Oh, we
cut this fucking child molester with that.
So because of that, now everybody has
to be like, give me a fucking break.
They always have like, you
know that there's, you know,
a handful of good examples for
that level of fucking control.
And then there's a zillion bad ones.
So I am 100% against the shit.
And um, there's always been evil
people in the fucking world.
There's always going to be evil fucking
people in the world. And when you get,
when you have this kind of technology that
you're going to, you're going to stop.
They're going to stop small,
evil,
like individual,
you know,
a fucking a serial rapist. What? You
definitely want to stop, all right?
But the price we're going to pay is
you're going to allow a Stalin or a Hitler
Pol Pot,
whoever the fuck you wanted that you're
going to leave you with that level of
technology up to someone like that could
get in power and run the fucking world.
So, you know, I don't know. And I, I
totally 100% believe that you could
roll all your fucking eyes all you want.
I honestly believe that.
And I also believe that the reason why
there's so many of us right now and that
the people at the top are not fucking
concerned about it is because we're all
expendable. And when the waters rise up,
the temperatures goes up and everything,
they're not going to be
the ones who are drowning.
You can guarantee that they use in our
taxpayer money to build some sort of
something to make sure that they're okay.
And I think that their bail out plan,
because they know they can't
stop people from fucking,
because it feels too goddamn good and
Dixon pussies are readily available to
anyone. It's like air, you know?
So I think what they're going to gradually
do is phase us out with robots and
automated shit,
which is why I refuse to use it now.
How fucking crazy do I sound right now?
Has there been anything funny
in the last fucking five?
This is shit that I truly believe.
You know,
corporations own like the
DNA of a grizzly bear.
That's why they don't give a fuck
that they're cutting down its habitat.
They're like, I will fucking
grow another one in a petri dish.
We're trying to take over
everything and then wipe out.
I think they're going to try to wipe
out the poor and the middle class.
Keep a couple of us,
like a small handful of us.
You know the way that pandas are only in
like a zoos at this point or some shit.
I don't know. Maybe I picked the wrong
fucking animal, but that, that's,
that's the direction I think it's going.
All right. This is your first crazy rant,
which was based mainly in gut feelings
in a couple of emails. But, um,
I truly believe that
and I've browsed through enough,
enough history, a Cleo, what's up.