Hey, what's going on is bill burns
time for the Thursday afternoon,
just before Friday.
Monday morning podcast.
Just checking in on you. Listen to
this shit. I just got back from,
uh, where the hell was
I? Phoenix, Arizona.
Home of the sons home of the
coyotes home with a fucking, uh,
I dunno. Grapefruit League net. Grapefruit
League one instructional league.
I don't, what the fuck is homer?
The Diamondbacks home
with the fucking condos.
Okay.
All right. I just got back from
there. Okay. I'm coming home.
I'm taking a cab because I'm old. I
don't do fucking Uber. I don't do Lyft.
I don't do any of that bullshit.
All right.
I'm fucking calling somebody and they just
pull up in their car. I just, I'm not,
I noticed I don't do it right.
I fucking take cabs.
So I pull up to my house
and this is fucking
whatever state truck there for.
These fucking guys are in my yard.
The gates open and one of the guys got
a ladder up to the side of my house,
so I just walk in. I'm like, uh,
yeah. Hey, what are you guys doing?
And he goes up, God, somebody finally
somebody's home, and I'm like,
what do you mean my wife didn't let you
in? He was like, no, there was no answer.
And I'm like, then what are you doing
here? And he goes, well, you know,
I keep coming by. There's nobody here.
I got to check the meter. You know?
They'd said,
you put a new electrical box.
You know you guys didn't have a home.
I mean, what was I supposed to do?
I was like, I don't know. Not coming
to my fucking yard. What do you,
what was I supposed to do? Every time I
go to the bank, the bank's closed. I mean,
what was I supposed to do? Come back
when they're fucking, they're yet can't.
He just kept saying,
what was I supposed to do?
You trust passing you
asshole the F up fucking.
He just kept saying what any
I've, you know something. I
actually kept my cool up.
I just calmly said, I don't know,
not coming to my yard. I go off my,
if I keep one of my neighbor's
house and he's not there,
that doesn't mean give me a right
to go in there. And he goes, well,
I've got to go over. I got to get
to the pole. I mean, you know,
when they changed the box,
the only put temporary whatever,
fucking things on there.
I gotta put the right things on there.
I don't have your phone number. I'm like,
well, whose fault is that? Some I fault.
Nobody asked me. You guys never called
me, or I guess she couldn't call me,
but you should have gotten from the,
from the electrician. He goes, yeah,
the electrician did give it to me.
Why go? There you go. So the guy,
the guy is grabbing a ladder,
he takes it down and he's fucking
walking out and go, you know what do you,
what do you need to do here? He goes,
no, no. You know, go get out of here.
It's just like, dude, you,
I'm going to fucking pout now.
You know what I'm saying is right
fucking walking.
You just open the gate. You just
fucking walk in. Unbelievable.
I like the guy. The other guy immediately
was fucking, you know, he's looking down.
He knew he was feeling you lose. The guy
was wrong. The guy was basically like,
this is like the third time I come over
here, nobody ever answers the door.
I'm getting sick of this and he just
fucking, it'll climbed over the wall.
I don't know what the gate's locked.
I don't know how they did
it mean you had a ladder?
I guess he just fucking
went right up and over it.
I mean, what was I supposed to do? One
fuck. You mean what we are supposed to do?
That's the dumbest fucking thing
I've ever heard. So then I go,
what do you need to do?
He told me when he did do I call,
how are you want to go down and
do it? Get the fight. I mean,
he still did way too
much. Don't, I don't know.
It was the weirdest fucking response
ever. Well, you know, I, I what,
what was I supposed to do? So, but
I was actually happy that I, I mean,
I lost my shit on it now thinking about
it on the podcast way more than I did in
the moment.
And um,
yeah,
you know, I said to the guy said, I'm
not trying to be difficult, but you know,
that's what you're doing here is it's
not right. And you know, it's not,
I shouldn't say I should said that.
And you know it's not right.
You got inpatient and he
just said to hell with it,
I'm just going to do this anyways
and you're trespassing. You know,
you trespassing. I don't care that you
worked for the state. That doesn't,
you know, I guess, you know, if,
if my fucking house was on fire
or the the poll or some shit,
there was a live wire hanging from it,
then yeah,
I guess you have the
authority to go up and over.
I don't think you can do that just because
you're fucking tired of knocking on
the door. Nobody answers. Anyway, sorry.
So I just got back from Phoenix,
Arizona.
I had the best fucking time when I was
out there, ate a bunch of great food,
but all basically I kind of
ate mainly down near um, um,
wherever, wherever the fucking
Phoenix Suns play the, uh,
traveling Riverside resort arena,
whatever the hell they call it. Um,
had a couple of really cool,
um, meals when I was down there.
Went to this really good pizza joint.
Um, good for the southwest pizza.
You don't mean let's not
get crazy right. And, uh,
got a good burrito down there.
I didn't work out at all.
I was driving over to see my dog.
I was starving.
I got a fucking whopper with cheese and
fucking burger king and all freckles is
a, that's it. I'm done.
I'm, I'm officially,
I'm on the wagon for the first time in a
year, like really hardcore on the wagon.
Like I'm fucking done.
There's no drink in,
in site other than water for
me. Um, I don't know. I was,
I was, uh, I don't know what happened to
me the last two times I went on the road.
I just spent under a fucking
a lot of stress, you know,
not sleeping with the kid.
And then I got to put this
new hour together and uh,
my fucking shoulder is still messed up,
although I finally turned the corner
with it. And, um, but you know,
so I just,
you know,
I just haven't been able to work out the
way I want to and I swear to God, dude,
I am starting to get dad bought and
I have to stop this immediately.
I am too goddamn vein,
you know,
you know when you just
look bad in a tee shirt,
I have a pothead body right now
and I do not fucking like it. Oh,
I forgot to tell you still have to
deal with that guy. Hey, you know,
what the fuck was I supposed to do?
I come into my house and there's this
strange odor, like, what is that?
Is that some hippie candle?
What's going on?
And I come downstairs and Nia tells me
that a fucking pipe or some shit bursts
the night before and all this water came
out. I go, you gotta be shitting me.
You gotta be shitting me
and I go, okay. Did you,
did you go to the front of the house
like I showed you and turned off all the
water?
Okay.
No, I turned it off under the
sink. I'm like, Oh God, okay.
I'm smelling water.
And then I look at my bedroom ceiling
and there's a brown stain just ever so
small and this little fucking crack.
And I was just like, oh my God. Dot.
Again, please tell me not
against. So I run upstairs.
I shut off the main fucking thing.
You know,
this is thing about these feminists,
they don't want to do fucking
housework anymore, but they,
they're not going to
do the guy shit either.
Like no one had to shut the
fucking water off. It's like,
so what exactly are you going to do?
Okay,
fucking watch Mary Tyler Moore
reruns. So it's, I'm sorry, whatever.
I'm flying up, run upstairs at flying
out the fucking door. I shut it off.
And then I,
you know,
now I got my stupid can iPhone flashlight,
because the fucking guys outside checking
the box of cut off the electricity,
the water's off.
Now this is just basically a glorified
fucking log cabin and I'm going through
the crawl spaces and all this shit and
I'm trying to find out where this water
is coming from as it collected.
Is the ceiling going to collapse?
What is going on? And um, fortunately
I think, I think we're all right.
Um, and it was also fresh water.
So I don't think you guys like,
you don't have to deal with mold, which
I don't know if that makes sense to me.
I mean, it doesn't also it on what
the fuck's in the inside the pipe.
I have no idea.
I'm sure there's going to be a bunch of
people tweeting at me make scaring the
shit out of me. So that's basically what
I came home too. But the plumber came by,
change the fucking thing
that needed to be changed.
Hopefully everything's going to
be all right. But I once again,
you know,
everybody in your house,
I'm telling you right now,
needs to know how to shut
off the fucking water.
Everybody.
In fact,
that's the first thing I'm going to
teach my daughter once she starts walking
around,
you know what I mean?
What'd she understands?
The concept of
water and what it can do to your house.
All right.
And I'm just going to be like,
look, the next time a fucking book,
I sweat the next, I'm going
to, I'm getting rid of this
house. I'm done with it.
Fuck this house.
I've had it.
I've just had it with his fucking
house, you know, smell, goddamn faults.
What happened? You buy a 100 year old
fucking house that has a lot of character.
You know,
I'm going to sell this fucking house and
I am going to buy some brand new home
depot doubt. No character
whatsoever. I mean,
I want it to look like a fucking
food court. I don't give a shit.
As long as everything's brand new in it.
No,
don't mind like the people
won't put it together. Right?
And I'll still have the problems,
but um,
I was literally when I was
in the crawl space, right?
It's all these fucking cobwebs and
all that. I just, it just, it was it.
I officially fell out of love with this
house and I was like, you know what?
Fuck this house. You know why?
You know what? You went house,
you fucking when you brought me down.
Cool Hand Luke,
you finally fucking did it. What
should dirt doing? A boss man's hole.
That's what this house has been doing me
the entire fucking time I've lived here.
I Dunno boss.
We got to get it outta there.
What's your dirt doing? A boss
man's yard. I don't know boss.
Yeah.
Ah Fuck. Anyways, homeownership,
you know they always show all
of the young couple on TV,
fucking smiling and all that shit.
They had a fucking show me my fucking
whopper with cheese. Fucking body
crawling around a goddamn crawl space.
Of course. What are going to
walk around and crawl space bill.
Okay,
so then I fucking thank
God. It's all right.
So then I leave, I go down to take care
of all the bills and all of this shit.
So why the podcasts late is
late. And I'm like, alright,
I gotta I gotta pick up
a salad or something.
I got to start on the right
foot here. And, uh, you know,
typical La Thing, oh, this is the place I
want to be. Um, that's a restaurant that,
you know, 40 people can eat at
and there's four parking spots,
two of which,
you know,
are taken by the cook in the manager and
the other two are taken by the fucking
waitstaff. So as always,
there's no fucking place to
park. And I turned the corner.
Lo and behold, there's
a fucking spot. And, um,
I went down and turned around like a
gentleman and of course someone else said,
fuck that. And they made the three point
turn into the goddamn parking spot,
took my fucking pocket spot.
Yeah.
And uh, that, and then I, then that was
it. That was enough. All my meditation,
everything went out the fucking
window. And, uh, you know,
so I had my first fucking
meltdown in awhile and in weeks,
my first meltdown in weeks.
And then I basically,
I went from yelling at the guy who
fucking took my, took my parking spot.
It was my parking spot, right? He
got there first. I saw it first,
but he fucking made a better move. And
he gave boxed me up like, you know,
you've got the rebound.
I went from yelling at bout him in the
car to myself to yelling even louder
about the electrician to yelling even
louder about shutting the fucking water
off. The second day is
of God damn problem. Um,
and then I found a
parking spot and I got out
and I think I was yelling so loudly like
somebody walking by was looking at me
all fucking weird and I dunno, whatever.
I had a little bit of a setback. But uh,
anybody out there if you'd like to buy
a house with a lot of character, oh,
does this out. This house is
a character. I'll tell you,
it'll have you scratching your head.
Um,
okay,
maybe I'll sell this idea
and talk to me about this.
Maybe I'll sell this fucking house
and we'll just do the, do the, uh,
moving to one of those soldiers.
Fucking high rises. You know,
you know those things that people do,
the empty nesters do when they just
don't want to deal with the fucking house
anymore, which I never
understood. It's like,
why the fuck would you want
to be live in your house?
All the kids are out of there. You know,
you now, you've got all these spaces.
It's going to be great now. Right
now I know why. Now I know what.
Yeah.
Oh, do I know why? Cause
this shit's going to happen.
Yeah. I, I completely fucking get it now.
Like I don't give a fuck about a view.
I don't give a fuck about, you know,
old school shit.
I don't give a fuck about anything.
All I give a fuck about is if
something breaks, it's not on me. How,
where can I live like that?
I might go back to renting
this house is just, it's just a fucking,
it's a motherfucker. I'm never again,
I'm telling you right now,
don't have a buy a fucking old
house unless you're handy. You know,
or unless you just like making your
life fucking difficult. I'm telling you,
this is the classic. This is what mean
versus you were laughing about all week.
I was, how he makes his life easy
and I make my life difficult.
He buys a fucking house, the last fucking
guy, three dead, the whole thing. He gets,
he turnkey.
I need to be more Versie.
I gotta I gotta I gotta I gotta
fucking do that my next fucking place.
I don't give a shit what it is. I'll buy
a fucking Winnebago brand new though.
Just live in that right where bill,
you just don't fucking parking spots
out here. I Dunno. I'm sorry. Anyways,
so I'm going to be Billy elliptical head,
Billy fucking no booze bag and we've
eaten salads and all this fucking shit.
And uh, you know, I got
to get this under control,
disgusted with myself,
you know,
it's time to walk into the fucking
bathroom mirror and just trashed myself,
you know, take the shirt off.
Let's see what it is. You know,
it looked like Tom Brady.
I just first way,
and you know when he was a college student
just eating Cheetos and he was like a
third string quarterback or some shit.
Well, when I don't look like his face,
I look like his stomach.
Just no muscle tone whatsoever. I'm
exaggerating, but it made, I don't know.
It's not a, it's not what I want.
It's not what I want to see.
You know what I mean?
Yeah.
It's Christ.
It's like my belly is to the point.
It's going to be like when
I stand in the shower,
my knees aren't going to get it wet.
Um, feed are totally dry, you know? Um,
but that, you know something, I'm not that
bad, but that's the road I'm heading on.
And I was sitting on the plane today
watching all these fucking people who just
destroy their bodies, just getting on the
plane, just getting on a fucking plane.
They're like winded from walking
down that movable hallway,
whatever you call that. It's not the
tarmac. When they, what do they call that?
The jet way
people could you put your coats under the
seat in the overhead compartment so we
can expedite the boarding process.
We still have a lot of peoples standing.
I'm on the jet way.
We want to have it on time departure.
Um,
and I'm just sitting there
watching all of these fucking,
you know,
just fat Fox walking by.
This gotta be something amazing though
about living that way.
Okay,
well you, Oh, you just always just,
you're always eating exactly what
you want to eat, you know? Hey Mike,
you want a devil dog?
Yeah.
Do you want to get a breed
off? Sure. Absolutely.
What do you feel like having
a cheeseburger, French
fries and a chocolate malt.
Okay.
You know,
it's like you basically,
you're eating like a fucking eight
year old whose parents aren't home your
entire life. You don't, you know, when
your parents took off, that was it.
You went to the enemy,
you're eating a fucking elements cake
or some donuts or those store bought
fucking donuts.
Those ones where it was like,
it was like four plane for powdered
cinnamon. Do they still make those things?
We had those things all the time.
I used to eat, I got dammit,
I ate absolute shit when I was growing up.
Then you went outside,
you ran around and just burned it off.
Okay.
You didn't have a fucking blew out.
Your rotator cuff is a fucking seven
eight year old you injury free brand new
fucking car. You know what? My Body's
like, my body's like this house.
It's just fucking old as shit.
Yeah,
I can't wait.
You know how they can like grow an ear
and I'd fucking petri dish now I swear to
God I, I, you know they
got to do that. Like
it's going to happen man.
When they see they can bro all the
organs and they can grow all your fucking
body parts up over again. I'm telling
you right now it's going to be like,
you body's going to be like
a a I will, you know it,
but they probably still would look old.
But yeah,
it looks like one of those
Resto Mod. Thanks. You know,
or it's brand new one Denise. But on
top it looks at, you know, like a 1960,
whatever.
Is any of this fucking make it sense?
I mean, what was I supposed to do? I mean,
I knocked on your door three
times and there was nobody here,
so I just figured I'd walk
into your fucking yard,
put a ladder up next to your house,
Jesus Christ.
You know what I mean? Can you imagine if
somebody did that at Ted Nugent's house?
How many fucking bows and
arrows would that guy have?
And it's stupid construction hat.
What do you got the hard hat on for?
This is like, like that's going to
help. Like when you fall off the ladder,
that thing doesn't fall off with you.
Maybe that's why he did it. He had his
hat so fucking tidy wasn't even thinking.
Um,
yeah.
Anyways, so I was on the road and last
night, um, I missed the Celtics speed,
the Golden State Warriors. Holy
Shit. I got that game tape.
They've got to watch that.
And the Bruins beat the fuck out of
the Detroit red with a beat him up.
But they scored six goals, man. Um, I
should try. We read, we see, you know,
one of the original six. They, I mean,
they, they, they play in hockey town.
Everybody, there's a town out there
where you play hockey. There's a town,
I know where the hipsters go call
bedrock. Well worn out twitch, twitch.
Let me read some.
Um,
okay.
How many goaltenders by the way,
did Z,
cause I've watched the highlights it
with every one of them was a bad goal or
your defense just gave it away.
You know,
my condolences to the, uh, all
the players on the Redwings today.
I can't imagine how fucking
horrific your practices. All right.
Uh, the black Tux or you know,
I saw when I was in Phoenix,
I saw Reggie fucking mouth.
Fucking amazing.
You walked right by me and I just
watched a waiting for an elevator.
I just kept thinking like
that guy lit up the garden
turn around as spike Lee and made
the choke sign. And they just look,
he's just standing there,
wait for an elevator. Totally
relaxed. Totally cheating.
Doesn't need to talk shit.
Right?
He's the shit that's Reggie fucking Miller
hits a three steals the inbound pass
runs behind the three wasn't good
enough to get them for two fucking hits,
another three point turns around
and looks at fucking spike Lee.
Does the church in the
garden. I mean that's, yeah,
it's fucking,
do you ever have to,
do any of you ever got an outdoor
accomplish anything else after that?
If I ever did some shit like
that, um, for God's sakes,
if I ever did some shit like that,
you know what? I gotta take this,
hang on a second. All right. I'm back.
I swear to God, it never fucking ends.
It never fucking ends, you
know, you know, it's it. Gee,
I just wish you could just for one day,
save one day of being a kid.
You know what I mean?
Just to go back for 24 fucking hours and
not have to deal with this fucking shit
of being an adult.
Okay,
good fucking Lord.
You want that fucking phone call was
about about some sort of fucking tax
abatement for some bullshit.
I don't even know what the
fuck they're talking about.
To go onto the website and it
can fuck you. I don't want to,
it's an abatement. You'll get money
back. You know what? Just fuck.
How about you just keep it.
If you just keep it,
can I just not fucking waste
those precious seconds?
One the they fucking get.
What if a tree falls on me tomorrow?
This is one of my last
fucking days and I went to
www.fuckingabatement.to whatever
the fuck. I just don't care. Sorry.
I am in such a country mood.
I had such a great fucking three days.
You know what it is coming home and
there's somebody on a fucking ladder you
don't even know. Just walked into your
goddamn house or you're, you're, you're,
you're on your, your and your proper
tie and then a pipe burst and you know,
in the powers that be,
don't go fucking shut off the goddamn
water and you've got a brown spot.
You know when your ceiling, you
know, makes you a little salty.
What I'm saying? I was talking about
Reggie Miller, right? I was just saying,
if I fucking, if I did, what the fuck
that guy did, I would, I would have that
playing on a loop on my
phone, right. The video.
And I would just walk around holding
it up as I walked towards other human
beings. That'd be it. You
know, it's incredible.
What the fuck that guy did standing
there waiting for an elevator. All right.
Let me read a little bit of a, what do
we got here for a little advertising yet?
Oh, the black Tux. Everybody.
Okay.
They're not selling any of these
to that fucking guy from the, uh,
the musical there, right? Whatever
his name is, Ryan Seacrest.
Uh, the black Tux looking great for a
wedding or a special event has never been
easier with the black tux.com with
high quality rental suits and Tuxedos
delivered to your doorstep.
The Black Tux is giving guys a new way,
a new way to rent and get this,
the black Tux offers free home.
Try on,
she can see the fit and feel the quality
of your suit months before your event.
What kind of a fucking man or does it
fucking Tuxedo months before an event.
How much is your wife nagging you that
you agree to that shit? Fucking 60 days.
Hey, you know fucker, March madness.
We're going to a wedding in May.
You want to try on some fucking
Tuxedos? Uh, no I don't. I,
I'd rather jump up to fucking window.
But what's the best part you didn't ask?
It's completely done online.
No trips to the Tux shop required.
The Black tux.com lets you create your
look or choose from tons of stylist
selected outfits starting at just $95.
These suits have a modern fit.
You know,
it's not like the old days where you
fucking yanked up your pants and your
ankles was shown right and
you did the Charleston.
Do you know people did you know
people when they were doing that?
You don't want to,
you know what I'm say we're doing,
they were built in my fucking house.
Uh,
the Black Tux dot coms lets you create
your look and choose from tons of styles,
selected outfits starting at just $95.
This, oh, I already said that shit.
And if you have any questions
or issues or issues, Jesus,
they're going to fucking be a therapist.
They're expert customers. Can team,
customer care team has your
back every step of the way.
How much is the a Tuxedo?
And when I was five,
um,
after ordering your suit,
after ordering your suit will
arrive 14 days before the event.
That's a full two weeks to try it
on and make sure everything fits.
If anything is less than perfect,
the black Tux will send you a
free replacement right away.
When your event is over,
just drop your rental back in the mail.
Gross shipping is free both ways.
How easy is that to get
$20 off your purchase?
Visit the black tux.com/bar as the black
tux.com/burr for your $20 off purchase.
You know, I tweeted about this, um,
does anybody know where people
in the NBA get their tattoos?
Where 90% of them go to get their tattoos?
They had did the highest paid of the four
sports, I believe at this point. And it,
you wouldn't know it by
looking at the tattoos,
Jesus Christ with the area codes and
the Ho the fucking highway signs.
You know,
I guess those could be cool if you
actually took the time to like,
I don't know where they get them done.
They, they're, they look horrible.
Um, I didn't have anything
funny to say about it.
I'm just always watching NBA
hoop and they just, they're all,
everybody's scribbled all over
and you can't make out
anything of what anything is.
It's just a bunch of fucking shit.
Like an NBA guy. We'll get a fucking
tattoo of his baby's face on his neck.
Then you got to look at that for the
rest of his fucking career opened.
He's like that guy in the globe trotter
does that also were fucking headband
around his neck. You remember that guy?
Whatever his fucking name was. Anyways,
blue apron, everyone, blue apron.
Not all ingredients are created equal,
fresh, high quality ingredients.
Make a real difference. So it's important
to know where your food comes from.
I would not want to know where that
fucking whopper with cheese came from.
Talk about your personal experience with
Blue Apron. I've never fucking used it,
but I've got to use it now. Maybe
that's how I'll get in shape. You know?
I'll be like Oprah. I
love, yeah. You know,
do one of those things and maybe I can
have a giant fucking house that doesn't
fall apart.
You know what I lie like potato chips.
Yeah.
Can anybody pinpoint the year
she officially went insane?
Yeah.
She's just been famous too.
Fucking long.
I think it just makes you go crazy after.
Well,
everybody's always excited to meet you.
They're always giving you a fucking award.
There's no way to keep your feet on
the ground and then you just think
everything you're saying is interesting
or exciting to the fucking point.
You'll just scream something like,
I love bread
sitting in a giant fucking yard.
Every time I see her, I'm just like,
what is she doing? Jesus Christ. Oprah.
Just go to a fucking hot dog
stand. You know? Stand in line.
What you fucking turned and eat the thing.
Just do that every once in awhile.
This fucking
who likes carcase?
You got all those fucking
her cult of women.
It just hang on our every word.
Just hoping maybe this
complete stranger on TV.
She's the one that's gonna make me happy.
I mean that's,
that's the saddest part of
watching one of those Oprah shows.
I even know she does it anymore.
I'm just gonna pretend the
show still on the fucking,
there was all those women
that sat in the crowd,
the fucking look of hope on their face.
You know,
I always wanted to see,
you know,
what they should have had next door was
the sea of men that all those fucking
poor women were married to.
You know,
that fucking motley crew of insensitive,
constant never told them they were
pretty or whatever the fuck they needed,
whatever they needed,
they weren't getting there,
that they would go down
to the studio audience.
It just fucking sit
there with that fucking
okay.
Like you ever watched one of those shows
with is like 10 whores and they're all
fucking fight over some nerdy guy
and that look of hope they have,
if they're going to get the fucking,
you know, get handed a slipper,
which means they're going to
be there for another week,
whatever the fuck you need,
whenever it is they do,
they all had that look on their face.
MMM.
Do you know what? As much as I'm
making fun of Oprah, I also like Brent,
but no matter how fresh it is,
no matter how much I like it,
if someone was standing in a big
yard yelling that it would make me
uncomfortable and it would
take away from the experience.
You know,
it's gotta be weird to be
part of her fucking staff.
Just every once in a while I'll just
hear yelling random things. Costume.
Yeah.
Okay.
I bet Steadman knows that
a block that out, Huh?
Okay.
That's what she has those
giant fucking houses.
She probably likes to sound the echo.
You know,
she's like Rosebud level
famous citizen Kane. Um,
what the fuck was I to all blue apron,
everybody for less than $10 per month?
No per person per meal.
Blue Apron delivers seasonal recipes
along with pre portioned ingredients
to make delicious home cooked meals.
Choose from a variety of
new recipes each week.
All that blue apron
culinary team surprise you.
That's an Oprah thing.
We got to culinary TB as Supros.
You recipes are not repeated.
How bad is my act right now than I
did it six times? I can barely talk.
That's what's called having no jokes.
So what you do is you just scream
your shit, thrown it against the wall.
Some of the shit that came out
of my mouth, I'm a god. Somalia,
I made a reference to Whitney Houston
drowning in a bathtub like that.
That's how desperate I am for
fucking material right now.
Recipes are not repeated within a year,
so you'll never get bored.
Customize your recipes each
week based on your preferences.
Blue Apron has several different options
so you can choose what fits your needs
and there's no weekly commitment,
so you get deliberately
only when you want them.
Each meal comes with a step by step,
easy to follow recipe card and pre portion
ingredients and can be prepared in 40
minutes or less.
Blame brings freshness.
Guarantee promises that every ingredient
in your delivery arrives ready to cook
or they'll make it right.
Check out this meant this week's menu
and get your first three meals for free
with free shipping.
I'm praying to God they have a fuckin
they named a fucking ingredients cause I'm
going to scream at like
Oprah, uh, by going to blue
apron.com/burn. You will love
how good it feels and tastes.
You'll love how good it
fails and tastes to create.
And how much would Oprah kill this read
to create incredible home cooked meals
with blue apron. So don't wait.
That's blue apron.com/burr blue apron.
A better way to cook.
Yeah,
I want to go left two more.
Alright.
blinds.com whether you want privacy or
you jerk off during the day or just me
or just want to make a room,
a little doc,
you don't have to take out a second
mortgage to get a brand new custom blinds
from blinds.com yeah. Why are
blinds? Why are blind so expensive?
Um,
you can make over any room or your entire
house just by adding new blinds and
that blinds.com and att and
blinds.com has made it easy. Jesus,
Bill next,
please mention the talking points below.
Yeah.
Well, yeah, I mean it's
the next shit here.
I'm obviously going to read it after
you've read that. Then read this.
blinds.com
why is Dotcom mics picking out in
ordering brand new custom blinds, fast,
affordable, and shockingly easy?
Holy Shit. Are we done already?
They'll walk you through the measuring
and installation every step of the way
and what are 100% satisfaction
guarantee if you meet a mistake,
if you make a mistake, I should never
do this on a travel day. You know,
once they said a hundred
percent satisfaction guarantee,
I immediately started thinking of fast
times at Ridgemont high, you know,
instead of not 100% satisfied and I
don't want to, I want to read Front Brad,
Mr. If you don't shut up, I'm
going to kick 100% of your rash.
I'm sorry.
If you make a mistake measuring your
blinds or pick the wrong color or screw
anything up with your order, they'll
remake the blinds for you for free.
You want samples? They're free.
You like shipping, it's free.
It's all built into the price somewhere.
There's a crying child putting all this
shit together in a third world country,
but you don't need to think about that.
You just close those blinds.
He closed those blinds and
you never hear him crying.
What a whatever your level of confidence
in the following instructions, what,
whatever your level of confidence in
following instructions or even using a
measuring tape,
the design consultants@blind.com we'll
get on the phone with you and walk you
through every step. Oh my God, that's
gotta be the worst fucking job ever.
What do you do? Uh, um, I,
okay.
Over the phone.
I talked people through putting blinds up.
I find it really rewarding.
Okay.
Now when you're turning it,
are you seeing more of
the outside or less? Well,
okay then. Then you want to
turn it the other way? Yeah.
Turn it the other way and then yes,
they'll close. Are they closing?
You are seeing less of the outside. Okay.
Okay. Do you have any more questions?
They'll answer your questions and
even send you instructional videos.
However you want to interact.
You can't get this run.
You can get made to order custom blinds
without paying custom prices only
online@blinds.com call to action.
Capital letters must read g
two blinds.com and use promo.
Oh go. There's no, oh there. Oh,
I thought that was like
some shit right there.
G to the motherfucking blinds.com
there's no, oh in the copy here.
Go to blinds.com now and use
Promo code burn for 20% off.
That's blinds.com promo code bar
rules and restrictions may apply.
See blinds.com for details.
I'm definitely going to see
the details all of a sudden.
Don't know where there was rules
and restrictions. All right.
CSO. See, so I have,
I've had funny feelings.
I've gotten funny looks. I've eaten funny
smelling Sushi, but let me tell you,
none of those are as funny as
CSO streaming libraries stand up.
Television and original content,
especially not the Sushi.
Why do they try to write these funny?
Why would you do that?
Jesus Christ, the George Burns
right there. Our next place.
Next please mention the following
talking points. I'm gonna. We see.
So you get unlimited access to CSOS
original series next day, late night.
Hilarious. Standup specials. I'm just
not seeing the comments. Comments today.
Binge worthy classics including
42 seasons of Saturday night live.
The entire Monty python catalog,
the it crowd and more. We see.
So you get binge words.
The classics,
British called comedy original series
like Ham and quest and bazillion dollar
properties. Not to mention the entire SNL
library. Well, you already mentioned it.
I'm saying, not to mention, you
keep fucking mentioning how much.
Stop mentioning that including the new
episodes the day after they air plus CSO
brings, brings, brings stand up
who gave me the copy this week.
Two brings plus CSO bring brings stand
up right to your living room with
exclusive content from today's best
comedians on demand and commercial free,
including Nick Depalo.
He's got a killer special on them.
A sign up now to catch brand new
standup specials from Jenna Friedman.
Faheem onward and
Sasheer Zamata Oh my God.
But the privilege white males here.
Um,
or watch your favorite sets from
cusp comedians like Louis Ck,
Amy fucking shoe animal Paris.
Also nick the Palos.
Got One.
Access CSOS content from
anywhere at any time using Ios,
android, Roku, apple TV, Amazon fire TV.
Oh, Amazon fire TV. I just
can't see the comments.
Windows or Xbox one
ready for the punchline.
CSOS just three 99 a month.
No joke.
Less than four bucks per month
for all the comedy you want.
Anytime anywhere ad free.
Just go to Seeso, s,
e s o Sierra, Echo, Echo Sierra,
oscar.com right now to sign up for
two weeks for free with Promo Code
[inaudible] at checkout as seeso.com
spelled s e s.com Promo Code Bar,
seeso.com promocode birth. Holy Shit,
I never thought that was going to end.
I honestly didn't think that that
was going to fucking end all right.
38 minutes of just absolute shit
for this week. People. I apologize,
you know, but I feel like
for me that, you know,
it was just some things that
needed to be said. All right.
I don't know what to talk about next.
Sorry. Bitched about my house so much. Um,
enjoy this nuts little musical clip
here. Oh Hey. By the way, you know what?
I heard that,
uh,
that sneaker shit that I was saying
actually ended up on some big sneaker
websites, so I must be getting
fucking trashed on that one. You know,
I had no idea that, you know, I
knew people were into sneakers.
I didn't realize I went and
told him that much. You know,
I actually bought a new pair of sneakers
this week when I was out in Phoenix.
I got the classic fucking shell
toes. That's what I got. You know,
cause a lot of peoples were suggesting
that I wore those fucking, you know,
you know those giant lecture Chunky
fucking sneakers that people with feet
problem use. You know, I don't wear
those. Although I do have the Steve Jobs,
new balance.
You know,
if you look at the Daytona 500 picture,
I believe I'm wearing them there.
I did have a nice pair of sneakers but
I was not going to wear them to the
Daytona 500. So maybe I have a little
sneaker head and make it right. Maybe,
I don't know.
I wear the shittiest pair of sneakers.
I had to go down and that fucking track
with all the Goddamn oil and shit all
over the place. Um, once again,
I want to thank everybody that
came out to stand up live.
Everybody at Stan applied.
It had such a great time and uh,
I dunno, Paul Versey crushed it
and all week. And uh, I just had a,
I had a great time,
so thank you very much.
San Jose Improv in two weeks and uh,
that's it.
Please listen to the music if you'd like.
And uh,
we're going to have a greatest hit from
a podcast recorded in a different time
in another year and something else.
All right. Have a great weekend.
You constant. I'll, I'll
talk to you on Monday.
Is the Monday morning podcast
20 past nine on Monday morning.
A cloudy day out here in La as it is
the rainy season and a actually had some
guests over here, so this is going
to be quiet, kind of a quiet podcast.
Um, cause I also have to do to the, uh,
I have some friends in town from out of
town, so we have to do all the La Shit.
Uh,
and I gotta be honest with you,
I'm trying to think what the La should
is because I'm still new out here,
you know, and I lived in New York.
I knew what that meant. You know,
that meant they wanted to go to the
top of the empire state building.
They wanted to go to the
Statue of Liberty, uh,
Times Square.
Basically.
They wanted to go every place
that a new Yorker never goes.
And uh, so what my mission always
was whenever I had, um, you know,
friends coming down to visit New York
City was I immediately tried to convince
them that all the things that they wanted
to see, they didn't really want to see.
And um,
I like to think I was doing them a favor.
But uh, you know, part of it
was selfish cause you know,
I'm not fucking getting on a boat to
climb up into a statue that's looking out
into the ocean. You know
what I mean? It's like,
you know, I dunno. That's
what we wanted to talk about.
Underrated. Overrated. Okay.
Overrated climbing up into
the statue of Liberty.
If he can even still do
it with the whole nine, 11
America or whatever that we live in now.
I don't even know if you're
allowed to fucking do it anymore.
I'm sure they'll let you if they like,
you know,
if you let them fingerprint you and
scan your fucking retinas. But um,
anyways, um, I don't, I always feel like
when you go to a city, like personally, I,
you know, I want to do a few
touristy things, but, uh,
I want to hang out with the locals
because they always know the good bars and
the restaurants and that type of shit.
And so that's what I used to try to,
you know, convince people
like, but it's hard sometimes.
Sometimes you just got to give in.
Like when my parents came down and they
wanted to eat at Mickey Mantle's on 57th
street, 59th Street, and uh, you know,
you just can't stop people from
doing shit like that. You know.
Isn't this a great burger?
No, no it isn't. It's a great,
is a touristy burger and it's fucking
$18 more than it needs to be because when
you look out the window,
you can see central park.
What is wrong with you Mickey Mantle?
Yeah, that's great. Let's then,
let's go get a hotdog at Wade Boggs.
The fuck does Mickey Mantle know
about making a burger? Okay.
If you want to go Busan and Mouse, oh,
that's a low blow fucking dead legend.
What the fuck is wrong with me? I
apologize. The Yankee fans over that one.
I shouldn't end sports fans in general.
You know,
Mickey Mantle never did steroids. Diddy,
granted they didn't exist back then.
And uh,
I got to tell you some,
it's too bad he didn't and it's too bad
they didn't exist back then because we
would've got to watch
that guy, uh, you know,
have the body of a 22 year
old until he was 42. And uh,
I got to tell you something
man. Um, after, you know,
just watching some of these
guys get busted and you know,
getting busted for being on juice, uh,
you know, they always have that question,
you know, should people who do steroids
be allowed into the hall of fame?
And uh, I think after the rock
thing, I'm finally thinking,
no,
they shouldn't.
And just for the simple fact that,
like I just said, it's like,
it doesn't help you get better.
It just keeps your body in mint
condition until you like 40,
42 in, all of these guys would get busted
the second they get off them there,
they're numbers go
right through the floor.
And I don't think it has anything to
do with this skill. It's just like a,
you do roids it's like you
become one of the expert.
I'm not really big on those
action movies and shit,
but you know those movies where you know,
somebody gets super human
healing abilities and somebody
slices into his arm and
it made immediately heals up.
It's like you're literally doing
the real life version of that.
And uh,
I don't think it's fair to guys like Ken
Griffey Jr there really isn't like, uh,
that guy quietly hits 600 fucking
home runs and I, you know,
kind of stop noticing 10 years ago when
all these fucking gorillas will coming
up to the plate. I don't
know, I've said this before,
maybe they should have a special wing,
you know,
the roid rage wing of the hall of fame.
I have no idea, but I got to admit,
I think we're all hypocritical,
forgiven those guys shit because
no one gave a fuck about baseball.
And then all of a sudden when
McGuire and Sosa came around,
I was one of the best years
of baseball ever. And uh,
everybody made a ton of fucking money
and everybody had a great time and now
we're all acting like our feelings got
hurt because we got to watch people hit
600 foot home runs, you
know, then make any sense.
I'm half a fucking sleep out
here. Um, here's something that I,
uh, I actually read a quote
from one of these magazines,
I guess evidently a Clint
Eastwood was hyping that movie.
Gran Gran Torino. I don't know
if you guys have seen that movie.
I'm sure you've seen the ads for it.
Where he basically is, I get up late Lon,
you fucking person of another race and
I'm a white man and I represented my car
represents back when America
was good in the early seventies.
Um, I guess when he was, uh, doing
the interview for that movie, uh,
he called I guess the current generation,
the pussy generation.
And at first it made me laugh
and I'm thinking like, yeah,
Clint Eastwood obviously has earned
the right to call people pussies.
And I'm thinking, wait a
minute, Cleese was, is an actor.
Okay.
Who plays tough guys who never
loses a fight really any,
even if he does lose a fight in a movie,
it's a fake fight.
So at the risk of making my second sack
religious comment first trash in the
Great Mickey Mantle, uh, now I'm
going to go out to Clint Eastwood.
Unlike where his Clint Eastwood,
I want,
this is my question
for you guys this week.
Where's cleanness would got off like
where's he earned the right that he's this
tough guy
cause like he plays a tough guy.
I've known understand that
with like actors. Like I
remember like after nine, 11,
like,
um,
for some reason they wheeled out Tom Hanks
and like that was supposed to make me
feel relaxed as an American.
And I remember during that time I was
doing a joke on stage going and talking
about Tom Hanks saying he's done so many
army movies. He thinks he's a veteran.
You know what I mean?
It's not like you did army movies,
but he played an astronaut.
He was in saving private Ryan.
You know what I mean? And like all
of a sudden, like he becomes like a,
all these guys, like I said,
you know, here's, here's one
for you. I've got fucking,
you know,
friends out here.
Some were doing the touristy shit out
here in La and I take them down to Mann's
Chinese theater or grooming or
whatever the fuck they call it now.
And they got those, uh, they
got the hand prints in the feet,
prints in the footprints
there in the, uh, the cement.
And I found John Wayne,
I swear to God,
John Wayne had the smallest
fucking feet I've ever seen it.
I couldn't believe it. This is the
Duke John Wayne. This is the guy.
Everyone was one.
Just thought if even breathed on you,
he fucking knock you in the next week.
This guy had like,
I think he went to fucking lady
gap to buy his cowboy boots.
She's like so fucking
the smallest fucking things.
He could've fit both his
boots and his cowboy hat.
That's how small his fucking feeder.
If you ever go to La and you
go to Mann's Chinese Stereo,
it's on the right hand side.
He had tiny little ass feet,
you know, actors are fucking
annoying, you know what I mean?
So then they put on fucking leather
jackets and they play these bad asses and
it's just like, dude, you're
fucking, you're an actor.
Have you had any real fights, Clint? Huh?
Somebody of a fucking rear engine and
the drive through at Burger King and you
got out and you settled the score maybe.
Yes. I don't know what, but you know,
I don't know. I'm fucking
just fucking annoyed me. And,
and moving on from that,
somebody actually sent me an email
that kind of ties into this, right?
I'm not saying clinics and a tough guy.
The guy's fucking ridiculous.
He's 80 years old, he's still
lifting weights, you know,
the way his eyes are squinted.
He definitely seems like
a bad ass, but you know,
I want to see his fight card. I want
to see his arrest record. You know,
maybe he was a juvenile delinquent
before he came up. I Dunno,
I haven't Wikipedia them yet.
I have no idea. But this is
just, you know, there's just an,
I don't even know why I'm defending
this generation of people because I'm 40
years old.
So technically the only generation that
pop culture gives a fuck about is the
young kids, you know, which is
basically, I don't know what,
whatever it starts to is basically
once you're over the age of 24,
nobody gives a fuck about you anymore as
far as like a what music you listen to.
Um, anyways, so this, this
woman wrote me this, uh,
she wrote me this email and it said,
uh,
when it let me get down to the blah, blah,
blah, blah, blah, all this type of stuff.
Same really nice stuff to me,
which um,
I'm going to blow through here even
though I totally appreciate it.
And she was commenting on the guy last
week, you know, the guy last week,
I was reading the story where, uh,
he was hanging out with this girl,
most beautiful girl he's ever seen,
but she's dumb as a brick and there's a
fucking pothead and he can't figure out
how to close the deal with her. Um, so
this is what she said. She said, Oh,
and about the guy who asked
about what he should do with the,
with the pretty pothead girl asked him
if he tried to get physical with her.
Um,
wouldn't he know whether or not she was
interested in a physical relationship if
he had made a move on her, which is a
great point because maybe he didn't.
And she said he's probably one of those
hesitant guys that want the check to
make the first move.
So typical of today.
So I guess that's kind of backend.
Clint Eastwood saying that this
is like the pussy generation.
Um, I don't want to be a dick here, but
I think a lot of that has to do with, uh,
the oversaturation of a
date rape movies. And, uh,
these 100%
chick tone shows like
fucking Oprah and I'll,
I mean, they got, you're so
fucking, I don't know. I don't
know what it is they got.
Everybody's so convinced that women
aren't the same lying sacks of shit that
guys are with just different genitalia
that I think a lot of guys are
approaching, um, stupid pothead checks.
Like they're these princesses that
need to be rescued. In other words,
what I'm saying is he's you
just fucking bender over.
He should just stick her bag of weed
on the floor in front of our ankles and
when she bends down to get it,
he should handle this business. All
right. That was ignorant. There you go.
That's the first a straight up fucking
ignorant statement of the week. Um,
let's get on with it here. This is
the out of the Monday morning podcast.
If you're wondering what this babbling is,
um,
I do one of these every single week.
Like fucking cal Ripkin.
I'm the cal Ripken a fucking podcast.
I can't remember the last time I missed
one. Even when I fucking miss one,
I call up and I apologize,
you know,
does that count if cal Ripkin Mr Baseball
game in the middle of his streak and
he just kind of called in the Orioles
and said yes. Sorry about that. Yeah.
But he called up,
he called up before the sixth inning,
so that counts as him showing up.
Anyways, I do one of these every week.
People send me a,
they send me questions,
they send me their list of
underrated overrated. Um,
sometimes they ask me for advice.
Sometimes somebody sends
me a cunty email and uh,
they earned the right of a douche
bag of the week. If it's bad,
if it's bad criticism, if I deserve
it, I'll take one on the chin.
Um, and also I hiked the stuff
that I have going on in my career.
Okay. Bill, what do you have going
on in your career at this week? Well,
I will tell you on, uh, next Monday,
Monday the uh,
the fuck is today at damn this phone
once nine plus seven, the 16th,
March 16th, I am going to be
doing um, a couple of shows.
I believe they added a second show
at the punchline in San Francisco.
The first one sold really well.
And last I heard we were going
to add a second show. Um,
you can go to punchline comedy club.com.
I have all the information.
I probably don't even have that up
on my website. Do I? What a moron.
I'm going to do that at the end of this
podcast. By the time you hear this,
it's going to be up there. Hopefully. Um,
I'm going to be at the
punchline San Francisco next
Monday night with Joe Barton.
Nick,
um,
and the shows are at seven o'clock and
I believe they just added a nine or nine
30.
And that's what I like to do.
I'd like to hype Shit where I have three
quarters of the information and later
on this month, the final weekend of
March, whatever the hell those dates are,
I'm going to be at the house of
comedy and East St Louis White people.
Don't be scared. It's going to
be a nice mixed crowd, you know,
and you know, just like our president
nice and mixed, you know, they'd go,
I don't let me bring in America together.
Um, and then I got up after that, I got,
uh,
the Trump marina.
Why don't I get on my fucking website
here and figure out most of you listening
to this, by the way, on my website,
cause I gotta I gotta admit I'm
starting to find my space, my space.
I'm starting to feel like the survivor
of a nuclear holocaust, you know,
kind of like will Smith's
character and I am legend
every day.
Every Monday I will be doing a podcast
at the pier down at the bottom of
Manhattan, you know, and I
want you to saber tooth tiger.
I never understood those
fucking lions in that movie.
Where the fuck did they come from?
You know the only lines in Manhattan
or in the zoo. So if everybody,
the zookeepers all died of
whatever fucking disease it was,
was that some animal lover who came
up with the end of the world? Rabies,
I have to let these lions go and get
mauled to death just like you fucking
deserved. Um, okay. Here we go. Sorry. I
had to do that until I got to my website.
Um, April 4th, 2009,
I will be at the Trump marina with
uninformed Joe to Rosa Comedy Central
Presents Joe to Rosa,
every local bar in Manhattan's Jody rose.
Sorry,
Joel, if you listen to this, I, you know,
good things come in three and you only
have two good things in your life.
All right? And I'm one of
them. Don't ever forget that.
You fucking half Egyptian S. All
right, getting a little louder,
a little more angrier.
Um, what else do I got?
I got the funny bone and Columbus and
my Caroline's date got moved from the
middle of May to the last week
of April slash first weekend.
I guess it's the first weekend in May.
All right.
I'm sure I'm going to emails on that.
Oh my God,
I was coming in from Chattanooga
just through your show.
Send me a free DVD.
I will,
as long as you open your mouth and let
the mailman jam it down he fucking throat.
I
really get made here.
Um, oh, we're going to be getting
less than the girlfriend over there.
She puts a fucking makeup
on. Okay. Audience of one.
Um, anyways, uh, oh, here
we go. You know, it's uh,
something that really annoys
the shit out of me. Uh, parents,
I don't like former Fred boy date rapists
to then have kids and then sit there
and, and you know, now
because they have a kid,
I have to be respectful around them.
I think I talked about this last week,
but I'm going to talk about it
again because it's happened again.
I'm sick of you form a
fucking loud douche bags,
you know who just ruined people's flights.
You've ruined baseball games basically.
You like me? Okay, you're an asshole.
And now that you have a kid,
everyone else has to be on their best
behavior because you ended your life.
And the fun in your life. Everyone else
has to be on your schedule. All right?
Fuck you and your fucking kid,
all right?
If you don't want them to be around
a fucking animal like myself,
don't take them out in public, okay?
That's what they have board games for.
So why don't you sit there with your
board game and you'd dip and re your
turtleneck sweater that you don't want
to wear as the rage for the person that
you knocked up, builds up inside of
you. Why don't you keep that all right?
Walk out in your backyard
and scream into a bush. Okay?
Believe you fucking kids
because I'm still single.
I don't have any kids and I'm having a
good time and I'm not having you be a
fucking wet blanket because you have
this little creature that only half looks
like you. All right? Okay.
Comment of swinging.
I'm all right. I'm playing to the
crowd right now. I'm getting laughs.
I'm just fucking deliberately
being an asshole.
I'm really not in that bad of a mood,
Huh?
I'm not singling. You know what I mean?
I'm not married either. All right.
So watch your p's and q's over there,
sweetheart.
Um, ever tell you I got my girlfriend,
they gave us little fucking,
I want to put my makeup on.
I'm a little eight year old princess
women love that Shit and you know,
and you'd think it would keep them
from heckling you during a podcast,
but it doesn't. The fucking
happiness only lasts for a few days.
All right, question number one. Okay.
So if you new to my podcast, I do a,
and this one is going to be a little
short this week. I know, I would say that.
Then I ended up doing 50 minutes,
but uh, I'm already up to 18 minutes.
I'm gonna try to keep this,
uh,
kind of try to keep this about
30 minutes. Oh, by the way,
I went down to Irvine last
night and I watched, uh,
my old friend from the Chappelle show,
Charlie Murphy to a,
a nice hours worth of killer material
that I haven't seen before. Um,
if you get a chance, definitely check
out Sharley. I think he really has a, uh,
just a totally original, original
fucking style. That's great.
He just goes up there and he tells these
fucked up stories. Either that happened,
that he invented hybrid stories
that are partially true.
I don't even know what the fuck he was.
Great.
I sat there in the crowd like a
Goddamn Fan. Had a great time. Um,
and that is it.
So look at me hyping other,
took a little bit of a fucking great guy.
I am granted,
I already hyped my shows and buried his
hype fucking 20 minutes into a podcast
and I'm patting myself
on the back. Um, alright.
I do questions. I answer questions
every week here on the podcast.
So here are some questions.
Hey Bill,
I was wondering if you ever had a slow,
a slow spot in comedy.
Like if you ever had a period of time
when you didn't come up with any material,
any material for awhile.
Oh yeah.
That happens all the time then it
happens like every six weeks, you know,
or whatever. Or we'll have for
a six week period. But, um,
I've learned how to get,
I've learned what works for me,
how to get me out of those.
And I think I've answered this before,
but I know I have a Zillion podcasts so
I will answer it again in the name of
comedy. Um, what I do to
get myself out of those,
I take all rules of,
of being a hack.
I just throw those out the window and um,
I'm really setting myself up to
get trashed. Like really, Bill,
I never noticed that you ever,
uh,
didn't take the rules of hack
off with your awful specials? Um,
no, I just basically I do two things.
What I'm going to write his block a,
I will talk about current
events like that dumb broad,
but the eight fucking kids and just
basically shit that like every comic is
jumping on.
You know,
like you ever see when an animal dies
and the discovery channel's a bunch of
vultures sitting around it. That's
kind of like hack materials. Like,
and I'll fucking fly right down with my
ugly buzzard head and I'll take a big
chunk out of it. I basically just
basically if you're in writer's block,
just do hacky shit
about topical new stuff.
And also I try to ask my self
what's bugging me right now?
Anything from, um, my girlfriend,
it's going to bad look there.
My girlfriend too. Uh, like,
um, the fact that I can't
come up with any new material,
anything that's bothering
me. And um, I just,
you just kind of use that as an exercise
just to go on stage and just to be
saying something new,
even though you know it's hacky
shit that you never got to keep it,
it still feels good to not be doing
all the jokes that you're sick of.
And usually they'll end up spinning
into something else hopefully.
And you kind of pull yourself
out of the mud and uh,
and if all else fails, just pick on some
fat guy in the crowd. All right. No,
don't do that. Don't do that. Okay.
It didn't we learn anything
from Eddie Murphy in the clumps,
whatever the fuck that more than,
what was that movie called?
The night he professor,
you know, I fucked up.
I thought it hit all the questions right
in a row. Now I gotta scroll down. Hey,
how did you guys enjoy the music last
week? Did you like the old school music?
I'm going to play some more and we play
you a Ted Heath elks parade next week.
This is slowly just going to
become like fucking pirate radio.
I bought two more records this week.
I actually bought a clash record cause
I felt really bad about trashing them,
not trashing, I'm just saying
I didn't understand that music.
So I deliberately went out and I bought
a bunch of music that I never fucked
with when I was a kid cause I uh,
I got into ACDC,
which led me into Motley Crue,
which led me then down to a
really bad road of Glam hair metal
that I want to say
ended with Brittany Fox.
But somewhere in there
though, I did, I did.
I found Stevie Ray Vaughan when he did
the video for, couldn't stand the weather.
So I always had one foot in decent music.
But uh,
basically I totally shut out the
Ramones or the clash unless you know,
other than their radio shit,
Elvis Costello, this is all
shit I bought this week.
I finally downloaded, uh,
David Bowie, that, uh,
Ziggy stardust album.
And I was like, you know,
this is like one of these great concept
albums that people listened to in the
70s. And I was like, fuck this,
I'm doing it the way they did
it in the 70s minus the drugs.
So I got my headphones that I have,
I do have headphones,
I have the big fucking,
you know what actually for drums,
they kind of protect the ears from the
drums and he also can listen to your iPod,
which I don't have my dismay.
And I plugged it in my laptop and I
listened to the album and I fucked up was
because rather than listening to it in
the track order, I guess on my iTunes,
I had it in, you know, last downloaded.
So it kind of jumped all around the album.
I kind of realized when the Ziggy stardust
fucking kill themselves or whatever,
by the third song, I'm like, wow,
how's David Bowlby going to pull
himself out of this fucking thing?
And then I realized,
you know,
once again I fucked up with technology
but the fucking killer album and uh,
I dunno if anybody has any suggestions of,
of music from that era,
you know, all the shit that I
thought sucked, like talking heads.
I kind of like the couple of their songs,
but like some David Burns
Solo shit I found is amazing.
And to think that I was in a,
in a warehouse
just trashing him during that period of
my life thinking that he sucked as I was
listening to Cinderella
and poison and all this,
uh, Tesla, I'm not saying they were bad,
but that was definitely the smooth jazz
of heavy metal. It was a, I don't know,
it's just fucking
embarrassing.
Really embarrassing.
I think eighties music really gets a
bad rap when you start listening to, uh,
I dunno.
I Dunno what the fuck up.
I just literally asked you for advice
then and then I bought a couple albums.
All right. Actually, literally
still by him too, by the way.
Bought a couple of cds and
didn't even listen to them yet.
And now I'm already trying to tell you
guys what's good music from the 80s CDC,
the fucking most of the Inner Mussolini.
It's fucking me. I Dunno.
I'm not. All right. Um,
let's get to underrated
overrated here or what?
You guys want to hear a
story about revenge. Huh?
I like how I asked you guys questions.
You know,
it's like you actually have a say and
as you sit there and nod your head and
your cubicle, yeah, yeah. You know,
a pump your fist on your
fucking treadmill, you know,
or just say yes out loud,
loud,
loud in your middle seat on that Delta
Airlines flight you on Delta Airlines
right now.
Is there somebody with bad breath eating
pistachios next to you ever tell you
that fucking story? Unreal. And
he's eating the red ones too.
That made his lips all fucking pink by
the end of it. Horrific. Horrific flight.
All right, let's get to the revenge.
When the fuck is it? COSI generation.
I'm really disorganized this week.
Okay. Because I have guests. I have,
I'm entertaining this week. All right.
And wearing a Tuxedo for three days.
Underrated. Overrated, underrated.
Overrated with fuck is the revenge story.
God dammit. Oh, this isn't terracing.
I don't want to just read it.
I'm just going to start.
I'm just going to jump around.
I'm just going to jump around. Who's
at House of pain? Um, no. Well fuck.
Oh fuck you.
I don't know who it was.
I tapped out during that Perry
to write movie review bill.
I just got back from the
midnight showing of the watchman.
I really don't know how to review it.
I'm told it sticks pretty close to
the graphic novel and had cool special
effects, great story and good acting.
But I kind of felt eh after it,
after leaving the dark night,
I remember I was so amazed.
I didn't have a single thought run
through my head for at least five minutes
after ironman and hulk. I left feeling
satisfaction. But with this movie,
something just kind of left me feeling
depressed after watching and I think it
was the overall message of the movie
was serious told in a totally ridiculous
way. Anyway. Anyway, I would
recommend it. But go with caution.
If you don't like comic books and
have trouble following fragmented,
fragmented storylines like
Tarantino movies, I wouldn't go.
You know,
it's said God damn good review.
Got Right to the fucking meat and
potatoes of it. Oh, and by the way,
he says it was directed by the guy
who did the 300 story, 300 movies.
So there's a lot of man ass in
it. Yeah, I find that funny.
That guys really liked that.
Uh, that movie 300. I mean,
I thought it was pretty ridiculous,
but um,
the amount of guys that get pumped
after they see that, I mean,
that literally was playgirl the movie.
I thought,
um, I just thought, don't think ms
stupid. They, you can turn this spot. Ah.
All right, good luck with
the, um, you know what that's
like. That's like Beyonce,
my girlfriend downloaded
that fucking album.
The name of the album is
I am dot, dot, dot, dot.
Sasha fierce. All right, Beyonce. Well,
good luck with that character.
He kind of still sounded like Beyonce.
If you ask me. Beautiful, gorgeous
woman, woman really can dance.
But her voice, oof. Jesus Christ.
Yeah.
Yay.
Horrible punishing you.
Just fucking Polish into her.
Best thing was when she whipped her
head around and fell down on the stage.
That was probably one of the greatest
things I think I've ever seen.
And a lot of it's just bitterness. She's
just absolutely gorgeous. You know,
she's totally out of your league.
And is there anything funnier than
seeing a beautiful girl just fucking fall
right on her ass?
You know,
this is ridiculous and I'm sure she's
a nice fucking person, but you know,
I should really, reality is, I'm
kinda thinking like, this is Jay z,
his fucking wife. And uh, then he
stabbed somebody one time for something,
although he did it in a hacky way.
He walked up and he used the Godfather,
the line. He said, you broke my heart
and then stabbed him. That's all alleged.
Why don't I shut the fuck
up? Okay, I will. All right,
here's a revenge story. Bill.
I'm not really into revenge,
but if someone fucks with me to the point
where I think about pushing them off a
cliff, then yeah, I kind of feel like I
have to do something. So here's my story.
Oh, this is a good one. Settle in
for this one. If you're at home,
get underneath your ass can and roast
some fucking marshmallows because this is
like a, this is the closest
thing to what go story. Um,
this is just has that evil fucking,
uh,
last house on the left Vibe, um, which
I loved that they're making. Again,
cause that reference will
finally make sense to people. Um,
if you don't know what that is,
there was John Rose films in the 70s,
w which were basically rate movies.
Last House on the left gator Bait.
Fucking, uh, I spit on your
grave and evidently they're
going to make a comeback,
which I think is fucking
hilarious, you know, you know,
we haven't had a good rate
movie in awhile. All right. Um,
let's remake last house on the left.
I think that that needs to be
updated. All right. Anyways, Bill,
I had a girlfriend for about three
years. This is the revenge story. Bill.
years who ended up cheating on me when I
found,
and when I found out about it,
I called her out on it and
she got defenses and turned
on me, blah, blah, blah.
Wow, dude, that's, that's some
pretty, uh, she's got skills.
If she was able to do that, uh, you
cheated on me. You fucking bitch.
Yeah. Well you never do the
dishes. Okay. I'm sorry.
I guess you made a good point. How the
fuck did she turn on you? Unless you,
all right bill, just shut up and read
the story. Okay. I will. So anyway,
she turned on me. Um, then he goes,
I made the poor decision and
took her back about a year later,
about a year later,
she cheated on me again and I told her
to go fuck herself prior to the second
cheating,
I bought a trip to Disney world for us.
And about eight months after we broke up,
it was time for the,
for the Disney world trip.
So I asked her if she wanted to go see,
she said yes and off we went.
Now my revenge kicks in.
See, this is just like one of those
movies starts off all nice and sunny.
We'll go into the camp and
going to Disneyland and here
comes fucking Jason on a
crystal lake. Um, so
now my revenge kicks in.
All of the degrading things
I've ever wanted to do. This
chick I did to this one.
Okay. And I have guests, so I get a
mumble. This shit I busted on her face.
I pounded her into the ass
until she puked Jesus Christ.
Women are just literally ripping their
headsets off right now. Anyways, he goes,
it was fantastic.
On the fourth night we had an argument,
she told me that she wanted to go on this
trip to try and win me back cause she
felt bad for all the
things she had done to me.
Basically she was apologizing for
cheating when I told her that there was no
chance of us getting back together.
And the only reason why I fucked her
was to make her feel like a prostitute.
She bought a plane ticket
home and I felt wonderful.
I guess what I'm trying to say is
some people deserve what they get.
Oh God, what a great, great story.
Um, there's so many levels to that.
Okay. First of all, just the fucking,
the fact that she cheated on
you and you took her back,
he just liked dineros character
and casino, you know what I mean?
You didn't know how to handle it.
And then she cheats on you second time
and then you just become jaded and you
just go into like a, it was like, you
know those movies where the guy, you know,
the,
the week person's just getting the shit
kicked out of 'em and then finally they
just can't fucking take it anymore.
And then all of a sudden they turned
into like fucking like Clint Eastwood
character.
You actually did that with this girl.
And then the whole other
level that I love, okay.
Is that now that you've finally pound
in this skank in bed the way she always
wanted to, probably the reason
she cheated on you. You know,
cause you probably will do in the,
I love you kind of sex now.
You actually fucking do what you was
supposed to be doing with this girl.
Now she wants to get back with you.
Fuck that.
She didn't go to Disneyland because
she wanted to get back with you.
She went to Disneyland because she's
a fucking cunt who saw a free tip to
fucking Florida and she thought she was
going to play you again and get more
shit out of you.
Then all of a sudden you come in there
and you throw down like Johnny fucking
Wad and now all of a sudden that then,
then she wanted to get back with you and
then you told him to go fuck herself.
Which was perfect because I thought you
were going to crumble in that moment and
you didn't, you know, and then she
fucking left and then that's great.
And then you laughed your ass off and
jumped on the tea cups listening to,
it's a small world after all,
you know, that's fucking great.
Four stars. If you fucking film that,
I would, not only would I go see it,
I would buy it on DVD.
Great fucking story of revenge.
Um, all right. And we go, oh, we had a
lot of passion in it, Huh? Oh, we're,
are we up to 34 minutes? All right, let's
hustle through this. All right. Overrated.
Overrated. Underrated list for the week.
Overrated. High priced Mexican foods.
You can get the same shit for half
the price across the street. You know,
some shit is written so perfectly, I
don't even need to add to it. Exactly.
100% correct. I still had to add to
it. Alright. Underrated. Fake boobs.
Fucking awesome.
Um,
I like how that's written so short
and it's just up to me to draw my own
collusion, my own conclusions.
Fake boobs. Fucking awesome. Um,
have you ever touched him?
The fucking horrific. Um,
personally I guess I hate fake boobs
are the worst. Uh, don't ever do that.
I don't ever do that. Then all of a
sudden in a matter how good they are,
it's like you're having sex
with a fucking cyborg. I,
one of those awful Bruce Willis movies.
Remember those are judge dread.
You know those movies where you know,
they always,
they always ended up hooking up
with some half person, half robot.
That's what I feel about that stuff.
And I really don't understand why people
get face lifts and stuff, you know,
first of all it doesn't look good and
everybody noticed even if even if you
didn't notice for some reason
when you get your face lift,
it also becomes really shiny.
Can anybody explain what that is?
Is that the Botox?
What is it about getting faceless that
makes you face so fucking shiny and it
literally looks like laminated?
Um,
now you know what it looks like.
It looks like the apples and the grocery
store that they spray to make them
really, really shiny. Speaking to
which you ever get an organic apple.
I mean it's like so natural. There's
like a fucking warm in it. I like the,
I think I like the old shiny ones.
Um, all right, Phil Love U podcast.
Just wanted to say, I think using, I like
this one too. A bill. I just want to say,
I think using big words is overrated.
If you can express something by
saying a simple, normal word,
why use a big word?
I just broke up with my girlfriend today
and earlier she had called me anthro,
anthro phobic because I don't even know
what the fuck that means because I don't
like,
cause I don't like her friends.
She called me anthro cause I
don't like her friends. Um,
I just don't like most of her friends.
It doesn't mean I hate people in
general or even hate or friends.
I honestly didn't know what it meant.
So I looked it up.
It means a fear of people,
which isn't even what she said.
You're right.
She didn't even use it correctly or
actually what she or she has a delusional
view of her friends that her
friends represent everybody
or that her friends are
so great that if you don't like them,
then you just hate all people because
her friends represent humanity.
Jesus. Good movement. Dumping
that fucking stuck up Twat. Um,
anyways,
I definitely do not like a lot of people,
but I don't hate people
unlike that call last week.
Who messed with that guy's mom? Mom's car.
Yeah. That guy was fucking nuts. Anyways,
it seems like a,
you're kind of the same way.
I just don't see the point of using big
words other than trying to sound smart.
It's like if something can be said more
easily and in a way that's easily more
easily understood by using smaller wood,
words can't even fucking read.
Especially if you have an idiot like
me reading it. Keep the word small.
Would you say something like that
serial killer was, I can't even,
I don't know what this word is.
Dak Know Adac no maniac.
Or that Lee was obsessed with killing.
I don't think you'd say either.
I think you just say that
guy's a serial killer. I mean,
I think we know what serial killers do.
I know what you mean.
Do I know what you mean by this is what
I think. I think, I think big words, uh,
they're, they're much better
in print. You know what I mean?
Cause you don't want to read, you know,
a great novel and just have someone like,
dude, shit was fucked
up. You know, I was like,
damn, I mean I wouldn't want to
read like I, I don't, I don't mind.
I don't mind big words,
but I mean
they have to be coming out of the
right person's mouth. In fact,
I kind of liked them on some
level when, um, you know,
but person use a big word and it makes
me want to read and they're actually
using it in an obnoxious way and they've
earned the right to use it that way
because they actually do read
and don't watch TV. But yeah,
if it's just some chick you were dating
who has cunty friends and they watch the
Osi every Thursday night and then
she pulls out a word like that. Um,
that sounds like that, that was
a breakup word. She was like,
I'm going to use a big word here so I
can feel like I'm above this guy who's
dumping me because my low self esteem is,
is,
is gonna fucking flow right over the side.
And I'm going to break down and I'm going
to start crying and I'm going to have
a snot bubble and I'm
going to feel horrible.
And I know in six months I'm going to
realize this person isn't worth crying
about. So I'm going to use a fucking
big word here to try to save myself.
I really forgot what I was saying
halfway through that. That's weird.
I actually agree with that guy.
And then in that scenario,
I just sorta trashed him like
saying he wasn't working,
he was wasn't worth crying over.
You know what?
I don't know shit about either one of
you, but, uh, you wrote me the letter,
so I'm going to fucking side with you.
I'm trying to be more balanced because
I trashed chicks twice in this. Uh,
all right.
Hey Bill,
I've been a big fan of yours since
I saw your European friends, Sam,
as in his hand.
I was wondering,
when are you gonna come to the
punchline in Atlanta? Well,
why don't you go on my fucking website
and scroll down and look for punchline in
Atlanta?
That's usually a good way to find out.
When I'm at the punchline in Atlanta,
I'm there in June.
Why do I put my dates up?
You know, you know why?
Because 90% of you actually read the
calendar and this fucking guy is not going
to listen to this podcast.
And he's going to email me again
this week and you know what?
I'm actually going to send them
an email because I'm a whore.
It'll tell me exact dates and put a link
on it. So I'm just going to shut up. Um,
anyways. Um, all your
shit is lit up, man. So,
um, anyway, overrated, underrated,
overrated. Having kids.
Marriage is bad enough,
but for the life of me,
I can't understand why the fuck
anyone would ever want to have kids.
Your life effectively
ends when you have kids.
Everything you do has to be for them.
How fucking pathetic is your life that
you have, um, that you decide, you know,
what would be fun?
Never having any fun anymore.
I can't wait to clean shit out of some
douchebag. Infants, Asshole, Jesus Christ.
Only get four hours of sleep at night.
If I'm lucky and never have any
fucking fun with my friends ever again.
I mean Jesus fucking Christ.
Are you kidding me? Um,
underrated.
This is the same guy maker's mark whiskey.
Let me guess what you talk about after
you've had a couple of belts from that.
Anyways, he says, this shit is all I
drink and it's fucking spectacular.
Under 40 bucks a handle, 80 proof
and smoother than James fucking bond.
Uh, this guy's great. This guy is
like the guy's guy and he's the guy.
You know what I love about this dude?
This is the kind of guy when you're in a
bar and you know you're fucking up your
life, which is why you go to
the bar and you start drinking,
and this is the guy who's going to tell
you when you should face that everything
you're doing is exactly right. He's the
guy who comes up. What's the matter man?
I don't know man.
I blew with this chick and he's the
guy that you blue with this chick.
What the fuck is,
well,
you don't want to be with some
fucking Broadway you out of your funk.
And he just builds you up and then
you get him. Or did you get a Dui?
And then they take your shoe laces and
then you curl up on that burlap sack they
use for a blanket and you wait for
your dad to come down and pick you up.
You know? But in that moment,
before all that shit happens,
it's, this guy's the shit. Um, do you know
what it is? I think as you get older yet,
like me,
I,
I'm starting to really feel like I
want to have a kid now because it gets
pathetic after awhile, you know? I
Dunno. I Dunno if it's, it's the,
the magnetic pull of the herd,
you know what I mean?
Everything has like a gravity
to it and I think they,
as much as you tried to fucking
escape the orbit of the fucking heard,
you get pulled back into
it. And, uh, I dunno.
Sometimes I feel like I'm
having too much fun. Like,
as a 40 year old guy and
I'm sitting there, you know,
learning how to play good times,
bad times,
and I got the NHL package
and when I'm not watching TV,
I'm learning how to play ACDC songs.
So when I'm not doing that,
I'm fucking telling jokes on stage.
It just gets to the point you like
going like you start feeling guilty,
you know, I ain't guilty, but you just
started looking like, you know what,
I need to fucking teach someone
else how to do their life like this.
You know, I got to admit I am a
miserable motherfucker, but I am having,
I'm having a great time and you can have
it too if you learn how to talk about
your Dick on stage. All
right, last thing, Bill,
you started talking about the police last
week and it got me thinking about them.
Uh, the band, the police, all this.
When I was talking about all the, uh,
all the music that I missed
out on the police will,
one of the few that I listened to. Um,
anyways, you started talking about them.
And so it pulled me out,
made me pull out some of my old records
and I started listening to them. Um,
and his underrated for the week.
As he said,
sting is a very underrated bass player.
Most of the baselines
he plays are amazing.
I know most people think of him for his
solo work and all the crappy new age
stuff he does, but when he
was with the police, um,
he could rock a base like no other.
Uh, yeah, I've gotta admit. Yeah,
he's fucking, um, I would definitely,
I don't know if he is underrated
now with musicians. He isn't,
but I think with people he's underrated
because a lot of people feel that, yeah,
a lot of his solo stuff is cheesy.
And meanwhile he's playing with
some of the bet like Vinny,
Kali Uda in all these fucking guys.
And then I make God at songs like really
laying that that field is a gold song,
whichever it was like people think is
like, elevator music has him on base.
And I think Vinny call Udas
actually playing on drums. Um,
all right. I'm a music nerd. All
right. And, uh, and that's it.
It's kind of clock out
here and I have to go, uh,
I got to go do some touristy
shit. So, uh, you guys,
I really want to thank you for
continuing to write in the questions,
the underrated overrated. You
guys. You know, it's funny,
you guys are getting so good at
this shit that, uh, the podcast,
I think it becoming better.
I'm actually reading out loud and much
better way you guys actually using
punctuation and I,
you telling me some great stories.
I'm loving the stories about revenge.
Um,
and if you just want to comment on revenge
in general, cause, um, I, you know,
I dunno. Revenge really.
Uh, that's a line that I, I,
I've never, I just don't care.
I just don't cross that. I just,
I feel like that is the deepest,
darkest part of your soul that
you can go into. You know,
you're fucking, uh, you know what you
like. You like Jimmy Smits on Dexter.
Do you guys watch desks,
Dexter this season?
I'm gonna recommend a couple of
shows Dexter I liked, but, uh,
you gotta watch brotherhood,
showtime on demand.
You have to watch that fucking show.
And uh,
it's just an unbelievable show
and is actually, there's a,
there's a couple of guys first
season and Co Comedian Tony v that I,
that I learned so much from. And another
guy, I actually started out with,
uh,
Kevin Chapman who plays Freddy Cork,
who's one of my favorite characters
on that, on television right now.
Um, I don't know if you just did to
Gangsta fucking shows. It's the shit.
It's a great fucking show brotherhood.
Um,
I'm sure you can rent the first DVD some
even if you, even if you buy it, no,
don't buy it because maybe you don't
like it, then you're stuck with it.
Then I get to listen to you
to be a contact, but fucking,
uh, go rented somewhere.
I'm telling you it's a great show
and I'm also into breaking bad.
Those are my three shows. Other
than that, I just watch sports and,
uh, and that is it. All right.
This really tapered off in the end.
I hope you guys enjoyed it. You
guys have a great week and, uh,
keep everything calm and,
and I'll keep doing the podcast.
I'll talk to you next week. Please come
out and see me, uh, this Monday night,
this coming up Monday the 16th at
the punchline in San Francisco,
or I'll come and see me in Saint Louis
at the house of comedy in East Saint
Louis. All right. I got
a brand new hour and a,
I got a new chunk of Shit I'm working
on. All right. That's it. Take it easy.