Hey, what's going on? It's bill burn.
It's time for the Monday
morning podcast from Monday,
August 20th, 2018. Sorry, what's going on?
How are you?
How was your weekend?
Did you or did you not enjoy yourself
digital or did you dot abuse substances
that were a illegal and,
and uh, possibly. Dot. Um,
I was actually out in Las Vegas,
hot as Fuck Las Vegas.
Let's make it fun.
And everybody talking about how can
you believe how hard it is out here?
It's like, yeah, man, we're
in a fucking desert in August.
I can completely understand why
it is so fucking hot out here.
Um, and then you get the global
warming thing going on, you know,
with half, half the half the world's
on fire according to the news.
Um, yeah, I can, I can see why it'd
be a little small to read their, um,
you know,
it's so fucked up about Las Vegas is
I was thinking when I was out there,
it's like there's,
there's only one reason and one reason
only that that place exists and that is
air conditioning.
Okay.
I know back in the day, you
know, when they had like
three or four little fucking,
I dunno, one floor casinos
in the middle of nowhere.
Whatever the hell was going on out
there. I did. I forget the whole story.
All right. I've watched all the
goddamn movies. I saw casino,
I saw fucking Bugsy goes
to fucking pebble beach,
whatever the fuck it was called.
I watched that one.
Yeah.
I don't remember what the fuck. I'm
sure there was some fans, you know,
overhead fans. Is that all they had back
in the day? But I can tell you right now,
nobody fucking went out there in August.
Well, maybe they did. I don't know.
But I'm just anyways,
cause it different breed of people.
That was the greatest generation
back then. Okay. They, they, they,
they defeated Adolf Hitler,
defeated Japan.
You know, they date, they beat their
wives and then nothing was said about it.
You know, they will all those women back
there, Rosie the riveter. What happened?
I was a rebut.
I walked into a fucking door.
I, the meatloaf was called, you know,
was the greatest,
the greatest generation.
Um, anyways, I was just looking around,
just looking at the whole fucking thing.
It was like if there's no AC,
this fucking place is done.
All right. They, for whatever
reason they had in Nevada.
Is that the governor who's
the president of Nevada?
What's the highest political
position you can hold? Senator?
Yeah.
What is the Senate senators like?
An absentee father right
there fucking in Washington.
They playing grab ass with
their secretary going,
you're not going to meet to me now are ya?
Huh?
What if it's just a cigarette?
Um, so they're never around.
They come around once every
fucking six years or something.
That's when they get elected right
there and there for six fucking years.
Yeah.
Just sitting there eating just one.
Say I want you to after
another on a pretzel roll,
you know,
occasionally hitting the elliptical
lying to themselves that that 20 to 25
minutes on that elliptical just burned off
the nightmare level of eating that they
did the last fucking eight days. Right.
They just keep getting fatter.
They send their fucking secretary that
they're banging down to Brooks brothers
to buy the next size dress shirt is they
pushed their pants down a little lower
in lie to themselves that they're still
wearing the same size slacks that they
wore back in fucking high school when
they were president of the four h club or
whatever it is. Politicians do those
fucking worms. They figure it out early,
don't they?
Right.
They become head of the glee club with
the fucking student body president.
You know,
they fucking petition to have something.
I don't know what tree planted.
It's just bullshit like that. Whenever,
whenever they, whenever they write those,
those fucking autobiographies
about presidents, you know,
it was very inquisitive. Always love
that aims. I'm very inquisitive kid.
All kids are inquisitive once
they learn the word. Why?
Because they're looking at everything
is fucking brand new. What's set TV?
Why? And also we can watch a bunch
of shit. Why I cause what board?
Why I don't fight. I don't know. Why
is your mother here? All
right. That's how it goes down.
It's really weird that when you become
president for the rest of your life,
you know, you're out of power and
you still get that secret server.
I know that they're doing away with
it, I think. I think, was it George?
Debbie who was the last guy who's
getting it for the rest of his life?
It's kind of weird,
the first like half black president that
we get all of a sudden it's just like,
yeah, you know, uh, you, I did. Well,
we'll hang out with you for like
another 10 years, but you know what?
She hit your sixties.
You're wrong. You're wrong.
MMM.
Anyways, I, uh,
and then they fucking,
they'd sit there and they write books.
I cannot fucking believe that
Obama was on his third book.
He's only been out of office year and a
half. What is he fucking Stephen King.
He just cranking them out.
Did he? He wrote two of them while he
was still president running the country.
Allegedly.
That's what the president allegedly does.
He's running the fucking country and
this guy's in there. He's writing books.
Um,
anyways,
so I'm going to say it's the governor,
the governor ever just sat down.
You know, I was actually joking
on stage saying a great way,
you know, eventually they're
gonna have to thin the herd ditch.
They're just gonna have to do with this
whole fucking bullshit that we're going
to build a space ship and
we're gonna move to my,
it's like it doesn't have
a fucking atmosphere.
Okay. And am I talking about oxygen?
I'm just saying this. No five.
You want to fucking go
all the way out there,
right?
It just sit there looking
at a bunch of fucking rocks
inside your little space. They, how much
others? Scifi channel are you watching?
How many times did you rub one out
to that chick on Star Trek? I mean,
I don't,
I don't even know what the fuck you
doing that you would even even want to do
that anyways, at some point.
Even these blueblood guys,
I think eventually why think what
they're working towards right now?
I apologize because I am
completely fucking wiped out.
This is why this podcast is so
fucking nuts right now. Okay.
I flew myself out,
my instructor out to Fucking Vegas,
uh, yesterday and then today we
flew over to Utah and went through,
I think it's Zion National Park
and then flew back.
I flew a helicopter day
for 6.4 fucking hours,
whatever the fuck you call it. Um, and
those things are not built for comfort.
All right. Anyways, that's why
I'm all over the fucking map here.
I'll talk about that shit later.
Anyways, plowing ahead here.
Um,
the fuck was I talking about? Oh God.
Nine let you leave to go. Oh, this one.
I think these fucking rich
guys are going to do all right.
I think their solution is,
is
they either don't give a fuck
about how out of control
the population is right now.
You know what I mean?
Where any scientists
who's not on the payroll of some fucking
corporation that produces energy will
tell you that 2 billion people is the
maximum amount of people evidently that
the earth can handle.
All right?
Without it, I'll go into fucking hell.
And we're up to, we're over seven.
All right, we're red line in it.
We're in the left lane on the highway.
We're still in first gear and
the engines at fucking 8,000 rpm.
So that's what the fuck we're
doing day in and day out.
We're like a fat guy walking
up a flight of stairs,
eating a cupcake while
smoking a pack of cigarettes.
That's what the fuck we're doing.
Okay.
So I think the reason why
they're investing so much
in robotics aside from then,
they won't have to hire people.
This thing won't.
There'll be no back sass
and from this fucking robot,
they won't want a union.
They won't give a shit.
Right.
They're basically gonna replace
us and rather than killing us,
I think they'll just fucking shut off.
The AC is as the world heats up and then
that's going to be yet it's going to be
it for a lot of people.
You know what I mean?
I want, do you think the Kardashians would
last without fucking air conditioning?
How soft
and cushy,
you know,
let's say they happen to work for what
they have, but I'm just saying, you know,
when you, when you get designer
bag sent to your fucking house,
I would think if they took away
your air conditioning at that point,
that would literally, you would go into
depression. Like you lost the limp,
right?
So anyways, but don't worry. Okay. When
they shut off the AC and you die, a slow,
miserable death and the heated future,
the upside is, is that the rich
guys, they're going to die too.
Because what they're gonna do is they're
going to make these robots have such
human fucking qualities that eventually
they're going to feel slighted that
they're doing all the fucking work,
you know,
and the weight. Then they're making them
so fucking good. I saw this whole thing.
They go like, yeah, hey, this robot
beat a video games like beat
the best gamers in the world.
They couldn't beat this robot.
It's like, it's a fucking robot.
You know?
Of course it didn't.
But you understand that we made the robot.
Human beings figured out
how to make a fucking robot.
Why are you talking about the robot?
Like it's a fucking person.
It's not a person.
Did you hear that?
A a fucking a guy with an egg beater.
The fastest guy in the world with the
fucking fork in a bowl of eggs. Can you,
can you believe that? Yeah. The machine.
So anyways,
they're already starting to talk about
these things as if they're fucking
superior
to a mouth.
Breathing more on like myself.
Who Right now is sitting
in air conditioning talking
to himself into a fucking
microphone.
All right?
This is going to be their downfall because
they're going to make those things so
God damn human,
they're going to feel fucking slighted.
All right?
They better build into chip where they
feel unbelievably fucking grateful
that these sociopaths who own them,
poof,
who fuck them, they can have
sex with them and shit, right?
They better put in.
They didn't Beldam they,
they told some fucking nerve to do
it and the fucking nerd day, right?
Everybody thinking nerds is
so goddamn harmless. They say,
make one fucking goddamn dream after
another come true for absolute fucking
sociopath's with unchecked power.
Thanks a lot.
You fucking four.
I'd fucking cunt.
You know,
so you could do what by doctor
who on fucking laser disk
anyways, these fucking thanks.
They're there. Eventually.
That's what's going to happen.
They're going to feel fucking slighted.
They're going to feel
superior. And uh, you know,
cause I'll keep making it better and
better and better right now. They try to,
you know, make everything a little faster,
a little fucking bored. Our dynamic,
they're gonna make the things work a
little better. Thank a little better.
Fuck a little better at the whole thing.
And then eventually they just
gonna look at you like that.
Bear looked at that woman on the talk
show who snuck in beside him and they're
going to do the double take and
then that's just going to be yet,
and there's going to be no trainer there
in a fucking karate suit to pull the
fucking thing off you.
It's going to be yet.
MMM.
Those are the thoughts you have when you
fly a helicopter over the Mojave desert
and then on and know where you come up
over the fucking hill and [inaudible].
There it is. This, this fucking
thing that shouldn't be there.
Knowing that I live in a city
that it shouldn't be there.
I got to read up on the history of La,
like
who was the driven content that decided
that we should build fucking a city
here?
It doesn't make any fucking sense.
There's no water. It's unlivable.
I don't worry about it.
We'll get some,
we'll figure it out.
We'll name it after me.
The aqueduct,
the river, whatever the fuck it is.
Um, I think I have sunstroke right now.
Everybody. Um, I will
tell you, you know what?
I was psyched about
going to the gym and uh,
working on my legs for the last
month. Like I don't feel, you know,
I got out and stretched a number of times.
Dude,
it was one of the sickest
fucking flights I've ever done.
Breathtakingly beautiful,
beautiful stuff.
And then just other places where you just
like, how the fuck did people on horses
used to survive here?
Native Americans,
the white men that came along and
slaughtered them, you know, come on.
We got him at this time.
Right? Just openly talk about
the transitioning
gentrification of countries,
how that happens. Um,
you know, follow this,
this, this fucking thing
on Instagram where they're
talking about the changing of
neighborhoods and there's all these people
going, you know, when I was lived here,
it was a neighborhood.
There was a Korean guy across the street,
there was a Russian guy up the street
and everybody knew me and all of this
fucking blah, blah,
blah, blah, blah, blah.
And all of a sudden all these white people
are coming in the state of themselves
and they make it everything,
all nice.
We all to leave and I'll
fucking neighborhood it goes
away. And she's like, well,
you know,
well who was there before you got there?
You just keep going back
and back and back and back.
And eventually there's a bunch of native
Americans. They're living off the land,
not hurting anybody.
Yeah.
So
I dunno, I dunno. I don't know how to,
I don't know how to rationalize that.
I will tell you this.
I don't know what the fuck's going
on as far as like everywhere I go,
they got like they're building these
luxury high rise apartments everywhere I
go. Luxury high rise of
plant with, first of all,
what kind of a dumb fuck
would rent a luxury apartment?
Why wouldn't you just buy a shitty house?
Why are you going to take all that money
and put it in somebody else's pocket?
Not to mention who has the money
to rent a luxury apartment.
He need a fucking apartment.
All right.
Is this all goes back to all of these
fucking who is on TV walking around with
their big fake ass lips.
They've fake fucking tits acids
jacked up in the air, right?
These big stupid designer. Everybody's
living this designer fucking life.
All right, let me, I do, I, I, I realize
how crazy I sound right now. By the way,
everybody,
I'm just going to talk until 60 minutes
is up and then I'm fucking going to put
my giant Charlie Brown
sunstroke fucking head to bed.
All right.
I know a lot of you can see right now
you're enjoying this because I'm sounded
like I've walked myself off in this
authorities outside my house right now.
I understand that. I understand
on some level how crazy I sound.
It took me about 17 minutes
to fucking realize it,
that this was a little fucking nuts.
And then amazing being a comedian. How
you can feel time. I just looked down.
It was eight minutes,
18 minutes and 19 seconds.
Okay.
Um, anyways, after a while you can
feel the club owners staring at you.
Like if he burns his fucking life,
I'm going to end his career and he's
going back to his fucking day job.
Do you can feel it?
Um,
yeah,
like I think that they're just going to
build all of these fucking things and
there's not going to be enough people that
can afford to live in them. The whole,
fuck that thing's going to crash. And
this is what I love. It's all our money.
These banker costs are doing it again.
They did 10 years ago,
a collapsed with the fucking houses and
now they're doing it with these goddamn
buildings. And once again,
it's our money at once again.
They'll say we're too big to fail.
And once again they'll write themselves
bonuses and they will just leave
nameless and faceless.
And then Steve Carell is going to
have to start another fucking movie
called, what's the deal with
bankers part too, right.
And do you think that fat ass
fucking Senator Reed that say,
what should that fucking pretzel roll
pushing his slacks down to just above his
pubic line is going to fucking do
anything about it. I don't think he is.
There you go buddy.
There's a fucking 19 minute fucking swirl.
A Horse Shit for you.
MMM.
I had one of the best shows of my career.
I'm not going to lie to you last night.
I had so much goddamn fun.
MMM.
That what used to be, I got to get this,
I got to get the name of this casino,
correct.
All right.
It used to be the mining Carla
and then the MGM bought it.
Uh, let's see. Casino now it's
called the MGM something or other,
uh,
fuck you.
Fuck you. Where the hell is it? I
am not going to be able to find it.
Bonkers casino. I'm an idiot.
I got to write Las Vegas. Ah,
okay. All right. Hang on a second.
Las Vegas,
fucking Nevada.
The park MGM is what it's called now.
Monte Carlos now called
the park MGM and a,
I performed there with Joe Barnick
Rosebowl tailgate legend Joe Barr.
Nick. We had a great time
and it was all these awesome,
amazing comics were in town.
Uh, Todd rex, the beige band.
Ditto is, he calls me, he calls himself.
We still gotta do that toward some point.
The Beige Bandido when the
freckled Fucko right. Again,
we had the whole tour poster.
We had the whole thing mapped out.
Just haven't gotten around to it yet.
Anyways,
one of the hardest people I've ever
had to follow in the business, uh,
he swung by, uh, Ron White was in town.
Dice clay was in town.
Um,
yeah, it was pretty fucking awesome.
So anyways, I went there with my laugh.
My mother in law came along and um,
for the first time we, uh,
we actually had our, uh,
daughter's staying with the God mother.
That was a little nerve
wracking. But um, you know,
we were only gone for a day and uh,
came back,
I basically didn't see her
for maybe like 30 hours.
And uh, it was awesome. It was
all great to see her, you know,
dropped her off and I read her like
frigging like nine books. That's my thing.
You know,
it's funny like this is how much,
like technology's just
all over everything.
Like she was grabbing all these
books and I go, let's, let's, let's,
let's read a quiet book.
And it just struck me as so funny cause
like all of the other ones have like
sound effects and you know,
the farmer,
he looked over and he saw a, and
you press the button, it's like
you gotta go roaster.
And then he saw his mirror. It's just
like, can't, I can't fucking do that.
I Dunno. Maybe you know what
it is. These book people,
I think they fill in
the pressure of IPADS,
not the office.
Probably the people that make books,
they're like, we're doing what we
can. We're putting books on kindle,
but we're losing the children.
Okay.
Is there a way that when they read,
I dunno,
Moby Dick,
is there a way it can there be like they
turned the page and water squirts at
them? Like everything is going to
turn into like a fucking imax movie.
Uh, I really try to limit the amount
of time. Uh, my kid watches TV,
but she loves the puppy dog
pals. And every time, you know,
she knows like her scheduled,
like we let her watch it in the morning,
she wants his puppy dog pals may
be a little bit of Disney shit,
Mickey and Minnie Mouse,
uh, in Vampyr arena. Right.
And then this is fancy Nancy thing.
I don't know how I feel about that show.
You know,
she's just really into,
into fucking clothes and shoes and shit.
And she's always trying to be
the cool kid, but she's not.
And then she thinks if she fucking buys
some shared or has some shit made or she
has the best fucking tree
for it, uh, it's just like,
what the fuck am I watching? So I
finally said to me, I got in the A and I,
and I don't know if I like
this check and you know,
this is why I love my wife.
She's like, yeah, you know,
I don't know if I like her.
I don't know if I like to read it.
You know,
she already said about another like
show. She goes, I don't like this show.
And I was like, well, what's wrong
with it? You don't like the, you know,
like the characters? She goes, no, they
always kind of lie and do shifty shit
to get what they want.
And I was like, wow,
she's watching this on a whole other
level. She's watching it as a parent.
Okay.
So I started watching him
like that. Oh, shut up bill.
You Watch fancy Nancy.
What you saw was an eight year old who
in the in the future looks like she's
going to marry a guy because of how much
money he makes. That's what you saw.
Okay?
It has to do with your issues with women.
That's why you don't like the show.
All right?
See that I don't need to go to therapy.
I can get down on my own
fucking issues myself.
So anyways, I went on this helicopter
ride today up to the Zion National Park
and the shit that I saw,
I saw this thing called the Monkey Mesa
and it's a set of railroad tracks
that goes, that has to go for like it,
it looks like for like
three quarters of a mile.
We flew right over the fucking
thing and when it gets,
and it goes right to the edge
of a cliff and just stops.
Back in the day when NASA was testing
our parachutes and shit like that,
they'd put a fucking monkey on the thing.
They'd send it down the track and they'd
shoot this poor fucking monkey off the
goddamn cliff
if it lived the next day.
You know, like chuck Yeager was
like, did the monkey live? All right,
I'll fucking give it a shot. Let's have
balls those guys had. But you know,
what about the monkey?
Is it any wonder that you know,
some day they're going to learn how
to talk and try to take us over.
I may go with what the
fuck we fucking deserve it.
Probably don't even give it a flight
suit or a cool nickname like maverick.
They just fucking throw it in there.
Give it half a banana.
Yeah.
Think about how fast a
monkey moves on its own.
Now all of a sudden it's getting launched.
Fuck it.
Then goes to space.
You know they can do that shit now.
They look at these ex football players
and they look at like the damage they've
done to the brains, to
CTE. I want to take and,
and I know that they can look at
your brain and see what stress does.
I can't imagine when a monkey
comes back from fucking space,
you know that fuck it thing has got
to be just stuck around like, dude,
what the fuck?
What the fuck was that?
You just fucked that monkey
over for the rest of it's,
they can't relate to anybody. You
think you know the astronauts, they,
they had enough of a fucking problem.
We're, after they went out there,
the only other people they could
talk to his other astronauts
of what they saw, where they went, what
the fuck they did, how scared they were,
how exhilarating it was, how much more
they believed in a fucking higher power,
that level of experience.
And then they come back and they try to
hang out with other human beings who are
all excited.
Go Age.
You see the new Starbucks sip building
and that's going to be a really nice one.
You know? And then you,
as you're sitting there,
you orbited the fucking earth
and you've got to try to how to,
how to enter the orbit of
that fucking conversation
without your brain kitchen on
fire, man. It's fucking unreal.
You know, I, if you're
sitting there going,
what the fuck is this guy talking about?
I don't even know what I'm talking about
either. Right? So go fuck yourself.
Anyways, so we went and flew
into a Zion national park.
We actually set it down, uh,
before we got into the park. Uh,
we will try and find a
place to fucking land.
I wanted to stretch my legs and that's
one of the great things about flying a
helicopter is you really fly as far
as how close she can fly to shit.
If you just want to set down
somewhere, you know, we will.
It's so fucking hot.
We were actually looking at this lake and
you want to sit down and just fucking,
I was like, dude, if I had, if
I had packed a bathing suit,
I would fucking jump in that thing right
now in the middle of fucking nowhere.
And then he can, you know, I, but I,
I actually wouldn't do it because I'd
be too afraid of bear would come out of
nowhere. Fucking mountain
lion or some shit, you know.
But uh, we flew over Lake Mead, who you
always heard blink back in the day. The,
um, all the gangsters, you know,
that all the people that the mob would
whack that they'd dump them out there.
So read up a little bit on that.
I don't know.
It's basically the water that got
backed up when they made the Hoover dam,
which I was not aware of
because I was thinking like how the
fuck does this lake exist out here?
Oh that's right. Once again,
we fucked with nature and uh,
you know, as I sit there flying a
helicopter over blasting unleaded,
I leaded fuel into the atmosphere
becoming part of the problem.
I'm not pointing any fingers people.
Okay. I'm, I'm as big a problem.
Is anybody else?
Right.
So that lake is like on either side of
this mountain and in the middle there's
like a little valley that this water
goes through and we fucking went down and
flew right up the thing.
Okay.
Like some magnum Pi Shit over
people on jet skis and boats.
It was incredible. It's fucking
incredible. And the coolest things I ever,
I've done since I've
been in the helicopter.
And then we flew up to Zion
National Park and just saw like,
you remember those things,
they'd sell you if you are
tourists during the summertime.
If you're in summertime, Campbell,
they'd have all the different colors,
sand and stuff.
They put it in a bottle than your older
brother would come up and shake it up
and he'd start crying and be like,
mommy shook it up.
But she was working two t two jobs that
she was too tired to do anything about.
It said work it out amongst yourselves.
Um,
yeah, like these, these
cliffs looked like that.
Just these crazy,
unbelievable colors.
Unfortunately there was a fire so there
was a lot of smoke and shit, like, uh,
just a lot of haze and stuff.
So it wasn't as vivid,
but still it was one of the most
incredible things I've seen. Um,
but it was hot as shit,
man. I out on these,
these Adidas that were all black and
my feet, I had to keep, you know,
like once every like 40 minutes,
you know,
I had to give controls back
to my instructor so I could
like move my feet to a
shaded area underneath the GPS system
where I could have my fucking feet cool
off. I guess that's why, you know,
over in the Persian Gulf army boots
aren't black anymore cause it's your feet
get too hot. That's why they're this sort
of the color of Pete Carroll's pants.
Isn't that interesting?
All right.
You know what's even more interesting
than any of that bullshit I was just
talking is,
um,
is listening to me read out loud,
which you're now you're going to
have to suffer through. All right.
Everybody hotel
two, two, nine, two, nine. Oh
hotel tonight is to go to app for
booking great deals at great hotels.
Yeah. Fucked up. Is that song
okay?
Right.
Is it called tonight
and how much could Phil Collins not miss?
Did he just pick d just says that
word over note tonight, tonight,
10 anything.
Grapefruit, grapefruit, grapefruit.
No. Fucking stadium's going nuts. Anyways,
unlike other hotel booking sites,
hotel tonight doesn't have long,
endless list of a zillion hotel choices.
They know you don't have
time for that stead.
Hotel two shows you only the
best deals at the best hotels.
They partner with top rated hotels
to help them fill their unsold rooms,
which is how you get such great deals.
And even though the name is hotel tonight,
it's not just for tonight.
You can book tonight,
tomorrow or beyond.
It's perfect for planners
as well as procrastinators.
You can book spontaneous weekends, three
day getaway staycation, road trips,
business trips. You can book a
hotel just so you can use the pool.
Download the hotel to app today to get
great deals at hotels you actually want
to stay at.
And with Promo Code Burr,
you can get $25 off your
first first element,
eligible booking. Look at debt.
You book yourself in a motel.
You could probably stay there for seven
bucks and have money for a low rent
hooker hotel tonight.
Promo Code Burke, B, u.
R. R. A. Look who's back.
Dollar Shave Club.
Yeah,
yeah.
No matter what you do in
the bathroom to get ready,
Jolly Shave club has everything you need
to look and feel and smell your best.
They have amazing shower stuff.
Hey is styling products,
toothbrushes, and toothpaste and of
course raises and shave supplies.
I'm literally fucking light headed.
I need to drink some water.
I was out in the elements all day to day.
You might have,
you might shave your whole body
to get ready for a bike race doll.
You might have Shavia, but your whole
body, your ready for a bike race,
dollar shave club's executive
razor and shave can help you,
might do your hair to get
ready for your soccer match.
Bogies by DSC can help you
get your style right. Oh God,
those days are long gone for the fucking
freckled Kiddo here. The thing is,
no matter what you do to get ready,
d as c has everything you need
and right now I'm so stupid.
I thought DSC was like,
you know some outsource thing.
Yeah.
You know like like an AMG Mercedes.
They sent it to the AMG factory and right
now you can get ready with an amazing
deal on any of their,
their starters sets like the
daily essential starters that,
but you can't go wrong with any of them.
Head over to dollar shave club,
dotcom slash.
Bird and pick up your own dollar shave
club started set for just $5 after your
start a set product.
Products ship at the regular price and
make sure you check out their new video.
Two that's dollar shave
club.com/burr jolly shave club.com/.
Burpee you are are. I'm not kidding,
man. I'm fucking late at it.
Um, maybe that's from screaming tonight.
58 times bill. You ever think about that?
We'll do you all right.
Oh,
the black Tux like the
Ohio State University,
the Black Tux wedding season is upon us.
You're going to be doing it big and
going out to all your buddies weddings.
That's right. You're not going to yours.
Good move. When you're bringing a date,
you want to look fresh,
but it has to be convenient.
That's where the black
Tux dotcom comes in.
The Black Tux has awesome
suits and Tuxedos and all
kinds of styles and you rent
them on line.
Then you put them on your body,
you go to the wedding,
you pick up a chick,
you banger wearing most of the Tuxedo,
then you bring it back for
getting it ever happened.
The black Tux offers the kind of suits
and Tuxedos styles that would normally be
wildly expensive to buy and you might
only wear it once with the Black Tux.
You can do you and blow it out
for your big onetime event.
So try out a new look,
do something different and try
your style to the next level.
With the Black Tux free home,
try on and I'll try on.
You can see the fit and feel the quality
of your suit months before your event.
After ordering your suit,
after ordering your suit will arrive 14
days before the event that anything is
less than perfect.
Get out of the relationship now.
Now the black Tux will send
you a replacement right
away and remember how simple
returns are where it turned heads. Then
send it back three days after your event.
Shipping is free. Both ways.
To get $20 off your purchase.
Visit the black tux.com/bar.
That's the black tux.com/burr
for $20 off your purchase.
What do we got left? We've got two reads
left to right. Let's give you a break.
You deserve it after listening to
my fucking end two rambling there.
I was going Alex Jones on
your wasn't I? Alright. Okay.
Jane Fonda Myth.
Uh,
I knew everybody's with a dead Guy
Day. Never eat. Ever got fucking,
he'd ever got fucking
tortured. All right. Uh,
just to note, I love your work. Really
pleased you exist on the planet.
I'm no historian,
but some comments that Tom Rhodes made
on your recent podcast about Jane Fonda.
Didn't sound realistic to me, so I
looked it up. Turns out they were not.
Maybe you can correct Tom, so he doesn't
continue to perpetuate this myth. Listen,
I've known Tom too long
to try to correct them.
I'm sure Jane Fonda had her faults,
but my guests is,
she tried her best to be a good,
a good person and to fight for
peace on our planet. Who wrote this?
Jane Fonda might be,
she is as heroic in her own
way is some as those on the AH,
Jesus fucking Christ Jesus
Christ on the battlefield.
Oh yeah. A starlet going
to the enemy, you know,
as opposed to some guy who's fucking poor.
So he has to go to the front
fucking lines. Yeah, yeah.
Maybe. Maybe they're both,
oh yes. Heroic. Yeah, I can see that.
You know what I mean?
Like me doing this podcast.
I think in a lot of ways I'm
sort of like a navy seal,
you know?
Um, sir, I understand what
you're saying. I am the,
I am a pacifist too.
I really do not.
I don't understand why war is legal.
Okay.
And I just think it's the temper Tantrum
of rich people is all a war is okay.
I'm not saying this not
crazy psycho fucking people,
they get in power and need to be
stopped. That there's also that. Okay.
But a lot of times it's just the fucking
land grab or you're going after some
sort of natural resource.
Okay.
And I want to tell you all right,
but having said that,
all right. You know, once
the troops are on the ground,
if you want to fucking bitch about
it, go to your politician. All right?
Go file for a permit to protest 90 miles
away from where any media coverages.
That's the way it's done.
Okay?
What you don't do is go to Saddam
Hussein's house and have the guy cookie a
fucking meal. You know, while all this
server, it's equivalent and you go, hey,
you know he's not even that bad of a
fucking guy, you know? Or maybe you do,
but at no point do you feel as fucking
heroic is some poor fucking bastard.
All right. Trying to Piss a top
of a fucking Scorpio blown off.
Yeah.
I think once you're wearing leg warmers,
the though I don't think you're a hero
anymore. Alright. Met a girlfriend on 10
dear Billy balloon tits.
I'll have you guys fucking know I'm in
the best Goddamn fucking shape I've been
in and I sense, I don't
know how long. All right,
I'm getting my abs back.
Okay.
I'm getting a little sick of the body
shaming here on the Monday morning
podcasts. I go out of my way
to not research on Jane Fonda.
I would think that you guys would do a
little more research on what I'm looking
like lately. All right. The last
three weeks. Okay. Listen to your pod,
your last podcast and heard all the leg
trashing dating sites and
Tinder. Well, I may be a dude,
but I wanted to offer
my take on the matter.
I have never gotten so much fucking
pussy in my life. I'm kidding.
He didn't say all right.
Since it's not all serial killers
and fuckboy Weirdos on this sites,
on these sites, fuckboy Weirdos
is, I don't know if this is,
that's gotta be the name of like a
punk band or something. First off,
let's make one thing clear.
There are shitty women on these sites
too. Oh, thank you. God bless you.
Gotta love somebody that
tries to balance it out here.
I know guys get and probably
deserve most of the heat, but girls,
cat fish guys all the
time and these sites,
plus there are the girls on these sites
who only want attention slash money and
have no intention of actually going
out and meeting New People. Second,
I met my girlfriend of almost a year
on Tinder and we couldn't be happier.
We were initially to admit to our
friends and family that we met this way.
But afterwards I had several people
talk about how they had success,
relationships blossom from these sites.
My cousin met her husband and father
of her child on Christian mingle.com no
joke, Jesus Christ. You know,
you'd think that Christians could
come up with a better fucking name,
Christian mingle.
It sounds too much like dingle and you
just picture a priest playing with some
fucking poor kids balls. Um, I dunno.
Belt it was,
it was just Catholic church.
It wasn't all the other Christianity
was it by a year. You probably right.
Anyways.
And I learned that my two friends met
on bumble after we told them we met on
Tinder. Yeah, well that's
all. Every, everybody's on
their fucking phones anyways.
You go to a nightclub and people
are on their phones. All right?
You want to meet or you
gotta get in the phone.
You can't be standing there
being an actual person.
I think it freaks these
millennials though. Third,
Tinder is a great way to cut through all
the bullshit of blind dating or hitting
on chicks who you have nothing in
common with at meat market bars.
Dating sites are also great if you're
single in a new city without many friends
to go out with.
Like I was in conclusion piece should,
people should stop all the hate on dating
sites just because their relationship
failed or because they never tried it.
Love you and your comedy bill.
Come back to Philly and go fuck
yourself. All right. Thank you, sir. Ah,
well there you go. I mean, I think we
shit on these fucking sites enough.
It was nice to hear, you know, that was
a, and then a little bit counterpoint.
All right. Isis, uh, bicycling.
Hey, uh, pay Billy White tits.
All right, I'll take that.
Um, have you heard of this story? Of
the couple that went bicycling and Tez?
Gica Stan,
they tried to prove that
people are actually good at
heart and ended up getting
stabbed to death. What the fuck?
You haven't heard of it yet?
I'll attach an article for you
if you want to try to read it.
Uh, thanks for all the laughs during the
podcast and go fuck yourself. All right.
I don't understand why,
you know, oh my God.
Is this real?
It's on people.
people.com.
It looks like the People magazine Logo,
but God knows the Internet.
You could just cure rate
that and use it for yourself.
American couple who spent life savings
to bike around the world killed in ice in
Isis claimed attack.
Yeah.
Oh,
I'm not going to see these.
Poor people's names were living out
their dream of traveling the world.
Bicycling tragically,
while out doing what they
loved with five other cyclists.
Their quests was cut short when they will
run over and stabbed to death by armed
men in tech.
Tez Gica Stan on Sunday.
Uh,
uh,
let's see here.
The woman's parents confirmed in a
statement to CBS news that the couple who
were both 29 were killed in the attack.
Isis claimed responsibility
for the attack to other tours.
Dutch and switched national were
killed while three writers survived NPR
reports.
MMM.
These two people started their journey
in 2017 they first biked through Africa,
Europe, and Central Asia before
finding themselves and test chicken.
Stan using all of their life
savings to fund their trip.
The couple also documented their
travels on the blog. Simple.
Simply cycling the year long bicycling
adventure with the woman and her partner.
Yeah.
Uh, we're in June. They were enjoying was
typical of their enthusiasm, blah, blah,
blah, blah. Okay,
well where does it say that
they thought the world was nice?
MMM,
I don't get this. Any.
All Great. Here's a quote.
You watched the news and you read the
papers and you led to believe that the
world is a big scary place. Uh, people,
the narrative goes are not to
be trusted people or bad people,
evil people or ax murderers and monsters.
In worse, he wrote, badness exists.
Sure. But even that's quite
rare. By and large, humans
are kind, this is still true.
How many people did they bicycle past
before one continent car ended their
fucking life lives a self interest
interested sometimes myopic sometimes,
but kind,
generous and wonderful and kind.
No greater revelation has come from our
journey than this. Yeah, that's true.
That is true. And they got
killed because, uh, you know,
basically of our foreign fucking policy,
you know,
there's a lot of people out there that
don't like fuck at Americans and there's
a lot of evil fucking
twisted people out there.
What those people were that killed those
other people who the fuck knows, um,
you know, yeah. This, you know,
this is how you wish the world was in
the way it really is and you have to act
accordingly.
All right.
And you have to know when you're
doing something like that,
that there is that chance that
that could fucking happen.
MMM.
Yeah. This, you know. Yeah. Most people.
I've always said that just walk around
and try and get a sandwich to try to find
love, you know, and we sit down and
you watch TV, you watch the news,
you get all fucking hysterical at uh,
but make no mistake.
The rest of the really fucked
up people out there at, uh,
some of them are in this country and some
of them are not, but they're out there.
Um, too bad. Um,
sounded like they almost
made it around the world
or at least that side of the
world, right? I Dunno. All right.
Boyfriend is fucking up big time.
Okay.
Hey Bill,
lady listening here.
I love when the ladies right in
desperate for some relationship helps.
So I'm getting straight to the point.
My boyfriend is about to lose me and
I'm desperate to get through them.
We are 30 bend together two years.
Both want to eventually marry each other.
They had babies together, et cetera.
The issue we need to help with his,
his ex-girlfriend they
dated for three years,
broke up then remained extremely
close friends. Yeah. That,
that's fucking bullshit. They had been
broken up for a little over a year.
When I initially came into the picture,
my boyfriend told me about her,
but originally told me they were friends
and completely failed to mention that
they were once a couple. All right. Okay,
and you were 28 at the time,
so I'll forgive you.
All right, but now you're 30 baby.
You got to read the tea leaves here.
I don't need to read the rest of this.
I actually thought I will.
I actually found out from her because
she saw us flirting on Instagram and then
messaged me.
She's a nice enough woman who now lives
with her boyfriend for the last two
years.
I've met her several times and while
I didn't particularly love the way she
looks at my man, I'm not going to
be a bitch about it either. Oh,
you are not being a bitch on any level.
What's your being is too
fucking accommodating.
She and I used to text quite
a bit quite often. Oh God.
She's probably milking
you for information,
but that has come to an abrupt stop
because I've been become fed up with how
close she and my boyfriend's still are.
Are you going to tell me at night?
You're sitting there watching TV with him
and she calls and then he talks to her
for like 2030 40 minutes.
At the beginning of our relationship
they would hang up constantly.
They lived in California and lived
in Colorado and I lived in Colorado,
so my boyfriend and I were in
a long distance relationship
for over a year until
he recently moved to Colorado
to start a life with me. Uh,
when he was still living in California,
he and his ex would go out to eat,
go shopping, go to concerts or even
go on road trips together. Now.
What are the odds that they weren't
still fucking at that point?
Yeah,
they had a shared hobby of photography,
so they would often take photos of each
other as well. Yes. This became an issue,
a huge issue. I would, I would say things
like, I get to you guys are friends,
but I feel like you are going on a date,
like things with her when you are dating
me. And he would always reply with,
I wish I could take you,
but I can't because of the distance.
So am I supposed to never go
out and do anything? Oh my God,
fuck this guy.
Any would guilt me and then manipulate
the situation until I essentially,
it had to be okay with it. Yeah. Okay.
You know, I gotta be honest with you.
This is you. This isn't him. He's a cunt.
But I mean you got to fucking come on.
Maybe the fact that I'm reading
your own words out loud right now,
you can see how obvious this is. Yeah,
yeah. Fuck this guy. Fast forward to now.
Obviously they don't hang out like they
used to do to him moving in Colorado,
but they still text all the time.
I've talked to my boyfriend about this
and how it bothers me. I say, look,
I know you and whoever, we're
very close. She's a good person.
So are you,
I know you guys have a lot of history.
I didn't know that I knew about her from
the beginning of our relationship and
he wasn't honest with you about it.
Did you ever ask them that?
How come you didn't say you fucking used
to date this person? You shift the cont.
However, what I didn't realize is
how close you two would remain.
Maybe I'm naive, naive, but I thought
that naturally as you and I grew closer,
you and so-and-so would
grow more distant and you,
you'd focus only on our relationship
bill and I'm on in my eyes.
I'm pretty cool girlfriend for knowing
that my man and his ex or close friends,
but they are pushing.