Hey, what's going on? It's Bill Burr.
It's time for the Monday
morning podcasts for Monday,
January 28th, 2019 what's
going on out? Yeah.
How's it going?
I'm doing this Sunday night cause
I'm a busy freckled viva this week.
So I actually uh, got a buddy over going
to smoke a cigar with him. I was like,
well why don't we kill two birds with
one stone and I'll just have you on the
fucking podcast. The uh,
the one and only Josh,
Adam Meyers.
Hello everybody.
How I can't do it.
My voice. I know the voice
of Holland, Hank, Dj Helen,
Hank on emphasis a family.
You can officially say that we're back.
We've got some funny shit for you this
week. Season for everybody. Season Four.
You heard me on the radio.
I have a feeling Dj Howland.
Hank will be making many, many
more appearances. I hope so.
I love that guy so much.
It's not really hard for me to play it.
You play a coke addict Dj. I mean that's,
you know, just think back into my past.
Don't worry. I thought you were, will you?
Oxy pills. What we're doing is I know,
I mean, I mean I got to do
the whole smorgasbord. Uh,
let's get that way. You from,
I'm from Germantown, Maryland, right
outside of Washington DC. Okay.
Sports affiliations. My podcast
listeners have to, here we go, uh,
all crap teams except for one of them. A
Washington Redskins, Washington Wizards,
uh, and the Stanley Cup
champion. Washington capitals.
I can't believe I get to say that. It's
like the greatest feeling in the world.
And uh, no Orioles, no national snowmen
oils in a nationals fan of cut his splits.
I mean, I will, I grew up in an Orioles
fan, but I loved brace. Harper and I,
I really just root for the whole town.
So I'm, I'm a diehard oriels fan,
but I'm also going to root for the nets.
I just want that you old enough to,
to have been a Baltimore Colt fan before
they left or no, I was, I was alive,
but I was already Redskins. I mean,
I mean they left a what, 82 84,
something like that. Uh,
something like that. 83, 84,
somewhere around. I remember,
this is what sucks is that I remember
just my foot from like from like zero to
10 it was just three Superbowls and then
at like 11 I think we got our last one,
which was in nine red one the red
skins. And then I was just like, oh,
we're probably going to be in this all
the time. And then nothing. Well that's,
that's what's going to happen
to like the Patriots and all,
all these kids who are lucky enough
to be born in the night 1990s
and remember 2001 the first
one or 2000 2001 you know,
it's going to be like,
you know, there was,
there was kids born when I
was born in 1968 and then, uh,
they got to watch Dan Marino.
I'm able,
I'm just saying as far as like
just being good and competitive.
I always compare it to Dan Marino cause
that guy was the best I ever saw man
other than Joe Montana. But even then,
I think Dan Marino with Bill Walsh,
she see definitely wins.
One.
I only remember, I only remember
bad knees Marino. That's,
that's where I was at mean bad back bad,
which is bad. Everything. When I got in,
he was already in the,
in the down trodden.
That was him.
He came in and he was with Don Shula and
Don Shula like was a man who was a man
but, but by then everybody
had caught up with them,
stolen all his fucking
tricks and he was on like,
cause he was in the final 10 years of,
of going back to like,
like the 19 like fifties I want to say.
He was on the giants at one point
and you was on offensive or defensive
coordinator and the other
guy was Tom Landry. Okay.
Those were the two guys or
something like that one though.
I always forget who the hell
it was. But anyways, um,
I just remember, you know, we,
they went from Bob Greasy to
fucking Dan Marino is his name.
They just kicked our ass for
like the first 20 years of
me watching the Patriots.
He just couldn't take it. And, and
I, I look at the dolphins fans now,
like this still waiting. I feel so
full for that. Next. Dan Marino,
my cousin is the biggest dolphins fan.
He named his dog Marino like he fucking
loves this team so much and it was like,
I remember at the beginning of the season
I was like, dude, they're looking good.
The winning some games and he's like,
they're going to fuck it up and then boom.
It's just what they finished like seven
and nine. There are seven and 19 I mean,
I can't talk to Redskins are what?
Like six and 10 I gave up,
what can I say once I know all four of
our quarterbacks, broken leg. I was like,
all right. I was like, we deserve
it. Racist team name. We can't,
you can't be four and 12
with a racist team name.
You gotta be 12 and four we can't help it.
I will say this too.
I still can't believe in all of this,
this fucking Hashtag and all this shit.
The fact that they still do
the Tomahawk chop all like,
I can't believe that in all of
that. Fuck it. It's so fucking bad.
It's so fucking bad.
And they sit there like it does.
I love when white people justify it.
Like it's literally the
people are saying don't
do where they're like,
but we're honoring the
parents because we committed genocide.
Who's kidding? Who with against those?
That would be like if the Germans one
and then at the soccer game everyone was
chanting, oh Yay or nay.
You know, it's funny,
is that,
Whoa is old school Hollywood imitating
their singing and all that thing on so
many fucking levels. It's just like,
dude, what can you just, and they just,
they fucking refuse. And
I don't know. That's why,
that's why there's this like a
backlash now on white privilege site.
There's people going out
there and uh, do what? Just,
there's white people saying that white
privilege doesn't exist, which is fuck.
And then you listen to their stories and
all their stories are as basically that
they weren't born rich, but at no point
was there, hey, I was driving down the,
and because I was
white,
I got pulled over tased and then shot
to death and then the cop got free.
I've got a cop was released. There's
none of that shit is not. Yeah. Like two,
two is like, look, there's to sit there
and act like the right privileges,
those privileges in everything.
There's all different levels to be
in white and this and this shit.
This shit that as if you're
just like a regular white guy,
shit that you see the private school
white kid doing. That pisses me off.
And there's different levels, different
levels of black people. You know,
there's the hugs for sure. Yes. I grew up,
I grew up middle class, some little note,
lower middle class and it's just like
I had that friend that just like, dude,
I had a friend who was like super rich.
His Dad worked for the FDA, right.
This kid always had money.
Their family always had money.
His Dad went into a lone star.
I remember that.
That steak house where they put like you
to give you peanuts and then you just
throw the shells on the floor. Right.
His Dad's slipped on the floor,
hurt his knee, got like $10 million.
They were already rich. Like,
that's the kind of shit that should
have happened to my dad cause he had,
she would've happened to, my
dad doesn't remember when, uh,
being in New York City one time and there
was this publicist who fucking snapped
or something out on,
on and she was out like I want to say
she was out in the Hamptons Long Island
and sh oh or something,
somewhere out there she snapped cause
something about some club or a restaurant
and she backed into like 17 fucking
people. I don't mean the lash rove away.
Oh that's horrible. Drove
the fuck away. [inaudible]
they got a license plate.
They knew who she was in.
The cops showed up and the
lawyer was in the driveway,
met the cops and said she'll turn
herself in tomorrow morning. Irish.
Remember reading that going like, what
the fuck? How is that possible? Is that,
what is that? Yeah, but so to sit there
and act like, I dunno, like I five,
it's fucking hilarious. It is
hilarious. It's, it's ridiculous. Every,
but the thing is back with the reds, the
work in a warehouse and unloaded trucks.
It's just like, I know, but there,
at no point did anybody ever look at you
and like you have white skin get out of
this neighborhood and
they just let him be.
That's the thing with the Redskins
though, is that it's, it's every,
every like six years a
senator or a congressman says,
you gotta change the name. And I
completely agree at this point I'm like,
just change him. I can't believe the
owner wouldn't do it considering,
I honestly don't notice now because it's
just been called that for so fucking
long now. But you're looking at this and
go look at the owner is first of all,
we have probably one of the worst owners
in football because he's like Jerry
Jones, just, it doesn't know
anything about football.
So he's fucking the team up causing
all these problems, you know? And,
and he wants money so bad that you would
think that he would change the name to
get all the merchandising money. Like
dude, that's like another, you know,
$100 million worth of shit.
Like that pays for a new parking lot.
And here's an argument that I been,
I been something that I've been wondering
about for a long for a while now,
and I think I kind of understand it.
Where in every sport that I
like Major League baseball,
I thought they counted world series titles
back to the 18 days, but they kind of,
the first one, that account was in 1903,
which I think was the Boston red sox.
I literally looked it up last week.
I already forget.
But like they caught the all
the way back to fucking, uh,
1903 all right.
When it was a segregated league,
all of this shit, right? Like, you know,
crazy Lake Johnson who was fucking 10,
loved him, 10 teams of whatever, right?
Stanley Cup goes about that far back.
NBA titles goes back to the 1940s.
And even the Lakers count an NBL title.
They somehow want an end and a title,
the NBL and that was counted as a fucking
NBA title was there when they were the
Minneapolis Lakers. Yeah.
They're first looking of,
they want an NBL and then they
want for NBA titles in Minneapolis.
And, uh, but they, they for
some reason caught that one. But
Superbowls, they only started
in 1968 and what kills me.
Oh I saw you post something
about this. Yeah. It's just like,
so see it telling me and people
are saying, because it's,
I guess because they call it a merger,
but it was like the AFL came in,
it was like the Xfl of the USFL
or the world football league.
It was just this other competing
football and the NFL laugh on you're some
fucking, you know, piece of Shit League.
But it was early enough on I
guess where they, you know,
and they made an up moves and had
enough money or whatever and then we'll,
the style that they played that they
started to compete with them and then they
played them in the first two games,
Superbowl one and two,
which were called Nfl
AFL championship game.
And they got the shit kicked out of them
because they weren't as good a league.
And then then the AFL one in Superbowl
three which was still not called the
Superbowl, it was still the AFL
NFL championship. All right.
So then after that they agreed to merge
all the owners agree in the AFL to merge
with the NFL.
Al Davis was the only one.
He wanted to put the NFL out of business
because he was fucking Al Davis and
she's like, this is why I
got to love him. Right. So,
and then at that point they just go,
all right,
so those first three
games against the AFL NFL,
that's when we're going to start like
I guess cause they called it a merger
rather than, but I mean like the Aba
in a way merged with the NBA. Yeah.
And they still count all that shit back
to the 19 four days. They only NHL teams.
They only took some teams from the
Aba. They didn't take everybody. Okay.
But still. Oh yeah. But still it was,
it was a competing league that was
fucking with their numbers and they had a
more exciting game just like the AFL.
And then in the end the NBA at euro
was losing too many players too.
It same way was the NFL. At some point
it's like can't beat them. Join them.
And then they came together,
but they still count all those Celtics
championships in the 60s and all that.
So it's like you're telling me
that Johnny Unite John Unitas.
I gotta look at him in a
certain way or in all of the,
and half of those fucking teams, the
browns, the rams, the bears, the packers,
the giants, all of those fucking teams
were in the NFL playing each other.
There was, it was actually in a way
you could say, you know, I could,
you can't say it was more talent than,
but I'm just saying like,
I don't get why they just wipe that away.
They don't fucking talk about it at all.
And that the Steelers with six fucking
chat in 2018 six championships.
Yeah. Like it's so fucking ridiculous
that, that the Patriots, right.
If we win Sunday, which would be next
Sunday, which would be fucking awesome.
We would be tied for the
most championships won in
NFL history and we've got our
first one fucking 17 years
ago. That doesn't, that
doesn't make sense. And you're,
you're, that doesn't make any
fucking sense. That's still,
I see where you're coming
from, but at the same time, um,
you know, we're going by super
bowl one. I think, listen, I'm,
I'm not a patriots fan.
I think they have in the instance they
started winning them and what 2001 was
that the first one? Yeah. I mean
they're, they're definitely one season.
They're definitely, you know,
one of the strongest things,
but all the people that want to fight
and put up the fight about saying that,
you know, will like saw that thing
that guy posted. The Greenbay has like,
we've got like 14 or whatever,
but here's green bay though.
Green base won four Superbowls and
they won like fucking 11 NFL titles.
They've been winning the
entire fucking time you have.
If there's ever one in a minute.
I mean,
how long has it been since Green Bay's
one was that 2005 something like that. Oh,
like nine or 10 or something.
Okay. You're right. Yeah, but well,
I'm not talking about that with that.
Well then why would you fucking count
the Broncos have a one in 20 years?
So what those there's don't count.
No, they, no, no. They count are they?
I'm saying they count,
but I just thought you were getting mad
about somebody posting that Green Bay
had x amount because they were enclosed
and the earlier one. That's my argument.
They should keep those. Yeah.
But those should fucking count.
If the fucking Montreal Canadians can
count when they fucking beat somebody
playing on a pond. Oh, I didn't know what
Jangle you were going with. I'm sorry.
I thought you were going against,
I thought you were saying nor
Octos people for it. Oh, okay.
Then I love the history of the game.
The NFL has been the NFL and a bunch
of fucking leagues have tried to, to,
to compete with them. They've
never, they've never been able to,
the best you've ever had was
the AFL merged with them,
but it was still called the NFL.
It wasn't called the AFL.
It wasn't called the NFL. Slash. Afl,
like Sirius Xm or whatever. And right.
It was called the fucking
NFL. You joined the NFL. Yeah.
So those other championships
were NFL championship.
That's cause now you call it
the fucking super bowl. Sure.
It was still the two best teams and
those, you know, before the AFL existed,
those were the two fucking best teams
of who the fucking classic giants Colts
Game Played In fucking Yankee Stadium.
The winter that it can't camp fucking
walk up to somebody who super bowl four
and said, I know what that feels like.
They know exactly what it feels like.
A lot of people are dying off, but
yeah, they know what it feels like.
100% that's a great point. They are
dying. I don't know. I count them.
I that the Green Bay packers are the
fucking New York Yankees and I think the
giants are next and that's the way
it should be. Did I think it was
Redskins are up there. The Redskins have,
we have no, you've got you. I have three.
And then we had, I think we had like
four of the world championship ones.
All right. I'm going to give
you some trivia. Where did
the rams first started? Um,
and city.
St Louis.
No, no. Cause I know it was
with Los Angeles. I don't
fucking know. Jesus. Great.
You know, you just sounded like
me and math class a long time ago.
That's what I love about you is that
you, I know, I know sports, but dude,
you know fucking sports
like you like I can imagine
because I used, I used to no fucking
everybody in the league and I just,
I just don't have time anymore.
So I don't know.
But they started off in Cleveland and
I've never understood why they were called
the rams. I don't know that there was
any rams in there. Um, all right, let's,
let's look up. What am I
looking at? Washington Redskins.
What's your fights on
all to the Redskins?
Don't re Braves on know
what bad fight for.
Oh, daisy. Oh there you go. And
then it goes into some weird thing.
Brandon doesn't jump in.
There's a lad, Steven Dapa.
Duba let the points.
So,
hey,
go NFL championships pre 1970 merger.
Uh, you got to right. Five
pretty good. I'll take it.
Yeah. So you've got five. So right now,
as for the way I look at your tie with
the Patriots, we've got five super bowls.
You got, you've got five champion.
We got, we have five championships.
I wish everybody thought like
you cause a lot of, you know,
do you a lot of people,
if you fucking people have ever said that,
no, I completely agree with
what you're saying. If he,
if the one before it was the official
Superbowl, it's still a championship.
Unfortunately a lot of
those people have died.
Yeah. Who would care, I guess. Um,
let's see here. Yeah, that, that
[inaudible] all right. Uh, Le
League championships. All right.
The NFL champ pre 1970s,
um,
the giants won four.
So they've won for NFL titles and
they won four super bowl ties.
Those you go to the stadium
said no way to be found.
They know they're not listed.
It's like it never fucking happened.
See the angle you're coming
with right now, and I respect
the, what you're saying,
dude,
100% that's not fair.
I'm not saying not fair. Not Fair.
I'm just, I'm just asking why,
why, why would your brother, dude lead
championships? Chicago bears. Okay.
They one fucking nine 19 2119
323340414346,
1963 and anyone a soup,
1985 and all they have is one fucking
banner hall hanging over their stadium.
Check one of the scores when they beat
the Redskins and one of those league
championships. It's like, it's
like crazy fucking lopsided.
70 to like 70 to eight from not mistaken.
So I don't know a lot about sports,
about facts, but I do know that,
that that is right. All right, let's
look up the, uh, Los Angeles Rams.
All right. And you'll find nervous. Are
you nervous about Sunday? Oh yeah. Always.
I'll tell you what's the funniest thing.
My a verse, he texted me and he's like,
dude, Todd Gurley, is it Todd Gurley
tug earlier? Yeah. He goes, he's heard.
And in my head I'm like,
dude,
there's no way to stand up comedians
know the injury status of the key running
back for the rams. If, if praise.
I got a guy on the inside. Yeah.
Who's your guy on the inside?
espn.com this is my, if,
if he was really fucking hurt,
we wouldn't know.
They would keep that under wraps.
But he was hurt in the last game.
I saw him on the bike for a little bit.
I know, but here's the thing, what is it?
Everybody's heard this time of year.
They all said he's got to funny bruise
of per cover. He's going to fucking play.
If they're leaking it out that he's hurt,
that means that he's,
he's way better than they thought he was
going to be because that's just good.
Always hurt and like, but they know
Bella check is going to be like,
well I guess we don't have
to prepare photog Gurley. Um,
but it was just funny. You know,
he showed up. Yeah. Alright.
Nfl Championships Pre 1970 the rams,
they wanted 45 and 51 and then they
won in 1999 and they were the yarn.
Cleveland Rams from 1936 to 1942 they
took 43 off to finish off the Germans and
the Japanese.
1944 1945 that was the last year
and then they moved to Los Angeles.
They stayed there until 94 came back to
2016 which brings me to something I was
making fun of and let, did you see, do
you watch the saints ramps game? I did.
All right.
Everybody thought the worst fucking
thing in that was that fucking helmet to
helmet.
No pass interference call.
The worst thing in that game was when
they cut to the stands after the rams won.
And you saw those guys in the rams
jerseys in their twenties maybe early
thirties crying. I saw that.
Yes. Yeah, I did see that.
Girlfriends were trying to comfort them.
It's just like buddy,
you will fucking two years
old when they moved away.
Like what are you doing here?
You can waiting since 2016 it says,
listen,
you're, you're fucking bill. Ryan went
bill when you, cause if you remember how,
what happened when we watched,
because you watched the caps game with
me when they won the cup where you are on
my computer.
I was in London in London that I was
facetiming you so you could watch the game
if everybody was asleep.
And I was a pitch black and I
was in the bathroom of my hotel.
My wife and daughter were sound
asleep and I was going to it.
I'm so happy for you just just,
and I was sitting there like, dude,
I care graduations,
you always facetiming with you
when you had your fucking TV on,
but you were like,
congratulations buddy.
[inaudible] I know it.
But my wife probably thought I was
in there talking to a hooker. Okay,
everybody's asleep. Oh
man, it's so beautiful.
It's so beautiful.
But what was,
what was so funny is if
you would have seen me,
and I mean like I remember in
[inaudible] 91 with the Redskins won,
but I remember the day
after because my mom,
like I was watching the game and
then the uh, my mom made a bunch of,
of her famous Superbowl Chili and I ate
a bunch of it and then I fell asleep in
a laundry basket.
Uh,
I was 11 and then I didn't get another
championship until this caps one.
And we were watching it together
and you were facing the screen.
And I remember I was just like cheering
as the clock ran down and then the
member, it stopped for a second,
there was like a stoppage of play,
like 0.06 seconds.
So I was screaming and then I got
quiet and then they win the game and
everybody's running on the ice and I'm
just dead silent. I thought, I was like,
am I dead inside it?
What is wrong with me?
And then they brought
the cup out and dude,
I just started weeping,
just weeping dude.
It's like, why does it
matter so much? It's so,
so it's everything. It's just
all the, it's all due to,
to everything. It's all the,
it's all the, it's all the, you
know, the Times that they, they,
they chunked it before when they were
supposed to win and all the times that,
you know, they, they did,
she put so much into it and to
finally get it just was so sweet,
man. And it was like, I started
thinking about like, this is,
I'm going to go really like
John Cougar Mellencamp here.
But then I thought about all like the
middle class people that live in the
Washington DC area that worked these
dead end jobs and then they just,
they get that championship cause they
want it so bad and that, that team,
whether it's the Redskins
and the caps or whoever,
it's like that's what they have to him
to help them escape. And so I, you know,
I wouldn't say spring senior team
raised the cup is just like I,
I kind of was just,
I don't think I'm ever going
to see the Bruins through it.
And when they finally did it,
I watched him from 1980 to 2011.
That's how long it took me to,
what's that 10 2031 years. 31
years I watched him. And um,
so from age 12 to a,
what does that 43 when they
finally they finally did it and uh,
I, I was, I told this story before,
I was at the Chicago Theater on
Jim Norton's tour with Jim Breuer,
David telling myself on this
tour called the antisocial tour.
And I watched the first period and a half.
Then I went on stage and
then when I got off stage,
I watched the final seven minutes upstairs
in one of those where the green room
is something like that.
And I remember being up there by myself
cause none of them cared because it
wasn't their team.
And the show ended and they went out to
do the meet and greet and I stayed up
there and there was like three minutes
left and they scored a goal or it's just
not enough time for the
other team to come back.
Vancouver and I was by myself
and my eye went up like 900
because I was like,
and I
one to see, they were like,
they were like, come on,
you got to come down from the
meet and greet people saying,
where the fuck are you calling you?
The bony for now. And I was like, wait,
did I say, I just had to see him
lifted up and I told my wife to tape,
but I knew she was taping it. And just
when I saw it as a, and I'll just lifted,
I'm just going,
good dude. That was 31
years just coming out of you and just,
Ah,
all those years of not being
able to get past the case,
not being able to win in the forum,
man.
Fucking getting past the Canadians and
then run into those fucking Gretzky
Edmonton Oilers in the mark messier the
Edmonton Oilers and just, and then just,
you know, Neeley's getting his
fucking leg taken out, you know,
and bore Kevin. It goes somewhere else to
win a cup and it's just fuck, fuck, fuck,
fuck,
fuck the lockout.
Oh yeah,
all of that.
[inaudible] I'll just go through
your head and then Bam, that's like,
you literally feel like they're good.
There's going to like look at,
look like at your television screen and
go or do you want to hold it up and you
can just like grab it.
It's just such any crazy.
It was such an incredible feeling.
I have such respect
for that trophy. I would never
touch it. I won't even touch it
because I'm not a cause.
You should be.
You should be on a team that
fucking wanted players who
play in the League won't
even touch it unless they want it so me,
some fucking asshole
because theirs was
lifted up and drink all. They're not
going to let you lift it up, dude.
They might let you get like a bomb on
it, but that's about it. All right.
I respect that.
I've seen pictures of guys,
I know that no players and shit and
they're like holding it with them like,
what the fuck are you doing with your
hands on that? Ferris, I respect that.
I respect that you would appreciate it
being respected back with a green baret
that cy action.
And you got your face all painted too.
Like you did something
your paint balling with
with your paint ball gun.
I watched you on CNN.
Um, anyways, I got a little bit of
advertising here like I have to read. Uh,
let me see here. What are you good? Where
the fuck did this? This always happens,
Joe Santa Maria is, why does this
always happen? Okay. Oh, 1-800-FLOWERS.
Um, Valentine's Day is
coming up there, buddy.
By now most of us have started racking
our brains about what Valentine's gift is
truly going to make her day
special. Dude. Fuck that.
It's any woman out there fucking racking
their brains about what kind fucking
stupid thing they're going to get.
You know, you know, a guy should do,
we should get into some what
fucking thing get you pressure them.
We'd be funny like ladies,
you know, Valentine's Day.
What kind of flat screen
TV because they get a bad,
some so knows audio. Oh,
that's shiny shit. Uh,
with one 800 flowers.com.
It's really not that complicated.
Roses from 1-800-FLOWERS
are a no brainer right now.
When you order early 1-800-FLOWERS has
amazing deals on vibrant and Romantic
Valentine's rose bouquets.
Is it bouquet of bouquet?
Who says bouquet bouquet?
Bouquet.
Oh my God, it's the bouquet bouquet.
I'm going to get a boat bouquet.
Okay. Tomato, tomato. It's not like that.
Arrangements and more and starting at 29
99 this is a great thing to do though.
Take fucking get this done.
Oh yeah,
the order ahead of time to get this
fucking thing done, and then you,
then you just,
then you just find some other stupid
bullshit thing that you can do.
You send the flowers to work so everybody,
she can feel the again for
all fucking friends, you know?
That's what it's all
about. Oh yeah, absolutely.
Don't send it to the house you get and
send it to a public day. Hey James,
he pulled to see, you know that
stupid car. I love this woman.
That's what they want.
Say My pussy is better than yours.
There are so many unbelievable
things from 1-800-FLOWERS,
but you have to hurry a roses.
Roses are red roses from 1-800-FLOWERS
are picked at their peak and shipped
overnight to ensure freshness or maze.
I just pictured them miserable bastard
picking those things. Gorgeous.
Does he have any love in his life?
Balance,
gorgeous valentines bouquets
and arrangements starting
at 29 99 is an amazing
deal, but it won't last long bouquets
prices will be going up soon,
so take advantage today.
Pick your delivery date and let
1-800-FLOWERS handle the rest.
When it comes to Valentines,
I don't settle for anything
less than my rose authority.
I guess that's supposed to be talking.
One 800 flowers.com to order valentines
bouquets arrangements and more.
starting@twentynineandaninegotooneeighthundredflowers.com.
Click on the radio icon and enter Berbee.
You are ordered today and
save@oneeighthundredflowers.com code bird.
I love how you slowly turned into Waylon
Jennings. Towards the end of that,
I just get sit.
I have to do anything I can cause I can't
read out loud anything to keep it in
entertainment. I love the, the
bouquets. That's fantastic. Hello?
That's like I tell me there's
no basement and gallium,
there's no okay at the Alamo.
That's, that's my fucking
shit, dude. Alright. Hymns.
You know what I'm saying? It wasn't us.
It was them. That's what I got him from.
That's from a, the warriors was I'd
never seen the warriors. Who them.
You never seen the war?
Never seen the warriors.
I started it and then I fell asleep.
I'd look like two months ago.
I didn't do it one day. Okay. Hymns. Uh,
why did guys turned a weird solutions
or do nothing when they can turn to
medicine and science?
What are they talking about?
Solution for hymns.com a
one stop for hair loss.
Skincare. Sexual wellness. Oh
God. What the fuck was that? Oh,
I turned it on to make sure
I knew you were coming.
Uh Oh fuck. I forgot to send that
fucking lady at check. All right,
what am I doing here? Um, for him. A
one stop shop for hair, less hair loss,
skincare, sexual wellness for men.
This is the whole thing, dude.
You're going to clear up your skin.
You got to get your bag and you get,
have a fucking blow job. Motivate
your audience. Talk about the,
your experience with the product. Well
you don't want to be talking about that.
I'm married. A fucking
bald skin. Looks Great.
[inaudible] right? Yeah, that's right.
Choose one to two copy points
to rotate into your spot.
Why are they telling us thanks to science
baldness can be optional. Well fuck it.
Thanks for telling me hymns.
Connect with your,
with connects you with
real doctors and met good,
good real doctors at this time and medical
grade solutions to treat hair loss,
well known generic equivalents to name
brand prescriptions to help you keep your
hair. No snake oil pills
or gas station counters.
Supplements a prescription solutions
backed by science. I like that.
Snake oil and gas station solution.
Who they said to you,
what's that was from like the 1930s.
They still do that.
They go to any like any like uh,
you know,
gas station and you can get those like,
black Mambas or like just this
like Dick Pills, whatever dude.
They sell them all behind
the counter. Yeah, Dick Pill.
That's a good name for a band. Uh, no
waiting room. No awkward in person.
Doctor visits. Save hours
by going to, for hymns,
for h I m s.com so easy answer,
a few quick questions.
Doctors will review and can just prescribe
you products are shipped direct to
your door. All right, uh, order now.
My listeners get a trial of
four hymns for just $5 today,
right now while supplies last.
See website for full details.
This would cost hundreds if you went
to the doctor or a pharmacy, go to for
hims.com/bird that's f o
r a h I m s.com/burr for
hims.com/burr.
And lastly,
but certainly not leastly stamps.com
postage rates have gone up again.
Can you believe how many cents it costs
to send a fucking envelope from here to
fucking New York?
Thankfully stamps.com can ease the
pain with big discounts off post office
retail rates.
stamps.com makes it easy.
They'll send you a free digital scale,
automatically calculates exact postage
stamps.co where we will help you decide
the best class of mail based on your
needs. They'll even give
you postage discount. She
can't get at the post office,
including 5 cents off
every class class stamp.
I use stamps.com to send
out all my posters. I'm a
moron if I can figure it out.
So can you right now
my slash our listeners,
my listeners get a special offer that
includes a four week trial plus free
postage and a digital scale.
See for yourself why over 700,000 small
businesses use stamps.com just go to
stamps.com click on the
microphone@thetopofthehomepageandtypeinburgerburrthatstamps.com
bet.
Durbar a righty. Um,
hey, you have a podcast?
I do. I, you know, it's funny,
I was watching you read that and like
you just keep going when you make the
mistake. And like when I tried to
tape stuff like that, if I like,
if I fuck up at all, I just like,
I'm like, all right, God damn.
And I just like to have a start over.
It's just seeing you do it so
effortlessly perfectionist where you're so
comfortable doing it.
Well I do.
I've established right out of
the gate that I'm a moron. Yeah.
I guess out in the front of it.
Yeah. It's like [inaudible] an idiot.
Bill Clinton saw what happened to Gary
Hart and you just got out in front of it.
They would just like, did you, is I fucked
them all and then he fucking, you know?
Yeah.
But then he went back to his old ways.
I did not have sex with that woman.
That's a good Glenn Dude.
And I, if I said, if I would, I,
I do not have problems reading out loud.
Like that would be the end.
I would get impeached. Sure. That'd be I,
you know, I wouldn't leave just like him.
I need to leave my flaws in. That's
what it taught me to do. Yeah,
I do have a podcast. Uh, I love it.
Bill. I'm telling you I love this.
I'm more than 500, the 500.
It's about stock car race.
It is not about that. It is about
the 500 greatest albums of all time.
I'm going through rolling Stone Magazine's
list of the 500 grade his albums
starting at 500, working
my way down to one. Uh,
each week I sit down with a
comic actor or musician now, uh,
you know,
and I gave them a week with the record
and then I break the record down and we
sit down and talk about it is kiss
got one in the [inaudible] I just did.
I just did with Jeff Ross kiss destroyer.
I was going to say, you know he shit,
you could've got Steven Adler.
Ah. I mean I've got he lose love.
I would love to get Steven again in there.
Dude,
I love this so much man.
Like,
cause it's not just being able to sit
down and talk with my buddies about the
album and ask them questions around like
the meanings of the songs and the facts
from the record. But Dude,
since I've started doing this,
like I have listened to music than I
thought I would never listen to him,
didn't even know about. And it's like
touching me and it's just so incredible.
Right now I'm listening to Steve Earle
Guitar town. You ever heard of him?
This guy is funny. He's
like, he's like the key.
This is like his born in the USA,
but country record dude,
I'd never listened to country.
I fucking love this record dude.
When did it come off?
1985 and he has a song
called guitar town and it's,
it's just, it's just incredible.
I mean once, especially
once you know, the history,
this guy and like how he dropped out
of school and then went to Nashville,
like you know, to, to find
Townes van Zandt and leg was
writing songs for people.
And then the record company was like,
all right,
well we want you to make a record.
And he was like, all right. And He's,
he just sat down and wrote the first
song and the last song and then just the
whole album came together. But it's like
that's what I love. How many albums?
Yeah. Oh he's got a shitload.
I listen to anything else.
So he must be real quality cause I don't
know who we are. You know what I mean?
Cause I figured like if I know who a
country person is for the most part,
they suck because it's going to be like,
you just know like the pop kind of,
here's the thing though. You don't
know. It's like, you know, like if, if,
if you were,
I don't know if somebody say name
is speed battlement metal band.
Everybody would say motorcycle.
That's right. You would
say motors. Motors, sickle,
our favorite band. Now
this is, this is the thing.
The guy could have been like enormous.
But then he developed like a drug
problem and then kind of fell off.
And now he actually still makes
music but a country, the country, uh,
fan base doesn't really fuck with him
anymore because he leans very left.
And I was actually watching
a documentary of his,
cause I'm getting ready to record the
episode with Tom Everett Scott from that
thing you do. Um, he played the drama,
you remember when he came
and did it at the jam. Um,
and you look at the youtube comments, you
know, of this documentary and it's like,
I used to like his music but he's a
fucking stupid leftist, liberal, tarred.
And it's just like, because they
can't accept that, you know,
you can play country music
but still lean towards. Yes.
It's also why I think,
you know,
you shouldn't be constantly putting out
your political opinions. Like, listen,
I just completed, I completely agree.
I make fun of people, you know,
the white privilege thing. I like
this. I make fun of feminists and shit.
I try to be like even handed
or whatever. But uh, you know,
all you do is just like nobody,
all you do is get people who agree with
you to agree with you and then people
who don't agree with you too now hate
you and not want to watch something that
you do because they
can't separate the two.
Like I can stay at a fucking Trump hotel
and not like Donald Trump and for a lot
of people can't get past
that because in their minds,
the people who run the Sheridan,
who were also billionaires for some
reason didn't vote for Donald Trump.
They're all there. They're all the same.
Fucking get 100% yeah, by no, not dense.
Imagine like it's just, they're just
painful. His name outside the thing,
it's not like living, it's, I've been in
a Trump hotel. They're extremely nice.
They're incredible. They're
incredible. Yeah. I said Nice. I mean,
everybody knew what I meant. You don't
have to one up me and say incredible.
It was incredible. I've only stayed
at one. It was fucking fantastic.
Like does that one opinion credible what
this guy should be doing? Fuck yeah,
dude,
it is to stick to a hotel on residency.
Was he competent as his fucking
hotel? I mean this, this, this.
We would be back.
He would make it great again if it's tax
cuts were as good as his bath towels.
I made come the fuck. You know what?
I was making fun of it the other day.
Somebody said, well, like there was some,
I guess there was some
sort of taxing out there.
If you make $11 million or more and
people make $11 million and while we're
complaining, Oh yeah. So, uh,
somebody had tweeted that, you know,
hey, you know, this is fucking bullshit.
Just pay your fair share.
So it makes $11 million a year,
doesn't work any harder than
somebody who makes 20 grand a year.
And I was fucking dying
laughing. I was like, oh yeah,
they do. Yeah, they do. Yeah,
they do.
You wonder why a guy make an $11 million.
He's getting a fucking divorce.
It's cause he never sees his wife.
That's why it's true. It doesn't see
his kids has a pool, never been in it.
And it's just like, yeah, this,
there's 24 fucking seven. I,
I've made 20 grand a year.
You always great.
It's the second the fucking whistle blows.
You don't even think about that job.
But once I think that nobody calls
you up, hey bill, uh, tomorrow,
when you unload the boxes,
could you maybe do we to get out of
her fucking conference call and how you
unload the fucking truck?
It's just his people don't think that
people think of like when you think
somebody makes 20 million a year,
like we just know shit from like Falcon
Crest and dynasty. All those shows are,
they're like, they
don't do anything. Yeah.
They hang out in country clubs and
they piss on us 20,000 hours. Yeah.
And you have pay petty fights with
people within your family? Yeah,
that's all they do. Like nobody sees
them like you know in the office from,
you know, from 6:00 AM until like
3:00 AM and then they go home,
like walk into their kid's room,
the kid's sleeping,
they sh t single teardrop falls and then
they'd go bang the mate and go to sleep.
Yeah. It's kind of what I, that's
what I assume happens. I have no idea.
I grew up lower middle
class, but I love, I,
what I love about this podcast is that
I would do this if nobody was listening
because I wanted to
listen to these albums.
And I started to, um, I was just
going, I want it to feel inspired.
I think I was as musically tapped
out and, and I was like, all right,
I'm going to listen to an album a day,
over 500 days.
And I started posting about it.
And when I got to like four 98,
which was like on the third day,
Jim Jefferies reached out to
me. He's like, dude, he's like,
that stone roses record is one of
my favorite records. He's like, oh,
the stories that I think of when I
hear that music and then like hit me.
And I was like, that's the podcast.
I've been waiting to do a great voice.
He can sing.
He's incredible voice.
Uh, but he came on and he
did, and he did that episode.
And that's basically what
it is. It's like, you know,
we're going to go through these great
records and we're going to talk about,
and we're gonna, I'm gonna, I'm gonna ask,
you need more than a day to listen to
one album that no, I give them a week.
He just pointed at me. No. Oh we, I give
you a week. Oh yeah. Were you did it?
You did.
I thought you only took a day to listen
to it because you're so busy because
you're making $12 million.
So you're out on how can we can have
$1,000,001 11,000,001 so I was the one who
complained.
I could tell it was you that was so,
but what it is is like I give every comic
or actor or whoever it's going to be a
week with the record,
and then I break the album down and
like ask them questions about their life
using the meaning of the songs,
the facts from the records. So,
so the album is really just like the
celery and the carrots and the onions have
the soup, but it's really just, you know,
the basis for me just to have a really,
you know,
funny or deep or whatever the fuck it is.
It's just a good conversation
when you run out of those albums.
And I was over that. Oh, I know
how you'd do it, which I do.
You could do the 500 albums.
That should have been in the
top 500 that'll be a 9.61 years.
And uh, that's not a bad
idea, but I might just be,
you know,
I think I've been,
when I retire it on May 31st, 2028. Oh,
that's what I'm going to have.
My goal is on the final
episode to have a Oprah.
I don't know why, but it's
just, it's my way. Wales,
what's the number one sergeant
pepper's lonely hearts club band.
Then it's, then it goes a
number one album, number one.
Then number two is pet sounds.
And then number three,
I think his revolver,
this is white rough.
The number one white
rock in the top 10 note,
Marvin Gaye's in the top 10 Marvin
Gaye's number six, Marvin Gaye,
what's going on?
But it's all over the place.
The like album 500 was outcasts equipment.
I and then for life I'll be saying is
because the Beatles who really went rogue
and started their own Beatles where
essentially a boy band and then they that
they took control there,
Chris with a lot of people because the
Beatles now get a ton of shit by people
being like, you know, like they, there's
like people who think they stink.
Like I've, I've listened to two things.
The Beatles stink dumb people will their,
they're dumb. Yeah. I'm not
saying you can't be into them,
they don't move you or whatever. And
they spent a long time but that, that's,
that's like saying count Basey
steaks or something like that. No,
it's just a night. Yeah.
He don't learn. Teach.
That's the thing is that somebody like
my age, I'm 39 like I, I, you know,
was born in 79 so I wasn't really
alive during the Beatles era.
And from what I've been told
and everything I've read,
like there will never be an artist
as big as the Beatles were like,
they were enormous. Like
we can't even, this was,
they broke out of what usually binds you
and they took control of their career
and started their own label. And then
when they should have fizzled out,
they made this left turn where
they reinvented themselves.
You know, when they started doing drugs
and grew their hair and all that shit,
like rubber soul and then yeah,
in revolver
and all that stuff.
And then when that kind of went to,
they will now what the fuck do
we do? It's like, all right,
let's just play characters
now will be these, these guys.
How would these guys do that? So
during that time, Marvin Gaye,
I think he was stuck in the Motown
shit and he's got to sing what they're
writing for them.
And by the 70s you know,
he was doing what they did as far
as he kind of broke away is like,
well I want to sing about
what I'm thinking about
rather than doing my version
of she loves you. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Where he's doing like heard it through
the grape vine and all that stuff,
which I still love all the songs.
I mean,
but then he wanted to go like deeper so
maybe they think that that's because,
well sergeant pepper, I was asking what's
going on is a better record than that.
Sergeant pepper.
Yeah.
I mean it's, listen they, all of these,
all of this whole list is completely,
you know. Yeah. It's, it's,
it's all over them. It's designed
to do, there's your, you got like,
cause the way they made it, because I've
already had this discussion with people.
What is it? It's 20 years
ago today. It's not the job,
the band and play that are going
in and out of style. Common Schema.
Lava down the dial. That's good.
You the one in eligibility,
she is escaped diva ski but Duba Doo.
Yup.
Something like that.
One of the best moments we've had on
the jam is when Jim Jefferies sang that
first time he did it,
he did sergeant pepper and then into
with a little help from my friends and he
was wearing a jacket that he bought at
John Barbados that the only reason he
bought,
it's the gaudiest like most expensive,
weirdest Jackie you
ever seen in your life.
And it costs like $10,000 and he only
bought it because he was at this John
Barbados like event.
And he put it on de Laugh about it.
And then Ringo Starr walked by and when
you look good in that, so he was like,
well, I gotta buy it now. I
mean, if a beetle tells you
you look good in something,
it's like you gotta fucking get the fuck
I'm gonna go start was there? No. Yeah,
dude, bring, it was always at like
Barbados events. He wears all that.
Like interview with a vampire.
Clothing was an event. It wasn't as,
it wasn't a store. Not
a did. No, no, it was,
I was at an event. I spaced halfway
through the okay out. It's great.
It's great. It's what I'm
saying is, is that, you know,
Sargent pepper was this huge thing
for the Beatles. What was the coat?
What did it have on? Oh my God,
I'll send you a picture. Sorry.
It was like an alligator gold style,
like,
like Rock Jack.
I don't even know what you'd call it.
Just like an allergy piece of that. If
he buys it. Was it a Beatles coat? No,
it was just a job.
He wasn't,
he was seriously saying he looked
good in that fucking coach.
It just saying to John, he was ain't
a gym that you look good in it.
And so he told him, you know, he's
like, you look good. So Jim bought it.
That's the story areas. It was boring
the second time. It was interesting.
The final spaced out. The moment
everybody's laughing at, you know, I'm not
fucking listening from, but we're
not paying attention or whatever. Uh,
you didn't think that when
I sang a Johnny paycheck,
take this job,
but shove it down day,
I believe.
But now buddy
do what Josh has been
trying to get me to do.
You're going to do it. Um, he wants
mother fucker. You are gonna do this.
Wants me to get a brown curly wig.
Go out on stage is Don Henley.
And then he wants me to play
drums and Sing Hotel California.
Doug doesn't Hauwei.
Yeah,
I can't say I'm going to help you.
I'm going to help you in the
crowd's going to help you.
So everybody knows because
bill's talked about it.
I do a show called the goddamn comedy
jam where Comedians do stand up.
They tell the story about a song and
then they sing it. Bill has done it.
You've done it more than
fucking like anybody.
You're the only counts it cause
it was pre the NFL AFL merger.
They don't call back.
Alright. But, but uh,
we had my birthday coming up and,
and I asked you,
I was like, could you please do
that? And I was spend the bird,
I said, I'm about to do it. And then you
called me and you'd gave me one of your,
you this. I've gotten this call a few
times where it's like, Josh, dude,
I got too much shit going on.
I can't learn this fucking song.
Don't make me learn this.
I can play the song.
But the fact that they have to sing
along with it and I can't sing, but you,
you understand that's a song that's so
popular. The second you start playing it,
the whole audience is going to fucking
join in with you and then you can just
kind of mimic it.
And then I'll be singing
in the bass player will be
singing the [inaudible] like
all the fucking lyrics in front of me.
Like it's going to be a shit show
thing I could do. I think, you know,
I can make that happen. We'd listen.
There's one in March. I got one coming up
March 20th do we haven't done
one in awhile? Yeah, I do.
Like my schedule doesn't open up again
until fucking April. Like I'm just,
I'm straight. I know what
the fuck happened, dude.
I got in this business to not working now,
but we're doing,
we're doing F is for family, man. I gotta
be, cannot wait dude. Right. And Shit,
we're already up to episode three.
We're cruising. That's great. Yeah,
we're cruising. But I made, yeah, it
takes a lot, a lot of time. Um, all right,
let's get into a some point.
I Will Sing Hotel California.
Oh, where did my hair, boom. Boom, boom.
So does [inaudible]
I just want to do that. You do that
one part where it's like boom, boom.
Then what is the date you
just kid killer bees do,
do, do, do, do on the tin. Bali.
Uh, all right. Body shaming.
We got people write in and then they,
for some reason they want advice.
I know this goes down. Okay. All right.
Body shaming. You'll Billy Brown shirt.
I don't know.
Brown ship meat.
So it wasn't that the people who
are sympathetic to fucking Hitler,
I have no idea who won't. Brown shirts
went brown shirts. Uh, wait a minute.
I can look that up.
Now you got to Google something political.
Maybe they hear sole unit picture that
you posted in a brown shirt and they are,
they're just rhyming in it.
Brown shirt.
Do they said so many weird
things like Billy elbows or
Billy dangled down. Yeah.
So they just made it up.
No Brown shirts.
Political.
Uh,
Nazi party.
His original parliamentary did played a
significant role in Adolf Hitler's rise
to power. Oh, I guess I'll eat
meat. It was brown shirts. Say.
See that's what the Internet
stupid cause I just,
I just fucking grazed over all at
gray's. Breezed. Graced. All right,
you'll Billy Brown shirt.
I vomited a little in my mouth halfway
through your tirade against fat clients
when you suggest,
I don't remember doing this.
Those who don't conform to your body
dysmorphic ideal should get therapy and
sort out their lives.
Did I say that guys?
You have to understand something like I
have to do an hour usually by myself and
whatever topic comes up,
I have to destroy it because I'm
trying to make you laugh anyways.
I haven't heard anything less healthy
commodity your mouth for some time.
All right. You know
something dude? First of all,
the I vomited a little bit in my life.
You're the fact that I'm
supposed to literally take
what you're saying seriously
and you're speaking in soundbites.
Let me get Stan,
did you shake your head before
you rolled on the floor?
Laughing your ass off anyways.
If my partner thought my
weight was a deal breaker,
I'd thank her for the honest
glimpse into where vacant prisons,
soul and abandoned her in a
heartbeat. No, you wouldn't.
You overly sensitive jackass,
uh,
in a heartbeat to the Greyhound Hound
inspired Instagram influencers and
consumer program. Neil Neil
is, you seem to champion,
diversity is not a mental
illness, but body shaming is, ah,
God. Yeah. Wow. I gotta I
gotta I gotta like that's,
that's worded so much in that speak that
I don't even believe that that's true.
No, they're just throwing
buzzwords together, Brown shirt,
all of that type of stuff.
I love,
now I see why they called you Billy Brown
shirt. Like I'm a not mad at you. Yeah,
they're mad at,
you know,
cause what it was was there was
a guy who is with some chick,
she had a little meat on the bones,
whatever,
and he was went into it thinking I should
probably fucking lose it eventually.
I don't know why he thought that
people tend to just get fatter.
Yeah. People, people do tend to age. It'd
be like this guy has a little gray hair.
Maybe it's going to turn Brown. No, it's
going to fuck it again. More Gray. Yes.
So anyway,
my age and if so what happens is,
but she was putting it on at what he
considered to be an alarming rate.
So he wanted to stay with her,
but he needed to know how to approach
to ask her in a polite way to stay in
shape. Here's what all
these not least gained way.
Here's what all these proud fat people
are not like they're killing themselves.
So if somebody gives an intervention
and that this isn't about fatties is
they'll fucking sit there and
I'll talk about how addiction,
food addiction and all that is
no different than drug addiction.
I agree with you.
You legally agree with have it.
You have an intervention
with people to be like,
you're killing yourself with this heroin.
So I haven't for some reason
with big MACs. Yeah. You
can't fucking be like, hey,
why don't you lay off your
fucking chicken tenders there.
So I have a friend that, that
just had a kid, uh, my buddy, and,
uh, he, he was, he lost a little bit
of weight because he had prediabetes,
but he's putting it back on again. And
like, we had a thing tonight. And, uh,
and I was like, I was like,
hey man, like you, you know,
you look like you're putting on more
weight. And he goes, yeah, you know,
it's just the stress and blah, blah,
blah. I'm like, I know, but you know,
we're celebrating your kid's birthday.
It's just, you should just, you know,
and he read wants to do it.
It's like that by saying that,
it's just that reality check just to
let them know. I'm not shaming him,
but I don't think he's shaming his
girlfriend either. That the, you know,
that dude that, that wrote in. So it's,
it's just kinda like, hey, you know,
it's like you said, it's health. You know,
it's, you gotta you gotta Stop, you know?
Yeah. Fucking, just, you gotta
be exercise. If you want to live,
you got to exercise and take care
of yourself. What you eat is fuel.
It doesn't need to be doing everything.
I'm not gonna say his name, but a guy
I knew a couple of years ago. Yeah. Oh,
the last time I saw him, I saw him sit
down and go, this guy does not look good.
And he was not eating healthy food.
Any I you fucking dead a month later.
Fuck yeah, dude. And it's just like, but
you're not supposed to say something.
Somebody who is addicted to heroin
but out and I got a temper and shit.
My wife can skin step in on that. But
there's something about like, you know,
being fat. These people are just
like, no man, I'm a fucking eight.
You've just been convinced by sis.
Like they take it, like you're saying,
they're not beautiful
people. It's like, you know,
if I just saw you would just some
fat shit. Yeah. I don't know.
But it wasn't my fucking idea
either, man. So yeah. Yeah.
You can go fuck yourself with all
your stupid like that, that, that all,
all of that.
So you went to about brown shirt.
The way this whole thing is written,
this is the kind of person that
tries to make you lose your job.
1000000% there.
They're very active on Yelp.
Yeah. All right, and then
fell titles. Hey, pasty pigs.
Spin takes chem professor, you've
asked about super bowl titles. First,
NFL championship. Oh Great. Maybe
this person has this solution.
The issue here is not the answer,
it's the question.
If someone asks which team
have never won a Superbowl,
it has a different answer than if someone
asks which team has never won an NFL
championship.
Even a complicated more,
you could ask who has never
won a league championship,
which also includes AFL champion
chips and other leagues. All right,
I understand all of this.
For official NFL champions from 1920
to 1932 there was no championship game.
The championship champion was decided
by the best record only. Okay.
Now none of this is answering my question.
That's like back in the day when baseball,
all those world series that they count,
do you not winning the pennant was
back in the year. Back in the day,
you had the brand of the regular season.
If you had the best record in the
American league, you won the pennant,
there was no play off. Yeah. And
then you went to the champions.
You went to the world series.
Yeah. So all those years,
the Yankees won all those fucking titles.
They had one playoff series to win.
It wasn't this divisional,
it wasn't three rounds of playoffs,
which people have to do now are
they doing, but were they doing,
when they got into that world series was,
how many games was it was [inaudible]
seven that was still seven games.
The early 19 hundreds where it
was best was best five on a nine.
That's five out of nine. Yeah. Fuck Dude.
That would go until like December if they
did that now, like I think the Red Sox,
1903, we won that world series
five games to three. Hey man,
it's gay made coming to
your house for gay mate.
Um, anyways, from 1933 to 1969,
there was a championship game and the
winner of that was the NFL champion from
1966 on that champion went on to play
in the Superbowl and then when it was
called the world champion,
that's not true. 66, 67, 68,
the end of those seasons or
whatever, those are 66, 67, 68, 69,
whatever it was.
Those first three against the AFL was
called the AFL NFL title was not called
the soup bowl.
Later on retroactively,
it was named the super bowl from
1960 to 69 AFL had champions.
That's true.
But they aren't counted as NFL history,
but they are counted as the
team's history. If you are
asking how many? Yes. Okay.
Uh, from 1966, 69 in the NFL AFL
champions played the Superbowl.
I skies just telling me Shit. They didn't
play the Superbowl. It was renamed that
designers should be called facts.
Yeah, just facts. Facts. Facts, facts.
Facts. Okay. So in 1966, the AFL channels,
the Kansas City's ship chiefs, the
NFL champions, green bay packers.
This is the plus one league
championship for each team.
Chiefs lost when they played
in in the first NFL. If so,
they didn't get a Superbowl win,
but they still the AFL champion.
I understand all of this.
None of that cleared anything up.
I'm saying why don't they count those?
Yeah.
It's like you go to the stadium,
like the AFL merge to be part of the NFL.
So you're saying that at
any most NFL stadiums,
there are no trophies to represent
the league champions. Just yes.
If you look at the flow,
I'm sure in the,
somewhere in the stadium maybe
they'll have, they'll have that,
but it's just like, you know
when you go to a, you know,
you go to the fucking Red Sox,
Fenway park,
I mean we have our banners
right down the thing,
1903 to fucking 2018 yeah.
Everybody has all of that.
They're all of them count.
Know that that's there. I appreciate
it was fun to read all that history,
but that didn't answer my question.
Why aren't they counted?
Yeah.
I mean when it comes to the Superbowl man,
it's just if it's not in,
there's those words super in bowl
or before them they, they just,
they act like it didn't happen. You
Act like it didn't happen. Yeah.
Well I mean it's just,
you could still say do championships,
but I I, I completely see
what you're saying right now.
It actually kind of fucked up
day on set about the eagles.
They've never won a Superbowl.
They last thing they one was an NFL title.
It's like,
yeah,
well that was the peak of fucking 1960
they were the best fucking football team
out there. And you're talking about her
like it would like they, they, they,
they lost the election. Yeah, I
dunno. Anyways, living in Wyoming.
Hey Billy, silly. It's silly city slicker.
I was listening to some older podcasts
episodes and came across a rant you had
about Wyoming. I like Wyoming. I didn't
remember what I said. Like these people,
they just find tidbits. I
live in Wyoming. I got to say,
you are not too far off.
I listened to the podcast every
week while I feel my cows off,
feed my cows off the back
of a flatbed truck. Shut up.
I know this guy's fuck with me.
Last week we killed a problem mountain
lion and next weekend we'll be entering
into a competitive coyote hunt. I live in
the absolute middle of fucking nowhere.
This sounds amazing. This guy, this
guy listens to Steve Earle. Yeah.
But this guy is way more interesting in
a party than I am. I do stand up comedy.
Oh yeah. What did you do? You know,
I saved five of our sheep, you know,
from a mountain lion by, uh,
I came in third in it off.
I came in third in the coyote hunt
nationals. I want to talk to that guy.
The nearest town population is 3000
miles and it's 40 miles away. Also,
just to clear the air,
most of the billionaire
cons live up in Jackson,
uh, and the rest of Wyoming.
Oh, that's what I was saying.
I still want to be the Douche in Hollywood
that gets a place in Wyoming and the
rest of Wyoming pretty much discounts.
Jackson is being
part of the state anyway,
so I'll pretty much discounts it as
being part of state. Partially unrelated.
I finished getting my pilot's license
last year and hope to start on my
helicopter rating within the next year.
Good for you.
My family has used a bell jet
ranger to hunt coyotes. Jesus.
How much more of an advantage do
you need for three generations now?
And I'm ready to start flying the Holly,
do you have like one of those fucking
Vietnam guns? Dead Job. Yeah. Job Doo,
Doo Doo Doo Doo Doo. Today.
How do you shoot a doe? Easy.
You just don't lead him as much.
Uh,
am I ready to start flying
the heli to carry on the,
Oh and I'm ready to start flying.
They had to carry and a tradition,
so cheers to a fellow pilot.
That's cool as shit. Uh,
just wanted to let you know there's at
least one can listen to your podcasts in
Wyoming and love all the shit you
put out things. And Go fuck yourself.
That's cool man. I'm trying to get
eight hours a month, uh, flying.
And have you been flying a lot recently?
I got 7.9 for this month and
I'm fine tomorrow morning.
And then what are you
gonna take me up dude? Huh?
When I have three over 300 hours,
uh,
I want to do a little bit of instrument
training and just get better at it and,
and like do some full,
I would,
I would do full downs in the whole fucking
thing before I would ever take up my
first passenger. And I love you too
much to have you be my first passenger,
but there's a few people in my life that
I like, so I'll be taking them up first.
Okay. I believe that. And then, do
you know what I mean? It's just like,
do I want to kill this guy or this guy?
Wait,
dude wasn't like Sophie's choice with
a helicopter. How are we going to go?
We're going to go to see iron maiden in
Las Vegas and then that should be like
the time that we do that.
Does that,
sorry. Ps. If you want to try
a new cigar, checkout deadwood,
tobacco company out of Deadwood,
South Dakota.
The sweet Jane is is my favorite
cigar I have ever smoked. See you.
You see your ball.
Fuck.
Well I mean some guy out there in
the fucking range shooting coyotes.
I bet you know. Go to deadwood. Yeah,
that sounds fucking pretty cool to me.
All right,
we've got to wrap this thing up.
Do we get some gas and the smoke in the
desert? It's our three minutes. Perfect.
Alright. Drone. You'll Billy up there. Uh,
you were talking about a drawing last
week that would taxi people around.
Sounded like the one you mentioned
was unmanned. Check this thing out.
It's 57 batteries yet to do that is, I
was joking about that fucking thing dude.
They,
they're going to do this thing rather
than deal with the population problem.
The next thing they do is have
like, like I got, it looks like a,
it looks like a helicopter
and you just get in it.
There's nobody in there and he'll
just like take you across to la now.
First of all, I would think it would be
super expensive unless it's electric.
Unless, yeah. Uh, Elon Musk can
make the thing, but dude, you know,
you fucking laptop crashes. Your phone
craps out on you. Oh, you open like dude,
you're going to fly somebody like over
eight, like the level of insurance.
Like how are you going to do that?
I was joking that you're going to have
some hipster come fly through was on his
way to a pocket watch convention out
in fucking Venice beach or something.
Oh we found was his handlebar mustache.
Yeah.
He was on his way to this to meet
this food truck. Um, yeah, whatever.
I think it was. So there, there is a, so
what I just thought I'd get this clear in.
Okay. Can I show you something
super pleased show to me. Boy.
I remember just trying to, cause
I'm not, I'm kind of confused.
You're saying there is going to be a
transportation that like is it a drone?
So it's like you get into a tube and
then it just lifts the tube up and flies.
You kind of looks like a helicopter.
It looks fucking cool as shit.
I figured it looks fucking cool. You show
it as though he's showing me now. Wow.
I want to show you this,
this app here for flight.
Um, and this is what I'm getting
better at here. So this, this here,
once I get good at,
you know,
confident enough in my abilities and
I take up a passenger so it just,
you don't have to know.
It's not like back in the fucking day
we'd had to have like a fucking sectional
map on your and you fucking
thigh as you're flying around.
This thing gives you all the,
uh, the airports, all the, um,
any of Santa Barbara. Where are we?
Where are we? The, there's Van Nuys,
there's Burbank right there. So
it's pink. So that's a Charlie. Uh,
and then you got,
oh,
it's so great is you could just fucking
type in whatever you want to type in.
It gives you, the aid is, it
gives you the, uh, contact tower.
It has a map runway.
This is probably what most of the time
would you land out there and why they
slam on the brakes because
this is so fucking short.
That is a small ass
landing strip. Yeah. Uh,
well I don't know how he
could tell it from the APP.
I think cause I just told you it was
um, uh, being a cut right now. Uh,
there's Lti Burbank,
there's El Monte.
It's one of my favorite ones
but it has all but it has,
see what would you see with,
this is so boring for people here,
but you see right there, that's
a delta. So grounded 2,400.
So right here when you're flying
it on the, the two 15, you know,
I'm going to be in the aerospace,
I got to call them and they'll just
give you clearance all the way through.
And then once you learn how
to read this fucking thing,
you can kind of just fly around out here.
Now the rest of the country,
they actually have to
deal with that weather.
See I don't have to deal with because
people like you should just fly across the
country. It's like, this is a dry climate.
I don't have to ever deal with, hey,
everything's do all that it all of
a sudden yet I can't see anything.
There's a brutal fucking call of a guy
who like me is not instrument rated.
Yeah. Which means if the
clouds came in underneath me,
I don't know how to get back down other
than to just shut my eyes and go through
the clouds and hope I fuck. Yeah. Yeah.
So he's up there in the soup is or
whatever the fuck they call it and do this
guy is free. I've got a
dog. And then they fought,
the guy talked him down and then
afterwards he fucking so he lived.
Yeah, but he called the tower.
He goes uh yeah, thanks about,
and the guy says total ice go. Yeah. Well
he goes, what happened up there? Yeah,
you fucking pussy is basically saying
what happened up there as he got involved
in some shit that, that you know,
he wasn't looking for. So that's,
that's the one weird thing about flying
is you learned by other people die
are doing dumb shit cause he died one,
one size going,
she'll be one one time with this guy
was doing a tour in the 44 a Robinson 44
and he had three people then
when he took off, right? Yeah.
I'm fucking just did this really just,
I don't know what, he just didn't go,
like he just ignored everything
you're supposed to do.
He was loaded up with people. He
had, I imagine, you know, a low,
heavy with fuel.
So what you wanna do is you should
forward momentum to get going.
And he just pulled all this fucking
power and as low RPM horn comes on.
And now the weird thing was the chicken,
the passengers, she was going, whew.
Like why did this like
the same fucking note?
So he didn't hear it at first and
all he had to do, he was bank,
come out of the bank,
lower your collective and it'll go
off and then just gradually climb up.
And he did it for a second and
then he pulled it out again.
And it came on again and then
he just started descending. And
your instinct is want to poke
cause you want to go up. Yeah,
she wanna you actually want
to bring you collect it down.
He kept pulling power in
these. Fuck, we're in the
ground. They all fucking died.
Oh fuck man. So I'll take you up.
All right. Girlfriend is pregnant.
Hey Billy sat. It's um, I'm,
I'm 28 years old. Am I? 26 year old
girlfriend just found out she's pregnant.
Now you're saying this dude like
you didn't blow the load dinner.
She found out she's pregnant. Like she
got fucking shingles of something. Uh,
this came as a big sharp
because I previously had a
vasectomy when I was 22. Ah,
there's the ants. Jesus Christ at 22. You,
they had nine kids by then and he never
wanted any here in the second 22 said,
I never had never wanted
kids after she told me,
I went to a urologist who told me I had
regained a sperm count, although rare,
it was not unheard of. When I met
this girl, she changed my life.
I had never trusted her.
Loved any woman the way I do her.
She's the light of my life, but weren't
planning on this. We both have okay jobs,
but living in California is expensive
and adding a third mouth to feed and
paying for doctors visits
will crush us financially.
She doesn't have health insurance.
Do you have any advice for me?
My fear is losing the chance to have
kids with her as this may be a miracle
considering my vasectomy and considered
you waited a long time to have kids.
I want to know if you think this would
be a good for someone in my position to
go through this.
Thanks for taking the time to read this
poorly and probably not under understand
my situation. You will. Great.
Cont uh, the old grey county word,
he used to be.
Love your shows and I hope you here.
I hope to hear more of
your ramblings from you.
Best to you the baby and go fuck
yourself and your gay ass patriots.
All right. Um, can I take this cause
I think that he should do it. Yeah,
I think you do. Don't, don't wait on life
for your financial situation, man. If, if,
if you guys will make it work,
that's what you will make it work.
You'll figure it out. You might not think
that you have enough money right now,
but something like life is constantly
changing and evolving and it's just like
lay off the micro Bruce and
have the kid. Yeah, exactly.
It's like you'll make it work. Just
I think you should, you should.
You should consider it a miracle. Just
like you said, I think it's a great thing.
I'm actually really happy
for you and I think a, put it
this way, I wish, you know,
I wish I didn't wait as long as I did.
And the other day I was watching this,
I was watching this,
uh, this kid's song. Um,
it's just as simple as like
snow flakes, Snow Flake lit. Oh,
snow flakes, no flakes, snow
flake, Dah, Dah, Dah, Dah.
And my daughter was trying to sing it
and she was throwing her head back goes,
Yo. Flags I think wasn't
quite impaired, dude. I,
I had to fight off getting emotional.
Just watching her do that.
She's the most beautiful thing in the
world. And there's nothing, up until then,
anything fucking I've done. Madison
Square Garden was not as good as that,
not eat and not even remotely is he
like lit Madeline's programs like wow,
that's amazing. But that moment
with my daughter, I was like,
this is what life is all about.
100% this is what it's all about.
And then another great thing is you become
a dad and one of the greatest fucking
things ever and some sage advice I
learned from a good dad is he said,
how awesome is cause he goes,
it's not about you anymore.
And at first I kind of took that as
like, you know, cause I'm a very like,
like don't tell me what the fuck to do
idiot sometimes. And then I realized,
uh, uh, how great that is.
Like the other day I finally had a day
off and my wife wanted to go on and go
get some breakfast. She goes, you
want to do that? I was like, no,
finally homeowner to stay home
instead. I was just like, I fuck it.
That's what she wants to do. And we
just went out there and I said, yeah,
it's not about you.
They want to go out to breakfast,
take them out the fucking breakfast.
And I went out to breakfast and I had
a great fucking time and I had a great
time. And it's weird when you're home,
you're a dad or whatever, blah, blah.
But when you go out, you kind of feel more
like a dad. I don't know why. We know,
it's like you can take them out to
dinner or whatever out of the car.
You're walk and she's holding your
hand or you're carrying her. You go in,
you get her in the little booster seat,
he'd get her or whatever.
Like it's usually like a Mac and cheese
or like a cut up hot dog or some shit.
And I assume that she's at that
age and you didn't, you just,
people are looking at the kid and look
how beautiful the kid is and everything.
I know. It's just like, dude, you're in
your element, man. Yeah, no, it's awesome.
I know what's cool. She's really,
really beginning to talk now. So, uh,
yeah it's getting to the point where I
can actually convey to her and she will
understand how much I love her, which is
going to be great cause that's doable.
Yeah. Cause I always say you as how
much I love you. Do you understand that?
And it should just be looking at
you smiling or whatever, but I'll,
I'll actually be able to say it.
She'll be able to understand it. Yeah.
I can't wait.
Can't wait to fucking play catch with her.
I want to teach her how to drive my truck.
Three on the tree.
What kid born in 2018 is going to know
how to work seven. Sorry. No, I know.
I did forget about drivers stick five
three on the column. I took it today.
I took it over to a Jiffy Lube,
which I know a lot of fucking car people
are going to give me shit for that.
You went to Jiffy Lube? Well
I would change it but the,
the way they designed the,
the guy who ever fucking design the
engine did not talk to the guy who fucking
design the frame on that truck.
Because the frame,
there's like literally a piece that
goes from one side or the other right
underneath the fucking plug for the
drain play at Penn. So the only,
it's just a giant fucking mess.
Like when they do what they have to have
this giant thing underneath it and it
comes down and it splashes all over that,
that piece that goes across.
And then they have like this spray thing
and then the air thing that they shoot
all off.
It's like,
I'm going to do that in my garage and
have a fucking oil spill. I can't do it.
I hate it. I used to love doing it
when I was a kid. I used to though.
It was like my favorite thing because I
knew how to do what I would change the
fuel filter. I knew how to do a loop
job and he'll do the whole fucking,
all of that maintenance stuff.
But I never had the balls to start taking
apart the fucking engine or whatever.
But uh, anyways, that's the podcast.
We've got a cigar to smoke. Uh, Hey,
your pick for the Superbowl patriots.
A Rams I think is going to
be the patriots. I really
do think so. I do. I can do
to be honest with you. Like I, I kind of,
I love watching greatness and I know
what people like to hate on the Patriots
and I know I teased you sometimes, but
it's just like, dude, he's, he's so good.
The team is so good man.
And it's like to be able to say that
I watched Michael Jordan wins six.
Like I know I was alive during that and
nobody else has matched that greatness
except for Tom Brady.
Well,
I think it's going to,
I'm going to die a thousand deaths as
always and I really think that, uh,
I mean we're going up against what's
looking like the next bell a check. Uh,
I mean the kitchen big to me, he's
like fucking 33 34 years old. I mean,
it's fucking ridiculous skin dude.
He was our offensive coordinator.
Like we gave him up like he,
we have fucking one of the Goddamn
Gruden's you ain't doing shit. I know.
Felecia coached the browns at one point
and it happens too. It happens. All right.
Uh, that's the podcast.
I'm hoping my patriots win.
I have no idea what's going to happen.
The fucking rams look great.
And I think their quarterback, like
they just don't make quarterbacks away.
They used to like,
they don't come into the league scared.
They just fucking come in like Ah,
whatever. I don't know what it is.
Maybe because they video games and shit
they've already seen. It's like, oh,
I remember that gauge to beat them
all the time and eighth grade.
Now I'm playing him
now he's fucking older.
I'm not scared of any of these
people. All right, I'm rambling.
Can I get my final pitch on the
podcast? Yes guys. Everybody, uh,
my podcast called the 500 with Josh
Adam Meyers join the record book club or
going through the 500 greatest albums of
all time. Bill's done it. Jim Jefferies.
We got to just table Wanda Sykes. Do
an earth wind and fire. It's cool.
It's my fucking favorite
thing I've ever done.
Experience the greatest music of all
time and then here a me and had done a
comic talk shit about it. Not Shit.
We just go through it. I had a great,
listen to it. Check it out. Josh.
Adam Meyers, the 500 all right,
I'll see you on Thursday.