Oh my God, you guys, I have to
tell you this story. So I'm flying.
So I do an episode of Kroll show. Um,
and always working with necro.
You're guaranteed you're gonna laugh
your ass off. I'll fucking bet.
Can I kiss the kid's ass any? I
fucking love him. I think he's,
I think he's a fucking
genius. So anyways, um,
I go, I go to the airport
and I'm taking the red eye,
taking this 10 55 flight, nine fucking
stop. Cause that's how I do it.
All right. I'm on a good plane.
Why would I want to get off it and switch
and roll the dice and get on another
one? You know, let's
just fucking get there.
When I drive up to San Francisco,
I don't pull over and fucking Burbank
and then get hit. No another car.
We get it built. All right? So I
get on the fucking plane, right?
I use my miles, bumped myself up
like a fancy person. You know, maybe,
maybe I invented the cheesecake factory.
People are thinking and then they
see how I'm dressed and I go, oh no,
he didn't vent the cheesecake factory. Um,
and I go to go to sit down on my
seat and I go to set my bag down.
I was going to set it
down right in front of me.
And the nice fellow sit
next to me. He goes,
why don't you stick it in
the middle of this room?
And he moved his bag out of
the way. I'm like, all right,
this guy's a solid dude or whatever.
And then all of a sudden the waitress
comes by as stewardess, whatever.
She comes by, a flight attendant, whatever
the fuck you supposed to call them.
She comes up and she's, uh, can I get
you jealous with Drake? And I was like,
yeah, can I get out? Let me get a
water please. I sir. No ice. What?
However you make it.
Stop acting like it's a fucking
Martini. It's war, right?
Just give me a water
with ice. Thank you. Um,
and the, the guy next to me, he orders
it. Doers. Neat. No ice, no nothing.
Just put it in there so they
bring our drinks, all right.
And I'm really thirsty.
So I start sucking mine down
and he just throws his back.
Like it's nothing like fucking John Wayne
right before he's going to turn around
and beat up three guys, three
moustachioed guys in the 1930s. Right?
So, um, I'm just sitting
there and everybody's getting
on the flight, you know,
when I'm looking around at
the passengers, you know,
fucking doing whatever I'm doing and
all of a sudden the guy next to me,
Mr Doers goes to me, uh, he
goes, excuse me? He goes,
are you afraid to fly? And I
looked at and I was like, what?
He goes, are you afraid
to fly? And I go, no,
no, I'm not. And he goes, he goes, all
right, but you know, it's [inaudible].
He goes, it's okay. You know, it's okay
to tell me if you're afraid to fly.
Okay.
And it's immediately getting weird. And
I'm like, no, I'm not afraid to fly.
And, and I'm thinking in my
head, wait, is he afraid to fly?
And that's why he's drinking
the way he just drank.
And now he's hoping that I'm going
to be afraid to fly. So, you know,
he just wants to open up. That's what
I'm thinking. And I got, I'm like, yeah,
no, I'm not afraid to fly and he
won't leave it alone. He goes,
all right, cause you know,
you're, you're, you're fidgeting,
you're looking around at other passengers.
And I'm just sitting there looking at
it like, is this guy fucking serious?
And I go, no. I go, I'm not afraid to
fly. So now I'm like, fuck this guy.
I'm not talking scaffold rest
of the flight. This guy's
weird man. It's like 30,
just get painted pictures like
32 year old wirey in shape,
but like, why are we white dude?
He's got a skully cap on
with fucking glasses. Um,
[inaudible] you know, and uh,
he goes, uh,
like there's like a minute of silence
and people still getting on the plane and
then he goes, hey, sorry
about that. So we, we just,
we just got off on the wrong foot. He's
like, my name is so and so. He goes,
what's your name? And then I'm thinking
in my head like, what's my name?
My name is frank.
I wanted to give him like a f by just
some reason I just wanted it's bill.
And he goes, Oh hey bill. And
he goes, nice to meet you.
So we shake hands and I'm just looking
at, I don't have any poker face.
I'm looking at the guy like,
what the fuck is your problem?
I'm not even trying to not,
I'm not trying to be pleasant.
I'm already done with this guy. So then
the guy goes, oh hey bill. He goes,
why are you going to
Indianapolis Bill? Right?
Like he's fucking interrogating
me and I, I'm like,
is this guy fucking serious? And I
start doing the math in my head going,
when is this guy like an Air Marshall or
something? And I'm like, no, he's not.
He's fucking slamming Bose
over here. Fuck this guy.
So I just go, I go, look, I don't, I
don't have to answer your questions.
That's it. And I just looked straight
forward [inaudible] he goes, okay,
now I'm concerned. Okay. I am
concerned and I'm looking at,
I'm like concerned about what he
goes, you're fidgeting your, you, you,
you have issues with other
passengers and blah blah blah blah.
He's such a Peyton like,
like this. Like he's been,
I don't know what the
fuck like psychologically
breaking me down. All right,
so now just by this point they've closed
the fucking the door to the fuselage
and we're starting to taxi
and I just finally looked
at the guy and I go,
I go, you know I came up
with the fight one point.
I literally stick my hand out cause he
kept saying I was nervous and I stick my
hand right in front of his
face and I hold it level.
Oh that's what I did the first
time. Yeah. I hold that level. I go,
I'm not nervous. Then he goes,
well not anybody can do that.
And that's when I was like, fuck this
guy. I'm not talking to the guy. Sorry.
Fuck this story up. Then Denny Denny
came back, got my name. Now he's going,
why are you going to Indianapolis? And
I find, look at them. I say, listen pal,
I'm drinking waters. You're
drinking doers. Okay,
there's no issue over here. And
then he goes, it wasn't doers.
What she gave me wasn't doers really.
What was it? Some sort of spy juice.
You fucking jerk off this point.
I want to punch him right through his
fucking stupid wirey glasses, right?
So he's going like, you
look around hostels.
And I said something that just ticked
him off. I was like, yeah, dude. I go,
I don't have to answer your
questions. All right, leave me alone.
And then he goes, uh, he goes to
egos. He starts going like, okay,
now I am really concerned right now. He
goes, why are you going to Indianapolis?
And I just look at him, you
know, when I start doing,
I start doing like this Ryan
Gosling, you know that little Smirk,
that fucking Mano Lisa Smile. He has his,
he smirks his way through all
his fucking movies. I do go,
I go full on Ryan Gosling.
Now I'm not talking to this guy and I
just keep looking at him and I gave him
that little half of smirk and I
just shake my head. That's my game.
Now that's, this is my gets like,
if you're going to be a Dick Right now
with your fucking delusional authority,
right?
That you're going to see like we're in
fucking Guantanamo and you're going to
waterboard me. Huh? There's no water,
there's no board. Go Fuck Yourself.
Here's my smart and I'm just going to
shake my head at you like you're a fucking
pathetic human being. This
is what I'm doing. Alright?
And this is the funny thing. I'm such
a Dick. All I have to say to the guys,
I'm a comedian,
I'm going to do a sold out show there
and that would make them back off,
but I'm a dick. I'm like, fuck this
guy. I want to see where this is going.
So now he's all fucking amped
up and he starts droppingF ,
you know he's saying the
f word. He sitting there
going, if you don't, he goes,
you don't fucking answer my question by
fucking now I'm going to hit that call
button. We're sitting there taxiing
down and fucking getting in line.
I'm going to fucking hit this fucking
button if you blah, blah, blah, blah,
blah,
and I'm just fucking monoliths to smile
smart into shaking my head like you are
a fucking retard, right?
So now he sees saying the efforts so
much the way who sitting in front of me
diagonally in front,
right in front of him,
turns around and looks at us and
now my heart's racing. I'm like,
where's this going? This is going to
be great. I am 100% fucking innocent.
This guy's drunk and I think he's
going to hit that button. Oh,
I've got a feeling he's going to hit that
button. What's going to happen? Right?
I want to see what the pilot looks like.
Let's see where the fuck this is going.
Right? So he goes, you don't
fuck you. He starts eating.
He starts bringing his hand
up to the button going,
I'm going to hit that button. You
don't have to go fucking do it.
I'll hit that button and I'm sitting there
smirking and I'm thinking in my head,
go ahead and hit the fucking
button. Let's see what happens.
Let's see what happens. Right.
So filing now he wants to hit the button
and he can't fucking find it and it's
an in defense of him. I couldn't find
it either. I was looking up there,
I half wanted to hit it
myself. Then he finally,
he finally finds it and he hits
it right? And now I'm just like,
Holy Shit, what's going to happen?
And he sitting there going, yeah, Huh,
you want to fucking play this game and
you want to fucking play this game.
And I was surprised.
I mean it took like fucking like 30
seconds before a flight attendant,
the one who gave him the booze, which
evidently wasn't booze comes over.
And at this point we're like doing
that shit where we're behind a plane,
we're almost ready to take off,
like we're pulling up and
then stop and pull it up,
then stop in as planes take taken off.
So she goes, yeah, what's the problem?
Over here. And he goes, ah,
I'm not comfortable to fly
with this guy. This guy,
he's fidgeting, he's looking around at
other fucking people, but blah, blah,
blah, blah. He's doing
all this thing, right.
And then the stewardess looks at me and
I'm just sitting there fucking my little
smart, just shaking my head.
And I just looking at this
dude just shaking my head like,
this guy's out of his fucking
mind. I don't say a word.
And this guy goes on and on and
on about his fucking psychobabble,
about how I'm the security risk.
So she goes to the, so she goes, okay. Um,
any other passengers?
Have you noticed anything?
She talked to anybody
first-class at this point.
Does anybody noticed
anything odd about this guy?
And The lady who was sitting right in
front of the dude diagonally from me turns
around. She goes, yeah, I've been
listening to this guy brew right,
Berating this other passenger.
She's on my side and I haven't
said a fucking word. This is great.
And I'm just sitting there smirking.
Then the let students looks at me
and I shrugged my shoulders like,
I don't know what to tell
you. So finally she said, sir,
do you have anything to add to
this? And I just said, I look,
I'm just a guy trying to go to
Indianapolis. This guy over here,
he starts slamming his doors. I kind
of felt like a rat when I said that.
He goes, he's slamming his
doors. Next thing you know,
he's dropping the F bomb to me. Then
I'm thinking, oh fuck. I just said bomb,
right. Fortunately nothing
happens. So now another fucking,
the male stewardess comes over right
now. He's going like, what's going on?
And the captain of the
fucking now at this point,
we pulled over and the plane has stopped.
250 people trying to get to
Indianapolis and jerk off over here.
Can't hold his fucking alcohol. Who
just watched a person of interest every,
every, I guess, evidently I have no
fucking idea. Now the plane is stopped.
His fucking jerk off his,
stopped the plane interrogating
a Goddamn comedian.
Like I'm in the fucking Taliban and
like he works for the CIA, right?
So now we're just sitting there,
okay.
And the captain is up front in the plane,
like saying to the stewards
is going basically relaying,
do I really have to
fucking come back there?
This is the last flight in the night.
Is there really a God damn problem?
And that was the vibe. And they finally
said to the [inaudible], sit next to me,
are you going to be okay to fly with him?
And at that point it appeased his fucking
ego that he was somehow in control.
And he goes like, you know what? Okay,
it's fine. It's fine. It'll be fine.
It'll be fun. So they go, okay.
So now the plane's going again and now
we're now we fucking come around and he's
sitting there fucking, he's in my
ear. And at this point I am laugh,
like to fucking laugh. You hear me doing
the podcast? That's what I'm doing.
And he's sitting there going, I, he
goes, you don't, I'm glad. I'm glad you,
I hope he fucking do. I hope
you fucking try something.
I'll be fucking try something
when we're up there.
I really hope you fucking try something.
And I'm just fucking like God,
Boston laughing. Shake him at like,
what are you gonna fucking do to me?
What are you gonna do to me? How are
you going to punch me in the face?
You fucking wirey jacket
with your fucking glasses on.
You know, that's a federal offense.
You're going to go to jail if you do
that or something. I don't know what.
Right. So I'm just in a fucking
laughing at the guy going, I actually,
at one point I put my fucking little
eye pillow thing on, you know,
like I'm going to sleep. I had
that out too when the store,
this was talking to me, I was like
putting it on is this total mind fuck.
Like I don't know what this guy is. I'm
just trying to go on to Indianapolis.
I'm going to sleep. And um, so I got,
I got my fucking eye thing on right as
he sitting there threatening me, just,
I was going with total passive
aggressive. It's like, dude,
I'm so not concerned with you. I'm
literally putting a blindfold on. Alright,
so this fucking guy, like
he starts going, he goes,
yeah. He goes, you think you fucking
won this, you fucking won this. He goes,
Mike, you know my dad is my dad.
He started saying his dad's
some major CEO in Indianapolis.
Does it sound like a fucking made up
story? I swear to God, this is all true.
He Goes, Mike, my dad is a
major CEO in Indianapolis in La.
Have you fucking arrested? And
The lady turns around again,
how have you fucking arrested
the second weekend on the ground?
I'm thinking like, for what?
For what? Sitting here,
you fucking lose her. Learn how
to hold your alcohol. Right?
And he starts describing the view that
I'm going to have when I go to jail,
like some fucking law and order
episode. Oh, you're gonna love it.
You'll be able to see Lucas oil field
and blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
And I'm just sitting here cracking up
laughing and then there's this pause,
right? And I'm thinking finally he finally
shut the fuck up. It's like a three,
four minute pause. He finally just gave
up because I wasn't giving him anything.
I was just laughing and shaking my
head. I was being a dick to him.
I was cause I was enjoying it and then
there was like a three minute pause and
then all of a sudden he just goes, why
are you going to Indianapolis Bill?
Okay
so we're like 20 minutes into the flight
and am I going to be honest, he was,
my adrenaline was so
going during all of that
because I knew I didn't do anything wrong,
but I thought we were literally going to
go back and it was going to be fucking
cops there. And they like if, if, if,
if the fucking stewardess or the pilot
asked me who I am and where I'm going,
I'm going to tell him I respect your
authority. You're just some, Gee I don't,
you don't have any fucking authority.
I don't have to answer your questions.
It was pro was one of the most
fun experiences I've ever
had with another human.
Like when somebody thinks that they have
power and you know they don't and all
they can do is try just keep bluffing
and raising their voice and start cursing
at you. And if you just
start laughing at them,
the look on their face
is fucking priceless.
So
the last thing he said, he said, why are
you going to Indianapolis Bill? Right.
And I fucking started howling.
Just fucking holding my stomach,
shaking my head.
Yeah.
And with my fucking eye
pillow thing on right.
And I know I'm going to get a ton
of shit that I wear one of those,
I fucking underrated. Get the one at
Brookstone where it's literally a pillow.
I'm telling you, you could fall asleep
12 noon facing the sun. It's awesome.
So anyways, like after he, he asked me
what, what, you know where you're going,
Bill, you like there was like a 10 minute,
like probably 10 minutes had gone by and
I can't fucking sleep because it's so
fun and in me, I can't wait to tell
the story to every comic. I know.
I can't wait to try it on stage to
see if it's funny or whatever. Uh,
so finally I just like got fuck it.
Maybe I'll just get on my computer and I
bring up my eye pillow and I like,
I got to look at the guy cause I know
he's fucking staring at me waiting for me
to do something right. So I lift it up,
I get my fucking Monalisa smiled going
and I look over at the guy and dude,
he is fucking passed out.
Okay.
He looked like he got shot.
He was sitting there like his head was
just hanging straight down and anytime
the plane move like his
head was, I mean he,
the way you got knocked out and for the
rest of the fucking flight all fucking
uh oh what's Matt Damon's
character? Jack Ryan.
Whole fucking Jack Ryan over here
is just, you know the sky marshal,
the fucking Bose bag and God
knows what else he was on.
He was just completely out passed out
for the rest of the fucking flight.
And this is why I'm on to Dick. I am,
I was having so much fun with this guy.
I start, I can't sleep,
so I start slamming waters because I want
to have to get up and take a piss just
to see if this guy's going to freak out
because this security risks is getting
up. And this, the joke was on me,
he never regained consciousness.
And then I really had to take a
pest, but I'm such a stubborn fuck.
I was holding it because I wanted to
make sure he was awake when I got up,
cause that was going to give him a little
smirk and then I was going to get up
CV at the call button
again. Um, but he didn't,
he didn't wake up til we
hit the ground. And um,
and then it's funny. Then he woke
up and it was like four hours later,
so now he'd kind of slept off
whatever the fuck this guy was on.
Yeah.
And I'm sitting there smart and waiting
for the guy to start talking to me.
He won't look at me and I,
and I think at that point
he kind of fucking realized
that maybe he got a little
, uh, a little extra little too patriotic.
So we stop,
we stopped with the gate and
everything and we're going to get up.
So I grabbed my shit.
I get up and I'm just kinda looking
at him and he won't look at me.
And then the lady who was sitting in front
of me had this big smile on her face.
She goes, hi. She goes, I don't,
I don't want good. I go that I go,
that was an interesting one. And I
said it really loud. So the guy heard,
and he didn't say anything, and t this
is what he did to try to save face.
His pillow was kinda stuck behind,
was kind of stuck behind his
shoulder and like a weird place.
So he was frustrated with it.
So he ripped it out from behind him
and kind of threw it down on the floor,
went [inaudible] like tried to do some
caveman grunt to try to still have some
sort of, I don't know what. So,
so that was my flight to
Indianapolis people. Um,
how far into the fucking
podcast are we? That was a long,
that was a long fucking story.