Hey, what's, [inaudible] Jesus. Hey,
what's going on? The fuck was that?
It's Bill Burr and it's time for the
Thursday afternoon. Just before Friday,
Monday morning podcast.
And
I'm just checking in on you.
So I just woke up.
I had a frog in my throat. Oh, Billy.
No Vice William without 12 days in here.
No booze, no cigars. Although you wouldn't
know what that frog, Ej said my throat.
No, nothing. Ah, he's
being a foe. Billy Angel.
I'm going to open for Chris Angel
out there and a fucking Vegas.
I'm going to sit there and just wag
my finger at everybody in the crowd.
Tell them how they live in a life of vice.
I got to tell you people
when you find Christ, um,
I got into the,
the mornings.
The mornings are the best when you lived
a vice free life the night before you
wake up. It's amazing the birds
to sing it a little louder.
There's a few more nooks and crannies
in your fucking English muffin.
She'd sit there watching the
melted into it.
Um, yeah, I you don't have
to. Mornings are great.
I am bored out of my fucking mind
at night out of my mind. Bored.
Um, anyways, let's, uh,
let's put, you know,
here's one for sobriety. Now, one of
those fucking poor bastards at Aa.
Just sit there, Chow and donuts and
smoking cigarettes. They need something.
They got, they're trying to
get a buzz, nicotine, sugar,
something to break up
the fucking monotony.
Yeah, let me gay. Yeah.
Fucking tell glazed the
fucking jelly doughnut,
just shoving it down their pile.
Um,
that's the worst thing about opening
Pandora's box because once you fucking do
that,
then uh,
you just know how much fun
you could be having. You know,
he's just sitting around playing
fan tan or something like that,
drinking a Goddamn Arnold Palmer.
You know, I remember one time
I was hanging out with this guy,
I'm not gonna name the name of the person,
but he was hanging out with
this super fucking legendary,
famous fucking rockstar that
dude had never got married,
never had any kids or whatever. And I
remember hanging out with that guy and he,
and he could not,
it was all these beautiful women around.
He was barely looking at him.
He could not have been more bored because
he had gone so far down that fucking
road.
Like what?
Literally what it took at that point to
even keep the pilot light going in his
fucking eyes. I'm not going
to sit here with this fucking,
hang on a second.
Sorry.
I had to clear my throat there. I want
to fuck did I hit stop instead of pause.
Now I'm going to edit those two
things together. You know what it is.
It's when you're living as clean as I am,
the toxins through years of abuse start
to come to the surface and your body is
reading them.
Cleansing them.
Yeah.
Um, anyways, yes to this
guy. Well, he was just like,
there wasn't any woman in there
that could turn his fucking head.
There wasn't a joke that could make
them smile. This guy just, he just,
he went too far.
I went too far down the hall.
He got pulled out and now he's just
sitting there just fucking bored.
Yeah.
You know, I mean I had
a fucking, you know,
once you participate in like an orgy
and you're the only male participant,
I just don't understand like why,
you know,
what the fuck does that guy do?
Hey,
you want to go to Brunch?
Yeah.
You know, hey, let's go, uh,
let's go to this. Go to a game.
Let's go to this arena that you
sold out and had an orgy and,
and let's go watch other people fucking
chase a puck. You want to go do that?
There's like nothing you could
suggest to this guy. He'd have to,
you know that that guy like his next
fucking move to get his adrenaline going
would probably be do that red bull jump.
We,
you just falling from outer space.
Um, anyways. I don't know what the
fuck I'm talking about, but that said,
that's what you expect.
So what you expect at this one,
I expect out of this podcast
and that's what's wrong with America.
Americans podcasting with absolutely
no expectations on how well the show's
going to go. All right, let's talk.
Let's Talk Yankees Red Sox. Oh,
it's heating up again.
Okay.
The Red Sox raped the keys 14
to one on Monday or whatever.
Was it Monday? I'm sorry.
Tuesday. All right.
Remember I remember when
I was a kid to be like,
they should save these runs for tomorrow.
Like you can save runs.
And then yesterday our stat and pitch
your price, he got hurt or something.
So our pitcher was shit yesterday
and the Yankees ended up winning, uh,
which is fine. Um, there's
like 9 million games left,
but I think it was really stupid of the
red sox to get into a fight with them.
That fight was, was good for the Yankees
because they're not as good at team.
They got bats, but they
don't have pitching. And
pitching is always gonna win.
Come October. You don't need to
get involved in that stupid shit.
And um, and we did. So now they have,
now they're all fucking loads.
They're all fucking excited.
You don't do that. You know, the guy
wants to slide like that. I mean,
up until last year, that
was legal. Who gives a shit?
Who gives a shit to strike the guy out,
have them sit down with this
big fucking stupid face.
I hate baseball players in this stupid
fighting where everybody comes out and
piles on each other and uh,
nobody does the A,
you're lucky you're holding me back
better than fucking baseball players.
Maybe basketball players, I
don't know. That's stupid.
After the fight and there's like two
guys holding you back and then you still
have to do that stupid charge, you
know, you're not going to get there.
It's over
button your shirt and go to the showers.
Um,
but anyways, when we were getting
killed and we still liked,
it was almost like the Yankees
couldn't score enough runs.
So we have bats and we have pitched you,
we're in a great position.
Why would we get involved
in that Tom Foolery?
I mean this is sober built talking.
Yeah.
Oh,
you know,
it's so stupid is in the middle of the
fight that you just see this guy going.
Yeah, yeah. Kid Shot Red Sox Fan.
Can we retire that stupid shit already.
It's like,
it's, it's like fucking men
sharing candidate level.
Like the second anything happens,
you've got to start chanting that. Okay.
Um, not that Yankee fans are
innocent. That stupid 19, 18 forever.
And then when they,
the one that champ was over,
then they switched it to a Boston saw,
which is the worst shit
ever. Um, I don't know.
There's so much of it that it just makes
me want to hit mute. The sweet Caroline,
the Yankees suck chant,
all of that stuff.
It just says to me that people do not
think for themselves and that fucking mob
mentality,
I don't like the Yankees,
but we beat them.
The movie is over.
It's over bro. Credits.
We won the world series.
They are now reduced to go at, Hey,
remember what we did last century.
Remember that?
I mean,
it's what they've been reduced to.
Why would you like make them actually
feel that they hold some sort of position
by continuing to chant?
Yankees suck. They don't chuck,
they're a good fucking team and I love
the way that they've built from their
farm team and then added that big
free agent from Miami or Florida,
her fucking, uh, Tuscaloosa, whatever
the fuck they call themselves now.
MMM.
Opiate Showbie the Okeechobee
Marlin's. Um, I like what they've done.
They don't suck.
And I think that Aaron Boone is going
to be a great manager and I look forward
to the competition between both teams
and who gives a fuck? Either we win
or they win or somebody else wins.
Who gives a shit?
Just enjoy the fucking game.
Don't go there and be a fucking mouth
breather. And for the love of God,
will you sit down when they
play that stupid sweet Caroline?
How many fucking times can you do it
by
the fucking Yankee fence at this
cigarette? Fucking why MCA. I,
you know what? I want to, I should,
I shouldn't go this heart. You know,
it's for the kids. It's tradition.
It's what brings people together.
I don't know. I thought the Yankees did
pretty good before they had this thing,
that fucking song during
the seventh inning.
And this stupid grounds crew doing
the little twirly twirl. Oh my God,
I'm such a continent. Um, anyways,
I'm sure Dan Shaughnessy is very excited
that it's heated up again and you can
actually write about the sport that he
knows about and ignore the Bruins playoff
run.
Why do I always pick on Dan Shaughnessy?
I don't hate that guy.
I just like picking on him because I
will never forgive that fucking guy for
after 2004 when we won and then 2005,
we were in first place in September.
We got a bunch of injuries
which clearly affected the team.
And then the $200 million Yankees I
believe ended up coming in passing us.
And Shaughnessy is like, is the
curse back. I was like right there.
You're not a red sox fan.
You're just not.
You're a guy making money off of misery.
Um,
you're your own little corporation,
you know,
profiting off of war in a sports sense.
Jesus bill, you went big there. Yes,
I did. And I'll do it again. Anyways,
the Bruins playoff run starts tonight
and I have a lot of nerve given Shaun to
see shit considering I may be
watched four games this year. Um,
now that I got the little one and uh,
we're playing the Toronto Maple leafs
and those poor bastards are going to
have to fucking endure the highlight reel
of what happened the last time we played
them and just know that I was at that
fucking game. Um, I
actually know something.
It's funny, I feel like maple
leaf fans hate the Bruins.
Um, and uh, I don't hate the May
police. I actually liked the maple leaf.
I hate the Canadians.
That's it.
In a couple of knee breakers on
the penguins. Other than that,
and not even at the penguins have knee
breakers insists that they then turn
around and complain, but somebody
gets a little rough on the other team.
They were attacking Sydney.
They bug me. Um, that's it. Other than
that, I don't have a problem with anybody.
I'm looking forward to wonderful.
A seven game series.
We'll see how it goes, but uh, it
comes on at four o'clock. Here I am.
I'm balancing my entire fucking schedule.
Is that it?
Is that I always said my
entire fucking schedule is, uh,
is going to be based around that. My
daughter takes a nap from three to five,
so I figure I'll get to watch
the first period and then,
um, and then I'll probably
be fucked. Whose kid? No. Um,
I'm actually flying to the Rio tomorrow.
I'm flying out to Charlotte
for the rough and rowdy fight.
I'm going to be commentating,
watching regular people's
Americans on Americans fighting.
There's going to be over 40 fights and
I'm feeling that this is going to be like
when I did the Joe Rogan
Doug Stan Hope, uh,
end of the universe
podcasts on election night.
That's the vibe that I feel
like it's going to be going on.
So I'm just going to be,
I'm trying to get in as
many jokes as I can't.
It's already entertaining while getting
out of the way of the action. Um,
I'd never done any shit like this.
I remember when I was a kid,
my mother thought I should
be a sports commentator.
I don't think she pictured me doing,
starting my career in an event like this,
but I'm looking forward to
it. I really am. And uh,
it's a $15 paper view unless
you wait till the day of.
So today's the last day we
can get a flight 1599. After
that it goes up to 1999.
But if you're a college kid,
you know, a couple of two,
three your fence throwing like
five and a half bucks each.
Get yourself a Domino's pizza
and whatever else you want to do
as Mike goal liquid,
say an adult beverage and uh,
enjoy the fights. Um, anyways,
plowing ahead here. Uh,
I've started my workout,
my serious,
my theories workout regimen to somehow
stave off the fact that I'm turning 50
and fucking June the big photo.
But Ba,
ba Ba ba Ba,
you fucking fucking old you fucking balls.
Hey Dan to the,
um,
I actually feel fortunate to be,
to have made it this long considered
has got a bunch of my friends did not.
And then also the direction
we seem to be going here.
Why are we bombing Syria?
Why are we going to do this?
How much further into this fucking
Middle East shit are we going to go?
I don't understand why France, US, Russia,
all of these fucking people.
Why the fuck do we keep
intervening over there?
You know what I mean?
People have been fighting with each other
forever and then we're going to come
in, hey, settle down. Settle down.
Give us the oil. Settle down.
You shouldn't do that to what another
give us the oil stopped doing that.
Frances President Emmanuel Macron says
he has proof that the Syrian government
attack the town of Doma
with chemical weapons.
Last weekend he said he would decide
in due course whether to respond with
airstrikes. Um, I don't
know how these guys,
world leaders do that
shit. It's like, you know,
you're gonna respond with the airstrikes
and they're not all going to land on
the people that did it. And then you
have to go to bed that night going like,
well, I think most of them landed on
the people that were guilty. You know,
the others landed in a food court.
I think that's why they age. Um,
although I think Donald Trump is going
to age wonderfully during his presidency
because I don't think he
really understands the
ramifications of what the fuck
it is that he's saying or doing.
Um,
who fucked tweets about when a country's
going to strike another countries and
that's supposed to kind of be a secret
or the way he's trying to do the
three card Monte. It could be now.
It could be not at all or maybe later.
You know, it's funny, there's probably
Syrian people actually looking at his,
at his tweets,
you know, like, uh,
like looking at it like, like
they found clues. I'm sorry,
I just got this fucking email.
These goddamn fucking state of Wisconsin
just hit me with this huge goddamn tax
bill at. It's like, how the fuck do I
owe you guys all that God their money.
Yeah, I know. I know why they hit me
with that shit. I know why. I know why.
Because we're spending money in this
country in a bunch of other shit.
So then I come down there and
they fucking pull the pants down.
They give Oh freckles a good spank.
And before I leave the state.
That's like a new thing.
All of these scams do you
know in Pittsburgh they had
an entertainment tax for
awhile.
If you are an entertainer,
you spun plates and
you went to Pittsburgh,
they taxed you for entertaining people.
Literally doing your job.
When I was in Saint Louis one time I was
in a hotel and I actually took the time
to look at the bill and this,
the city of Saint Louis or the
state of Missouri charged me.
Uh, what the fuck did they call it? A,
an occupation tax on the room.
They tax me for occupying the room.
They just shaking like fucking third 20,
30 bucks out of your pocket.
We'll take that.
Thank you for coming here. Did you
get a chance to visit the fucking Oh,
um, I don't know. I'll tell you.
It's all the God damn scam.
What am I gonna do?
Am I going to take on a whole fucking
state? Michael Moore would do it.
Um, all right. The penguins, Jesus Christ.
What they went 18 did nothing
against the fucking fly is, um,
I didn't get to watch any
of the hockey last night.
I was editing season
three of f is for family.
Um, I think, I'm just going
to tell you right now,
and I can say this with total confidence.
This is without a doubt our best season.
It's a,
it's a noticeable jump between
the first and second seasons.
Um, and I can't wait for you guys
to see it, but it's animation.
So I'm be like Donald Trump.
You could be seeing these
episodes soon or maybe later.
Possibly not at all.
Or maybe they're on right now.
She got a giant fucking to pay.
Like he doesn't have to pay.
I think he did a comb over and then he
did some hair plugs and they didn't work.
But now the hair plugs of better
and I think maybe they worked,
but then he just has to kind of commit
to the comb over.
You know, I actually think
he kind of has a nice air,
you know, the way he gets died, all
golden when it goes orange, it's bad.
Bonnie is like the golden sort
of fucking a stray cats haircut.
You know, we're going to bomb this town
bomb. It is sad. I think it's a, uh,
I think it's a good look.
I could see him with like an upright bass.
I want to get one of those fucking, what'd
you guys do if somehow I got fucking,
oh, I actually cave and I get
fucking hair plugs, right?
And I add a giant red stray cats
fucking hairdo out of nowhere.
No, not out of nowhere. You would,
you would notice it like
pictures of me after shows going,
what's going on with
the top of bird's head.
And I refuse to like when
someone's slowly transitioning,
there's that thing of like, wow,
that's an interesting outfit.
And then people started, are you trend?
And then finally they'd say, yeah,
you know what I am.
I would,
I would do what Bruce Jenner
did except to my hair.
All right,
but what if I never fucking addressed it?
What if I never went on and talked
to Diane Store Sawyer? You know,
and just sat there going,
I was sorry I was story.
What if I never did that and refused
to ever address my new coauthor fucking
here and I tried to just, I
just, I erased all my podcast.
Any fucking evidence of me ever admitting
that I went bald and I would just say
that I was just refused to,
you know,
like Turkey when they refuse to
see. Yeah, that never happened.
If you say it happened,
you go into jail.
Okay.
How much would I be getting heckled
if I came out with a fucking ric flair
haircut?
Oh fuck. You know something
I was talking about Moto GP
and the, uh, what was it?
The Art Argentina Grand
Prix. Is that where it was?
What a fucking race that was.
I don't even, I don't even,
I haven't watched racing enough to
even understand what the fuck happened.
And I was dealing with my kids and all
of a sudden the race starts and there was
like one person in the front row and
nobody in like 30 rows back or something
like that.
And then a bunch of people in the back,
Mark Marquez had stalled this bike.
So according to the rules that you had
to leave and go restart it or something.
And he was driving around in circles,
refusing to fucking leave.
Um, so then he ended up, those race starts
okay.
And he gets penalized or
penalized depending on what
part of the country you're
from.
He got penal lies and he goes to the back
of the race and this fucking guy just
row. And he was like, I swear to God,
he was like 40 seconds ahead of everybody
who's going to win the race going away.
It was one of those tracks where it was,
uh,
it was still wet or whatever and he was
just riding way faster than everybody
else. I don't know how. And uh,
they said, hey buddy, buddy,
you a, you've got to go to the
back of it. This is so stupid.
I didn't want him talking about you
got to go to the back of the race.
So they send them all the way to the back,
goes to the pits first,
and then they send them to the back of
the race because he fucking ran over this
guy.
You know, he basically, yeah,
went to go pass somebody who's,
he's bumping them out of the way,
like they're in cars except around
motorcycles. And he would wave like,
sorry about that,
that and continue on. And
they're like, hey buddy,
you got to go to the back of the
fucking race, right. The first time.
I think today they, he bumped
into somebody that made
them sit there in the pits.
I don't remember. They,
they, they, they, they
penalizes guy so many fucking times.
Long story short,
he went from first place
all the way to last.
So now he's blowing by everybody
and he gets up to Valentino Rossi,
who's basically the Wayne Gretzky,
uh,
the Lewis Hamilton to fucking person
you're not supposed to touch a fuck with.
And he's trying to get around them and
Valentino Rossi. He's like, fuck you.
You're not getting around
me. And, uh, rather than,
than waiting for a straight away,
he tried to pass him on a turn.
Eddie just fucking slammed into him and
Valentino got pushed to the outside and
he had control the bike, but then he went
on the grass and he wiped out the fee,
uh, fell off his bike and Marquez turns
around waves like, sorry, pop that right.
Valentino gets up, he's Italian, he
goes up on blah blah, blah blah. Right.
And then he picks his bike up. Now he's
ride, no, all the Valentino Rossi fins.
Like what the fuck is with this guy?
Mark?
Mark has gets penalized again I believe.
And uh,
so at the end of the fucking race,
Marquez walks down with somebody
else to Valentino's a pit area,
whatever they call it, the pageant, I
forget what they call it because of the p.
And Valentina is like, oh my God,
I am like, so not talking to you,
some of the mechanic or the chief
fucking steward stewardess down there or
something. He's yelling at Marquez
and Marquez ends up walking away.
And then Valentino Rossi said he wasn't
man enough to come down by himself.
He came down with somebody else,
blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
And I'm sitting there agreeing with
Valentino Rossi and then all of a sudden
everybody starts sending all these
fucking highlights from like three years
earlier when Rossi basically donkey kick
to Mark Marquez off his fucking bike or
out of the goddamn race or something
like that. So it's, it just seemed like,
um, Lewis Hamilton behavior where
it's like, it's okay if I do it,
but if you do it,
you're a fucking asshole and now I'm
going to have a hissy fit about it.
So I think I like Mark Marquez
better. You know, I respect Rossi.
You know the little I know about the
sport being the legend that he is a,
but I like Marquez. Fuck it. If he
did that two years earlier, yeah,
pass them on to turn,
knock him off his bike and give
them a wave. Who gives a shit?
I'm telling you guys, you
miss it out or this, this,
all of this took place in like 25 laps.
You can watch your race in like 40
minutes and you can watch these,
these unbelievable,
this unbelievable fucking sport.
I can't even tell you how
sold I am on motor GP. Um,
just to let you know,
there's moto GP two and three and they're
all going to get recorded and there's
going to be like five recordings of
them and there's a chance your, your,
your recorder's going to shut off,
which is what would have happened to me.
I would have missed the
end of the fucking race.
But fortunately I got to watch it live.
Um,
I don't understand. Trying to take one
of those races is practically impossible,
so I have to make sure I don't,
I don't lose the one here.
The Motogp of the Americas
is what they call it.
Why don't they say they say Argentina?
You know,
they say they say Italy,
why can't we say USA?
You know, what are we embarrassed? The
Americas? Where is it? Canada, Mexico,
Falkland Islands. Um,
anyways, check it out. If,
if you get a chance, um, you know,
usually this is the time when I actually
do a read or something and it's just I
don't have any advertising,
you know what I mean?
I'm like that real housewife on the real
housewives that just trashes too many
fucking people and then the,
you know,
just doesn't have any friends anymore.
Um,
that's where the advertising
is slowly going okay.
On this podcast and
yeah,
I am, now that I've cleaned
up my act as far as my,
you know,
offstage behavior,
I am now going to clean up this
podcast in an effort to try to get my
advertising back.
Yeah.
I am not going to have any
sort of opinions. Okay.
Just stop right now and just talk about
how amazing and strong women are and how
whatever,
look at your,
your girlfriend or wife right now and
just look at whatever she's doing and just
realize how strong she is and really
just take time in your day to understand
how amazing women are
and how right they are and how
they do nothing wrong whatsoever,
ever.
And if they do something wrong,
just know that it's because
of something that you did.
I want everybody to close their eyes
and talk to Jesus right now.
Should I go that far? No, I
think that'd be too limiting.
I think if I just say
positive things about women.
Yeah,
I can't do this.
Fucking annoys the shit out of me.
A clutch. Is there anything
more annoying than a clutch?
It goes to my house. I don't have any
pockets. Can you hold all my shit?
Hey, why don't you bring
one of your fucking bags?
Why did you bring a bunch of
one of those recycling bags?
Once you throw that over
your fucking outfit,
maybe you'd be making some
new fashion statement, right?
Like back in the day when women will
wear business suits and fucking sneakers
put on something nice and then have
like a little fucking grocery bag.
You don't stick sticks to
call your shit in there. Yeah.
Giant fucking fucking cell phone.
I already have my cell phone in my pocket.
You want to meet you to radiate fucking
both sides of my scrotum. I mean,
not to mention my taint. Do you have any
sort of consideration for me whatsoever?
I am.
I just a fucking pack mule,
right?
Once you get a smaller phone,
you're gonna walk around with a clutch.
I say you go back to a flip phone.
That's what I say.
That's my big controversial
fucking take on this Thursday.
Uh, playoff hockey tonight.
Everybody playoff hockey.
The third game of the Red Sox Yankees,
90 million games that we're
going to play this year.
I got 50 bucks on every game with,
uh, my booking agent and, uh, Paul Versey
and I called the two of the panic
brothers because that first game,
they will literally go in like with
done. I'll they guy was so screwed. Uh,
bullpens,
admit the Yankees had major problems
and they'd like literally the next game.
It's just like, dude, we'll
go to the world series.
And then all of a sudden fucking,
uh,
Hanley Ramirez had set grand slam and
we'd go down from being like fucking down
eight to two and now it's eight to six.
And then it was all of a sudden,
it's like if we blow this, the
pulpits, the problem, it's like, dude,
there's this 150 games left.
I can't fucking do this.
But it's so funny to watch the Yankee fans
act like how red sox fans used to act.
Um,
they don't have any swag or anymore.
They're a bunch of fucking
nervous nellies. It's tremendous.
Which is why, once again,
we shouldn't have gotten to
that stupid fight with them.
Stupid. Why give them an emotional
point to rally around you.
The better Goddamn team.
But it doesn't mean that the better teams
going gonna win. It doesn't mean it.
Because when you start getting
involved in that stupid shit,
it's fucking baseball.
Nobody's going to get hurt.
Everybody's gonna come running out.
I was wanting to talk to people like
who come running out of the bullpen,
you know? Is there like a knowing
that by the time you get there,
like the fights already been over
for fucking three minutes, you know,
and you can tell the way they come
running out. It's like, what are you,
you're going to just so you're
going to be sitting there,
you're not pitching that day,
right? You're blowing bubbles.
You're coming up with fucking games.
You can play to get through the fucking
GAM thinking I'm looking at something
green and your buddies
guy art green monster. No.
Uh, their persons, a red sox
Saint Paddy's Day hadn't. Ah,
right. And all of a sudden
you're like, is that a fight?
Is that a fight in the phone?
Fucking rings. Hey Buddy. Yeah.
I don't know if you noticed,
but there's like a 40 on 40 fight
about a but a football field away.
Why don't you come out to it?
It's good.
It's going to look good
for the team in half.
And he gets up without fucking stretching
and you see them jog out there.
They're not going to come running
out there full fucking full speed.
They're going to pull a hamstring.
They're going to throw a punch and fuck
up their hand. They can't, their pictures,
their pitches, you, you, you're looking
at a Ken doll. It's, he, it's got it.
There's no fucking, uh, no genitalia.
It's running out with that.
Every once in awhile you see somebody
come running out and that's usually the
fucking warmup. Catchers, that
guy will come flying out of there.
He's got to do something to keep, make
sure he stays on the Goddamn team, right?
That guy only catches the knuckle
baller. He's like, oh Geez,
is I get to do something?
Right?
Anyways,
a rough and Rowdy Charlotte,
North Carolina in the house
that ric flair built. Um,
I cannot fucking wait and I am actually
going out to buy a little habit dash for
the fucking, uh, I'm, I'm going
all out for this thing and uh,
it's going to be a great fucking time.
All right?
It's going to be as great as
every woman on the planet is.
They're just great people.
Every single one of them.
None of them needs to do any
sort of self examination.
Anything that they're doing,
it's because of the man that's in their
life or maybe a man who isn't even in
their life.
Maybe a man that they've never even met
before is the reason for their behavior.
Um, that's it. Everybody have a great
weekend. And Go fuck yourselves.
You con and I will.
I will talk to you on Monday.
I look forward to high level competition
tonight between the Boston Red Sox in
the New York Yankees.
Alright,
see Ya.
[inaudible]
[inaudible] call you back
this way.
[inaudible]
cool.
It's like a boss.
Here's the story,
lady
gotta beat. Marsha. Got To get closer
than a quarter of an inch rubber.
That one Greg Brady
striving that fucking caprice classic or
whatever the fuck they had whipping it
around the parking lot.
I get closer than an engineer.
Marsha,
making fun of how broad can't drive
one of my favorite fucking episodes.
Well,
that's a typical male chauvinist reaction.
You prejudice against women drivers.
So I'm now not as long as they
stay off the roads, you prejudice.
It's not prejudice, it's just that
men are naturally superior drivers.
Two favorite episodes was the first half.
Not that Brady Bunch episode.
When Greg Brady was bringing the
fucking hammer down and it was gone.
Let me tell you three fucking
stepsister bitches something.
None of you brides know how to drive
and that includes your mother who I'm
banging by the way,
who I'm banging by the way.
All right. With her weird ass
haircut, whatever the fuck you know.
But um, yeah, I had a date
with them and you know, it was,
I kind of felt like I was,
if you were in school
and I were the teacher,
did anybody ever have that fucking
haircut at other than her? I mean,
that is like,
I don't know what it was.
She took like Mo from the three stooges
haircut and then she put a fucking sort
of mullet that she did a little
flip too on the back. Anyways,
let's get back to you brought,
so you don't know how to fucking drive.
That goes for you with the
fucking speech impediment.
You don't know how to fucking drive
Jan with your awful fucking Hasidic Jew
fucking curls. I don't know what
you're trying to do, you know, and,
and,
and Marcia who,
I don't know why I'm not banging you some
reason I skipped over you and started
banging your mother, right? None
of you bitches can fucking drive.
And I'm watching this episode going,
this Greg radius is shit Greg, Bro.
Fuck Fonzie. You know, with
this stupid fucking, you know,
spinning around a punch in a jukebox.
So play Shaboom Shaboom I don't give
a fuck about that. I like Greg Brady,
you know,
for as much as Fonzie was talking shit,
he was always nice to the ladies and he,
that's,
that's seventh grade game with a woman.
Yeah.
[inaudible] [inaudible]
Greg Brady.
That's it.
That's how Greg ended up fucking their
mom because he didn't give a shit.
You didn't give a fuck Greg. Fuck
you Carol. You're not my mother.
You don't have to drive either. Oh my
God. Took him in that fucking groovy.
Adic they had started blowing
up twice. Hair got all curly.
So anyways,
that episode,
he's telling these fucking broads
that they don't know how to drive.
And then in the end of course,
cause they always have to cater to women,
these nerdy fucking writers. Okay. You
know, and then they, uh, they fucking,
you know,
Marsha goes around this stupid fucking
track and they had a cone with a little
egg on it. You guys have seen this and
she fucking, you know, I forget whatever,
Marsha in the beginning,
and then
in the end just to fucking even it out.
So everybody's happy.
And they could sell tide during the
commercials. They have Greg. Fuck up.
[inaudible]
knock the I golf. That's, that's
what I was trying to get to.
Wasn't that what I was trying to
get to that one on so fucking long.
I can't even remember.
All I'm saying is
that the guy you want,
you don't,
it doesn't fucking matter
how many yards you throw
in the regular season.
It doesn't
fucking matter.
[inaudible] and downs on the
[inaudible]. Hey, what's going on?
April 12th, 2010 and, uh,
I'm actually just putting this up here
right now to let you guys know that I'm
not doing a podcast this week. I
apologize. I'm calling in sick.
All right. I'm fucking,
you know, airborne cal.
Cal Ripkin voluntarily took himself out
of that game and he ended his streak.
I'm ending my podcast streak. Uh,
this is the first week that I, uh,
I'll ever willingly not do
a fucking podcast. You know,
it's like an NFL football. The
big question is, can you go,
we tape it up and we freeze it.
Can you go,
and this is the first time I
could tell you no, I can't,
I can't go this week.
Everybody. I apologize.
So we're going to have
a substitute this week.
I'm going to pass the mic
and I'm fucking with you.
I really should have had someone
stand in. I'm a, I'm spent.
All right, I'm back to drinking.
I'm disgusted with myself.
I, uh, I was in Atlanta this
week. I didn't drink Wednesday
and I didn't drink Thursday.
Okay.
And then Friday was coming
along and I was tired.
Now my buddy was opening for me
and I had a couple of drinks.
I had two beers,
then I switched to water,
which is a great thing and it usually
makes me stop. But the thing was,
is I left the punchline in
Atlanta. Uh, that's where I was at.
I was at the punchline and I walked
across the street to this club to 90.
Yeah. And Yeah. Well I dunno.
Somewhere walking from the punchline
across the parking lot to club to 90.
I then switched back to, uh,
to alcohol.
I Dunno what happened.
Jesus Christ hear my phone
ringing in the background.
How many times can it ring before you
realize either I'm not home or I'm not
picking it up. There's probably
some fucking telemarketer.
Oh Jesus. There you go. Person
finally quit. So anyways, uh,
any way I walk over there
and people are drinking.
So I add a couple more Budweisers and
then the fucking bartender over there.
If you guys live in the Atlanta area,
and I feel really bad telling you this.
All right.
Cause it's such a cool fucking thing
that I don't want it to get ruined and
become anything touristy. Ah, you know,
I can't remember what the name of
the thing was. Just go in there.
There's a bartender named Tommy and
just ask him if he can spin the wheel.
All right. This guy out of nowhere
says to me and Paul Versey,
who is opening up for me,
you fucking killed all weekend.
A deep just pulls out this drum head and
it's got an Arrow and it has a bunch of
shit written all around the rim of the
drum hit and he goes, spin the air on.
You'd spin it and I didn't even,
I was so drunk,
I don't even know what I got and
Paul's fun at first he got something,
the guy goes, okay, you got
this. Then he has me spin it
and he goes, all right, you
got, you know you've got this.
And then he walks over
and he picks up this,
I dunno what it is.
You don't like that thing like that.
They put like a Yeager and you know when
you do like they have Yeager on tap and
all those things.
He basically picked up something like
that that had a door on the front of it
and he just puts it on top of his head
and he's just staring at us and all of a
sudden he opens the door and he has this
dumb cross eyed look on his face and he
starts singing slash rapping.
I don't know what,
and it doesn't even sound like English.
And at the end of every sentence that
kind of fucking rhymes and right as you
start to figure out what he's saying,
he stopped,
makes a weird face and slams
the door right in his face.
It's the most fucked up thing. When he
first did it, I was like, all defensive,
like is this Guy gonna make me look
like a fucking asshole? And then I,
and then right as I caught on that
he was just acting like an idiot.
He slammed the door on himself and it
was the best fucking laugh I've had in
like three months. I can't even imitate
what he did. And that was just for Paul.
So now he's standing,
he just slammed the door,
this fucking thing on his right
in his own face, this little door.
And now he's just standing
there looking at me,
but he's not looking at me cause he's got
this fucking thing on him, on his head.
And I know I'm next and all of a
sudden he opens the door again.
He's got that same dumb look
on his face. And he said, ah,
Bill Byrd up [inaudible] Dah, Dah. I
can't even fucking do what he was doing.
And me and Paul at his point,
like pounding the bar,
fucking dying laughing and
you didn't want it to end in.
All of a sudden he just stops with this
fucked up look on his face and he slams
the door in his face again, club
to 90. The guy's name's Tommy.
Just hang out there.
I'm telling you what all the fucking
weird Shit I've seen in bars with people
doing tricks with matchbooks people
telling you jokes and everything was the
most unique fucking thing I've
ever seen in my life. And um,
it's called the club to 90. Just just
go in there. Um, whatever. That's it.
The next night I was going to bring
actually my video camera and video tape it
and put it up on Youtube,
but I didn't want to because youtube
ruins everything because everything then
becomes mainstream and it can't be a
who's just this cool underground thing.
So what I did to keep it underground was
not videotape it and then fucking talk
about it on my podcast. What
an asshole. Um, so anyways,
so I went hard that night and then I
stayed out till like four in the morning
and we ended up driving
out of there and uh,
and verges going, come on,
hey, is anything open? I
want to get something to eat.
I'm like, dude, I'm not eating this
fucking late. That she was like three,
I got to sleep by force was a little bit
before three. And he goes, no, no, no.
He goes, I think Mcdonald's
opened. I'm like, dude,
it's not going to be open this late.
And he's like, all right, come on.
Just drive up there. So I say,
fuck it. I drive up there.
He sees the lights around and he see,
you see that one lonely fucking person
standing in there walking around doing
everything and he's all excited
to do the drive to use open. Yes.
It's fucking open, right? So we'd go, we'd
go to the drive through and he's like,
dude, you going to get some like, Nah
Dude, I'm not kidding any of this shit.
I can't eat this fucking late up to
too old to be in this light. Right?
So we go up to the drive through and
the guy goes, hey, welcome Mcdonald's.
Can I take your order?
And immediately my mouth just starts
going yet let me get two double
cheeseburgers, a small fry and a coke
and verse. He just starts laughing at me.
Cause two seconds ago I wasn't going
to get anything in the second I just
started smelling those
fries. I said, you know what?
Actually now that I think of it,
I'm going to order about
1,280 calories of trans fats.
I think that that's what I'm gonna do.
So we get our shit
fucking drive back to the hotel, fucking
eat it in his room. And then I go to bed.
You know, I wake up the next day at
like 1230 and I'm not worth shit.
I'm not worth fucking shit. We
get up, we go to the waffle house.
This is what I did to my body this week.
This is why there's no podcast this
week. This is not a podcast. Okay?
So if you guys don't like this podcast,
don't write me and say
that podcasts sucked.
What you need to say is
you're unbelievably long
statement announcing why you
weren't going to do a podcast sucked.
All right?
All right. Get it right there. Can face.
So, uh, yeah, we go into the waffle.
We're both fucking
hung over.
I've been to the waffle house a bunch
of times because I traveled this fucking
country.
Paul Versey has never been to the fucking
waffle house because he doesn't work
this part of the country much.
Or maybe he just never went to it,
which I would understand because of the
piss yellow sign that they have with the
incredibly bland black
font. It is. Um, um,
as a question for you guys
and this non podcast, what,
when you guys look at like
fast food, don't, you know,
at like some signs of like appealing and
they make you want to eat the food or
at the very least try it.
We have an an earthquake.
Is that just wind and having a
lot of earthquakes lately? Um,
that was one of those little ones.
Every once in a while I'll get one
of those little ones out here and uh,
it just feels like,
you know,
if your eyes are closed at
night and you get one of those,
you feel like if you opened your eyes,
they'd be some guy standing at the
end of your bed just shaking it like,
I'm gonna fucking kill
you. Um, anyway, so we go,
uh, which uh, Jesus Christ, I got
nothing. This is not a podcast everybody,
I can't even fucking think right now.
I had a Muffin,
a bag of m and m's or water
and some sort of chicken wrap.
All airport fucking food.
I've destroyed my body.
I think at least two of my organs
of shut down at this point.
I'm going to go with one kidney. And,
uh, let's see the pancreas now that's,
that's the fucking grand central
of the, uh, Oregon's isn't it?
What exactly does the pancreas do?
That's for all you geeks out there who
let me know that facetious is not the
only word that has all
the vowels in a row.
You hear that Geeky?
The person who sent me that fucking email
that said the interest is legal bolt.
The word facetious. Is this the
only word in the English language?
We're all the, uh, all the vowels.
Not only all the vowels in the
English language, in the word,
they're actually in order. It's the
only word in the English language.
I'm sorry to tell you sir.
You're actually wrong. And A,
I can't remember what the other word is,
but at least two other nerds emailed me
to let me know that you were wrong. So,
uh, I'm not gonna read the emails
because this is not a podcast this week.
I am taking this week off.
So what you need to do is you need to
deepen the level of nerd that you fucking
hang out with before you make an ass of
yourself like that again on the podcast.
Lucky for you, I'm not trashing you
on another podcast or as you would be
Barris right now.
Fortunately for you,
this got buried on the back page
of this non podcast this week.
So anyways, what, which
have fast food restaurants.
You guys feel like the sign makes the
food look like the least appealing for me,
I would go with the waffle house because
they have like that piss yellow fucking
sign and they have the
plaintiff's black font.
It's just horrible. Absolutely horrible.
And it makes me sick to stomach. Arby's
is another one that blood orange color,
that fucking hat. And they're
gray roast beef. And by the way,
I ate there last night at about
fucking one in the morning.
Jesus Christ.
You know what I used to hate to was this
the subway back in the day when they
had those piss yellow counters in the
newspaper, articles all on the walls.
Remember that they literally had
urine colored tables with newspapers.
The only thing was missing was a
homeless guy rolled up in the wallpaper,
pissing on the tables.
That was the,
that was basically subconsciously what
they were creating. And not only that,
the pictures on the wall Onaway no, no,
no, no, no, no, no, no. The newspapers.
Oh,
I'm fucking this up.
The subway used to have
pictures of Old New York on it.
That's what it had. Wow. I fucked that up.
The newspapers were actually the
tabletops of the old Wendy's.
There's a bunch of guys,
41 years old and older right now.
Fucking punch in their dashboard going.
That's right.
I was going to fucking say that.
I remember that Shit.
You go in there and you'd, you'd order
the triple during one time. You know that.
I see.
You remember one time you don't,
one time I was standing in line at Wendy's
and I was making my girl crack up or
maybe my girlfriend at the time,
I can't even fucking think this week.
I was making her laugh her ass off
because I was making fun of who the fuck
orders a triple, uh, triple cheeseburger,
you know, I don't even know of him,
what I was saying,
but I had a dying laughing and I was so
site that I was making her laugh because
it was making me feel good.
I had a cry and laugh and then I had
said triple cheeseburger so many fucking
times that when I walked up to the
register, I ended up ordering it.
And then she looked at me like,
what the fuck did you do that for?
And then I felt stupid for ordering it,
but then I asked will felt, you know,
I didn't want to be like, oh
wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
I didn't want to look like an asshole.
And then the glutinous side of me is like,
oh great, I get to eat at triple
cheeseburger, you know, like a fat fuck.
So anyways, I would go with Arby's and I
would go with the waffle house signage.
So it was you walk into the waffle house.
For those of you who have never
been to a waffle house, uh,
don't ever put your elbows on the table
because you won't be able to get them
off without taking off at least two
layers of skin because there's still
somebody kill me. You know,
I just had an urge to do,
I'm wearing a thermal right now.
I had the urge to take this thing
off and hang myself by the sleeves.
I got nothing. I got absolutely
nothing this week. This statement
is going to be a long
statement of so many ways.
We walk into the fucking
waffle house and yes,
I did lose some energy in my voice.
I'm running out of batteries here.
Yeah, I'm sweating here. Uh,
we walked into the waffle house and
we're both fucking hung over it and I've
been to the waffle house hundreds of
times, so I already know the menu. Paul,
on the other hand,
does not know the menu.
So the waitress comes over and she goes,
you guys ready to order?
And I'm like, yeah, yeah, actually
I'm ready to order it. So verse,
he goes into a fuck at panic and
it's a big overwhelming fucking menu.
They have like 98
different kinds of of uh,
hashbrowns smothered covered fucking
sheets shit on or whatever the fuck you
supposed to say there that he just, you
know, I order what I ordered and then he,
he didn't know what the fuck the dope,
these just looking at the pictures,
pancakes, toast, eggs, and he
finally just goes, yet you have a,
what are the order?
He ordered eggs benedict
fucking waffle house.
You know,
who the fuck off? That's like trying to
order like a ribeye steak at Mcdonald's.
They don't have it.
Paul over easy or fucking scrambled.
I mean there's like toothless truckers in,
they're convicted felons has been rappers.
It's a,
it's a shit hole, but their
waffles it delicious. Special,
especially when you're hung
over their food. So fattening,
I actually had a little hiccup
there as I was just describing it.
So anyways, and this is,
this is, this is the kicker.
Like that night I have three
fucking shows. All right.
But because I'm a professional,
I'm able to push all the feelings that I
have of the horror that I've done to my
body over the last fucking 24
hours. I go onstage, kill it.
Seven kill a 10. I do. I go to
Duke, no, seven, nine and 11,
the 11 o'clock show.
I literally have a splitting fucking
headache and all I can think of is Jerry
Lewis.
And now we never ever sat down in his
Tuxedo pants and he always gave him a
fucking show. And I was like, you
know, instead of what would Jesus do,
what would Jerry do?
He would give them a show lady.
So I plowed through that one.
And uh,
then that was the end of my weekend.
So you're probably thinking
to yourself right now.
Well then why he wished shoeing
a statement. Bill. You fucking,
you will finish Saturday. It's fucking
Monday. Did you recuperate yesterday? No,
I did not.
I went to the masters yesterday and
watch Phil Mickelson when his third green
jacket.
And uh,
it was an incredible experience. I
went to the Superbowl Gulf, everybody.
And after having gone there and seen
how fucking beautiful that golf courses,
I don't know why they don't call the
Superbowl, the masters of football.
You know why?
Because nobody fucking watch his golf
to the level that they watched football.
That's why I knew the
answer to that question.
I'm just trying to tell you that
it was a beautiful course and,
and basically you don't get
tickets to the masters. All right?
Cause I want to tell you guys, this is
just like Royal Albert Hall that I saw.
This is another thing that if you're
into golf, you have to do at some point,
you don't get tickets.
What you do is you get a badge and you
have to get a badge from some sort of
dude who knows a member
who knows a fucking guy,
who knows a guy who fucking
knew a guy who knew a guy.
And when you go to pick up your tickets,
you actually fucking,
at least we did.
We actually drove to somebody's house.
And I remember I thought it was gonna be
like, some will call shit and it wasn't.
We're driving through this neighborhood
and I'm looking at the addresses and
I'm like, I think it's the next hat.
It's a house.
I must be on the wrong street.
And then I look and there's this woman
sitting in a garage waving at us and I
was like,
all right,
well either this is the place where
we're supposed to be or this is the
friendliest fucking
neighborhood I've ever been to.
Or maybe I look like one of her neighbors
or maybe she has a rape fantasy and
she ordered a redhead.
Cause you know how many Red
Ed Gigolos are out there?
Everybody I'm telling you were
in demand where we're dying off.
Well, like the white rhinos
of fucking human beings.
People are trying to bang us before
we disappear. Let me think about it.
Think about the Dodo bird.
Think about if you actually
stuck your dick in a Dodo bird.
The the just the fuck you
Trump every story in a bar.
I fucked something that
doesn't exist anymore.
What do you a necrophiliac. No, you
fucking asshole. I fucked it. Dodo bird.
Um, anyways, now, right there,
I would have complained if
that was on a regular podcast,
I would have complained
about that last bit there.
But fortunately this is not a podcast on
just issuing a statement that I do not
have the energy to fucking do
this this week. So anyways,
we get these fucking badges and they
actually bring you into the house.
We sit in this library and I'm sitting
there and this woman is debriefing me
about these badges.
Okay.
I'm already freaked out about going to
the masters because there's a level of
whiteness and a level of education that,
uh,
even intimidates me is why
it is I am now. Um, oh,
if aesthetically a e s t h e,
t,
I c a. L. L. Y. Aesthetically. I
don't know if I spelled it right,
but I know how to spell it when
I'm not fucking brain dead.
It's one of my spelling words.
Let's get smart America. Um,
aesthetically I'm very white.
Alabaster. If you asked my girlfriend,
that's how she describes me.
A porcelain ask.
That's how white I am. But, uh, there's,
this is the different kind of white,
this isn't a Thirstin howl the food kind
of white and a ivy league kind of white
Illuminati, you know, rubbing
elbows with the Kennedys.
We summer in the Hamptons,
we have a house on Martha's vineyard.
You know,
when Jesus comes back, he's going
to have to be buzzed into our house.
After we talked to our lawyer, our lawyer
will be present when Jesus judges me,
like that level of fucking white.
So I went on the Internet
and I actually was like the,
I know there's a dress code here and the
last thing I want to do when I go to a
place like that is I don't want to
come in there and disrespect the place.
I don't give a fuck about the approval of
those people. But you know what I mean?
You go into that place.
It's an unbelievable golf event.
I respect the history of an Arnold
Palmer, Jack Nicholas, Ben Hogan,
all that type of stuff.
So I want to go there and show it the
respect that it deserves. All right.
And also, I don't want to walk in
there looking like a fucking bump.
So I go on the Internet and I check
out the dress code and it's literally
collared shirt, no jeans
allowed, all this shit.
So I for the first time in about
I think 20 years, I actually,
when I had some sort of a soup job,
I actually bought a pair of dockers,
dockers. Everybody I buy, at least I went
with the black ones. I did not buy khaki.
I refuse to ever wear khaki.
There's only two people in the world
where a khaki animal experts in date
rapists. All right, I'm not wearing khaki.
So I bought a pair of
black doctors and uh,
I had this blue like Nike Golf Shirt
and then I had the tiger woods,
um, the tiger woods, Nike had
the black one with the Red v.
Why am I acting like I'm walking the
red carpet from my movie date night that
came out last weekend, which is
a huge fucking hit. Everybody.
I'm so fucking site.
Date night was a huge head.
It made a ton of fucking money.
And if you went out and sought, um,
I, I want to say thank you because I hope
it's such a huge hit that they make a
fucking sequel. And, uh,
maybe I'll be able to repop
reprise my role as detective Walsh.
You know, maybe I'll be, I'll,
I'll turn bad in the second one,
like a fucking key Ho
and another 48 hours.
Remember that I'll grow one of those.
A walrus mustaches.
I don't give a shit the first movie
I've really booked ever in my career.
I'm average in one every 18 years.
If I can go on a run with this thing,
I'll be psyched. For those
of you who haven't seen it
and, uh, enjoy this podcast.
This is not a podcast,
it's just a statement, uh,
but enjoy all the other free podcasts
season. That'd be like, you know what,
he never comes and tours in my area,
or I don't care to see his act live,
but I would like to
somehow pay it forward.
You could pay it forward by buying a
ticket to date night. You could even do,
we have bigger favor is if you're gonna,
if you've already seen it or you
don't even want to fucking see it,
you'd rather see another movie.
Do me a favor,
just buy two tickets to date night and
just go into the other movie that you
wanted to anyways,
just so it pads the stats,
um, date nights starting
Steve Corral and Tina Fey.
Is that a local Cineplex near you?
Please go see it. So anyways, um,
so we get the badges and a,
this is the deal.
You're not allowed to
bring his cell phone in.
You're not allowed to bring a camera
and you're not allowed to bring video
equipment in.
You're not allowed to bring shit in.
All you're allowed to bring in is
yourself the close that cover you and some
fucking cash and some sunblock.
That's it.
All right.
So you walk in there and you literally
get going through like a metal detector,
like you going through the airport and
immediately there's this sense of awe is
the president nearby because that's
what this security feels like.
And,
uh,
and the big thing with these badges is
it's not like you get the badge at the
person's house. So we're however the
fuck you get it and you get to keep it.
You have to return the badge.
And when you have this badge,
you have the responsibility to not break
any rules because if they kick you out,
they take your badge so
you'll never come again.
So not only can you never come again,
the person who's badge it was does not
get it back ever again no matter what
because you are obviously not good enough.
A judge of character considering that you
gave this badge to this person that we
now have to object.
And when I went there,
all I heard was stories of people
that they had seen get eject some,
some ejected,
some guy actually got a cell phone in
there and it rang at some point during the
match and people just
appear out of nowhere. Okay?
One guy puts you in a fucking choke hold,
another guy snatches the
badge off your shirt in.
The badge has to be
displayed at all times.
And you would think with all
those fucking people there,
if he didn't have it
displayed, you had, you know,
very small chance of someone's
stopping you. I didn't have my,
I had mine in my pocket and I walked like
10 feet with it and all this guy just
appeared on a nowhere with his masters
that green colored shirts or was your
badge, where's your bad sir, sir,
do you have a badge? You know,
fucking gun drawn. He may be reached in
my pocket with two fingers, you know,
pull it on kid, whatever. Um, so anyways,
so we walk out until we get there.
First thing we do is we walk into the
pro shop and I already told myself I was
going to spend it like 400 bucks
and I got, if I, if I didn't,
it's exactly what I did. I got some
shot glasses, I got some golf balls,
I got some hats for people. They actually
sell those masters. The flags, you know,
that they have on the pins all
around there just as a the masters,
2010, very clean, very elegant.
The Shit bought a bunch of those for
some friends and a couple of golf shirts,
you know, the usual bullshit. And
uh, then I bought one of those, uh,
the best in the best souvenir I ended up
getting is you actually cause you don't
want to stand up for fucking 12 hours
watching people golf. What's up Cleo?
Are you doing? I didn't know you
will lay in there. How you doing?
You guys haven't heard
a fucking Moen lately.
Anyways. Um, I just do that
for me. Um, so anyways,
uh, they sell these, these
chairs there that you can uh,
sit on. Oh Jesus. You see,
this is why this isn't a podcast
and hear what I just said.
They sell these chairs that are,
you can set on,
is that what you do with the chair bill?
And they actually,
they end up being one of the
most coveted, um, souvenirs.
Because when you go to get on the plane
the next day, you see everybody got 'em.
They get 'em slung over their shoulders,
the way they fold up,
it looks like you're carrying like a
yoga mat except at ways like fucking 20
pounds. So anyways, let's,
let's cut to the chase here cause I
gotta finish this statement early. Um,
I went out onto the golf course and
those of you who are big fans of golf and
you watched the masters every year,
you gotta go there because when
you go and you see the clubhouse,
she can't go in it.
But when you see it and you
just start walking the course,
this is,
this is what I suggest.
Get there at like eight in the morning
and start at 18 and just walk the course
backwards all the way to the front.
I didn't do that because I had
too much shit that I bought.
And uh,
I just walked two different
holes that I really liked,
but that's what this guy told me to do.
Walk the whole fucking course.
But we got there a little lake because uh,
I was in a bar the night before watching
a guy with a box on his head sing songs
that I couldn't really
understand. Um, but anyways,
you go onto the course and I,
I've never been to anything
like this as far as nature goes.
I've seen it was like seeing famous people
except they were, they were fair ways.
Like I walked
up and around so when I came to 18,
I was inbetween where you tee
off and looking down the fairway,
you know when someone's just bringing
it home and is going to win the masters,
there's a roadway where you walk across
and I looked right down that fairway and
I don't know, it's one of those fucking
things we just like, this really exists,
you know, it isn't, this is real.
And then I'll let you go over the whole
number 12 I got the little pamphlet here.
They've got all the holes are named the
12th hole. What the fuck do they call it?
They have like the Golden Bell is the
name of this is how white this is.
You guys want to hear the
names of the holes. Now,
usually when I talk about
holes on the podcast,
it's a lot more crass than this whole
number one is called t all live.
All right? That's not to whole.
Number two is called Pink Dogwood.
Tell me there isn't a porno to
be made with some of these names.
Flowering Peach.
It's the third hole.
These are all mildly sexual art.
They flowery crab apple.
Oh,
that's the one where like if you're
into watching guys fuck old women,
this is really just going to get
disgusting. Fifth hole is Magnolia.
You get the point.
Juniper's is sixth
pompous. I don't what the fuck
it yellow jasmine, but whatever.
They got all these flowers and
everything's in bloom and it's just,
it's unbelievable.
It's unbelievable.
Walk around looking at all these famous
holes like I couldn't be like when I was
coming up onto 12 to see that
little bridge there on a,
whatever the fuck they call it,
the pink Petunia Golden Bell.
It's just unbelievable when you see it.
It's literally iconic.
The same feeling I got when
I saw Big Ben in London.
How fucking awesome is my life
this past month when I saw Big Ben,
you just stare at it.
You can't believe it.
It's just something you've seen your
whole life and now you're standing there
looking at it and I'm telling you
the fucking urge. This is the thing
about it. There was so many things.
You can't talk to the golfers. Like
if tiger hit something, hit the ball,
hits something, his wife, if
tiger hit the fucking ball,
you could literally go like, uh, you
know, as he came walking up to a poly bag,
come on tiger. You could say something
like that maybe, but that's it.
After you hit the ball, he
couldn't be like, you're the
man to a u turn. That's it.
Someone would pair out of
nowhere. Chloroform, rag,
read over your fucking nose.
Somebody yells, yanks off your
fucking badge. And that's it.
They pummel you with Billy clubs that are,
that are the same colors,
the masters green,
and they just beat the shit out of you
and they toss you over the fucking fence.
That's how it works. Um, but I
got a man with all those rules,
all those rules, the urge to just do
something like that and get kicked out.
Like I almost had like Tourette's.
Um,
cause what I ended up doing is I settled
on the 15th hole and I sat in the
bleachers and I don't know what
that one's called, wispy pubic hair.
What the fuck do they call this one?
The 15th fucking hall is called
Fire Firethorne and it had this,
uh,
so this is basically what we did.
We realized that there was so many
fucking people there and we had our chairs
that we had to lug around and a
$400 worth of shit in his bag.
I wasn't going to walk 18 holes
and just follow tiger around.
I didn't want to do it because
there's too many fucking people.
And as people camped out around where
they tee off and they're camped out around
the green.
So what you could basically do
is run down the fucking fairway.
If you can get there,
knowing that all the golfers have a point
a to point B once they once you know,
just to keep play moving,
you on the other hand have specific areas
where you can crossover fairways and
that type of shit. And if you don't,
they fucking, they, they, they,
they destroy you and they take your badge.
So,
um, we just said fuck it. We're going
to go to 15. We're going to sit there.
We can watch them hit their second shots,
a power five and we look over our
shoulder. We can't see them tee off on 60,
but we could see the results
of their shot. And uh,
we sat there in the bleachers and
knowing that we had a good two and a half
hours to wait until they came,
I think it was actually three hours.
So we just sat there and a,
you would think it would be
boring as hell and it wasn't.
You just shoot the shit with other people,
older people who've gone to the master's
since like the early seventies late
seventies one guy from like 1952 I
didn't get a chance to talk to them,
but they talk about,
you know,
Nicholas went in [inaudible] 86
and I'll share with, you know,
if you're a sports fan,
it was fucking incredible.
And meanwhile all we're doing is we're
sitting waiting for the bear trap taps to
be turned on.
And this is how this style
secret of this fucking places is.
No one had any idea when they get
turned on somebody up in the clubhouse,
in the inner fucking catacombs of the
clubhouse gives everybody the go ahead to
turn on the beer taps. And they can't
even tell you when they, I don't know,
maybe 1230 maybe one we're not sure.
And they don't have any advertising.
So just as domestic beer,
regular beer, the whole fucking
thing is just like, look,
we're in control. All
right, you want an import.
This is important. You want to domestic.
This is domestic. What kind is it?
I can't disclose that.
I'm not allowed to tell you when,
when you turned into bear on,
we're not allowed to tell you, sir,
why are you being hostile?
You know?
So we're just sitting there and there's
a couple of turtles outside the fucking
pawn there and we start
gambling on the turtles.
Which one's going to go in
the fucking water first.
Then they turn on the beer and we start
getting shit faced and we're waiting for
the first fucking golfers to come. And
then it's just like the Indy 500 you just,
you just,
you just bet on golfers.
It's like the most elegant track you've
ever been to and you just wait and they
come in through two at a
time. Ernie els, you know
Kenny Perry's coming through
fucking Sergio Valenti,
whatever his fucking name is.
Either they just right in front of you,
this shit and you're just sitting there
getting hammered betting on golfers in
fucking turtles. That's what I
did all day. Sitting in the sun.
Fucking saw two holes in one,
or at least the results of them.
I heard him hit the green or hits the
green and I hear the crowd go crazy.
I look over and I see it roll in the
cup and everybody goes fucking nuts. Um,
I lost 100 bucks in the first one and
100 on the next one. So I was even,
and I gotta admit to when you sit there
and all of a sudden you look in there,
you knew, know taggers come in
next cause you've got like the, uh,
the whole list of golfers is fucking
unreal and you see him come over the hill.
All right.
Like a fucking
one of those deer hunters
say 15 horn fucking dare man.
20 point are coming over the
hill. And I got it. My such man,
I'm going to choose to
ride the fucking head.
That was the other word is like tiger
comes over the damn hill he's wearing,
he's, you see him, he can't even see
him. He's so far away. You see a guy,
you see a black guy who looks like a black
guy who was actually a mostly fucking
Asian or whatever the hell he is.
I don't know what the hell he is.
You see some Tan Dude beyond the Tan
that a white guy can get coming over the
hill with a red shirt in the
fucking black pants on you.
Like that's fucking tiger woods.
And a hush
falls over the entire,
the entire hole like is like 3000 people
sitting there and it's dead quiet.
And you just see that ball fucking just
flying. I saw an eagle, the fucking hall.
I saw him, Eagle it. I saw
Kim, the Korean Dude Eagle it.
Um,
I think I saw did it was an Ernie els.
That was another thing that kinda sucked,
was kind of hard to tell if
it was their second or third.
You just knew with guys like Kim and, and
uh, tiger was the way they drove that.
Who says second shot? Anyways, whatever.
It was fucking awesome. And uh,
Phil Mickelson came in last cause he
was on the leaderboard and once he went
past us, I ran off the
bleachers, went down.
And actually he's the only guy who
watched t off, watched him tee off on 16,
and then we grabbed our shit.
And we ran over to 18 and
tiger had already finished,
but we stood there
halfway down the f three,
three quarters of the way up the 18th at
at Augusta and watch Mickelson tee off.
We watched him hit his
second shot and then we will,
we couldn't see through the crowd
when he sunk the winning Putt, eh,
but we stood there and I looked between
a bunch of fucking blue bloods heads and
I watched him put the green jacket on and
get choked up when he talked about his
wife. And it was one of the most
incredible experiences I've ever had.
And uh, it's making me really thankful
for the incredible fucking life I have.
And A, I hope this isn't building
resentment with you guys. You know,
you just lay off drinking it
for a little bit. You know,
you could get by one of those badges
by a stinking badge and go next year.
Just do one thing, do one fucking
thing. You know, I don't fucking know.
I don't know what I'm
saying. This, these are just,
this is just my statement that
I'm not doing a podcast this week.
I'm not fucking doing it, but I
know you can. You can go there.
Those cost me 600 bucks. I know that's
a lot of fucking money. I know it is,
but think how much money you blow
each weekend in a bar. All right?
Figure out what you blow each weekend
in a bar. Here's a good way to do it.
He's a nice healthy way and just just go
on the wagon for a while and then just
take the money that you
would've spent on booze.
He put it into your Augusta Fund,
you know,
and just fucking drive there.
Do a fucking road trip.
Get yourself a pair of dockers
and a golf shirt. All right.
Have a nice and pressed and clean
drive like a goddamn maniac.
Both you and your buddy, even if
you live in Seattle, tradeoff,
drive all the fuck way down there. Go
into somebody's house, get debriefed,
walk in there,
act like a gentleman and get
to see something that most
people never get to see.
And what's great is
there all the souvenirs.
They don't really sell
anything on the Internet.
So that's why you buy a ton of shit is
because everybody asks you to get him
some stuff and even if they don't,
you've got,
you've got great gifts for the
rest of the year. You know,
you could do all your
Christmas shopping right there.
You get somebody a fucking
hat at the masters,
they're going to be site because no one
else is going to have that fucking hat
and unless they went there.
So there you go.
That's the end of my statement for
this week. People 38 minutes statement
actually flew back this morning and uh,
I was, I was an idiot. I
guess something me like I was,
I was a little more buzzed than I thought
it was and I was really tired and I
got three hours sleep and fucking
embarrassed. I yelled at a cop
when I drove out of the master's,
it was like,
it was really late because we stuck
around to the end and it was like,
it was,
we sat through this fucking traffic
and all I had to do was make a left and
drive like 40 yards down the road and I
could jump on the fucking highway and I
was on my way and I was exhausted
and I wanted to go to sleep.
And what ends up happening is one of
those deals where the cops decide that
everybody's going to go, right?
We're forcing everyone, right?
And I want to go left so I can go and
cut hair down the street and get on the
highway. So I got my window down. I'm
like, I can't go left the guy or not.
He could keep the keep going. So I'm
driving and I know what they're doing.
So I get to the third cop and I
see a gas station. I'm just like,
I just want to get some gas. Can
I get some gas guys? I keep it,
go and keep them moving. And I just
went to one, I can't get some gay,
just like that.
Fucking screamed at him as I drove by
because he was on foot and cause I was a
little drunk and then I drove
away and all of a sudden I was,
couldn't feel my legs go like that.
I just fucking do that as a Yankee
in the middle of fucking Georgia.
Did I just yell at that guy clearly
though? It was I just obnoxious.
Then I was like, I don't give a
shit in the first left I could make.
I made a left and then I banged one of
the most illegal fucking you turns hybrid
three point fucking turns.
And there were two cops sitting right
there and my like, dude, dude, dude, dude,
dude, which is universal for this,
a cop, Doh, Doh, Doh, Doh, Doh.
And I was like, yeah, I
don't give a fuck. He's like,
what's wrong with you and Michael Lim?
I'm a little buzzed and
I'm a control freak.
Don't fucking tell me where I can't go.
I've been on that Goddamn
golf course every day.
All I wanted to do is run out of the
bleachers on somebody approaching shot on
15 and do a fucking cannon ball right
to that little mini lake already had it
planned out was going to get my badge to
my buddy and tell him, do take a walk.
Do what do you mean take? Just take
a fucking walk. And he'd see it,
my eyes and be like,
all right man.
And he'd just grab our shit
and he'd just walk away.
And then when I would do is I do a cannon
ball right into the fucking lake. Okay.
And I would immediately
be a fucking legend,
an absolute fucking legend on the,
on jackass.com if there's something, you
know, I'd be right up there with fan man,
that fucking kid at Yankee stadium who
jumped off into the, into the, the, the,
the backstop netting.
I Dunno who else that due to ran out
and grabbed the football and got slammed
down to the ground by the
linebacker on Monday night football.
I'd be one of those guys. I'd be
put on that fucking, you know,
whacked out sports or whatever.
I would be on that shit forever.
And then when they asked me, when
they pulled me out of there, you know,
they went to grab my badge, I
wouldn't have it. Where's your badge?
I don't know. It must be at the
bottom of the pond there. Thurston.
Why don't you take off your loafers and
roll up your slacks and go in there and
try and find it.
What's the word she going to do to me?
Prosecute me to the full
extent of the law. You know,
they know every big judge in the state.
I'd probably still be in fucking prison,
but I've got to admit and
I don't know. So anyways,
so then I just drove the rest of the
fuck away home. I stopped at Arby's,
went to bed at fucking 12 midnight,
had to get up at six 30 and a gun
on a fucking plane. I had a Muffin,
I had a m and m's and there was
a baby crying in the hallway.
And I don't give a shit. I know I
never care when babies cry on planes,
I don't give a fuck.
But there was some square had cut in
front of me who kept turning around and
looking at him. You know,
I was like, all right,
that's the career woman who hates kids.
I see why she's looking at him.
She didn't want to have kids.
So she's annoyed with their presence.
And then I see she has a
wedding ring and what's what's,
there's only one reason to get
married. That's they have kids. Okay.
So I'm looking at her like she
must be the worst mother ever.
Cause every time this kid cries,
she turns around,
starts looking for a mother
shooting alerts, shooting her look,
shaking your heads. And I just want to
be like, you know, it's a fucking baby.
It's a fucking patient. A baby man.
He's a fucking baby. Some believable.
When I hate when people do that shit. It's
like, how do you not understand? Like,
you know, we're in a pressurized
cabin. That thing does the Beta thing.
The baby does not have clearance ears.
It's a fucking baby. Stupid cunt.
So at one point I fucking,
she looked and I gave her such a dirty
look for fucking given the mother a dirty
look that when her
fucking eyes met my eyes,
she looked at me like surprised at first
and then realized that she was being a
cunt. And then she tried to
play it off with this smile.
Like, yeah, isn't an acute,
is an acute that the baby's crying
too late? I've already judged you.
You're a horrible mother and you're
a horrible person. And this ends,
this is the conclusion of my statement.
43 minutes said that I am not
doing a podcast this week.
I regret to inform all of you that do
to a circumstances beyond your control.
Um,
our host this week,
Bill burr abused his body
to such a fucking level that
he had an inability to do
a podcast this week and only
had an ability to, you know,
I should have done it in, in,
in the spirit of the masters.
What I should've done was I should have
issued an apology just like tiger woods
and droned on for 45 minutes. Boring
the shit out of you. Oh, wait a minute.
I think I already did that.
I believe I already did that.
All right. That's the podcast
for this week. Uh, once again,
I'm so sorry that I couldn't
give you a podcast this week.
I couldn't give you some laughs.
Um, I will become an fucking,
I'll give you both barrels next week,
speaking of which,
I'm going to be at the funny
bone and a Newport, Kentucky, uh,
right across the river from Cincinnati
and I gotta be honest with you guys.
I got a, I already have a new
killer hour. That's right. I set it.
I set it. All right. Maybe
it's not a killer hour.
It's like 40 minutes out of the hour.
I already have 40 new fucking minutes.
How do you like that shit?
I just taped to special in December.
All right.
We're midway through April and I already
can run my fucking mouth for 40 minutes
with some new shit provided I'm on.
If I'm off,
I have eight new minutes.
That's where my act, his act,
but I'm not going to lie to you.
I talked about Tiger Woods for like 11
minutes the other night. All of his funny,
crushing, destroying. I was so sites,
but in the back of my head, I'm like,
you realize that now after
he plays the masters,
uh, that, you know, I can only tell that
story for so long. It's basically mid May.
It's going to be an old story.
It already is.
I'm still talking about that
lady who got killed at seaworld.
I'm going to give you a little preview
for what we'll be talking about the way,
talking about my trip to church
and went again, by the way,
uh, when again, on Easter, I
went on Easter Sunday, you know,
the girlfriend's mom wanted to go to
church. She didn't want to go by herself.
So I said, all right, I'll go with
you. We all went little happy family.
I went there, sat there, bored shitless.
It was extra packs took
to eat that piece of
cardboard at the end of it.
And whatever other offensive
thing you want me to say.
Uh, I dunno. I literally
am like sitting here.
I'm laying here right now and I have,
I'm like, my eyes are squinting like a,
there's a doctor and he's like, you
know, I fucked up my elbow and he's like,
it tell me, tell me, does this hurt? Does
this yet, yet you're hurt yet right there.
I'm literally doing that right now as
I'm doing this fucking podcast. Um,
I got nothing.
All right,
I got nothing for you this week and I'm
the first one to tell it to you. And, uh,
oh, did I, you know what it actually did,
this started this podcast like six fucking
times. I forget if I said this, but, uh,
somebody sent me a really
nasty email yelling,
cursing me out because he sent me an
email and I didn't answer their email.
And he said,
because you didn't answer my email.
I didn't go to see any of
your shows in Atlanta. And,
uh, I don't know if I already talked
about this. I apologize if I didn't.
Uh, sir, I don't give a
shit. All right. If you,
if you haven't learned anything from my
podcast is I really don't give a fuck.
I don't give a fuck if you
listen to this or you don't.
I don't give a fuck if you go to my
shows, but you don't. I don't give a fuck.
You know, do I, do I not want people
to come to my shows? Of course I do.
Do I not want people? Let's my podcast.
Of course. I don't. I want, fuck,
I ain't think I got, you
know, I got messed up there
and those double negatives.
I want people to come to my shows.
I want people to see my podcast.
But let me tell you some right now. Fuck.
Oh, I don't respond to fucking threats.
Don't fucking threaten me or no fucking,
you know,
try to put some sort of ominous bullshit
on how you want me to fucking behave
with your fucking email.
I don't give a fuck about email.
I get a fucking hundreds of
emails every God damn week.
And if I don't get to yours, I don't
fucking get to yours. So go fuck yourself.
If you want to pout and not come
to my show, don't go to my show.
I don't give a fuck.
You sound like a content anyways.
You probably go to my show and then
fucking judge it. It'd be like, oh,
the first eight minutes,
we're good.
And then I toured for minute 12 to shove
in teen. Go Fuck Yourself. All right,
why don't you go stick your head
through your fucking computer monitor.
God knows you're probably still have
one of those old ones, you know,
shaped like a fucking microwave.
Is that what you got as you work?
Look how fast people drive
in this fucking street.
I'm literally getting to that age,
yelling out the window.
Kids stopped driving
like I did at your age.
There's another good character
for a sketch. You know,
crabby, honest, old man.
Honest, crabby, old man.
Stop treating me with the same disrespect
I had from my elders when I was at
your age. Um, or maybe not. Shit.
God knows.
SNL could turn that into,
I get 15 minutes sketch and then stretch
it into an hour and 40 minute movie.
Um, all right, there we go. I burned
a bridge. I burned a bridge there.
Like I was going to get cast on
that at 41. Uh, maybe I could,
didn't feel harm again on old or what
I perceived to be old when he got on.
He was probably like 34 at the time, which
was ancient to me. And now at my age,
I would love to be, I would
love to be fucking 34 again, uh,
to be that age. Um, you know, I remember,
you know what was great about
when I was a fuck when I was 34,
I could run like a fucking seven,
nine 40,
when I was 30,
when I was 34.
It was a very good year.
A fucking dog just licked the bottom
of my foot. It's a goddamn freak.
I didn't have a dog that shit on
the floor or needed to go outside.
I did what I wanted.
I went down water slides when I was 34.
What's up Cleo? Are you doing, you know,
site that wants to see you?
You know, it's like to see you,
cause you were sake to see me. You're
always psyched to see me or you, you know,
my dog actually misses me.
Comes into the bedroom at night
and it fucking looks around for me.
Then it runs into my little office area
looking for me. Right? If I'm not around,
who you're going to wrestle with?
Let me see if I can get you to moan.
You won't do it.
Will you know when you're ready?
You like that fucking frog
and bugs bunny and big party.
Then all of a sudden I bring in somewhere.
Hey Cleo,
let me see if I can get you to
how you want to go outside. Cleo.
This is going to be worth it. People
just listen clear. You want to go say,
Huh?
Cleo.
Cleo. Hey, just getting psyched to Cleo.
You want to go side
Cleo,
cleo. I wanted a house. Come on, Cleo.
You want to go side
Cleo? But you fucking do it. Please clear
your mind goes,
Hey,
what am I saying?
Clear.
Oh, you fucking burning me right
now. Cleo. Hey, fuck it. Cleo.
You want to go outside?
Cleo? You know what? Go Fuck
Yourself. Jesus Christ. What
was that? Three minutes.
Yep. Below it. Cleo.
Why won't you hold for these people?
And in conclusion, uh, there
is no podcast this week.
I regret to inform you don't come
over now. Don't come over now.
You want some food,
you want to go outside,
cleo.
Well let me have one more temp.
Clearly you want to go outside?
Hmm Cleo. Okay. Oh Jesus
screen or this is like,
you know what you mean
right now you're just like,
you know the hot chick that'll never
fuck you and she just keeps giving you a
glimmer of hope and you keep coming back.
You keep coming back,
whatever. I still love
you clear. You know?
Even though he just made me look like
a fucking asshole. You really did.
It was literally the Buler.
Anybody, anybody. All right.
That concludes my statement.
That's the statement I'm sticking by.
It's all in the police report is tiger
woods would say, ah, there you go.
There's another thing you should do.
Pick one of these fucking things to do
and if one of you guys ends up doing
something that I told you
to do and you enjoy it,
please send me an email like a year
from now. If you go to the masters,
let me fucking, no. All right.
Because I think I'm going
to go again next year.
That's how much fucking fun
I head or go to England,
do some shit to something for fuck
sakes. Alright, I'll talk to you next
[inaudible].