MMM.
Hey, what's going on? It's Bill Burr.
It's time for the Thursday afternoon.
Just before Friday. Monday
morning podcast. And Ah,
just checking in on you.
I'm just checking in on you.
I'm just seeing how your week is going.
This is, this is a a, it's a hard week.
Okay.
Coming off the holiday vacation, you
know, at some point on your vacation,
you know,
a certain thought pops into your head
and I'm not talking about walking out the
front door and just abandoning
your family, you know,
and not even because you
don't like your family.
Maybe it's a relative that's
just their cackle, you know,
when it's just making you ear drums
just vibrate in a certain way that,
that it wakes up that part of your brain
that just doesn't give a fuck. You know,
the part of your brain that sociopath's
are always said, you know what I mean?
Just the wrong cackle can open that door
for a minute and then your brain starts
going like,
what if he just got up and left
and what came back later?
No, no dude left, like left.
Not like left or right.
I mean leave left gone.
What if you did that right?
Um, plus also it's the beginning of a new
year. There's a lot of hope in the year.
Yeah.
Um, chance for new things and
if you'd like to keep that hope,
uh, you probably shouldn't
watch the news because you know,
I've been fucking working my ass off
already. And uh, I was like, wow,
I've got really nothing to talk about.
Let me take a glance at the news.
Good Lord.
Okay,
good Lord.
I just googled news there,
this whole article on Donald Trump about
how he never wanted to become president
and then just some of the
quotes they have, it's like,
where did you get that quote?
You know,
something about Donald Trump being like,
yeah,
I'm not going to win this fucking thing.
And then he finds out,
he made it to the next
level and he just showed a,
looked ahead and see and allegedly said,
this is so fucked up.
It's like, who knew that he said
that? And I don't, I don't know.
I don't fucking know.
And then I'm watching all this stuff in
Palestine and the whole fucking thing.
It's just about money.
Yeah.
That's all it is.
It's above fucking money.
Okay.
You know, sometimes I wonder
if everybody in the world right
in, it'd be a weird game to play, right?
But all these fucking rich people just
squeeze in the fucking life out of
everybody. Pitting everybody
against everybody. If you just,
if everybody in the world just was just
like, well, what do you, what do you want?
Huh? What? What exactly
is it the to just take it,
does that make you have, I don't think,
I don't even think they could enjoy it.
They could have the biggest fucking
house on the biggest hill and the biggest
side of town. All of that fucking ric
flair shit. Right with minus the humor.
They could have all of that.
And the fact that everybody beneath
them wasn't miserable on some level.
I don't honestly think that
they could enjoy it. Um,
who is a bill? Give me one name. I don't
know. I looked at the news for 10 minutes.
That's,
that's what I felt.
That's why I don't watch it cause it makes
me think things like that. All right.
I don't like fucking seen people
around the world crying. I don't,
you know, I gotta commend people
who actually try and pay attention.
Maybe that's why they,
they just blame one side or the other.
Cause other than that, if you just sort
of try to look at it in an impartial way,
you just like, we're just the
fuck are we doing to each other.
It's really depressing.
So let's get out of this.
Okay.
You know, grandma could solve any
fucking problems. Here was kitten hope.
This podcast is supposed to be an
escape. Um, anybody watched the,
uh, the Sally's Boston Celtics
First, the Cleveland Cavaliers.
I had a bad feeling about this one. I was
like that white dude and platoon like,
man, I got a bad thing. Um,
before the [inaudible] stop for shit
this time I thought Lebron was going to
come in and I was like, oh boy.
Oh boy. That was the thought.
Isaiah Thomas explained, but he wasn't
playing and love went down. But I mean,
he played most of the game, but, uh,
so that's the game. We should have one.
And not only did we win, we won by 20.
And you know what that means? Come April.
It doesn't made shit,
doesn't mean shit.
Maybe if we go down to one game
and it comes down to home court,
we win by one game. Maybe it means that,
but other than that, it's just a winter.
January.
But,
um,
I dunno, when I look at the Cavs,
I'm just like, all right, these guys,
when they get to the fucking playoffs,
they got enough grizzled vets and then
they got superman playing for them.
They got jr Smith was the Shit Isaiah,
we all know what the fuck he could do.
They got fucking Jae Crowder,
right? I mean they, they,
and then they got love. I mean,
that's a hell of a fucking team. So,
but when I look at the Celtics, I just
see that when next, you know what I mean?
It's like Cleveland is that old movie
star that's still fucking selling more
tickets than the young buck coming
up. But that person knows, they know,
right?
They know that that Burt Reynolds and uh,
I don't know with Tom Cruise,
I don't know who to pick next.
It went Burt Reynolds and
then it was Tom Selleck,
which was weird when I was growing up
every fucking like movie star Dude,
we had to be a guy's guy
with that fucking mustache.
So it went from Burt Reynolds,
who I think established the look,
right?
Danny had Tom Selleck,
Danny had that Guy Played Matt Houston.
And then somewhere in there
the mustache went away.
But there was like a seven to
eight year period without mustache,
you know, in the black curly
hair, you had to have that shit.
You know all these fucking groups that
think all you gotta do is just be a white
guy and the door opens.
No,
they're looking for that fucking dude.
You had to be that white dude with the
jet black hair and that fucking mustache.
And if you had to beat the Marlboro man,
you look like me. My fucking role models
growing up. Who was all be Ron Howard,
Ralph mouth burning for room two 22.
None of them got any pussy,
you know what I mean?
Rob Ritchie was fucking ear,
longterm fucking relationship
and the prime of his life.
Well Lori Beth lily doing this weekend,
meanwhile Fonz having a fucking
threesome over by the jukebox.
Everybody's looking together way.
Why? Because he had that hair.
We had that fucking, you had the right
colored hair. That's how it works. Um,
anyways,
I don't mean what the fuck up talk,
what the fuck was I just talking about
Burton while we were talking
about basketball here. Fuck.
Am I talking about Fonzie now?
Basketball. So that was a big,
there was a big one for us.
Big Guy, Dearborn for us.
But you know who's getting here?
You could beat the cavs in January,
but could you win four out of seven
April a bad ad. Let the big boys,
you got bad blood there plugged in. Short
job. One lady to dumb, all that bullshit.
Right? But whenever it was
a fun game to watch and uh,
considering I took my lady to a Celtics
game when I went home for Christmas,
uh,
she's kind of watching now.
I gotta watch and it's fucking incredible.
She's not rabid yet. She's not rabbit. I
got to get them into the day in, day out,
fucking soap opera of it. You know
what I mean? The way she got me into,
uh, uh, what does that
fucking show that she watches
hip hop a love,
something like that.
Love and hip hop.
That's what it is.
I fucking watched that show.
I can actually sort of handle that show
other than there's just one check on
there who just, I swear to God, I
don't know what she just looks like.
She looks like an evil man. You know
what I mean? And I don't mean like a
like sinister, I literally literally
mean like possessed by the devil.
How did they do this fucking weird thing
on all reality shows now I think they
kind of stopped,
but these were older episodes.
Do you know that thing they do where
they put those, those cat eyes,
whatever that filter,
whatever the fuck the proper
technology technological term is.
When they shoot those people talking
right on the reality shows they do that
thing where they give them like
three highlights in the fucking eye.
Then it looks like they're starting to
turn into something but they never do.
You know what I mean?
Um, they kind of do that.
I don't fucking know.
I don't know.
I never feel wider though when I like
when I watch love and hip hop though,
you know what I mean? Cause I have
no idea what's the fuck's going on.
I can't tell who's a good rapper.
Who is it? But I will tell you this,
like most white people,
if you change your fucking we've,
I can't stay I the amount of times
I'm like, that's the same woman.
Cause they'll cut back and forth
and the woman will go from jet black
hair to fucking blonde hair or,
or black with purple and then change
the color of a fucking eyes. You know,
as white as I am, I can't. That's a
completely different person. Yeah.
Um, which is why no white
person should ever be on a jury.
All right.
If there's somebody black evolved,
I feel just from just from my own
personal experience how fucking dumb I am.
I just made that blanket
statement on all that.
The entire Jujitsu judicial system
should work in this country.
How about those fucking Boston Bruins?
Huh?
They fucking want again, they're like
seven. Oh one, two when their last nine,
what did Jakob would say?
And then he said like 16,
three and two in the last 21.
They're on fire right now.
Yeah.
They were on fire when it doesn't count
now. Um, you know the deal, but it's,
it's great that they're playing with
at the plane and I haven't been able to
watch them as much.
I know that they're playing the panther,
so I'm watching that game. So, uh,
cause I'm in the both teams right now.
So now rather than,
I usually what I did was I would watch
almost every Bruins game and then I would
watch,
you know,
yeah.
Important Celtics Games or
whatever. But, uh, now I kind of,
I've gotten into both of them because
they're both young teams playing fucking
great.
And I got a kid and just the way it's
been working with the dad responsibilities
is every time the fucking Bruins have
a game, I got to do some dad stuff,
which of course comes first. No
disrespect to my beloved Bruins. Okay.
Um, but anyways, I have, I'm going to
watch what does it tomorrow night. Yeah.
Game comes on at five on the, I can watch
that. I'll definitely watch that. Um,
all right, so that's it. I think I don't
have anything else to talk about. Oh,
by the way.
All right.
I want to thank that person that fucking
said that I was an alcoholic and that I
should be a friend of bill
w for whatever the fuck it,
which just sounds like another Bush,
you know,
it's going to be running for office,
um,
later on sitting down to South America
with the fucking land that he bought that
sits on a fucking
aquifer painting.
Yeah,
I would,
I,
the amount of money I would pay
t to just be in George W's had,
you know, not Obama said Obama
just sounds like he would be,
he would sound like the way
you talk all Oklahoman Club,
all the fuck he was talking
about. You know, but I dunno,
there's something about WWE,
they always fascinated me.
He would just be sitting there
like, what the fuck was it?
What the fuck was that?
Did I really do that shit?
You know,
I don't sell about that guy I was looking
at that looks like the kind of guy
would take summer school with,
you know,
Obama was like the kiss ass
fucking raise his hand when
you forgot to assign homework.
You know, it really is, is
I don't like smart people.
You know, I have a lot of weird things.
I don't know. I don't let a certain type,
I don't like book smart people.
Uh,
just cause I see this is all petty shit
just cause I'm not good at it. And uh,
and the older I've gotten, I realized
somewhere along the line, uh,
I don't like beautiful women.
Obviously they're fun to look at.
Obviously my wife is fucking gorgeous.
I think she's gorgeous.
But generally speaking, I don't like
beautiful women. I just don't like it.
And it's for very simple
reason that did fucking rude
ditch there,
just fucking rude.
They just don't have just,
just common politeness I guess on some
level because if they're even remotely
polite, maybe a guy's like, oh, she wants
it. And then they can't get rid of them.
But,
uh,
ditches, ditches, fucking rude.
I can't tell you the amount of fucking
times at the end of my show is right.
Someone will come back,
some guy will come back,
you know, a couple of guys
and they got like, you know,
three or four beautiful women with them,
whatever.
And they come back to say thank you
for the show and the fucking woman,
I swear to God, they just
stay, they're always bored.
Never say thank you. And I always
end up feeling like, just this.
I always want to be like,
why didn't you two guys just come back
here and just say, obviously I don't,
didn't enjoy the show, or they're upset
that they didn't get to meet Oprah.
I don't know what I mean. This is
all I got. I went bald, red, edited.
Dad's jumps around like a fucking
monkey or more. Do you want from me?
I swear to God, take, they come back.
They don't even say thanks even if
you didn't like the shell. Right.
Okay. Like say I went to
one of their fucking show,
some fashion show where they
walked down the fucking runway.
Like they're all pissed off.
You know?
I don't know why God knows
I haven't bought a drink and
their whole fucking life,
I don't know what they're so fucking mad
about. Even if I didn't enjoy the show,
even I'd like that what they were
wearing was ridiculous. When I went back,
I would be nice enough to be like, Hey,
you know? Yeah. I liked the way. Yeah.
When you walk out your legs crossover
and funny, but you did a heck of a job.
You know you didn't, you didn't fall over
in those shoes? I could never do that.
I would at least have the common decency
to say that or I wouldn't go back there.
Okay.
Bored shitless. I'm bored
shitless. Which I, I dunno.
I always find have always fight the
urge to be like, what do you do?
What the fuck do you do other than
sit there and look at amazing,
what the fuck did you just sit there?
Mm.
How many times a day?
It is a beautiful woman,
sy just out a board as
you know what I mean?
I just feel like you could take them to
an SNL taping and they would be excited
until like, I don't know, somewhere
in the middle of it, you know,
when the sketch wasn't about them
they would just start to get upset.
This is really good. I shouldn't say
they're all like that, but just generally,
generally speaking. Um, I dunno,
that's just something that
happened to me recently.
Just struck me as funny and I was,
I called up via afterwards and I was
just going off on it and she was laughing
her ass off. I got that. Just
why are they so fucking rude?
I just don't understand it.
Go fucking go hang out with some
beautiful people. I'm sorry. I'm ugly.
Jesus Christ.
What the fuck do you want from me?
I didn't ask you to come back here.
I just kept thinking of
that Richard Pryor bit.
When he went to the fucking White House,
they invited him to the White House and
then they treated them like shit and his
wife's try to calm him down.
He's in the back room and he's just like,
I am asked to come in this mother fucker.
It was one of my favorite
lines he ever had.
I didn't ask to come to this motherfucker.
MMM.
Anyways, I don't even know what
I'm talking about. You know what?
I got my first advertising of the year.
Holy Shit.
I'll tell you I was dying on
the vine there for a minute.
MMM.
Maybe cause I say dumb shit like
I don't like beautiful women.
I have not beautiful women by
40% of our products. Ah, right.
Sorry, that was my
password. All right. Okay.
Here we go. Look who's
back everybody. Okay.
[inaudible] days, no more sweaty balls.
But it do to be a, these beyond the,
take the bitch to the mall by
everything in the fucking store.
She don't care cause she's a whore. She's
looking for someone with a shiny yeah.
Car.
This is why I don't watch reality TV.
That is really my big complaint
when Nia watches reality television,
just because I have major issues with
fucking women that I had been working on
for a long fucking time. And you know,
if you've noticed in my last specials,
I really have stayed away from,
you know,
the epic levels that I've gone to at some
point to the point I watched them now,
like, what the fuck is wrong with me? Um,
but now she's got me watching this
reality show and it's just every fucking
thing.
Every paranoia that I have about
him is just shown in his I,
it's just constant throughout
the whole fucking thing.
Um,
yeah.
You don't have to be like, it'd be
like if you were a Ya, you a woman,
you had issues with men and every night
you had to come to my house and watch
fucking Monday night raw or some sports
radio show we listened to like the
dumbest of the dumb guys.
Okay.
Are you talking about their secondary?
You know what I would've
done in first grade?
Just having to listen to that
like that would somehow, anyways,
let's get back to the underwear here.
Alright, me on these heavy buddy.
You know you were thinking about he awake.
We know you were thinking about the
gym membership for the New Year.
Wait a second.
This is me on these coffee.
All of a sudden they're
fucking doing horoscopes.
We know you're thinking about the
gym membership for the New Year.
Why don't you commit to comfort and
sign up for a me undies membership,
fresh new undies and socks
delivered to your door every day.
Choose from bold classic or adventure is
prince switch between membership plans.
Cancel or skip a month at any time.
May on d southern most comfortable
fucking underwear. Your will.
You'll ever own made from sustainably
sourced naturally soft fabric that is
three times softer than cotton. I
love how they don't say modal, modal.
They don't say that anymore.
I want to say it's because of me.
They finally got sick of trying to
teach me how to say it. Alright,
offer must read right now.
Get me up.
[inaudible] has an
exclusive offer for Jess,
my listeners and whoever else
they advertise with until
January 20th get 20% off
your membership and free shipping.
That's 20% off in already discounted
membership and be on is so sure you will
love their underwear.
They even offer a 100%
satisfaction guarantee.
You order a pair and if you don't love
your first pair, get a full refund.
I would love to listen to their
fucking complaint line. Oh I said man,
I love the colors are rot.
Yeah,
okay.
I got camouflage cause it got anal leakage
and I thought to being a brown in it.
The higher the fucking skid marks.
Become a member today for the best
membership you will ever sign up for me on
these four with me on these.com/bird
that's meundies.com/ [inaudible] become a
member today and start enjoying all the
perks of having a be on these membership
and start wearing the best
underwear of your life.
It changed my life ever
according to the copy.
It's time to let me on these change.
Yours.
Go to [inaudible] dot com slash
burr right now, B u. R. R. O.
When we got one other he likes Helux.
You know there are a ton of online
mattress retailers popping up these days.
All with a one.
So you think the heroin epidemics bad,
these fucking mattress retailers
that just, they're everywhere.
All with the one size fits all
solution to a better sleep.
It's like the music man, except
with mattresses. Well, guess what?
One size fits all,
doesn't work.
How asleep he looks, offers something
that doesn't exist anywhere else.
A mattress personalized to your unique
preferences and a sleeping style that
won't set you back. Thousands
of dollars. Go to helix,
sleep.com/board take their simple
two to three minute sleep quiz.
They'll build a custom mattress that we'll
even though we the best thing he ever
slept on for couples, they even
personalize each side of the mattress,
which we all know is the beginning of
the end of the relationship. All right,
for guys in the prime of their life that
sleep on their stomach and wake up with
a hard on,
they even have a little banana shaped
dividend there so you can continue to
sleep.
Everyone from Gq to cosmopolitan to try
to New York Times are all talking about
how like sleep and once you try it out
you go, Oh, you've got to know why.
Your custom mattress arrives direct
to your door in a week and shipping is
completely free. Tried for a Honda and
a hundred nights. If you don't love it,
they'll pick it up. Gross,
pick it up with what
fucking hazmat suit with a beekeeper
suit over and their refund you in full.
Oh Man. If I had that job, I would be
cursing out that BW fucking animal.
I would give him so much shit.
Why don't you just fucking just
tight onto the top of your car,
drive by skid row,
and then just cut the rope and let it
fly into those fucking people, you know,
you know,
site you be of a mattress landed on your
tent once you got over the fact that
the building is sleeping next to
it and collapse on you. You know,
I'm talking to mattress, not a box sprain.
I don't want anybody to get hurt here.
You just have it fall down and then
you just put your tent back together,
you know, right on top of the
mattress. That'd be the shit,
right? I mean, you know, other than that,
you live it on outside. Uh, go to helix,
sleep.com/pro right now and you get
$50 towards your custom metrics.
That's Helen's sleep.com/ [inaudible]
for $50 off your order. He likes
sleep.com/barb oh right.
There you go. All right, so
these Aa guys wrote in on Monday,
you know,
with their smarmy, we really
care about you. You know,
trying to say that I was
a fucking alcoholic. Why?
I want to tell you something right now.
Friends of Bill W it is July 3rd right?
By the time you hear it's going to
be July 4th and aloe already gone.
Three A's in a fucking row.
All right? It was on the wagon.
431 days jumped off for
six glorious fucking days.
Glorious days. Oh, it
tasted delicious. Right?
And I'm right back on it.
You know,
God Damn Aa people date,
they don't like that could do that.
That I can dip in and dip out.
They don't like that.
They think I'm going to lose my old
life in, in, in, in, in the bottle.
I'm not, and I'm stopping right now.
You know, just out of pure vanity.
I just like fucking
not just being a bloated booze bag.
That's why you stopped to begin with.
I didn't stop for the right reasons.
I stopped because I didn't want to
be a fat fuck. That's why I stopped.
You know, I swear to God, I want to go to
a fucking AA meeting. I want to go down.
I want to listen to those stories again.
It's fucking, stories are incredible.
You know, I can't imagine if quint
terantin and went to a fucking Aa meeting,
the movie that that man
went right afterwards.
All he's gotta do is
listen to their stories,
throw some karate in there
and get Jamie Foxx. I mean,
that's how do you not watch that fucking
movie and then put it in 70 millimeter
like he did his last one, the
hateful eight. Anybody else?
See the hateful eight and 70 millimeter
and that fucking stage coach came into
this with the whole orchestra piece.
It was incredible.
One of any writers do that Shit,
man.
You gotta feel bad how
he's just going down there.
All those people fucking
fucked up their lives.
The misery that they've gone through
and you're going down there pretending
you're one of them to see.
You can get some good dialogue for your
fucking script and maybe sell something
to see a wife will quit
calling you a loser. You know,
I don't know if this happens.
I have no idea.
I don't know why I'm acting
like this is fucking happening.
I'm not saying it's happening, but
you know, it wouldn't surprise me.
Right. You know, it's
really surprising me is, is
the fact that I still have another
four and a half fucking minutes to go.
And this is one of the few times that I
don't have anything to fucking say. Oh,
I got one for you. You know what I did
today? I did Jones, these jukebox on
K,
Los Steve Jones from the sex pistols.
I've always been a fan of
his is his radio program.
It's on from 12 to two in the afternoon.
He plays whatever he wants.
Sometimes he picks up the
guitar and just makes up a song.
He always has great guests
and all that type of stuff.
But I'm an old man, so I,
I never knew where it was.
I would always find it.
And then I, you know,
I don't know how to set the
fucking buttons in my radio,
at least the back in the day.
So I, I don't know. He had a,
he has a great one and then the guy
from the e street band, little Stevie,
what is his little Stevie's garage?
They just amazing fucking Djs in their
knowledge of music is incredible.
And the fact that they are
actually you listening to basic,
you listen to a fucking rockstar
playing the music that he enjoys.
There's not a lot of radio shows
like that. You know what I mean?
So I got to go down there
today and do it. And, um,
I knew that guy was funny,
but Jesus Christ hung out on his
show for like 90 minutes and, uh,
I, I could barely keep up with
the guy, you know what I mean?
He's not supposed to be standup
comedian level funny, right?
He's supposed to be musician level.
Funny.
It was fucking unbelievable. Guy Was a
guy was hilarious. So if you listened,
I hope you'll listen to it. Um, I
had a great time on that and um,
I also realized how little I know about
music because he plays all this cool
shit, you know, and I listened to all
the mainstream stuff, so he was like,
you know, think, what
did you listen to? Uh,
I said I was growing up. I was
like, you know, hair metal,
heavy metal ACDC.
Stevie ray bond.
That's about it.
And then my dad's big band swing,
I don't think you played that shit
on your Dhea and he's out playing.
So he ended up playing a motley crew,
uh,
looks at kill and then into ACDC livewire,
which I thought was pretty
cool that he did that.
But I was actually kind of nervous that
he was going to lose some of his fan
base. Like who is this stupid
comedian requests in this shit? Um,
but I don't think we got any
goddamn complaints. Um, you know,
it was cool was he actually
had the, uh, always at the, uh,
Chelsea arsenal game on
in the background and um,
I just cannot get into that
shit unless I'm over.
And if you over in England,
it's impossible not to get
into it. Everybody gives a
fuck. Everybody's drinking.
People care. He tried to get into
it over here. It's so fucking quiet,
you know,
which you and a couple of nerdy friends
that there's just no fucking place to,
to watch it at that level to get into it.
But at least when you watch the premier
league game, you can hear the crowd,
how much they're into it.
Um, but like American soccer,
Jesus Christ, he gave her
a fucking pin drop. Um, uh,
less Mexico's playing in,
it's out here in la.
Then it sounds like this is amazing.
So he had that game on the background
and just watching how much he gave a fuck
plus with his accent,
it was the shit.
And I got into the game and his team
went up a two to one and he was nervous
with 10 minutes left. And the last
thing I said to him was like, dude,
10 minutes left in a soccer game is like
0.8 seconds left in a fucking hockey
game in the pucks on the
other end of the ice. This,
this game is over that
nobody is almost like a rule.
They're not going to score
four goals in one soccer game.
So I go home and I'm fucking trying
to find the Celtics game tonight.
And I went on Fox sports and they were
talking about the game in fucking arsenal
, came back and scored a goal somehow in
the last 10 minutes. So it was to, to, to,
to ended up in a tie. They got
jinxed it. So my apologies. Um,
but you know what?
I've always been trying to have a fucking
team when I was over and I knew there
was no way I could root for man United
because that's like when I go over to
England, I see somebody with a
fucking Yankee hat on. It's like, ah,
you fucking mouth breathing.
Can't, why are you a Yankee fan?
Why? Who could take one, two motor?
It's the only fucking team
I know the fuck out of here.
I want to go over there and
see somebody with a blue.
Jay had on some shit like that.
So it's like there's no fucking way I can,
I can do that. So, uh, I've been trying
to pick a team over there and uh,
maybe I'll, maybe I'll follow
Chelsea. I have no idea.
I don't know what the fuck I'm doing.
All I know is it's late at night and I'm,
Oh my God, I wish I saw that text
earlier. Somebody just fucking texted me.
You going out tonight cigar.
Oh, that would be tremendous. Um,
I'm trying to cut down on
those fucking things too.
Just maybe it's good that I didn't see it.
I'm actually gonna I'm going to try to
live the rest of this month the way I
lived when I was eight.
All right.
Which is basically no booze,
no fucking porno,
no cigars.
You know, I'll go buy a bicycle,
paternity of a paper route again.
Um, I dunno. I'm fucking enjoying the, uh,
the clean living and then every once
in awhile fucking a little debauchery.
Maybe I'll do that.
I'll be fine.
I'll office six weeks on for four days.
That wouldn't be bad. Right? Would
that be bad for your liver? Um,
the thing is I have too much expensive
booze here and I can't just leave it
there and I'm not giving it away. At
some point I've got to fucking drink it.
Right? All right, Bill. You know what?
We don't give a fuck about you and
your stupid boots. All right. I get it.
I'm done talking about it. Um, all
right. That's the Thursday afternoon,
just before Friday, Monday morning
podcast. I hope you have an a great,
what are you new year's resolutions?
What are you doing?
You know what I'm trying again then I've
failed with all the fucking time is I'm
trying to get back to become
fluent in French again.
I'm back on that dual lingo.
Fucking train and out again.
I got the flashcards,
I got all of that shit.
I need a French friend.
You know,
someone just fucking hang out and
talk to me like I'm a baby in French.
You know,
the way my kids going to learn English,
like they got to teach it that way,
you know? And you know what it is.
There's been enough people going to do,
you never gonna learn that shit. Um,
that's the only way I learned
shit. Is it so much? Yeah.
You're never going to do that then. I'm
like, Guy, fuck you. I'm going to do it.
But if they say low, yeah,
you should have no problem,
then I blow it off and all right, fuck
it up. One or the other. I don't know.
Just feels like a fucking therapy
session. Um, all right. That's it.
I get nothing. I got nothing for you.
Um, I've got no gigs is fucking month.
I might be doing something.
I might be doing a show in San
Francisco cause I'm going up there.
Kevin Pollock for sketch fest. I'm going
up there and I don't, I don't know,
doing something with him at one in
the afternoon at the Castro theater,
which I believe is on the 15th,
the 15th in fucking January. Hold on
a second. Let me see if this is right.
Let me see.
That may see the 13th.
It's on the 13th. Um, and I might,
I might be doing a couple
shows at cops that night.
I'm trying to see if that's gonna happen.
I probably shouldn't have said
that because it just falls through.
Then they're gonna be like, what the fuck?
She's sharing a book. A book. Good. Um,
all right. That's it.
Enjoy the music. And, uh,
the new plane of another half hour
greatest hits from a Thursday afternoon
podcasts from a Thursday. Uh, I
dunno, early this year from years ago,
I have no fucking idea and maybe I'll
lose another fan because they say
something about Jesus. All right, see you.
[inaudible] [inaudible]
[inaudible] [inaudible] about
my week.
I had a fucking insane week.
I went to the rose with a fellow
comedian and I'm not gonna name his name.
Usually I'll do that. Maybe
it give somebody, you know,
bump up their friends or that type of
stuff, which I'd love to do for this guy,
but my behavior was so,
uh,
colorful. That's the word I'll
use that you know, just in case,
you know what I mean? I'm old
school. I don't name names.
When I start talking about a semi crimes
that I committed, not really committing,
well I guess being drunk
in public is a crime bill.
Why don't you shut the fuck up and get to
the story and we'll, I'll be the judge.
Fine. Fine. You guys with all the
tension beginning of 2009 you know,
so you guys be more relaxed this year.
You know,
things don't be fad in 2009
love the thing you gotta rhyme.
You know, just make it rhyme
and then, then, then, then
I'm supposed to feel good.
You know, and I'm not supposed
to notice that last year it was,
things are going to be great in 2008
and now you've, you've knocked it down.
Now it's things. They'd be
fine things. It'd be great man.
They're going to be fine.
You know,
don't freak out in 2010 oh did they
combine this with Canada in 2011
why am I fucking checking myself out at
a grocery store and I'm not getting paid
for it? Okay, so my name is,
I go to the rose bowl with a comedian.
We're just going to call him Joe.
All right.
Cause that's the classic alias name.
When you don't want to get somebody
in trouble, you just call him Joe.
But the ironic thing is this
guy's name is actually gel.
So me and Joe,
we go to the a fellow comedian in a,
now you can try to figure out who the
fuck he is and it's not fiscal. Um,
we go to the Rose Bowl and, uh,
we had great intentions. Okay.
Let me paint a picture for you.
Okay. When you go to the rose bowl,
it's one of the great
tailgating experiences you'll
ever have. First of all,
you go into the Rosebowl,
okay.
The granddaddy of them all home have
a bunch of Superbowls Superbowls with
polluted that super bowl.
Uh,
if you see that famous Lynn
Swann catch that wasn't made,
they're actually realized that was
made at Temple University, wasn't it?
I don't fucking know.
There's been on,
I know that Jackie Slater one where
he dropped the ball. That's right.
That that cowboy Steelers won
the greatest fucking, I dunno,
clash of two powerhouse
teams I ever saw was the, uh,
I dunno,
whatever they played.
Once you're fucking things there and I
don't have the information in front of me
and I'm really killing the momentum of
the story. So anyway, so you go there,
right? And, uh,
you get right behind the Rosebowl is
what I'm assuming is an 18 hole golf
course.
Cause God knows that's how big it felt
at the end of the game when I was two
shit faced and we couldn't find
the car and we walked before.
But that, that I'm getting ahead of
myself. You know what I'm foreshadowing,
I'm doing what all great movies.
Do you know what I mean?
You go see a movie whenever they
show a movie about a guy who dies,
everybody knows he's going to die. So
they show them, died in the beginning,
and then the next scene is they go back
to his childhood. You know what I mean?
Except they never do that with the Elvis
movie because then they'd have to start
the movie with some fat fuck dying on
a toilet and no one wants to do that.
I'll just won't. Well,
is that my pancreas?
PLOP? Um, anyways, so Jesus Christ,
let's get some momentum
here. So we fucking, we go
to this tailgate. All right.
And this is the deal. Basically,
there's just two of us. And amongst us,
we have four hamburger patties,
two bags of chips, hamburger buns,
12 pack of Bud Light,
12 pack of Budweiser,
and a Clint Eastwood canteen,
size of fucking crown royal,
and to Cuban cigars that I
snuck back from fucking Canada.
So we're ready to go. I got my
sunblock, we loaded up into the Prius,
which is, uh, which was just fucking
hilarious. You know, everybody,
everybody tries to outman people
at the, uh, at the tailgates,
people cone up there with
their, their fucking, you know,
for two or pickups with the lift
kits, you know, the generators,
Skype, fucking satellite dish
in a flatscreen TV. You know,
I came there with a little Hibachi,
but whatever.
We had the big thing of crown royal,
so people and Cuban cigars.
So no one fucked with us, right?
So we're having a great time.
All of a sudden this lady comes
walking by and she's like, Hey,
do you want to buy a little ticket
holder fee? A ticket? I'm like,
absolutely sweetheart. 10
bucks a whack. Let me get,
let me get that two times at baby. You
know, you got a cigar in your mouth,
you start getting a little swagger.
Some reason when he likes
starts rocking back and forth,
like you've got to sing it. Like you got
to sing an Elvis song. I was feeling it.
And the great thing was I didn't give a
fuck about either team USC or Penn State.
I was just happy to fucking be there,
you know?
But I quickly realized most
people were for the Trojans.
So automatically I'm a cunt.
Second concert of the year,
I'm like, you know what,
I'm going to root for the,
I'm going to root for Penn state because
this gives me way more chance to annoy
people. Plus, I, I've
never liked USC and uh,
most of it has to do back in the day.
I used to be a Notre Dame fan before
Lou Holtz with their holy or holier than
thou. We don't do steroids. Shut
the fuck up. Yes you do. All right.
I had acne when I was fucking a teenager,
right? But it wasn't all over my back.
And I also couldn't pick up a
house. Okay, so you fucking,
people are doing steroids anyways.
And also I always hated
the Trojans fight song.
They played every three seconds bad that,
that ad that you know,
they came like half a yard.
And it also reminds me of Fleetwood Mac
who I never liked. So fuck the Trojans,
right? So anyway, so we're sitting there
and we're drinking or partying would eat,
we eat burgers and a then we break out
the crown royal after we'd had polished
off a good half a case
between the two of us.
It's probably nine 30 in the morning.
And we just started
pounding this crown royal,
which is going down like fucking Koolaid.
I was really impressed with my ability,
or at least the, the makers of prawn
royal. That is some smooth shit. So,
uh,
so basically we start walking towards
the stadium and the alcohol is flowing
through me and that's when
I go into my transformation.
I don't know what happens
to me at sporting events,
but instantly I just become the loud guy.
I feel like I'm,
I'm doing a comedy show.
I want to make the people around me laugh.
And I also want to irritate as
many fucking people as I can.
So I start walking in there
and I quickly notice, um,
well I know I went to go buy a program,
I'm trying to put this all back
together cause I was pretty drunk. I go,
just to give you an idea of,
of the mood that I was in,
I get to about a hundred
yards from the stadium.
This lady's selling programs and she's
like, Eh, get your program. Come,
c'mon. Get the grants and
like, ah, fuck it. I want, I
want a souvenir. So I walk up,
Mike, how much are they?
She's like, 10 bucks. My God,
I find so this other guy comes walking
up because how much for the programs?
And The lady's like 10 bucks, right?
And the guy starts bitching to boot.
You kidding me? Right? So I'm standing
there, I got a Cuban cigar. I go,
you know what? Let me get another one,
two times. Let me get two of those.
All right, one for you over there.
And the guy's like, really? I go, Hey,
I go take a look at me. They go,
you know what you're looking at.
You're looking at a big shot.
Take a good look. There's not a,
there's not a lot of us left. I swear
to God, I said that and I was so drunk.
I was only half joking.
Like I knew I was being an asshole,
but like I was only half a fucking
Cuban cigar. Go Fuck Yourself.
I'm a big shot. Let's get a program
for this fag over here. Who,
who's bitching about 10 goes still rose
bowl in bitches about a $10 fucking
program.
You know what I mean?
He should have been de pants and he should
have his tickets removed right there
and sent right back to wherever
the fuck you keep key came from.
Send to an Applebee's, watched
the game there. All right.
Kind of fucking behaviors. That is
the granddaddy of them all. Thank you.
Fucking money out and play
the Goddamn game. All right.
So anyways, so I'm Hammock,
right? And we're fucking,
we're walking and uh,
I don't know what happened when we got
into the stadium. Everything was cool.
And then they have this weird sort of
like they funnel you in because it's a
really old stadium. It's like, you know,
it's like trying to go through the
Lincoln tunnel like five o'clock at night.
It's a pain in the ass.
So I'm standing there,
I'm getting frustrated
because it's getting close
to kickoff and I hate missing
kickoff. So I'm getting pissed. And
I noticed that the Penn state fans,
they've got this chant where one of them,
I don't know where it just yells,
we are. And then all the Penn
state fans go Penn state.
And then the dude yells again,
we are.
And they all go Penn state and they say
it like five times. And then the end,
the guy who starts the chant goes
thank you. And then everybody screams,
yo welcome.
And I immediately noticed that it annoyed
the shit out of all these UFC fence.
You know,
cause they kind of felt like it was a
home game cause they were out there.
So next thing you know, I didn't
even think it. Next thing you know,
coming out of my mouth, I'm
going, we are, I'm not even,
I'm not from Penn state. I don't know
Shit, right? But I just stuck on,
we got every site's going,
Penn state, Penn state,
and I'm like, thank you. And
they're like, Yo, welcome. I'm like,
this is fucking awesome.
I can do this to a whole game and annoy
the shit out of people around me. So
like it took us 20 minutes,
20 minutes to get through the tunnel
and I swear to God, I was like,
perfect timing light.
As we got through the tunnel,
this check is finishing
singing the national anthem
as we just take in the rose
bowl on a sunny California day,
everybody's wearing that Trojan colors.
Everybody's wearing that Penn state.
There's pompoms.
People are going fucking nuts.
And this lady's like, Eh, no.
Ho up the up wave.
And what is,
she finished a fucking stealth bomber.
Flies right over the goddamn top. I'm
shit faced. It's like a fucking acid trip.
I almost passed out. Right? So now
you know, we've got end zone seats,
you know, evidently I'm not a big shot.
And we'll wait at the top of the stadium,
which is a really rough thing to
negotiate when you're a redhead drinking
whiskey in the sun,
right?
We get all the way up to like row
whatever, fucking triple f and you know,
it's an old stadium. Okay. And you know,
back in the day, like you were tall,
if you will, like five foot six when
the stadium was built. And now you know,
with fucking growth hormones and
all the preservatives in the food,
we basically outgrown the stadium's,
not to mention the cheesecake factories
that have these fucking people go to
every other day.
So I'm trying to walk a tight rope down.
I'm literally acting this
out on my bedroom by the way.
This is how into these stories I get
to tell show I'm literally walking a
fucking tight rope trying to get down
to my seat and I just become that guy.
I fell, I didn't fall. I sorta like,
like Lyft.
It was like almost like I was on his show.
I was the only guy in a ship that
was in a fucking perfect storm.
And all of a sudden the whole thing just
lifted to the right side and I landed
on this like 55 year old lady back.
Didn't like land like I was doing.
I was on one foot and I put
a knife forearm a little,
I'll Samuelson in front of the net fucking
action right on her back and I was so
drunk it took me,
I swear to God at least 28 seconds to
get off her and the entire time I am
apologizing with my fucking cigar whiskey
breaths just got on site on the side
of the fight and I just,
I couldn't get off cause I the only way
to get off or was to put all my weight
on my forearm and use her as a Bannister
to push me back up because nobody's
fucking helping me because
I'm obviously the drunk guy.
You don't want to touch me.
So 28 seconds to try to figure out if I
have the quad strength to pull myself up
without pushing off the back
of this old lady's neck.
I finally just say fuck
it and just drive my,
the meat of my forearm right between
her shoulder blades and I get up,
I apologize profusely and I don't
know what Joe was doing at this point.
He was fucking probably just
standing there watching the game.
But basically we finally get to our seats.
It was unreal.
I didn't know. We got to our
seats and I, we turn around,
we faced the game to watch the game and
next thing you know this lady is just
screaming at us.
She's like,
hey screaming and she's yelling,
you can't smoke in here.
And I'm like, what the fuck is she talking
about? Because I put my my cigar out.
I'm going to tell you to do the
fucking Cuban is sweet too, man.
I smoked that thing all the
way down like a Goddamn Roach.
It's like burning my fucking fingers and
she's yelling, stopped smoking. I'm like,
the fuck she talking about do I smell
like a cigar? And I turned, I looked,
I looked to my right and Joe is standing
there with the fucking Cuban cigars
still lit in his mouth.
I don't know how the fuck you got pass
security I think is cause we had our
tickets, those tickets, things
I bought around our neck.
I don't know if he had
it down by his side,
but he's sitting there chomping on
it like fucking Archie bunker. So
you know, in the sense to me, if she
just turned around and she had just said,
hey guys, um, you know, that, you
know, I don't know if you know,
but there's no smoking in here. You
know, I would've been like, you know,
I'm a happy drunk. I swear to God, I'm
angry when I'm sober, but I sort of,
I'm a happy drunk. I just
would've been like, hey, so I
bought that. We didn't know,
oh, what do you use a good
luck, uh, by Ha High, whatever.
I would've kept it at that,
but she fucking was yelling at us.
So I don't like being yelled at.
And I like the info.
I like fucking with
people and I'm shit faced.
And Joe is of the same ilk.
And then that's when it all started.
She just based, she's like, Hey, she
goes, there's no smoking in here.
And then immediately I just
go and I just go and was like,
hey says, whoa. She goes at
California, you, I just smoke indoors.
We're like, we're outside. And she goes,
you're not allowed to smoke it. And I go,
you're not my mother. This
isn't our section. This is
in your section turnaround.
Right. I just kept being an
asshole. And then finally she goes,
I'm going to call security.
And I'm like, column. She goes,
I'm going to call him. I go, go ahead
and call them. And then in my head,
my brain is going, Bill, shut up, shut up.
You're going to get,
we're 90 seconds into the game,
you're going to get kicked out.
And I just couldn't myself.
I just kept saying
column, column. And then,
then she made some sort of comment,
I think about the size of Joe's knows,
and then he said, hey, he goes,
you need to lose a hundred pounds
to talk to me, bitch. He said,
and then the guy to the left of us
turns around and he's like, Hey,
I got my kit, I got my kid
here, what are you cursing?
And then Joe goes, well then don't
bring them to a fucking football.
So now I'm doing that laugh,
you know that last way,
like your mouth is wide open,
but there's no air coming in or out.
I'm having the time of my life
and then the fucking guy goes,
he goes, I'm going to call security.
And then I'm just then at once I can,
I'm going call up,
I'm gonna Call Him God and call up call.
I was just calling that bluff because
we were so fucking jam packed.
And I knew they weren't gonna
walk down there and go do that.
So that lady makes
another fucking comment.
At which point Joe makes another comment
about her weight and then she just
turns down and it's like mark and yells
down to her husband and next thing you
know, this fucking dude comes running
over and he starts screaming at it.
Since he's screaming at us.
This spray is coming out of his mouth
all over his wife. So it was easy.
I didn't fucking, I was just going,
sir, sir, you're spitting on your wife.
And once you know, that whole thing
was pathetic. He was like 53 but like,
and I'm 40 and I'm thinking like that
and I'm too old to fight this guy.
You know, it was just, Oh God,
I'm trying to piece this together so we
all sit down, right. So then we sit down.
I think Joe would put out the cigar.
Maybe he was just holding it down.
I don't know what was going on.
But now by this time we'd
already missed the kickoff.
The Trojan's get the ball
and I think this is the,
basically the one good play
Penn state made all day.
They Trojans their first play.
I think offense,
they handed off the ball and they tried
to do like some sort of sweep the Penn
state defense strung out and just stuck
this guy either for no gain or full lots
of one yard. And then Joe, cool.
I forgot to mention is
a good six foot four,
just a huge guy just start screaming
like an inch from the back of the Lady's
head, who's a Trojan Fan. He just
started screaming like, Nah, Nah,
Nah. I said, I can't believe
like her hair wasn't moving.
He was yelling so loud and then she, I
know she turned around, she had that shit,
that shit, that shit. It was, it was,
it was great. It was fucking great.
And then basically what would
have for the rest of the game,
shit would calm down and then we would,
we would,
I don't know,
we would mumble something about,
and then she would fucking yell down
to her husband and that he come over
threatening to kick our ass and we
would just laugh at them. And then,
I don't know,
I just realized I was so drunk.
I can't even remember the rest of the day.
I remember it was at the
very end of the game, uh,
somebody,
Joe,
if somebody said something about the score
and then the lady in front of us goes,
yeah, I'm surprised you can
count that high. I go, yeah,
why don't you try counting calories,
right. Something real mean like that.
And then once again, she's like
mark. And then at this point,
half the crowd and left
because it was such a blow out.
This dude comes over and he
starts fucking screaming at me.
It doesn't scream at Joe
because Joe is six foot four.
He yells at me cause I'm fucking barely
five 10 and I'm a fucking red head.
Right? Even with the shaved head, I
still look like fucking howdy duty.
So he starts yelling at me
and he keeps telling me, yeah,
I'm going to fire you down on the field.
So he kept saying,
he kept telling me he's going to grab
me and fire me down on the fucking field
and I was just, you know, and
I was just being an asshole.
Good dead do it. I'm going to fight on
bail. You said that you already said that.
You already said you already said
it. You fucking cunt. All right,
you've got to do it.
You would have and you didn't see you
not so sit down and shut the fuck up.
Which is funny because
by the end of the game,
everyone in the stands somehow
like dust and hated those people.
I mean half of it was
cause they were assholes.
The other half was they couldn't
hear the shit that we will mumble.
And at this dude's wife
pool,
I know at this point you might
have a little bit of sympathy for,
but I mean I'm telling
you she was, she was, uh,
she was an asshole and she's the
one who made it personal first.
She made the comment
about Joe's knows she, uh,
she was doing real hacky lines too.
She's told me I was ugly.
She goes and I always can lose
weight, you know, which, uh,
I believe I saw during the second
season of def jam and um, you know,
and I thought,
well we will come in with was a lot more
clever and if it was a battle of the
bands in a standup situation,
I think we won. So, uh,
basically what ended up happening,
I know this is a long ass fucking story.
I don't even have time for questions
this week. But long story short,
we ended up walking out.
Um,
I want to believe that somehow the lady
in front of us to who was being a jerk
had a bunch of these dark
streaks on the back of her shirt.
Towards the end of it.
I don't know what it was.
It almost looked like a
ashes from a cigar. But um,
I know that that didn't happen because
there's no smoking in there. But anyways,
we go to leave and we're
basically so drunk.
I don't know man.
It took us like fucking nine hours.
It literally took us 50 minutes to find
our car and I think it was calmer for
being such assholes in,
in, in, in the stadium.
And I don't, I don't know who the fuck's
set up the parking lot things out there,
but they basically,
the way they do the sections on this golf
course is they have like balloons that
they just have numbers, number
one, number two, number three.
But they're not lit up so you
can't really see him at night.
So you walk out of the stadium
drunk and you look up and you see,
I saw the number to where we were,
where we were parked and, but you know,
you got to follow the path because you
can't walk through the sand traps and
shit like that.
So you look down for half a second,
then you look up and there's like a big
fucking oak tree in front of you and now
you don't know where you are.
It's like the end of the shining without
the shrubs. It's a fucking golf course,
right?
So,
and you're far enough away from the
stadium where you can't get your bearings
and were just wandering
around and around and around.
And it's getting to the point like,
you know,
like hypothermia is becoming
an issue because it's a desert.
It starts getting cold,
was shit faced and we just can find a car.
It was like the Blair witch.
We kept coming back to the
same goddamn ladies keys,
whatever the fuck we were.
And then I lost all confidence in
my ability to find the damn car.
So I start following Joe,
who is convinced,
even though we both know
we're parked in section two,
we went from section three,
section four to section five,
and he keeps telling me to go in that
direction because for some reason he
thinks numerically it's going
to go three, four, five to,
I dunno, took us an hour to
find the fucking car. And uh,
at that point I started sobering up and
I started thinking about a behavior and
I was starting thinking like, yeah,
I kinda can affiliate asshole. Yeah.
You know,
I shouldn't say I shouldn't taken the
higher ground even though that girl was a
cunt, you know? And he was just
like, what are you talking about?
What are you talking
about? You, she was a cunt.
We treated her like one in and that's it.
That's what I love about that guy.
He just, he just breaks it down
to the simplest fucking point.
Hey Buddy, I've got my kid here. What?
Don't take your kid to a fucking
football game, which, you know,
I know that's harsh, especially if
you have kids, but think about it.
Think about it. Why would you bring
your kid to his professional to,
to sporting of that now only that,
that the guy with the kid is
being hypocritical because
he was me before he had
a kid. All right? He was having the
time of his fucking life and what now?
Cause he has a kid now all
of a sudden I'm supposed to,
I'm supposed to fucking act my age.
You know,
it's like the fucking
baby boom generation.
They banked so much the fucking in the
mud at Woodstock that by the time I come
around there's herpes and aids and all
this shit. And then these, you know,
then they come around with it.
Don't do drugs where a condom shit
after they had the time of their fucking
lives. I'm so glad all of them are getting
that whole generation is getting hip
replacements now,
but their fucking,
cause they all had that fucking Olivia
Newton John High impact aerobics tape
that they did try to stay in shape.
That's the one good fucking thing.
Consider I gotta fuck with the God
damn trash bag around my dick my entire
career. Right. The very least,
I at least knew to stretch before you
lifted weights and I also dangerous of
high impact aerobics. Okay.
When I did my aerobics,
I definitely was rocking the leg warmers
but I did not let my feet leave the
ground. Okay. Um, so anyways,
so that's my rose bowl story, um,
to fucking law when I know that.
But I think it had some nice moments.
But um, yeah. But getting back to that,
what do you guys think about that stuff?
You know,
sporting events are not for children.
Okay.
And I know they always try to talk
about the good old days of sports.
The girl days of sports is bullshit.
Okay.
When I was a kid, first football game
I went to, I was fucking terrified.
I was terrified.
It was not a place for kids.
It was a place for adults who hadn't
achieved what they thought they were going
to achieve in life to get their
fucking anger and frustration out.
People within loveless
marriages, you know, people,
you know,
people who could tell they were going to
get laid off the next week or maybe the
already got laid off and they just wanted
to get it out. Okay. And they, you know,
they've now turned going to a
fucking football game into like,
you're standing in line with a bunch
of people waiting to get their kids,
you know, photo taken with
Santa Claus. You know,
and even if you go further back than
my childhood, which was seventies,
early eighties, um, if
you go back to the 1950s,
they talk about that. Oh, the
good old days of sports. Oh,
what do you mean what when,
uh,
when they finally let a black guy
playing baseball and they said,
we'll fucking black cat on the field and
all that racist shit that was going on.
Can you imagine the shit that was
getting yelled in the stands when Billy
crystal was going down the go down
and go watch the mic, boy, your boy,
I got myself a hotdog and assess Barilla.
You know,
they always tell those stories about
how great it was back then. It wasn't,
it wasn't great. They were
way more racist, way more
ignorant, way more sexist.
And people went to the games and
they saw Johnny Unitas. Okay.
So now for some reason,
now it's my turn to be an asshole and be
a drunk and have a good time and all of
a sudden I have to take everything down
a level, you know, not now. Now it's,
it's Chuckie cheese time. It isn't.
And I know you guys are saying,
well that's because you don't have a
kid right now. No, fuck that. Fuck that.
I wouldn't bring my kid to the game
or if I brought the kids games,
I would prepare them. I prepare them,
you know, this is what's going to happen.
Okay. You might see a fight, you know,
hey dad might even get in one. No, I'm
not, I never took it to that level.
But you know what I mean?
I think, uh, I don't know.
This is how guilty I am from
my, my behavior though. The,
I actually pulled up a quote
from George Orwell who, uh,
granted,
this is from Wikipedia,
which the other day I looked up something
that I knew something about and it was
completely inaccurate.
But this is, according to
Wikipedia, George Orwell said,
serious sport has nothing to do
with fair play. It's a bound up.
It's bound up with hatred,
jealousy,
boastfulness disregard of all
rules and sadistic pleasures,
pleasures and witnessing violence.
In other words,
it's war minus the shooting. Exactly. Now,
why the fuck would you bring a
child to that? And not only that,
when was George Orwell alive
a long fucking time ago?
I don't know when he was
alive. When he, right.
1984 he didn't write it in [inaudible]
83 I know that he wrote like the 30.
Stephanie. I'm just saying.
See, that's how he described
sports back then. So guys,
like, you know, these Billy
crystal guys, what do you do?
Those little heartwarming
stories about, uh, you know,
their baseball cards and going down to
the baseball stadium and acting like it
was this fucking, you know, this
time that was lost, you know,
George Orwell right there,
according to Wikipedia
did guy proved my point. I'm a
moron, but I did have a good time.
I'm going to tell you like this right now.
If you ever get a chance in your
life to smoke a Cuban cigar,
definitely do it all right.
Because I'm not even a big smoker.
And I could tell how fucking amazing
that cigar was because I've drank fine
wines and I can't tell the difference,
you know?
And it took me a long time to be
comfortable with myself. You know,
when you go through the whole long
process of spinning the big red wine glass
around, I see read up on wine
to try to learn. So I, I,
you know about it.
So I wouldn't feel so fucking stupid when
they bring a nice bottle of wine over
and I'm like, you know, this tastes like
the shit I used to drink in high school.
You know, I learned
that, you know, red wine,
the reason why it's in a bigger glass is
because something about the oxygen and
you didn't want it to believe
more and how to, you know,
move it around the fucking table and
then you shove your fucking nose all the
way in it and yet put it in your,
switch it all around your mouth.
I've got all the moves down and
I'm like swallowed. I'm like, yes,
this tastes like every other fucking
red wine I've ever had. That's not true.
I can tell the difference between like,
you know, a Cabernet or my lowest,
something like that.
But like I can't tell like the
difference between a 1499 bottle and a,
a $60 bottle and uh, you know, I guess
I'm trying to say with this podcast,
I'm not that cultured.
Okay. Alright, well,
so why don't you guys shaman what that,
okay. Like what do you think David?
He should have a kids section. Should
they just have a chuck e cheese section?
It's not my fault.
You're knocked her up and you can't go
to a game and have a good time. Now,
you know, you want to be getting drunk
with me. See what I just did there.
That's how I made myself write, made this
guy who can't even defend himself, uh,
actually be secretly agreeing
with me. That's how I do it. Um,
but I mentioned I have a rental,
so
[inaudible]
hey,
what's going on is Pilbara and this is
the Monday morning podcast for Monday,
January 4th,
2010.
And I'm having a lot of difficulty doing
this fucking podcast right now because
I feel like this is like, you know,
it's my second attempt to start it.
I can already feel like this one's going
to fucking suck because I feel like I
can't fucking do what it is that I do.
Cause my downstairs neighbors
of fucking cunt, you know,
I told you guys that story,
but my downstairs for fucking neighbor,
how he waits till I'm on the road and
he starts yelling at my girlfriend about
how loud she is, you know?
And then when I come back,
all of a sudden he doesn't yell. He's like
real sarcastic. He used to do, you know,
if I drop something he'll be like, do it
again. Right. This old guy. So you know,
I'm a deck so I fucking whatever. I
dropped, I dropped it from a foot higher,
you know, like I was at yelled,
fuck. You know, this isn't even,
this isn't even like my attitude
towards the guy. Alright? My girl,
you know, she, she, she called me and
she said, look, this guy's yelling at me.
I'm really getting tired of this shit.
You know,
I want you to go downstairs and
say something to the guy, okay?
And if you guys listen to my podcast,
you know, I came to the resolution,
like where is that going to get me?
I'm not going to go downstairs and
get into it with some old guy, okay?
I don't fucking yell at old people,
all right?
I might whisper about them and column
cuts on my fucking podcast, okay?
But I have respect face
to face. Okay? He's old.
He doesn't have the Internet. He's
never going to hear this shit, you know?
So anyways, long story short is a
yesterday. And when the fuck was,
it was too,
it was January 2nd you know,
I get a big thing January 2nd
Christmas tree comes down. That's it.
It's fucking over. Alright, I
wait till the end of new years.
I went to all that stuff.
Happy New Year. Oh that Abby.
If I got air, go fuck yourself.
I go through all of that shit.
But the second that's over, it's like,
all right, it's, you know, it's game time.
Alright, back to reality. There's no fat
fuck coming down the goddamn chimney.
I don't have a fucking chimney. I have
a boarded up fireplace. All right?
So Christmas is on me.
If I don't go to best buy,
it ain't happening. You know? So, you
know, that's one of those fucking things.
If you've got kids, if you've
got kids right now, don't have,
don't have him listen to this part
as one of those fucking things.
If you're a parent, right? And you know,
you're renting a place like mine that
has a fucking boarded up fireplace.
That's when you know the questions come.
You know,
you get even further into the lie.
You know
Santa Claus, Jay do average hey yeah.
Gives you everybody around the world.
Yes he does. Yes he does.
Hey Shay comes down to Chevy.
How's he gonna do well
actually in our place,
um,
there is a chimney he comes
down at and he has a secret key,
a as a secret key and he's able to unlock
and you just sit there and your head
go on Jesus. How deep are, did you
know? You know what? There is no
fucking Santa Claus. Okay. Jesus Christ.
How fucking dumb is the person that I
made it with that you actually still
believe this shit cause I know that that's
not my half of the brain asking that
fucking question. All right kid,
do the fucking math. You know,
fat fuck has time to deliver all these
gifts to everyone around the world.
And even though you can't even
grasp the reality of that,
we have a boarded up fucking fireplace.
All right.
Come on. Let's see. Get him back his
fat ass through the fucking thing.
So anyways, so it's January 2nd. Okay.
Fucking trees coming down and uh,
I don't do it most Douche bags too.
Okay. I know fucking just, you know,
drive down the highway and toss it
off on the fucking medium strip.
Like some sort of mob
snitch. All right. I don't,
I gave two in the back of the fucking
anyone actually do I take it outside.
All right.
I fucking whack my Christmas tree.
Like fucking a Vigoda.
Remember that?
And the Godfather and he looks at Robert
Duvall, you know. Hey, fulltime sake.
Sorry. Sorry. Fish can't do
it. That's, that's how I take,
I take my tree out to the fucking driveway
and then I cut it up like a fucking
body.
I do,
I fucking saw off all
the limbs and then I,
I cut up the trunk and like four or five
different sections and I stick it into
the green trash bin like I'm supposed to.
All right.
Then I sweep up the pine needles out of
the driveway and all the fucking ones on
my living room. And that's the end.
There you go. Now the Christmas,
go fuck yourself, right? So
this is the deal. You know,
when you first get the
Christmas tree, you're watering
it. Oh, Christmas tree. Oh,
Christmas tree. In three days into
it, you're so fucking stressed out,
you stop watering it. You start telling
yourself what's fucking dead anyways.
You know, it's on its last
legs, whatever, right?
So basically by the time you drag the
fucking thing out that the tree is so God
damn dead, all right, it it, you know,
pine needles fall out, the little needles,
they fall out everywhere. All right?
And I know they're not pine needles for
all you fucking nature freaks out there.
Whatever the fuck they are,
the goddamn evergreen needles,
they start falling all over the place.
So I bring it out my front door,
stand in awe, and I start dragging
it down the fucking stairs. Okay?
And I'm trying not to be loud,
okay?
I am taking a tree down a flight
of fucking stairs. All right,
fucking water spilling. The needles
are going all over the place, you know,
but I'm being quiet and it's 10
in the fucking morning. Okay.
If I wanted to build a house,
I could actually legally
start at seven in the morning,
10 in the fucking morning,
right?
So I dragged the thing around and bring
it around the back and all of a sudden
fucking a grumpy old man sticks his head
out the door and he looks at me and he
just screams
with this bizarre look on his face.
He just said something like,
what the fuck did he say?
He just yelled out.
Beautiful morning, isn't it?
You know?
And I was looking at him like,
why the fuck did he just say something
so nice with that angry look on his face?
And for half a second I was gone at,
man, I think that guy's crazy. You know,
he made me that guy in clockwork
orange food. All right.
You know,
so I was like,
I just sort of looked
at him and I kept going.
I always forget that he's
fucking sarcastic as hell.
And whenever he says he means the exact
fucking opposite, he's basically saying,
yeah, what a beautiful fucking morning
for you to make an almost god damn noise.
So I walked back around again.
This time I look at him,
cause now at this point I finally figured
out he was fucking with me. So I'm,
you know, I'm staring
down an old man, right?
Just this is really embarrassing story.
So I walk up,
I walk upstairs, right? I
stare at him, he stares at me.
He doesn't say a fucking word
cause that's it. That's his ammo.
He doesn't like confrontations.
He says shit.
He doesn't mean he means
the exact opposite.
And he yells at people through floors.
All right? And He fucking lives alone.
If it's really sad situation, okay, so
whatever. So I go upstairs. All right,
my girls all heated, he just fucking
yelled at me again. Right? Or at our hour,
I want you to go down
that time I got it right.
I'll fucking do it
against my good judgment.
Do not go down there against my gut
saying what the fuck good is going to come
out of this.
So I go down there and I walked down
and he's fucking sitting there, right?
He's got this brick path.
He had to walk up and he's sitting at
the end of it just staring at me, right?
Expecting me to walk by his path.
But Lo and behold,
I make a left and I start walking up
his path like some sort of fucked up,
high noon Shit. And I'm
staring right at the guy. Okay?
And you know what I saw on his face?
I saw fear and I see did what all
guys do while you fucking cunt.
Jesus Christ,
Carson Palmer,
just through a fuck another interception.
The chats are up 24 nothing.
Oh my God,
it's fucking over.
Have you ever seen a fucking
team back into the playoffs?
More than the fucking jets did? Jesus
Christ. I'll tell you right now,
I fucking hate the colts as a patriots
fan, but I'll tell you right now,
maybe just sidestep this fucking story.
Let me just tell you something right now.
I feel bad for everybody in Indianapolis
that should not happen to sports fans.
When you're going for something like that,
you should lose it because
you got beat by a better team.
You don't put in fucking some guy from
home depot to be quarterback Jesus
Christ.
This is killing my prediction that Rex
Ryan was going to make an attempt on his
fucking life.
I think the NFL knows it.
So they pulled Peyton manning out a bet.
Everybody in Indianapolis Douche bag
of the week as you're fucking GM or
wherever the hell made that God damn call.
So now this week they're playing the
fucking goddamn bangles who had their best
receiver fall off the back of a
fucking truck. I mean, Jesus Christ,
I hope we don't play them. I want to do
fuck what's going to happen on our team.
I think the jet's got some sort of Mojo
going. If they're on your schedule,
something fucking horrific
is going to happen.
You're going to make a bad decision
or somebody is gonna die. So anyways,
so I'm walking up to this fucking old guy,
right?
And,
uh,
and I see fear on his face and he does
what all guys do when they get scared is
they turn the fear into anger so
they can function during this thing.
And my whole thing is, I'm coming down
here, going, build, don't lose your cool.
Let's try to fucking work this shit
out with this guy. So I just say,
uh, Hey, uh, you know, I came
out to fuck. I said, I just
said, you know, hey, you know,
you're kind of always
yelling up at my girlfriend.
We always hear you yelling up
at, as I was just, you know,
one and what the problem was. He's like,
what are your main, what is the problem?
Is faces all fucking twisted up? And
I'm like going, oh Jesus, here we go.
And like, no, you know, I just, I
know that you think that we're loud.
We try to walk around, not
put our shoes on, you know,
I just want to come down here and
you know, I just want to work it out.
And he goes, what do you mean
work it out? I'm like, you know,
I'll try to come to some sort
of resolution or whatever.
And he just starts fucking going.
She just shouted like,
she just dropped a brick on a
damn floor is screaming now.
He's screaming out. His fucking voice
is echoing through the courtyard. Okay.
And I'm fucking sitting there trying
to be civil, but I don't give a fuck.
He just banged on the fucking floor.
I'm doing an impression of you.
You fucking asshole.
So he bangs on the fucking,
I think he just banged on the
fucking floor. Dude. This is fucking,
I'm 41 year old fucking man. I'm still
dealing with somebody downstairs.
It's ridiculous. I've got to get
a fucking house. Um, anyways,
so, so he starts fucking
yelling. I don't give a fuck.
Even if you were in that loose man,
a whisper on my own fucking podcast,
fucking cunt guys been here 50 years, he's
probably paying $7 a month in rent. Um,
so anyways, yeah, I don't give a shit. The
second an old person is yelling at you,
even if you're being relaxed and when
people immediately think that you're an
asshole, you know, it's Kinda like when
a check throws a drink in your face,
it's awfully, well, well, yeah,
obviously you did something.
She has a vagina, right?
Obviously I did something,
his fucking whole body body looks like a
fucking wrinkled up, nuts sack, you know?
So this guy is fucking yelling at me
and I'm going, dude, I'm, I'm like,
I didn't say, dude, I was trying
to be aggressive with this.
I just tried to work things out. He goes,
what are, you mean? What's at work it out.
He's like, what did, what does that some
sorta new hip expression? I what he said,
it's like, oh my God, did he
just say some new hip expression?
And he's going, you know, you're
always walking across with your shoes.
And I'm like, dude, do you think I can't
hear you a TV? It's an old building.
What do you want me to do? And he goes,
AH, why don't you get lost, right?
Like, I'm in some little rascals
episode like fucking three stooges.
Why aren't you a scram? Right.
So I just kept going, no,
I didn't come down here to argue
with you. I'm, I'm trying. He goes,
I already called the landlord about Ya.
And I was like, well call him again.
Call him again.
You think they're afraid of you moving
out with your fucking $3 a month rent
fucking asshole.
They never called me cause they don't
give a shit because you're out of your
fucking mind.
So at one point I'm trying to make
a point to the guy and he just goes,
how's your band?
Like making fun of the fact
that I play guitar and I suck.
He said it unbelievably sarcastic can
really hurt my feelings for half a second.
The, he's so caught me out of
nowhere with that, that I wanted to,
I almost started re reading my resume.
I almost said,
actually I'm not event actually I'm a
comedian and I'm playing the Improv next
week.
Thank you very much.
Like that's how bad this guy caught me
and pardon me after he said, you know,
how's the band? How's your
band? I wanted to be like, dude,
how's she fucking life?
You know? But I didn't.
I didn't because I don't
yell at old people.
It probably sounds like I do.
By the way, I'm saying this.
This is the shit afterwards, when I'm
venting about it, I can really fuck me up.
So finally I was just like, you
know what? You're being a jerk.
You're being a jerk. Oh, is
that right? Is that right?
Is as I'm showing a new hip term,
if I can sit in there shaking like a leaf,
so fine.
I just,
I walked away and little did I know
that my girlfriend was standing on the
balcony above all of it, listening
to all of it. So not only did she
instigated the whole fucking
thing telling me to go down there,
she actually got to listen to this guy
trash my guitar playing, which by the way,
we both laughed our asses off about.
But before we did,
I went upstairs.
Okay.
And at this point I'm just sitting
there like mad at myself. Go,
why didn't you listen to yourself,
bill?
You knew that that wasn't
going to go anywhere, right.
So any fucking way I go upstairs
and I see my girl, I'll tell you,
see is he right? There you go.
Is that what the fuck you wanted?
Is that what the fuck wanted? I told you
that that wasn't going to go anywhere.
That wasn't going to go anywhere.
And now what he's going to do is he's
going to call all the fucking landlord and
he's going to pitch to high fucking
heaven and he's going to exaggerate
everything that fucking
went on down there.
Okay.
Unfucking believable. Unfucking
believable. And the thing was,
I felt really bad the second I got down
there. I just kept trying to go, no, no,
I'm trying to work this
out and everything.
I would say he would just repeat
it and be like, what is that?
You know? And I trashed my
guitar playing and, and I, I,
oh my God, I was like, Jesus
Christ. I was like embarrassed.
I was actually embarrassed. I
was like, wow, he can fucking
hear me. I know I suck.
I thought I played a quiet enough.
So now I'm happy with my aunt.
I got headphones on the next day
and I'm playing my awful ACDC.
It's a fucking hobby, you know, that'd
be able to get a hobby old fuck.
Like getting some friends.
See, see that's why,
that's why I kept my cool cause I would
have said Shit like that, you know,
that's fucking brutal.
And you know what's funny is my girl
still fucking pissed at the guy.
It's like a female thing I think.
Cause he's a guy and she kind of feels
like he's bullying her and stuff.
And I just kept telling him going,
you know what? I feel bad for the guy.
I just slammed the door downstairs. I
might be fucking loud. It's ridiculous.
I'm like borderline whispered here so
maybe you can hear the fucking story.
That's his passive aggressive way of
saying he disagrees with my last point.
Yeah. Slam something else. Your can't
do they have that word back in the 20s?
Can't water tap me. And it's actually,
I'm new hip word for vagina. Um,
yeah. So I was just saying that,
you know, I feel bad for the guy.
I have to whisper this part cause he
might hear cause due to that case and the
exact fucking nightmare,
Kate,
there's two ways you don't want to die
in prison and you don't want to be that
old person alone. You
don't, okay. You don't.
Okay.
You know,
if your spouse dies,
that's a different fucking story
because you live life, you know,
but you know it's, you don't wanna be
the person who never got fucking married.
Guys didn't even have a Goddamn parakeet.
He fucking always has the blinds,
you know? I know. Anyway, I didn't want
to get a fight with this fucking guy.
I feel like an asshole.
I really feel like a fucking ass hole.
So that's my situation
right now. And I, you know,
that's my situation like
the game that Jersey shore,
do you guys watch it this week?
I don't even know what week I mind.
I fucking watched the first half of
that shit and I gotta tell you, Mike,
the situation is my new fucking hero.
They actually finally showed the footage
because when Snookie got punched in the
face, I was wondering like,
where the fuck were all the guys?
How come they didn't do anything?
And they showed the footage
of Mike the situation.
Mack the situation, he didn't,
not only did he not do anything,
he continued to hit on
the girl that he was with.
And that's why I thought it was hilarious
if he didn't do anything because he
was scared,
that would've been something else.
But like this girl gets blasted
in the face by this guy.
She's on the floor sobbing and he just
looked at it almost like the way a wild
animal looks at you across
the fucking cage, you know,
when it's just sort of
looking at you and sees your,
not a threat in or whatever.
And he just immediately looks at
the girl he's with [inaudible],
you want to get something to eat,
you know, you want to get some knee,
I'll show you my edge
is fucking hilarious.
And then watching all those other guys
in the house going, you know Mikey,
the situation, he Shai the whole
fucking day. What did he do? He did not.
Then he get nothing. What do you
mean he didn't, he did no guts.
The situation, she was sitting there,
feet was enough. Played a Tortellini. Oh,
it's like the most offensive fucking
show on TV. But that was some,
that was fucking hilarious.
He didn't do a fucking thing.
He could, he could give a fuck.
And they were all sitting there
going, yeah, it's not a true friend.
You fucking right.
It isn't
whatever.
Mike,
the situation knows what he wants.
He does want to get in
the middle of that shit.
Fucking meatball standing
up there screaming at that
fucking ugly gym teacher.
Um, anyways, I didn't want,
I'm talking about now my fucking
self conscious because that's fucking
gay downstairs.
I always wondered about his life.
Like how did he end up down there? You
know, you ever see all people like that?
Like how,
how did that happen?
You know,
Jesus Christ is out here in la,
probably fucking tested from
Mchale's navy, you know,
went to network, staring across it.
Ernest Borgnine going this motherfucker.
I thought he did movies. Um, anyways, um,
I don't know where to go
with this fucking podcast.
I'm really kind of lost right now
because, uh, because of that, that shit.
Um,
so I dunno,
I was going to nominate the guy
downstairs Douche bag of the week.
I would have done that five minutes ago
when I was still pissed at and I just
felt bad for the guy.
Felt bad for the guy.
I feel bad about the
whole fucking situation.
Okay.
Jesus Christ. The guy was like
trembling as he was yelling at me.
He was so out of his mind.
I kept trying to calm him down going,
I'm trying to work this out.
Ah, I can't last. You know,
the whole thing took like fucking
it maybe two and a half minutes.
Anyways, what I know where the fuck
to go from this. Oh, by the way,
have you guys seen that
fucking scam on TV?
Whether that they're trying to sell you
that gold coin for 1995 the $50 gold
coin for 1995 and in the end they start
talking about how an ounce of gold is
worth like is selling for 1200 bucks.
I mean that's one of those things where
I don't feel bad for re I like
for people who buy shit like that.
You know what I mean?
If you're too stupid to realize that
somebody is selling you a $50 coin for 20
bucks,
that that person would be going broke
$30 a coin if you're too dumb to do the
fucking math on that.
And then also not to hear how they go 14
karat gold and then they use this term
a fee. I was going to write the
term down, I forget what it is,
but it basically mates,
they basically,
they picked up a rock at the beach and
they sort of dusted it with 14 karat gold
and it's so lightly dusted
with this fucking gold that
they can actually sell it
for 1995 and still probably
become multimillionaires.
And one of the great lines in
it is limit five per customer.
Also to put that in your head like,
Oh fuck, oh, wait a minute. People,
are these things going to be gone?
People are buying five of these.
This is a great investment. This is
a great investment thing. You know,
in case the economy goes south,
I'll have these $50 1995
made team,
95 gold coins that they sprayed with the
same shit that they spray the cast of
the Jersey shore with people who
just did fucking morons. Go ahead,
go buy five of them and hide them in
your snuggies. You're dumb fucks. Oh,
that's what I should
buy the guy downstairs.
I'm going to buy him a fucking
snuggie as a peace offering.
You know, get them that in a
package of fucking earplugs, Da.
What is that mean? Back in my day,
we just weren't deaf. Um, all right,
you guys want to watch? You're fucked
up youtube video. I got one for Ya.
That's actually not even on Youtube.
It's on a new website.
It's called a today's big thing.
T o d a y s big thing together.
I'll lower case look up. Uh,
this is what you search. Write
it down, get a posted. Okay.
Act like you're on the phone and
you're fucking doing something.
It's a enough for those of you
driving around, it's 22 minutes,
26 seconds into the podcast. If you
want to fast forward to write this down.
Look at me being fucking user
friendly. Uh, it's called, uh,
www dot today's big thing.com.
Um,
back slash 2009 back
slash 12 backslash 30,
um,
it's a fat guy jumping
into a frozen lake and,
uh, he goes right through the fucking
ice and there's a moment there where,
I don't know,
I didn't really find it to be a funny
video and I thought his friends were
unbelievably ignorant,
um, with their incredible,
uh, lack of urgency with the
situation, the situation.
I don't know how quick hypothermia
sets in, but uh, I don't know.
Judging by his,
the,
the fucking way to this guy and that
the stress that's already putting on his
heart.
The kid easily could have had a fucking
heart attack and they will try to pull
the mother fuck around.
And a, it's unreal.
He ends up walking out of
the lake like Godzilla.
He's just got to break the fucking
ice all the way back to the show.
Okay.
Oh fuck.
I'm sorry.
That fucking image just hit me.
Oh, all right. Anyways, anyways,
uh, this podcast sucks. I got to bring
the energy. I got to bring the energy.
All right. Uh, let's talk about
me right now I'm on the wagon.
I am seriously on the wagon.
I went to the rose bowl again
this year and this year,
rather than bringing a camera,
I bought my flip phone and
I was videotaping and I
was just embarrassed by my
behavior and it's not funny.
It's just embarrassing and no,
I won't be uploading it and
know it will never be extras.
And a, if you are part of
the tailgate next to me.
Remember when I said I was
going to email you the, uh,
some of the footage that I took,
I'm not sending it to you
because I'm in it and I am,
I'm just really embarrassingly drunk.
I sounded like animal and every foe you
remember animal from the muppet show.
That's what I sounded like the
entire fucking time. And uh,
it was the worst thing too,
was the next day when I watched the
footage not only being that drunk,
but when I was actually
looking at the unbelievable,
a spectacle that is the rose bowl.
And to realize that I've gone to a two
years in a row and can barely remember
more than 30 seconds of it.
I'm watching the jets game right now
and I just realized that he was playing
quarterback for USC last year in the Rose
Bowl. I actually sort of saw him play,
but I was too busy yelling at the fat
chick in front of me and listening to her
husband and telling me that he was
going to throw me down on the field.
So,
uh,
this year I actually passed out for eight
minutes of the second quarter just out
like a light, like an old person
in a fucking rock and chair,
two in the afternoon just to
out, you know, fucking, you know,
$600 a day after all is said and done
the fucking Cuban cigars and all the
bullshit in the parking.
I'm just fast asleep.
Granddaddy of them all
just a fucking mess.
Maybe the footage will be funny at some
point because I got to admit every other
thing is me cutting to my buddy who's
drunk or each time and every time he just,
he just looks at the camera and he,
he sort of slurs granddaddy of them all.
It was bad.
I was hammered and I was making,
we brought like these fucking Ribeye
steaks that she's fucking sweet things,
right?
So we forget a knife.
My buddy is buttering them up
with his index finger and uh,
I put enough charcoal on there
to cook a fucking Bronto Burger.
So the second the flames hit that butter,
oh my God.
It was unreal. It was like the outside
was well done in the inside was still cold
and everyone was just watching me going,
hey buddy, don't flip the steak too much.
It's like I can't, I can't not
flip it. It's fucking hot as hell.
And it was bad and, uh, it was
really bad. It was really bad.
And I'm fucking, you know, I'm just
really embarrassed with myself.
I scared and old man.
I was drunk off my ass.
Like I've been to the Rosewall twice and
I really don't even feel like I've been
to it. I mean, I was in there,
but I don't remember any of it.
And I don't know what happened.
I can't name one fucking player.
I know that Guy Blount who punch
that dude on a Boise state. Uh,
I don't know the name of
one person on Ohio state.
I don't know the name
of one person in Oregon.
All I know is Oregon hasn't won the rose
bowl since 1913. I didn't learn that.
And evidently cheap trick was
somewhere there playing and uh,
this is how much I was drinking
and how much I was enjoying it.
I W we got there at eight
30 in the morning for a one
30 kickoff and within two
seconds it was like,
it was almost one 30 was two o'clock
kickoff after all the bullshit.
And uh, I was actually
annoyed. I was like,
why couldn't it been like a four
o'clock game? I'm having a good time.
And once again we had a couple big
bottles of crown royal and we had a whole
case of beer between the two of us.
And for the life of me,
I don't know where it all
went. It was, it was just gone.
It was fucking gone. And at the end
of the night I bought, you know,
none of that you want to set to
about overrated expensive sunglasses.
Okay. I've gotten a couple as like gifts
and I always lose them on planes. Right?
So this time I finally go out
and buy a pair. All right.
And I don't take them on the road with me.
And this time I actually brought him,
you know,
made a little checklist this year for
the Rose Bowl and I fucking brought him
the end of the game. I got, um, you know,
tucked into my fucking tee shirt and
my buddy comes up, I want a game.
It gives me a big hug. And
I chair, they didn't break.
They just could fit on a,
I dunno,
pick somebody with a huge fucking head.
They could fit on that person's head now.
So it was bad.
So I actually came home and I dumped out
all the beer that I had in the fridge.
I had dumped out the rest
of my aunt, a little f, uh,
fucking little fucking flask things
ahead of that Jim beam. I dump that out.
I had a little bit more left quarter
of a bottle of gentleman jack.
I know people would
cringe and I dumped at,
and then I got this 15 year old scotch.
I kept that,
but I'm shutting it down, shutting
it down. I'm not going to fucking Aa,
but I'm shutting it down. And next
year I'm not drinking at the Rose Bowl.
I'm just not.
Okay.
I'm getting a fucking respectable
grill and I'm going to redeem myself.
Uh, yeah, it's just fun.
It's fucking pathetic.
My behavior was just completely,
and I just looked like such a douche bag.
I don't know. Gee, Bill,
what a week, Huh? You got,
did you do anything good this week?
And let's see, what did I do that,
you know what I, I ah, Jesus Christ,
can you fucking tackle somebody
is 27 nothing. The jets.
You know what the jets are the jet
to like Red Sox fans where they don't
understand. Again, not red sox
fans don't seem to understand that.
Singing sweet Caroline is one of the
gayest things ever. I got to admit,
you know something? I respect jets
fan because you're a hardcore fan.
If you follow that fucking team because
they kick you in the seeds every year,
right before they twist your
heart out of your chest.
So I totally fucking respect,
even though I can't stand you
because you're in a fucking division,
but I'm telling you to,
when they put that fireman,
when that guy lifts the other guy up on
his shoulders and he's dressed like he's
in the fucking village,
people with that stupid fireman hat,
and don't even fucking email me and
tell me who do actually a real fireman.
I don't give a fuck.
All right.
If you're wearing a fireman helmet and
you're not on your way to a fire or
sitting in a fucking firehouse,
you'll look like an asshole.
All right? And when he did
j e t s jets, jets, jets,
you know something.
That's the only thing of this year that
my downstairs neighbor would understand
because that is a fucking, that's like,
it's like a fucking cheer from the 1920s
gt use. Jude's do shirts and
they're all pumping their fists.
Like those guys in the Jersey shore
listening to house music, it's really,
really fucking bad. And, uh, speaking of
which, why do you guys need a new stadium?
What's wrong with that? That stadium
is fine. You know what it is?
There's this some sort of scam going on
with those new stage cause he amount of
fucking new stadiums that they built.
I kind of understood the new
Yankee stadium, you know,
it's not like they didn't have the
money to fucking fix it up again.
I guess they already did it, but the
metal lands is only like, what? 30,
35 years old.
Then they build another
one right next to it.
It looks like the exact same fucking
thing. Oh, let me guess what.
He can get Sushi at this one.
So now it's $200 more for a seat.
We got even bigger seats because
everybody's even fatter now. Um,
anyways, all right. Last week I
did a segment called oh Jesus,
where, uh, you know,
I stated my opinions on what I felt about
organized religion and all that type
of stuff and I got a
shitstorm of, uh, emails.
But believe it or not,
most of them were very a complimentary.
I'm saying that's exactly how
I agree. I how I feel. Um,
you know, see you in hell. My kids
want. Somebody said, dear bill,
southern mega church is a corporate
monster that needs to die to trick of the
church is that they've been perfecting
their scam since man started blaming
natural phenomenon on God's.
It's all based on fear.
And the constant charge decided at some
point point that they could make money
off of it. I don't blame the
sheep for believing the shepherd.
Blame the wolf for dressing like
a shepherd. Uh, you know what?
I agree with that. I think that's
a great point. But you know,
I have to admit past a certain age,
you're a moron if you believe stuff
like that. You know what I mean?
It's like if you're in your 20s you can
still blame your parents for shit that
they did to you. You know? And maybe
that's why you're a little dysfunctional,
but you kind of worked at shit out.
And that becomes a point in your life
where you got to stop blaming your fucking
parents. You've got to take charge of
your own life. And when you fuck up,
you got to take it on yourself.
All right,
Jesus Christ to fucking jets are
running a Goddamn wishbone offense.
Do you know what the genius of that is?
Like the reason why they never did it
in the prose is because the quarterback
gets fucking stuck,
you know,
and he can't have Joe
Montana getting stuck,
try to gain fucking six yards on the
ground. Right? But now the genius is,
is they, they, they, they stick like a
fucking wide receiver or running back.
And then why didn't anybody who came,
does anybody into football enough or
they know who came up with that shit?
I want, speaking of, uh, of which I'm
already going into football withdrawal.
I don't know if other NFL fans have this,
there's always that amazing excitement
when the NFL playoffs are coming up.
But then there's also like that depression
of like, fuck, it's almost over.
You know, I, I hate that like the
NFL seasons, just cause, you know,
one game of fucking weak, how quick
it goes. Um, and also secondly,
uh, I think I'm going to
try to get in into the, uh,
the English premiere league soccer.
I found out that I have a channel that
actually shows that shit and baseball's
coming up and I'm not, I, I, I'm
just not into fucking watching.
They've red sox angels and Yankees battle
it out yet it for the 90th year and a
fucking row.
Um,
so if anybody can over in England
can tell me when that leak starts,
when the playoffs are,
does it overlap in the baseball?
Because that would be fucking phenomenal.
Um, all right. So anyways, let's,
let's, let's get back to this,
uh, this stuff. So, yeah.
So that's how I look at it.
Okay. The same way, you know, at
some point you have to stop. Yeah.
You got to stop blaming your parents.
You, you've got to stop being like, dude,
chicks are psychos. You gotta
be like, no, I'm picking coach.
And he'd got to take responsibility.
I feel the same way about religion.
You know what I mean? If you're a
kid or whatever, and you're young,
right through your twenties,
you believe,
but at some point you gotta understand
it's a fucking guests and that it is an
unbelievably profitable fucking business.
You
know? I mean, especially, you know,
that shit that they say a rich man has
as much chance of getting into heaven as
a camel has walking through the eye
of a needle and you look at how these
fucking people in your religion 11,
uh,
then they don't seem too concerned about
getting through the eye or that fucking
needle, you know, wake the fuck up.
People go buy a $90 gold coin yet.
Jesus. All right. I'm not trying
to be judged. Whatever baby.
Maybe I don't understand it.
Um, all right, next one. Um,
it was actually,
you know what,
there was somebody who actually had a
real rational point here that I wanted to
read. Uh, all right.
And it's entitled for what it's worth,
you know, and first of all, right there,
that's what the Internet needs a little
more of, you know, for what it's worth,
rather than it being like, hey
shit head like I do. Okay. Um,
all right, bill, just want
to say I understand your
points on the religious thing.
Like you, I was raised Catholic
and left at this point.
I actually recently started
going back to Christian Church.
That doesn't have a denomination.
It's not baptists or anything.
It's just playing Christian.
Anyway.
I totally agree with you when it comes
down to the fact that people don't really
know and the whole idea is full of holes.
I think the biggest problem is that
Christians love to get into the debates,
only bringing the faith concept along,
which obviously makes no sense to people
that haven't bought into the whole idea,
which makes the whole argument
pointless. Exactly. Um,
and that's the problem with Christians,
just like other groups of people,
a lot of them are frankly stupid and
don't know what they're talking about.
It's not really their fault.
Just not everyone is meant to
teach others on every topic.
All right. You know, I, I don't know if
I agree with that. No, it is your fault.
If you're a fucking idiot, if you're born
stupid, you know, that's not your fault.
But,
uh,
if you just a fucking moron who repeats
shit that people say in bars like me.
All right. Why don't I shut
the fuck up and read the rest
of this? All right, Bill.
Uh,
I think something you could understand
is no one buys into the Christian thing
just because of the Bible. If they do,
they probably can be won over by anything.
People buy into the Christian thing
because of something they felt that is
beyond understanding.
After feeling it,
they start looking for an answer and
they are drawn into the Christian thing.
At that point you can just feel it
in your bones and you know it's real,
but it's a personal experience for
everyone and it can't be taught.
But I think what that guy meant
by asked Jesus and tell you,
it's not literally asked. I knew he didn't
mean that I was just being an asshole.
It's really a soul search, which isn't
something that usually happens overnight.
And eventually you will come to an
understanding within yourself. Uh,
reading the Bible going
to church can help.
But it all comes down to whether you are
even interested in finding out. I mean,
right there,
I want 100% agree with all of that.
Okay. And I like to sit think that
I made some sort of point where I,
I guess I believe in some sort of
higher thing because you can feel,
I know it's an exp likable,
but I also know that nobody alive
knows what the like. I feel that that,
that feeling that you're talking about,
I feel as a private thing and it shouldn't
be exploited and it shouldn't be this
moneymaking thing and you shouldn't
try to scare the shit out of me.
Then I'm going to hell and all this stuff
and start making up all these fucking
cartoon characters like they have.
You know what I mean?
That's what they're doing.
They're just making up shit and they're
making up stories and all this fucking
crap based off of this feeling and also
based off of people's fear of dying.
But I, I have to 100% agree
with all that. I mean, see,
that's the way you go about it.
Okay. For what it's worth. Okay.
The mere fact that he puts
in for what it's worth is
right there. It's like, okay,
I'm not ramming this shit down
your throat for what it's worth.
This is what I feel.
No point did he say he's 100% right.
This is just how we feel. Okay?
That's the way to go about it.
As opposed to this other person who,
this is what somebody wrote me, Bill,
there's an empty spot inside of you that
you try to fill with anything you can
fame hitting it, big fortune, family, dog,
etc. But actually there isn't
anything that can fill that void. EMP,
that empty void,
fill that void,
empty feeling inside you except for Jesus.
I mean,
that is the funniest fucking thing ever.
They're trying to convince
me that I'm not happy.
This is like the happiest period
of my life. I got a great girl.
I'm living with her. I love her. I love
living with her. I got a fucking dog.
I mean, how great my life is to
come home to them. It's great.
It's fucking great.
My career is right where it's at.
I've carved out a nice niche for myself.
People show up.
I got a cool level of notoriety,
but I could still walk down the street
with no pants on and no one would give a
shit short of why is this guy not wearing
pants and having a great fucking time.
And this person is super imposing their
own feeling of when they accepted Jesus
because they couldn't fill it up with
Shin that now they're going to tell me
that I'm empty and they don't
even fucking know me moron.
So anyways,
the only way to fill it up is to come
to our church and do except Jesus and
reach in your pocket. Take out that
legal tender, put it in the basket,
gave it to me. I'll go get a hooker
and we'll build again next Sunday.
Um, he actually made that spot inside
of you. Okay, let's, this is how,
this is how fucking you
guys into science fiction.
All you guys who can't afford
movie tickets because of
the recession and you're
really killing yourself because you can't
go see Avatar. I got one for you here.
Just sit back, close your eyes, take
a hit off, something you need to.
Here's the rest of this shit.
He actually made that spot inside of you,
uh, that only he fits into crepey. Um,
really so he wants to get inside of me
and that spot that only he fits into
Jesus Christ.
And all you have to do is ask,
you know,
I don't want to ask some dead fucking
hippie to crawl into a space inside me.
They don't, he only fits into, he's
knocking at the door of your heart.
Sort of go around making this up.
Is this lyrics to a bad Jim Nabors
song written by John Denver,
Sergeant Carter. Anyways, uh,
you only have to open the
door because he's a gentleman.
He won't force his way in. He will come
in if invited. He's waiting patiently.
But, but, but, and this is from me to you.
There's no time like the present.
Nobody knows how long anybody lives.
It says in the Bible also
tomorrow is promised to no one,
but don't get spooked.
Oh yeah.
Why would I want to get spoked
when you're telling me, you know,
tomorrow isn't promised to anybody in
this is dead fucking son of this dude who
was stuck into a vagina without any
seaman who wants to get inside me into a
space that only he fits into
a but don't we spoke to?
Doesn't mean as soon as you
do that it's curtains. No,
I'm not saying I you
this guys is the worst.
I can't even read the rest of that
shit is fucking ridiculous dude.
You know what you're doing right now.
It's like you went down to
the car dealership and they
sold you a lemon and now
you want to dump it onto me and you're
trying to remember the horrible sales
pitch that they gave to you.
Yeah,
come on in here. Or are you
tired? Are you weak? Are you,
are you broke? How many people out
there? I could fucking do that.
Jesus Christ.
Here I am trying to blow up telling jokes.
Why don't I just start
my own fucking church?
You know who out there who out there has
been tired this week and what you do is
you have any hand up the whole time.
Who thought there's been tired?
Let me hear you saying I'm tired.
Well, Jesus wants you to be tired.
He wants you to be tired of
living the life you're living.
Okay?
Staff you to wake up.
I get some energy.
Reach into your fucking pockets of,
I wouldn't want to curse in my church.
Is she a fucking pockets? Give me
some goddamn money you guys want to.
Who here wants to feel better?
But you guys go to a church.
If I just talk like this,
I didn't do that stupid sing song.
He stuff and stomp my foot wearing a
fucking sky blue three three piece fucking
suit. Now what'd you go to
my church if I did that?
Yeah, whoever wants to feel better. All
right. What do you want to do this year,
sir? You want to lose some weight?
Why? You're going to lose weight? Yeah,
you can do it.
Stop being a pussy.
He chicken breasts and fucking
Broccoli at seven o'clock go to bed.
Drinks of fucking water. All
right. That'll be five bucks
a five. I don't even want to
fucking go in with this already.
Getting self conscious and I'm going
to start screaming again. Don't worry.
The podcast will be fine.
I just got to let this,
I gotta let this shit died
down with fucking, uh,
I dunno that go plead Mr. Hand in fast
times at Ridgemont high. He's dead now,
isn't he? All right. Um,
all, let's plow ahead.
Do the, I like, he can't
believe all this shit I got,
I got another guy who actually,
um,
he was saying that he thought the podcast
was hilarious and all this stuff that
I sent in religion was really funny.
And then he tried to get me to read the
book of Mormons and I was real sneaky
and you know, I don't, his selling points
were also, I, I don't want to read it.
I don't want to, I, I've
been to Utah. I've seen what
your religion does to people.
Okay. I've been there, I've seen it.
Everybody sneaking around fucking
their girlfriend in the ass.
So she's still a Goddamn Virgin,
you know,
32 year old guys still walking around.
Never had a piece of ass in that fucking
life because some who's got 58 wives
told them not to. I mean, I
don't know what to tell you.
I'm not trying to shit on Utah.
All right, beautiful scenery. Okay?
But you only get one life.
Okay?
Go down to the drug store, get some
condoms and start talking shit. All right?
That's what the fuck is supposed to be
doing in your teens and in your 20s. Okay?
And then eventually one day you're going
to be fucking a girl that you don't
give a shit about.
You're gonna roll over and you're
going to feel this empty feeling.
You'd be like, what the fuck am I doing?
I can't do this anymore. Um, my God,
she really going to try to have
some false sense of intimacy. Now.
Isn't that the worst?
That's what I was headed about
one night stands was afterwards.
I always loved those professional girls
who just got the fuck out afterwards.
Not trying to, you know, suppress
any sort of a guilt, you know,
any sort of guilt as the worst one night
stand is when that fucking creepy hand
comes over and you know,
she puts her head onto your chest
and their fucking hair and
you're just sitting there.
I remember Billy crystal and now when
Harry met Sally and he's got that one foot
on his floor in his eyes are wide awake.
Yeah.
At some point you get sick of that
and he just like, all right, you know,
if I don't fucking settle down
and get a good one, you know,
I'm ended up like that fucking
grumpy old man downstairs. Uh,
all right. Somebody's trash
me on my ignorance on the
NFL network, you said, uh,
I'm surprised it's such a big force.
A sports fan is Jesus Christ.
Do you see the emails?
I guess, first of all,
let me say that I am surprised at such
a big sports fan as you is confused by
the NFL network and Nfl Sunday ticket.
The Sunday ticket is the exclusive
offering on direct TV that gives you every
game. Every week. I realized that I have
this so I can watch the eagles in DC.
And by the way, it's amazing.
It's like sports have an,
I can't imagine not having it.
I understand now the NFL is just a single
channel that is also on direct TV and
as a frequent too, I understand
all of this. Okay. I have cable.
It's not available for me out here.
Okay. In order for me to get it,
I have to sign up with direct TV and
they wanted me to sign like a three year
contract with a cable service that
I've never seen before or used for.
All I know they suck. Okay. I was giving
him shit. I understand they're busy.
I have no problem paying
for the NFL ticket.
I would buy it if it was on cable.
All right?
But I can't put addition to the side
of my fucking building. I can't,
my landlord does not
allow it. All right. So,
and I understand that they have
good matchups and they show a month,
Thursday as a way to entice
me into a and to fucking,
you know, buying the network. I get
it. It's fucking business. But Dude,
you know,
to black out a game on Christmas is a
corporate conti fucking mood and you
fucking with people's holidays, you
know, show me the God damn game.
Take one day off. You know? That's
all I was fucking saying. Okay.
I understand the whole concept
because explaining the NFL network to
me, I don't understand that. Oh, really?
Did you enjoy watching
your fucking eagles today?
Get pounded by the God damn
cowboy cowboys met. What?
A what a rough weekend Philly. Huh?
What a rough month. They lose cliff Lee.
They get trashed by the
Goddamn cowboys and uh,
they lose the winter classic to my Bruins.
And over time I got to met dude.
Nobody takes over a stadium like
Philly fans. Did Anybody Watch that?
It was the sound like it was a
fucking home game for the flyers.
Really disappointed with Bruins fans.
But you know what? Tickets was so much.
It was the fucking rich
people there anyways. They're
never going to do anything.
Um, but still, I gotta give it up
for the fucking Philly's fan. Uh,
Philadelphia fans. All right. That
might be the end of the podcast,
one of my 49 whispering
minutes into this thing.
Um, anyways, I dunno, this is my deal.
I think when it comes down
to that whole God thing,
I think that's a personal fucking
journey and I'm not working on it at all.
So what I'm really doing
is just blown off church,
but I'm never gonna go back to church
anyways, but I'll, I'll, I'll, I have to,
I have to start living by some
sort of a fucking code because, uh,
because I'm not,
you know,
and when you become an adult and you
don't have parents anymore, I mean,
as long as you're not breaking a law,
you can pretty much do a lot of scumbag
things and no one really calls you on it.
And, uh, you know,
pass it out in the second quarter
of a fucking Rosebowl. What a loser.
What a fucking loser. Um, anyways,
what else do I got here?
I just got sorta like fucking,
this is like holiday leftovers.
This podcast last week I was talking
about some girl who was too dumb to fuck.
I had somebody really latched onto that.
That time I,
my buddy was hanging out with that girl
who thought the sun and the moon were
the same thing.
And I was saying like,
you have to get with a
girl who is so stupid,
like you can't have sex with her
because it feels like a form of rape.
Ah,
fuck.
Anyways, this guy said, hey bill,
I love the podcast but never
felt compelled to write
you until you mentioned the
story about the chick who didn't know
the moon and the sun were two different
stories and too dumb to fuck you.
The first guy I ever heard mentioned
that I cannot agree with you more.
I have a too dumb to fuck story. Okay.
I think we have a new segment here.
Um,
here we go.
This is this guy's story about meeting a
girl who was too dumb to fuck. He said,
when I got out of college I was doing
the traditional stint in the restaurants
serving industry.
Uh,
there was this smoking hot 19 year old
waitress working there that every do I
sound like creepy right now cause I'm
kind of whispering, there was this slogan,
God fucking 90 year old waitress and
he's creeping up arrays of working,
uh,
there that every dude and at least one
other girl was trying to get a piece of
build. This girl was a
legitimate 10. Anyway,
we were at a party one night and
I was spending all my time with,
they're listening to a talk
about all sorts of nonsense,
trying to be the nice guy trying to get
some play right. You putting your time.
And so anyways, he said, well,
the booze was kicking in and uh,
things were starting to work out.
Uh,
we started kissing a bit and things
were looking promising, but, uh,
I knew it would be some time
before I get anywhere worthwhile.
I don't know why you would think that to
what you should have closed the fucking
deal. Um, he said I was
w that's classic dude.
You know what I would've done? I
would've fucked her right through. Um,
I was willing to put in the
time. All right, so anyways,
a little later in the night she started
talking about a rabbit she had when she
was younger and she was upset
that her rabbit never laid eggs.
Have you ever heard of
something so stupid?
If you ever heard something so stupid,
you can't believe you've heard it
correctly? I could not. Oh man,
that must have been fucking hilarious.
Cause I'm sure there was music playing.
I'm sure you did. Like,
like we're like what?
And then sort of like put your ear all
almost inside of her mouth to make sure
you fucking heard her. Right. He
goes, I cannot believe my ears.
So I questioned her only to have her
repeat the claim with even more vigor.
I had a rather, it didn't even lay
eggs. My childhood was so difficult.
Could you buy me another drink? Um, I
shit you not bill. She was dead serious.
If that was not bad enough.
She argued with me for 15 fucking minutes
telling me that rabbits laid eggs and
her proof to this was wait.
Now he says, wait for it.
If rabbits don't lay eggs,
then why does the Easter,
well then why does Easter have
Easter bunny and Easter eggs?
Wow.
This girl really took that Cadbury egg
fucking story to heart from that point
on.
This girls 10 status dropped by a half.
I cannot even think about fucking
this girl anymore. To this day.
She's probably still so good looking
that no dude ever told her that she was
wrong. So we could just get in her pants
and she's probably still tasting rabbit
pellets hoping for m and m's
like,
yeah. Do I that's, that's a uh,
that's a strong fucking move of your age,
your age.
I probably would have still
plowed through I on, I dunno.
I've always had that man.
I always had that thing that I
did not connect with somebody.
I do know something.
I tried to do what most guys
do that basically, you know,
fuck anything that moves and then they
come back and they tell the horrific
story and uh, I was never
able to do that. If I,
if there was like no connection, like
I've just never been able to, uh Oh,
that's bullshit.
I got a couple in there.
I got a couple in there. I think that's
right. Oh Jesus. Am I going to tell this?
I can't fucking tell this story.
Yeah.
Okay. Here we go. You know
what? This is just builds a
piece of shit. Wake. Okay. Uh,
yeah. I, I got, I didn't yell at the old
guy, you know, the guy I was. So I find,
you know,
what is,
I'm so upset with it or how that all
gay thing with an actually feel like I
yelled at him and I didn't even yell
at him. He's fucking yelling at me. Um,
all right. So I had the old guy incident.
I passed out during the second fucking
quarter of the granddaddy of them
all and a, okay, here's this story.
Uh,
early on in my life I rode career.
I was like, I dunno, I dunno how,
Oh, Jesus Christ, they have fat.
Fuck just soul.
Now.
I love that one football players
run into those fat guys who like,
their job is to hold like that
sound thing for the NFL films. Um,
you know, they feel that
for weeks to anyways. Um,
all right, here's the story. I think
it was about 30 years old and, uh,
I was doing this club and,
uh,
I was in this bar and the Jello
shot girl comes by, you know,
the Jello shot girl is always like
fucking smoking hot, you know,
she has to be,
she's selling Jello.
Do you want to do a Jello
shot? No, nobody does.
They just want to talk to you
with your fucking ass and titties.
So this girl looked like a
fucking Barbie doll. Right?
He had a fucking as Teddy's blonde hair,
just fucking gorgeous. Right? So, uh,
I don't know what to follow. I remember
what happened. Did the classic,
when I had fucking zero game with women,
I just invited her out to a show. Yeah.
I'm working uncle fuckees down the
street. Oh, like God, I like that judge.
So anyway, she shows up the next
day with a friend, you know,
looking even better and
uh, Yada, Yada Yada.
As long story short,
the end of the fucking night when she
showed up with like four other girls,
which is a of automatically a fucking
problem. But this girl was like,
she was raring to go. I mean, she sat
down on my lap within fucking 10 minutes,
so I'm trying to get out of there, but
her friends keep fucking cock blocking me.
It's a long story short. The night ends
were in a parking garage. All right.
I'm 30. She's like fucking
18, by the way. 19 maybe.
So I look like I'm fucking 106. So, uh,
all of her friends,
wait a minute,
she couldn't have been that young
because she was serving Jello shots.
Was She 21? Maybe I was like
32, 33. I can't remember.
It's all fucking run together.
Whatever.
I was too fucking old to be with this
girl. Let's put it that way. So, um,
they're fucking, uh, it's
the end of the night. Okay.
And we're in the parking garage and a
friends are telling her to get in the car
and she's like, Nah, I'm gonna, I'm
gonna pack and go home with this guy.
And they go, that's cool. Just come
over here and talk for a second.
And she walked over to the car and she
sticks her head in the window and for,
I swear to God,
10 minutes,
they're trying to talk her out of not
leaving with this creepy older guy.
And I'm standing there like an asshole.
And I was standing there for so long,
I started rooting for the girls
in the car. I'm like, yeah,
come on and talk her out of it.
She shouldn't be here with me.
And of course they fucking
didn't. And uh, you know,
and there you go.
That's the podcast for the weekend.
I did pour all my booze down the fucking
sink except for the last bottle of
Scotch. All right, go fuck yourself.
What am I a saint? Maybe I do need Jesus.
All right, you guys have a great week
and I, I'm saying that jokingly, right?
You fucking maniacs. We'll keep
emailing me. Trying to get me into, Gee,
I'm not into the guy. All right. Put a
fucking shirt on and stop complaining.
All right. Your father gave you the
fucking ability to walk on water.
Float off the fucking cross. I didn't
ask you to die for me. All right.
You're fucking martyr.
Um,
that's it. Everybody have a great
God damn week and, uh, that's it.
Happy New Year and hope you
guys all have something.
[inaudible] [inaudible]
[inaudible].