[inaudible] is another one for you here.
My wife and I are two months away
from the birth of our first child.
That's fucking awesome. Congratulations.
I want to hear your opinion on one
of the names we have been favoring.
First name Birdie. Fuck you.
You're not naming a kid birdie.
You're full of shit. Ah,
I don't, I don't buy this.
I don't buy this at all. First
name Birdie, middle name.
Oola U. L. L. I.
A short from my grandmother or
Sula last name starts with a g.
Her initials would be B U G bug.
Is this too weird of a name?
Oh, you fucking hipster
cunt. No, it isn't. Go ahead.
Name your fucking baby
birdie. You fucking dope.
I imagine the DMV calling her name or a
teacher calling her name and roll call.
What do you think? You
know what I think you know?
Name a kid birdie.
Yeah.
Why would you do? I don't understand.
People who got the [inaudible].
You never get the shit kicked out of you
for no fucking reason when you were in
school.
You're literally giving people a reason
every fucking day to fuck with your kid.
Why would you do that?
Give her a pretty name
Birdie. Yeah. You know, I,
you know why God gives someone like you
sperm that works. It's just, it's just,
I don't understand it. I mean, you know,
was I too harsh this week on people
is Birdie? Is that like a, you know
what? I gotta look that up right now.
I gotta look that fucking thing up
right now. You gotta be fucking Shit me.
There's no way is that going
to be like the new, like
Kathy Birdie, the name that's
sweeping the nation Birdie?
Uh, that's, that's a golfing
term. That's what you hit.
And badminton. Barry
girl. Girl Name. Okay. Let's
see the history of this
birdie meaning of the name.
Well, I remember there
was lady bird Johnson.
Birdie was until recently
a middle aged ladies club.
What
birdie was until recently,
a middle aged ladies club member
wearing a bird decorated hat.
But now it's just kind of a
vintage nickname. Think Haiti.
Does that supposed to be Lucy Josie.
Oh, Josie eyes are going, Mami. Milly.
That's coming back into
style in a big way.
Actress busy Phillips named her
baby birdie inspired by first lady,
Lady Bird Johnson as did soap star
Mora West in an earlier
hay day of nicknames,
the 1880s Birdie was a top 200 name
people who also like Birdie also like
Alabama, Alfie, Alfred, Aspen, blanche,
Sicily, clover Dixie, Franklin Hawk.
Who Fuck names a kid. Hawk.
Lynnora Oswald Oss one.
First of all, if if celebrities are naming
their baby that it's a good fucking,
that's a good one to avoid. Oh my God,
look at these fucking names.
Spero remi ransom,
the fuck names a kid rant. Vesper win,
win, wet wet, goddammit.
Zero to Lucy.
T. O U l o. U. S e t loose.
I looked at that and that was my fucking
dyslexia. I just saw a tool shed.
Patients who named patients.
Okay,
the fucking irony that I just
flipped out about that Dixie. Wait,
I want you to call her truckstop
whore. Frank. There's a normal one,
Franklin. That's all right,
Gertrude. Jesus Christ.
What's she banging someone in
the fucking Gestapo. Gretel.
Cosmo Guthrie. Lodhi maple.
Marilla. Dude, these are fucking,
these are fucking white people.
Douchebag, fucking names. Oh my God.
These fleas are way more dumber.
India,
heroin. Heroin.
That's like how black people say
heroin. Heroin. He's on that heroin.
You're gonna name a fucking
name. He get a drug,
a slang for a drug. Does these,
these fucking names are
horrible. Wait a minute.
Let me get to s popularity. Okay.
These are the popular names I got to keep
going with this podcast. This is fun.
Birdie is number four 69 on name.
Barry, what the fuck is named Barry?
All right. It reached its peak
is like Casey case. Um, the,
the name Birdie reached its peak
in 88 80 at to ranked at two 10
and then by the forties. Wait a minute.
It w it dropped all the way down to the
fucking thousand where it prolonged.
Enter a different name.
All right, let's enter it.
Tell me what's a worst
fucking name I can think of.
What's a fucking Douchey name? A hit
hipster would know would name their kid.
I'm going to go with just
to lift over and solid lamp.
Let's see if that's one. No, no.
Lampi is open if you want to be
fucking original. How about fridge?
F. R. I. D. G. E.
It's something of fucking stupid
white person when named their kid.
Uh,
we found 21 results.
There's no way anybody's name and
their kid fridge. I bet in melty.
How about Milt?
Milt popularity is 1000% this week
that I already saved seeing melt.
I'm not going to think of some of the,
some of the fucking old singers
back in the day it was Engelberg.
Humperdinck about a Ebeneezer.
I can't spell this. Is
there a noisy in there?
Just for the record? I'm
spelling. N. E. B. I. N. Ea.
Z. E. R.
No fucking results for that. Oh go
fuck yourself. All right, I got it.
I got you. I have one fucking name that
comes out here. Come on. Ebeneezer.
Ebenezer.
If I spell it and you
guys still listen to this
boy name, Ebeneezer boy name. Alright.
Meaning of Ebeneezer.
Ebeneezer is a name of a biblical place.
The stone set up by Samuel to mark his
victory over the Philistines rather than
a person who was adopted by the British
puritans as a first name and then
exported to America where it had some
early popularity entering the top 1000 in
the 1880s Jeez. I'll tell you,
1880s was a rough time to be born,
not only fucking the scurvy and
all that fucking horse shit.
You had fucking names like
Ebeneezer and Birdie. Yeah.
You can just feel their itchy clothes
with those fucking names, can't you?
I'm all right. I can babble with
this shit forever. All right.
That's the podcast for this
week. Everybody, as always,
if you would like to donate to the
podcast but not spend any fucking money,
next time you go to Amazon,
just swing by Bill bird.com first click
on the merge page and then click on the
Amazon link. It will take you over. The
Amazon won't cost you any extra money.
They'll kick me a little dull for sending
traffic their way and then I kicked
10% of whatever they give me. Two a the
saint Jude's hospital. There you go.
That's the podcast for this week. Go
fuck yourselves. Uh, have a great week.
Don't name your kid birdie.