Hey, what's going on is Bill Burton is
time for the Monday morning podcast for
Monday, July 23rd, uh,
2018. How's it going? How are you,
what do you say there? Um, before we
get going, I have something to promote.
Uh,
all freckles,
all ringside red face is going to be
at the next rough and rowdy event.
August 1st in Youngstown, Ohio. Legendary,
legendary in the fight
game, Youngstown, Ohio.
Um, it's Sunday, August 5th,
2018 at 7:00 PM eastern time.
You can preorder at r n r
for pay per view stream.
Um,
you go right to the website,
rough and rowdy brawl.com.
R O u g h,
the letter n r o w d
y Brawl B r a w l.com.
Check it out. I was at the
last one. And uh, you know,
it's one I want the most favorite
things I've ever done in show business.
It's just a, you know, it's
everything you want to see. You know,
it's a,
it's,
it's conflicting groups of people duking
it out with not a lot of skillful and
you just get to sit there and enjoy it.
Um,
I'm thinking there's gonna be
a lot of maniacs there. Uh,
as you know, Youngstown
is no joke. All right?
And I can't wait to be there and not
fight anybody like the coward that I am.
Having said that, let me be, uh,
let me live my best life.
Let me be a hero to myself.
My goals for the second half of
2018 is to be my own personal hero.
Okay.
These fucking social media people,
have you ever like,
there's nothing, I don't know. I
didn't know where to begin with this.
If I see one more fucking fat,
miserable loser
was wearing a tee shirt that has
some sort of self help, advice to me,
like they've reached the Mecca of peace
and happiness. It's just like, Ooh,
is that fucking tee shirt for you?
As is it for me?
You know,
I just saw this,
this fucking miserable look in person
sitting down in the airport, you know,
tens and tens and tens of fucking pounds
overweight eating shit food with a tee
shirt that says love yourself.
You know what I mean?
And all of this fucking crap.
Now will you pat people on the back
because they're fucking up their lives,
but they still feel good about,
you know what? I like who I am.
I'm not saying you shouldn't
like who you are, but I mean,
you gotta look at yourself in the mirror
at some point. It just be like, dude,
the fuck are we doing here?
You know,
not saying I'm perfect.
I'm not a perfect person,
right? But I'm not, you know,
sitting around here like
calling myself a hero,
you know,
based off of all my fucking
shortcomings,
Hollywood puts pressure.
[inaudible] is that Hollywood.
Hollywood gives people what they want.
All right?
You fucking cons.
So sick of everybody
blaming this innocent town
we hear in all he would happen
to be some of the, the most,
uh, dependable, loyal, honest human
beings you ever get to, mate. Yeah.
I couldn't even get through without
laughing. Whatever. Fuck you this car.
This time we'll give you
whatever the fuck you. Bye. Okay.
And you've been looking at fucking abs
and big tits since the second they had
moving pictures. So I didn't want to
fucking hear it. These fucking assholes,
you know.
Then I liked those other people,
the fucking fat guys with the, uh,
with the tough guy. Shit
on this shirt, you know?
Do I look like I give a shit? You
know, that's no, no you don't.
Yeah, I don't. I, I, I would believe that
you don't give a shit about anything.
All right.
With you fucking fungus riddled toenails
while wearing your little fucking flip
flops.
Oh my God.
Do you ever see people
that their toe nails,
they look like fucking petrified wood and
they're literally walking around just,
you know, I guess living their best
life but making you look at them.
I swear to God, man. I saw somebody
in airport recently that had a,
these flip flops that also had
like this toenail flap on it.
Joe Is really excited about,
I hear stomping feet. That
can only mean one thing.
Oh, hey buddy, how you doing?
Daddy's in here making a fool of
himself running in here. Come on.
How big are you getting?
Oh, come on. Come on buddy. Do
what your mom says. Trust me.
I've tried it the other way.
It doesn't work. All right.
The money morning podcast has
been previously interrupted. Oh,
somebody is tired. Fly By.
Oh, you want to say hi?
Let me give her a hug. Hang on, I'll
get any pause. All right. I'm back.
Crisis averted.
The fuck was I talking about
how great people are in
Hollywood? How we are, you know,
there's a couple of bad apples.
I'm not going to lie to you if there's
a few people out here, you know,
I might be one of those people who knows,
you know?
Um, anyways, what was I talking about?
Dog Gone It. Ah, Jesus Christ.
They're just interrupted Christ
and fucked up my whole flow.
Okay.
I Dunno what I was talking. Who
gives a shit, right? What do I pitch?
Stop and go back and fucking
try and listen to it. Um,
anyways.
Yeah.
I have no idea what I was talking about.
Let me plow ahead here. As I always do,
I swear to God, this fucking house,
if it's not one thing,
it's another.
Every time I get I get something fixed.
Something else breaks.
You know what I mean? This kid be
what? Owning a house is like. I just,
I had to bond out. There's gotta
be some sort of fucking lemon law.
I'm fucking,
it's fucking believable.
What are those people?
They have a lawyer on retainer that just
means a constantly getting in fucking
trouble. So they're just
constantly paying the fucking guy.
I should have a plumber on retainer.
I don't know what that means.
What the fuck does that mean? It just
sounds cool. I have a lawyer on retainer.
Okay.
Oh my God. Oh my God. Give me an
idea. What the Fuck my dad does
that has got I,
I still cannot get over the fact that
an adult said that to another adult.
Do you have any idea what
the fuck my dad does?
You know, it's like, it's you like
your there and the other guys there.
You guys are facing off with each other
and then the fucking other du grabs her
by the throat,
throws him down to the ground and
then he stands up and all he has is,
you're fucked. You're fucked.
And I evidently, he walks
away to go get his dad.
The kids in his twenties,
Dad,
what's the matter? Is that 35 year old
across the street picking on you again,
Sean.
Okay.
Um,
anyways,
I went down to a comic con all freckles
who's done nothing but make fun of comic
con, um, forever.
I went down there on Thursday because,
uh,
Vince and all the guys at better call
Saul were nice enough to ask me to
mediate. Is that the word? Basically
host the panel, the better call Saul,
uh, to promote their season
premiere August 6th on AMC, um,
season four premiere.
And uh,
and after that, the 10 year, um,
breaking bad reunion 10 years
since their first episode debuted,
I would think 2008. And, uh,
I went down there and there was all
these people dressed like superheroes.
Most people are not dressed up,
but there's enough people that
dressed up that it was cool.
And I went down there and I gotta tell
you I've really liked those fucking nerds
man.
They were really cool people.
I only teased him one time cause I was
saying something that was a spoiler and I
was like, hey spoiler alerts, everybody
saw it last season of better call Saul.
You saw what happened in the last episode
and this dude down front was like,
yeah, I didn't see it.
And I was like, all right,
well a stick a couple of light safers in
your ear because I have to fucking read
this show. Something like
that. And everybody left.
Everybody had a good time with it.
I wasn't sure if you know
the self sabotage NB wanted
to walk out and open with
I,
you doin you fucking nerds.
But I just didn't want to
bring them back to high school.
I figured I was in their Dojo. I'm going
to be polite. You know what I mean,
is fun as it is to do what that fucking
guy on Fox News did that one time when
he went on that show with Barbara Walters,
you know,
remember that half the fucking
crew of them walked off the stage.
I can't remember anybody's
fucking names anymore. Anyways,
I was down there and I had a great time
and I flew a with my instructor down
there and an our 44.
It's the first time I've flown.
I hadn't flown since the end of
May, you know, it was overseas, uh,
you know, doing gigs and celebrating
my birthday probably far too long,
admittedly. And then the last
week of June, I, you know,
at the beginning of July had to get
caught up with all the work that I lost.
I missed, I mean, sorry. And uh,
I flew and a, I did all right man,
you know,
little rusty at first and then all
fucking came back and I had my best f
landing.
Yeah.
I've ever had as far as uh,
you know,
not having to look at my instruments too
much and just feeling, just failing it,
being common. One with the
fucking machine man, uh,
was getting dark out and we came back to
Burbank and we will listen to the 80s,
which is just the information that's
updated every hour for the airport.
You have to listen to it and
some computer voice, you know,
we're in Scarborough tow driver, a girl,
your wire up information night gave, okay,
so then you get on with Burbank Tower,
like Burbank Tower, helicopter, Blah Blah,
blah, blah, blah, blah blah. [inaudible]
Elica at fucking Hollywood reservoir,
a requested full stop at
Atlantic with information Yankee.
So they know you got the
latest information. Then
they tell you what to do. A,
there was a bunch of traffic coming in.
So they told us to hold over old Maca,
which is his fucking hunk of shit.
Macy's off the one seventies that they're
finally redoing and he just fucking
orbit over there to all the big boys
go in and then they say, you know,
helicopter Blah Blah,
blah,
cleared for landing runway eight west
of Delta eight so that you just say all
that shit back. So I said all that
shit back. I come in, they got the uh,
the fucking whatever they would
call, you know, those, those fucking,
the power lines there.
She that chop your head off.
I flew over the tower like you're
supposed to, not over the wires.
And then I was coming in at the right
speed because it was a jet behind me. Um,
but I was a little too high,
so I just banked it really hard using
my gs to make the fucking helicopter
heavier. Don't ask me how physics.
Right. And then it fucking came down.
I was going to come down
to like 600 feet permitted,
which as long as I'm moving forward
is fine. But as I slowed down,
I got it down to 300 commercial fucking
landing right in the fucking glidepath
right in the numbers and
fucking banged a left on delta.
8:00 AM I instructor goes, that's the
best lesson that you've ever done.
The of becoming one with the helicopter.
And I turned around and
my wife's in the back end.
Her headphones weren't working and
she didn't hear it. And you know what?
I hate to say it. So it was
like, it never happened.
And it was literally sitting there like
a five year old talking to my mom going,
dia, did you hear that? Did
you? And she was like, wow,
you know,
there's a part of me that
actually thinks she did here,
you know,
but to keep me in fucking line to keep me,
keep chasing the fucking carrot.
She acted like she didn't hear it.
So anyways, um, moving along,
I want to thank everybody on uh,
uh,
the casts of breaking bad and better
call Saul for doing the heavy lifting and
telling the stories and all that. I
mean I was having like a, you know,
nightmares about hosting that and meet
turning into the real version of Chris
Farley, you know, that that character,
he would do a Paul Mccartney,
remember you and John Lennon you
guys wrote to the white album? Uh,
yes Chris. Yes, I do.
Yeah, that was awesome.
Like I was worried that I
was going to be doing that.
I'm not going to say there wasn't a
couple moments of that, but, uh, you know,
the whole time I was up there I was like,
why didn't they get Jimmy Kimmel to do
this? That was my first fucking thought.
Cause I remember he did. Um, he did the,
uh,
when they had the final episode and in
La they did this thing at the Hollywood
forever cemetery and they showed
the, uh, the final episode.
You could sit outside and fucking with
all these other breaking bad fans.
It was really a fucking awesome night.
And Kimmel hosted it
and he did a great job.
So I imagine the reason why he didn't
do it was because he had to host his own
show and uh, yeah, that
makes sense. Right.
He had the host is talk show tapes at
five and that was going to be from three
to five 30 down in San Diego.
Oh, there we go. Hey you go.
That's why all freckles got
called up from the mind, uh,
for a cup of coffee,
speaking a cut and called up from the
minors and a cup of coffee and all that.
I'm back into watching the Red Sox,
uh, Bradley's paying attention, man.
I'd started with me trying,
like using,
listening to baseball as a way to
not flip out and traffic and um,
you know,
and just settling in to just not,
I just stopped fighting the
city just like, yeah, man,
this is going to be a lot of traffic.
There's going to be a lot of people doing
things that I'm not going to like and
I just need to just,
I'm just gonna sit there and watch it
happen and just sort of inch along as I
listened to five innings of a baseball
game and go maybe three quarters of a
mile. That's what I'm going to do.
And that's what I've been doing.
And I just listened to the red sox games
and, um, the Red Sox, I'll tell you too,
they're on fire.
I was worried that the all star
break was going to slow them down.
Date one 10 out of 11. Um, I'm sorry,
they won 11 out of that 10 11.
They won 11 out of 12.
That's right,
because he went 10 and all than they lost
one and then they won a ripple for the
all star game. I know. I sound
like the fucking Raymond.
And then we just took two
or three from the Tigers.
So we went 13 out of the last 15. Uh,
and the Yankees just keep winning too.
Um,
but I gotta tell you,
I watched a little bit of the Astros
who have been watching those guys.
I still think they're the team to be.
Um,
they had Verlander, they
got a great picture of staff
and they, they got the bats,
they get the whole fucking thing and they
want it last year and nobody's really
talking about and everybody's all
excited for fucking Yankees, red sox and
uh, this is what I think.
All right. Yankees bullpens,
socks that's going to come
back and bite him in the ass.
And,
uh,
Chris sale is our guy and
you know, as much as I
love David Price, you know,
he had a really rough outing against the
Yankees in New York and a him cursing
out Dennis Eckersley.
I Dunno,
I don't know that that guy was like,
oh, that's a hall of fame a man.
You don't curse out a
fucking hall of Famer.
So I'm worried that that guy
is a little, uh, you know,
what, are you a little
shaky between the, uh, the,
is there little Odell Beckham there?
Right.
You know, I dunno. I hope
he is because if he isn't,
we got to beast.
He is a beast.
But I'm just worried that when he went
down in New York and all those people had
buy a fucking
kind of imploded rather than being like,
I'm going to ruin that fat
mantated singing fucking jackass,
Yankee Fan, they still do that roll
call thing. It's like Jesus Christ.
I always feel like a musical is
going to break out after that. Um,
yeah, they do have a lot of that
and then they do the Ymca thing.
I mean it's just,
you know,
and every time you think that's the
worst thing than sing sweet Caroline.
It's just,
I don't know what has happened
to both of those franchises.
It's so weird how so
much shit just got nicer.
But people are so much meaner in a way.
Yeah.
You know? Thank you. Go to New York
City, like fucking Yankee store.
I went to a game in 1983 there,
the whole family went down there and
it was like taking your fucking Louise
would day game
and as you got to New York,
there was literally cars just burned
out on the side of the fucking highway.
And I don't mean in the middle of nowhere
on some side road on the side of the
highway,
like burn to the fucking ground.
I remember that was one of the
things when Giuliani got an office,
so it was one of the first things he
did was he got those things off of the
highway.
It was such a bad fucking look for New
York or maybe it was a good look because
it was warning terror,
terrorists,
tourists about what they were about
to experience. But um, I don't know.
Everybody was getting Giuliani credit.
Who is the head,
the chief of police there that he fired
along the way so he'd get all the credit.
Oh, Bill, do you always have
to be a con? Yeah, I do.
Julie.
Uh,
the fees
chief of Foley's fired.
Let's see who this guys come on.
Come on.
Slow Internet A's bill as the
slowest Internet in Los Angeles.
Wow.
It's still fucking gone.
Um,
and now man, I like, I don't even know.
I don't even know like a sporting event.
They used to always be like an element of,
hey,
keep your head on a fucking
swivel in Jesus Christ.
You have no idea where you're going
to see that people acted like fucking
animals. There was fights in the
stands and all that type of shit.
I'm not saying obviously that
I wanted to go back to that,
but somewhere along the line like it just
became like, it's like, it's just weird.
It's like you go into a Chucky cheese,
um,
it's still loading by the way.
Still loading.
That's probably cause I typed in
Giuliani and something negative that,
that's my guess. I'm going to go with
the whole conspiracy theory here.
Um, yeah. Anyways, I don't know.
He go to sporting events now. It's like
every time there's a stoppage of play,
then something happens up
on the fucking flat screen.
Everybody just stares at it
with their mouth hanging open.
And I really think that
that's like this thing.
So people like don't fight
and behave themselves.
You know,
you know,
you get that camera on your flat screen
TV and all those fucking nerds at the
best buy sit there watching you jerking
off to the fucking Charlie's angels on
me TV, whatever you're
doing. Right. But you know,
in between those times when they're
waiting for you to fuck your wife or
whatever those fucking nerd perverts I
doing down there that for some reason is
not fucking forced.
You know what I mean?
You got all this fucking
me too shit happening.
And meanwhile these fucking nerds
are watching you in your living room.
It's, I'm not making this shit up.
Like they'd gotten busted doing it.
I don't know why they admitted to it.
They were like, are you doing that?
They're like, oh, you know,
we're not going to say we're not.
Um,
I dunno.
Anyways. Yeah, they just sit there
fucking, I mean, if you're gonna,
if you're gonna go after
the, the perfect. Okay.
Giuliani renews ties with police chief.
He ousted
in 1995 William Jay Brandon
left the New York City,
New York City police commissioner with
Mayor Rudolph Giuliani, the two men.
Yeah, that's the guy.
From what I've heard,
I granted this might've been
people that hated Giuliani,
which God knows a lot of people do.
MMM.
This might be bullshit, but I don't
know what it was. This coming from.
This is the New York Times. All right, so
they hate Giuliani. Alright. The two men,
Rudolph Giuliani and his
former Police Commissioner,
William j Bratton had not spoken
to each other in 10 years.
This is from 10 years ago. This was
written when they had crossed paths,
a social GAM. They exchanged a little
more than I see nods, but time,
tragedy and presidential campaign
has started to change all of that.
Uh,
all right.
I don't even what the fuck it is.
I think that was the guy
that really turned it around.
That started on the road where
it's now like, it's weird.
It's like,
uh,
my father in law seven came down and you
standing in Brooklyn because gee, wow,
this is like a, it's like
a theme park. You know,
it's like people ride bicycles
along the river and all the steps.
It's sort of like a, uh, it's
sort of like if you have money,
it's become this utopia.
There's something,
I don't know.
When does the pendulum swing back?
That's what I want to know. Jesus Christ.
Yeah.
Because I imagine
in the 70s when New York almost went
bankrupt, there was a bunch of old people.
When this place was,
was your dream or add,
what was that? Grandma. Okay.
Back when whites were only allowed to
play baseball back when hippo was walking
the earth.
Okay.
Well, I suppose yo change
weren't right, but uh,
you're a good wave.
Your door unlocked. Um,
that is the thing, man.
Anytime you say good old days,
there's always some fucked
up shit going on, right?
I don't, yeah. Built, yeah. That,
that really wasn't anything deep.
I didn't say it was.
Yeah.
All right.
So I've been doing lately a Speyside,
not boozing.
I'll tell you right now, all
fucking, uh, oh freckles here.
I haven't drank all this month. It's
been great, man. It's really been great.
I'm still fucking tired though, having
a kid, you still tired? But, um,
um, but like I remember one day waking
up when I was on the road anticipating a
hangover and not having
one and I was like, wow,
that's pretty awesome. You
know, I'm trying to eat well,
thinking of talking to a nutritionist,
you know what I'm saying?
I got to get the answers to the test
here rather than listen to fucking,
it'd be Tom, Dick and Harry. You know,
Dean del Ray knows what the
fuck he's talking about,
but I'm getting bored with the Diet.
I got to add on this shit and uh,
want to add some vegan
meals, you know, you know,
not because I want to go Vegan,
just because I know if you eat them
then you know, your stomach is flatter.
Just give my body a break from,
you know, the ballgame, you know,
skirt steaks and all of that shit. You
know. Um, I saw this thing the other day.
I said, he just, you don't even
know who the fuck the belief.
Like one of the things,
you know,
when you look at Vegetarians and you
look at Vegan people, uh, you know,
there's an astounding level of fleshy
fat people that don't eat meat,
you know what I mean?
And they'll eat French fries because
it's made from potatoes and they're a
vegetarian, but it's fried and they'll
say, you know, potatoes on Good Friday.
Anyways, I far as I know,
I'm actually even say that.
And I don't want to be all opera here and
get people to stop eating potatoes and
then the whole fucking potato farm farming
industry sues me here at the Monday
morning podcast.
Um,
yeah,
but there's just a lot,
you know, like fucking,
just all carbohydrates and shit and
they just stay away from me. Uh,
I think a lot of people love animals,
but they hate reading is what I've sort
of learned from looking at Vegetarians
and Vegan people, you know,
so they don't eat meat,
but then they don't really know
what the fuck it is they're doing.
But the people that do take
the time to do it, right?
Like nobody who lived in this house
for a hundred fucking years. Evidentaly
took the time to do something.
Right. Do it. Fuck it,
friend. To face it, didn't it?
Okay.
Fuck it in a permit. Fuck
it. Somebody licensed.
Fuck all of that.
What did they do?
They just fucking lived here. They
had a problem. They asked a friend.
And I think a lot of vegans
and vegetarians do that.
They fucking talk to
people rather than reading.
And that's what I do because it's easier.
It's easier than sitting down and
actually doing the fucking work. So,
you know, I see that, you
know, like can anybody,
it's Gundy your fucking head.
Can anybody tell you whether having an
egg is good for you? A bad. At this point,
eggs had been good, bad, good. And
now they're starting to be bad again.
While people who are saying they're
good or fucking, you know that Duke,
and it is like the rubber
match, the rubber game,
whatever the fuck it's called.
Right? Um, so I'm gonna, I'm gonna talk to
a nutritionist and I'm gonna, I'm gonna,
you know, try to read up on
it, but it's, it's really dry.
And if you actually look up shit
on becoming a vegetarian or,
or, or eating a little like
that, like a Vegan or something,
it's just Hatfields and McCoys McCoy.
It's between the fucking meat eaters to
carnivores and the vegetarian people.
And there's a lot of money at stake,
no pun intended. Sorry about that.
Um,
so I,
I think like the big farming cattle,
fucking people,
you know,
they're trying to have all this shit come
up first and then all the hit the tree
hugging like, hey man, like, you know,
trees are alive,
man.
Those fucking people are trying to
say that, you know, eating meat is,
is like,
like I saw this thing right where they
were saying that this guy was trying to
say that like animals get protein from
eating plants and when you eat an animal
it's an indirect protein because she
should've just gone directly to the plant
and it's like both then explain
tigers and they're fucking,
you know, Mister Universe
physiques as far as I know,
which is, I don't know shit. So I
should shut up right now in Google.
What a tigers eat.
What do tigers eat?
Okay.
Meet only one of,
they're always in a bad mood.
I can't even take a shit Siberian.
The species died.
Ordinary consists about 50% wild boar
meat. Doesn't that sound delicious?
If they cannot get their paws on some
wild boar, they've been known to eat elk,
deer in the legs. They're like, wait,
what did we fuck with me? For me?
I didn't do nothing.
And sometimes even bears,
oh my God, what size? Jesus Christ.
That's a big thing in Asia, Huh? Putting
like a bear in a tiger in a fucking cage.
And just filming it.
If large sources of meat
are not readily available,
Siberian tigers will eat rabbits,
fish and any rodents they can get to.
Yeah.
Let's see.
Okay,
well there's no meat in that do to,
and that's the first thing I saw.
Do Tigers eat plants?
What do tigers eat? Siberia and the
species side consists of still this,
uh,
tiger's diet,
eating tigers eat a variety of prey
ranging in size from termites to elephant
calves. All that would break my heart to
see a baby elephant get killed. However,
an integral component of the Diet,
Laura,
are large body pray weighing
45 pounds or larger,
such as Moose d.
What did we fucking me Moose and bear?
Where the fuck are those things?
I thought they would feel that most
were only over here. Deer species,
pigs, cows, horses, buffaloes and goats.
Yeah. Well they have a different
digestive system of evidently,
cause if you just fucking eat that,
that space,
they're basically on the
Atkins Diet, right? Yeah.
He's much fucking back in as you want
tigers looking at you like, yeah.
I realized that. I realized
that. Um, too. Anyways,
I'm going to try to fucking,
uh,
okay.
I Dunno,
I'm gonna talk to a nutritionist.
Somebody read all this shit that I'm
supposed to read and maybe try to get them
to tell me some bow pill.
And you really going to buy books on
nutrition like you're gonna fucking read
them today.
A lot of pictures.
Um, anyways, I should probably
read some advertising.
I don't feel like fucking doing that.
Hey,
I'm almost like halfway
through this season,
six of a 77 sunset strip.
Um, and evidently see, I, as I said,
season six, you gotta watch it.
It's on a 4:00 AM on BTBY.
Just take the fucking thing.
I want to get more people to watch it
because I'm worried because I found out
that they started broadcasting all the
episodes back in November and I missed
the first five seasons and we're getting
towards the end here of season six
because they didn't do a full season.
They got canceled like three
quarters of the way through. Um,
and I'd like to see the original ones
because I'd like to see what La look back
then. You know, hopefully
they do some exterior's,
although I know most of it was formed
on the backlot filmed on the backlog in
Warner brothers. Um, but,
uh,
I'm loving this season so I'm worried
that the other one's going to be a little
hokey cause I guess a lot of people
didn't like seasoned six. First of all,
they fired the whole fucking
cast as I butchered. Sorry.
Um,
but I also didn't realize that they made
Efram Zimbalist juniors character a lot
more surly and uh,
but I'm loving them.
So now I'm worried that I
saw the season six first.
And if I go back and look at the others,
I'm not going to like the show the same
with the other people cause I get you
just get used to how the guy behaves,
you know. But some of the lines, man,
some of the shit that people say on there,
here's some mix in like,
you know, women are, are, are uh, are
talking about how behave around them.
You know, like in some of the shit that
they say, it's like Jesus Christ. I mean,
I'm sure that guy's out there,
but what the fuck, you know,
sunset season six of
psalm 77 sunset strip.
They sounds like what some of these women
and describing is some of the shit I
heard them say guys saying to
women on that show pipe down,
shut up.
Not to mention after f from tries to bang
his fucking secretary tried to look up
or dress one ups.
I'm just sitting like this guy would get
me to and so fucking fast and have his
full head of hair spinning.
Right.
And then my favorite one ever favorite
one ever is that mentioned on another
podcast is when east sat down in um,
this episode with the actor that ended
up playing the professor or Gilligan's
island. Sorry, I'm talking
through yards right now.
The accident played the professor on
Gilligan's island and the guy was three
drinks in and,
and Av firms meeting him.
It's the middle of the day and
the guy orders his fourth drink
and a afro goes, you've got a pretty
active available for lunchtime.
You on the sauce.
That is the one thing also
that I love about that show.
It makes you feel better about
drinking and smoking cause uh,
that from Zimbalist almost made 90.
Okay.
And there's barely a scene.
He's not smoking a cigarette
and he's really smoking it too.
And that's just on the tape
that they use. So who knows? I'm
all right with that. Should I read
a little bit of advertising? Yeah.
Why don't I do that 77 sunset strip.
Um, oh Jesus. Here we go. There's
somebody new mint, mobile, mobile
[inaudible]. Uh, the big and big
wireless stands for a lot of things.
Big Contracts,
big bills and big fees like a t and
t's new $800 million administration fee
increase. Wow. They're just
making up phase now. I know.
I love when they do that because they
think that you don't have a choice.
What big wireless doesn't want
you to know at this. There's that.
There's a way out to cut your wireless
bill down to just 15 bucks a month.
Introducing meant mobile,
the game changing company that's taking
everything wrong with big wireless and
making it right.
Yeah.
Well,
let's hope they stay that way.
Let's hope they don't put the other
guys out of the business and then they
become the devil because that's
usually what happens. But right now,
mid mobile mobile dig
deep is are the good guys.
Mitt mobile makes it so easy to cut your
wireless bill down to just 15 bucks a
month. The what do you love?
One text. How can you do that?
Use Your own phone with
any mint mobile plan.
You can keep your old number along
with all your existing contacts.
Choose between two five or 10 GBS is
like gigabytes or four g LTE plans.
No more paying for unlimited
data that you'll never use.
Every plan comes with unlimited
talk and text. We'll answers
so you can safely and all your friends
and loved ones and if you're not 100%
satisfied,
satisfied mint mobile has you covered
with their seven day money back guarantee.
Outfox your old wireless bill and start
saving with mint mobile. Keep me moving.
Call to action to get your new wireless
plan for just 15 bucks a month plus free
shipping on your Mint Mobiles Sim card.
Go to mint
mobile.com/burr that's meant
mobile.com/berg cut your wireless bill
to 15 bucks a month and get free shipping
on your Mint Mobile Sim
card@mintmobiledotcommintmobile.com slash
bar
somebody, please try that out and
let me know how their services,
because that's a hell of a fucking price
and I can tell you I'm with Verizon and
these fucking cunts.
My below is ends up going up to like 300
bucks for no reason. And then I'm like,
why is it 300 bucks on ash weird at and
a ham like Dan, let's do the incident.
Which way stands for fucking
do that now it's only 180
they know
and then it fucking goes back up again.
I pay so much money for fucking cell
phone and fucking direct TV. You know,
somebody was telling me if you just
call up direct TV or something,
you just tell him you're going to fucking
get rid of it. They'll only, all right.
All right. All right. It's not 150 bucks,
it's 45 because I think they're just
losing it with the cord cutters.
Um, hotel tonight, oh
Jesus should be civil.
That fucking saxophone music from the
1950s every time a woman came onto screen.
Hotel tonight is the Goto App for
booking great deals. It create hotels.
Unlike other hotel booking sites.
Hotel tonight doesn't have long,
endless lists of a zillion hotel choices.
Instead,
hotel tonight shows you only the
best deals at the best hotels,
bedbug free.
They partner with top rated hotels
to help them fill their unsold rooms,
which is how you get such great deals.
And even though the name is hotel tonight,
it's not just for tonight. You can
book tonight, tomorrow or beyond.
It's the perfect. It's perfect for
planners as well as procrastinators.
You can book spontaneous weekends, three
day getaway stay cases, road trips,
business shifts. You can book a
hotel, Jesse can use the fucking pool.
Download the hotel app today to
get great deals at the hotel.
You actually want to stay in and with
the Promo Code Berbee you are are.
You can get $25 off your first eligible
booking hotel tonight. Tonight,
tonight, Promo Code Burn. Get some
cool advertising here now. Huh?
Cheap fucking
sell service hotel tonight.
You know you want to look your best
when you're enjoying both of those
advantages, right? Well, I got the
thing for you. Dollar Shave clubs.
It's plural. Dollar Shave Club
delivers everything you need to look,
feel and smell.
Your Best Dollar Shave Club has everything
you need to get ready in the bathroom.
Any particular product that you have
fallen in love with outside of the razor
and why? Oh, I guess that's for me,
I just love the idea of the one
wipe charity. I've never gotten any.
How about some free samples? You
Bastards Dollar Shave Club. Yes.
That dollar shave club delivers
everything you need to look,
feel and smell your best. You name
it, shampoo check conditioner. Got It.
Bodywash shut your mouth. Toothpaste,
hair jugs, Gel, even a white.
That'll leave your tush feeling tingly,
clean.
Evidently I'm a big fan of their amber
and lavender. Calming Body Cleanser.
I would love to try that
second. My wife goes, honey,
I'll just wipe it on top
of my head coming dear.
Never smelled anything like
it for just five bucks.
You can get their daily essential
status set. It comes with body cleanser,
one wipe Charlie. They're amazing,
but wipes. They're world famous
shave butter and their best razor.
The six blade executive.
Keep the blades coming for a few bucks
a month and add in shampoo, toothpaste,
or anything else you
need for the bathroom.
Check it all out@dollarshaveclub.com
slash bar that's dollar shave
club.com/bar. All right,
and lastly, but not leastly.
Yeah,
I'm not trying to cause any advertiser
real enemies here it stamps.com everybody
look a the u s postal service is
an important tool for any business.
stamps.com is the easiest way to access
all the amazing services of the post
office. stamps.com never
closes, right? Like Dad,
who was the legs up to street,
did print postage for letters
or packages at your convenience?
24 seven print postage for any class
a meal right from your own computer,
the exact amount of postage every time,
never under PAYE or overpay again.
stamps.com saves you time and money
which you can use to grow your business.
Buy and print official US postage
for any letter, any package,
any class with mail using your own
computer and they'll send you a digital
scale.
Automatically calculates exact postage,
stamps.com believe and help you decide
the best class of mail based on your
needs. No need to lease an expensive
postage meter and there are no long term
commitments. I use stamps.com
to send out all my posters.
Speaking of which my limited edition
that you can only get at my shows,
which I did not have in Minneapolis and
Detroit unfortunately because the ones
that got where the leftover ones from
Dublin and by the time they got here they
were all fucked up.
But I'm going to have them in Houston
and Dallas and I use stamps.com to send
them out.
I'm a moron if I can figure out how to
use their scale and get some postage.
So can you,
and right now you too can
enjoy the stamps.com service
with a special offer that
includes a four week trial plus
postage and a digital scale.
We've got the hiccups. Go
to stamps.com. Click on the
microphone@thetopofthewholepageandtypeinburgerthatstamps.com
enter
bur
are,
hey, by the way, you know what, I got a,
I got an email from a Darren king,
credible drummer.
Uh,
yeah,
one of the best drummers I've
ever seen to be honest with you.
And I had no idea that he
could sing and play guitar,
but he did a cover of Richie, uh, um,
I got him saber. Is it Richie havens?
Let me make sure I have
this right. Uh, fuck yeah,
let me yes,
I was correct.
Richie havens does a song
called freedom and um,
he did a cover version of that that
then goes into something else that is
fucking incredible.
Uh,
I tweeted out the video and we'll have
a link to it on the MM podcast. Um,
Jesus Christ.
Do you know,
I like watching how talented that guy is.
I don't even know what the fuck I'm even
doing in this businessman. Incredible,
incredible monster talent. Uh,
check it out. And I already,
as a solo album coming up,
people were alluding to it.
I hope he does. If he does,
we are going to promote it here and
I hope you guys buy it because, uh,
he is the real deal. Um, all
right, let's check out some,
uh, am I going to read
some stories? I know.
You know what I'm actually going to do.
I actually came across this foot.
Could think it says news is bad for you.
Okay.
This is from something the guardian.com
says news is bad for you and giving up
reading it will make you happier. All
right, now I'll tell you right now,
I didn't need this fucking
article to tell me this.
I just realized that I figured it out
after I went down a rabbit hole of fucking
,
uh,
you know, conspiracy theory,
you guys remember that?
People listen to the podcast 10 years
ago. I mean, I was fucking, I was, yeah,
I was missed, you know,
chem trail guy, you know,
I was that guy saying you got to shut
down the Federal Reserve and I had no
solution to do like what would what
you would do after that, you know,
I'm sure people that are well read
on it had the solution, but I didn't.
So I was just walking around freaking
people out. I was a cunt basically.
Um, so anyways, it says
news is bad for your health.
So I just stopped watching the shit.
All right.
I'm just banking on the,
that there's going to be some smart
people with a good heart that,
that, uh, that are gonna lead us out of
this fucking mess because I don't have any
solutions. All right. I go on stage,
I jump around like a monkey and I
make you laugh. Okay. That's my lane.
And it's a rock used to say no.
Your role in shut your mouth.
So I'm staying over there. I
tried to watch the news. I try,
I can't,
you know,
it's the weirdest thing going from Obama
to Trump going from Obama where all
they did was lick his balls for eight
years and then they go to Trump and it's
just like, all they do is shit on
the guy in the entire fucking time.
And they're both kind of doing,
you know what? The foreign policy,
the same fucking shit, although I
don't, Trump is like a fucking lunatic.
You know what I mean?
I, you know, I heard,
I was on the Howard stern show and he
went on this fucking rant about Russia.
It was just not talking about the fucking
people just talking about, you know, uh,
of laddy daddy over there.
He goes,
I'm sick of people fucking talking
about Russia. You know, like, like they,
they're not that bad. He's like, did they
fucking, you know, they kill gay people.
They kill reporters just for having
a difference of opinion in the,
and he's right. He's fucking right. Um,
I dunno, I once that his, his,
his fucking wife wore that coat when he
was going to go visit those kids, that,
that she was going to go visit those
kids that they had stuck in cages and she
wore a jacket that said, I don't
really care to you and then try it. Oh.
Then had to do with fake news.
It's just like,
it's literally like listening to a
toddler that ally and I, God bless you,
if you can still watch that and try
and stay politically active because,
I don't know, it's just too fucking
depressing. I can't fucking deal with it.
So I choose not to watch.
And the last presidency, you
know, I just, I just, it was, I,
I couldn't fucking,
you know,
I had hope and then I was just like, oh,
this is going to be more of the saying,
oh, bankers don't go to
jail. Oh yeah. If, yeah.
Insurance companies could do whatever
they, whatever they fucking want. And uh,
yeah.
We're not going to
constructively criticize our
foreign policy and we're just
going to stay the fucking course and
shut down the government every fucking
August for a week. And our solution
is always going to be the say, well,
what if we raise the
debt? Right? You know?
And then meanwhile,
everything that his wife did was just
considered like angelic. And it's just,
it was the whole fucking
thing was annoying.
That was like when he was in office
was like watching a fucking award show.
Everybody's just walking around,
blowing each other,
talking about how fucking
brilliant they are. And then this,
we went from an awards show
to a fucking train wreck.
I honestly don't know how people
have the stomach to pay attention.
Like you're, you're a whole other level
tough mentally than I am. So anyways,
here's, here's this whole
fucking article here says,
news is bad for you and giving up
reading it will make you happier.
All in the past few decades,
the fortune fortunate among us have
recognized the hazards of living with an
over abundance of food,
parentheses, obesity, and diabetes.
And having started to change and
have started to change your dies,
but most of us do not yet understand
that news is to the mind what sugar is to
the body.
News is easy to digest.
The media feeds a small bites of
trivial matter tidbits that don't really
concern our lives and
don't require thinking.
That's why we experience
almost no saturation.
Unlike reading a book or a long magazine,
articles which require thinking,
we can swallow limitless
quantities of news flashes,
which are bright colored
candies for the mind. Today,
we have reached the same point in relation
to the information that we faced 20
years ago in regard to food.
We're beginning to recognize
how toxic news can be.
I agree with all of this, but everybody
can't stop paying attention or else,
you know, somebody has to pay attention,
right? Somebody's gotta be like, you need,
you can't put it on cruise control.
So I don't know if I hundred
percent agree with this,
I just know I'm not going to be the
Gandy that leads us out of this.
You don't?
So as long as I know that.
Yeah,
I mean I will,
abuse can be content.
The listen to Howard in the morning and
then I listened to fucking baseball at
night.
That's what the fuck I do.
I don't pretend to know things. All
right. News misleads all my God. What?
Take the falling event. A car drives
over a bridge and the bridge collapses.
What does,
what does a news media focus on the car,
the person in the car where he came from,
where you plan to go,
how he was he transitioning?
How did, he didn't say that.
How we experienced the crash
parentheses if he survived.
But that is all irrelevant.
What's relevant?
The structural stability of the bridge.
That's the underlying risks that has
been Larkey and could lurk and other
bridges.
All they get to that after
they go painstakingly
through the horror of the end
of that man's life or life
altering injuries and then
they get to his family and
they're all crying and all
of that shit. Um, you know,
as much as a moron, as as I am, I
always turn that shit off. You know,
like out here, we had a hostage
situation. At a trader Joe's and um,
the people I was with were just watching
it and watching, watching. It's like,
like just out of curiosity,
what are you going to do with this guy
just runs out in such shooting people in
the fucking head. Like,
you want to watch this?
These people in the store
are fucking terrified.
This is the worst fucking
moment of their life. All right?
The news eventually is going to tell you
what happened and they're going to give
you an edited version so you don't have
to see people's brains getting blown out,
you know, and why, you know, they live,
he had like the were crying and all
that shit. And then I found on the end,
you know, some poor woman died was,
it was fucking terrible. The one,
I'm just going to sit at home
watching it for hours, ordering food,
you know, going online. Are they
tweeting from there or what's going on?
Then all these fucking
assholes on Youtube,
not youtube on Twitter or these social
media if are going to go on and say the
obvious, oh my God, this is so bad.
I'm like freaking out right now. I love
that. Oh, is that what you're doing?
Are you freaking out of the safety,
your own home?
Why don't you make this about yourself?
Your Fuck God. Jesus. Social Media,
I bet is people's, a lot of shit
that says that's depressing too.
But you know what?
Podcasts actually feed the soul.
I believe I'm part of the problem.
News misleads bill Burmis leads.
Uh, anyways, plowing ahead.
We are not rational enough to be exposed
to the press and see this guy same.
We're all dumb.
Watching an airplane crash on television
is going to change your attitude toward
that risk regardless of
its real probability.
If you think you can compensate with
the strength of your own inner con
contemplation,
you are wrong.
I think the subtext of this is you dumb
fuck bankers in economists who have
powerful incentives to compensate for
news born hazards have shown that they can
not the only solution cut yourself off
from the news consumption entirely.
News is irrelevant of the approximately
10,000 news stories you have read in the
last 12 months.
Name one that because you consumed it
allowed you to make a better decision
about the serious matter affecting your
life, your career and your business. Well,
I would say anything
about the environment.
You know Jesus gas guys
chip off the old block here.
Paint with a broad brush.
The point is the consumption
of news is irrelevant to you,
but people find it very difficult
to recognize what's relevant.
It's much easier to recognize what's new.
All right.
I think we get the point here.
News has no explanatory power news items
or bubbles popping on the surface of a
deeper world who that's deep.
That's something got fucking progressive
rock band like a line in the song.
Um, in 74 I imagine will accumulate
facts that help you understand the world.
Sadly no, the relationship is inverted.
The important stories are non stories.
I would agree with that slow,
powerful movement that develop a load
journalists radar but have a transforming
effect.
The more news factoids you digest,
the less of the big picture
you will understand.
Maybe this way everybody's showing
each other news is toxic to your body.
This is, I'll just read the headlines
here. News increases cognitive errors.
News inhibits thinking.
News works like a drug.
News waste time and news makes us
passive. Well, that worked with me.
News kills creativity. Uh, well
there you go. Jesus Christ.
That's pretty negative, Huh?
Let's get to some positive shit.
I gotta I gotta fucking note from
a possible visit to dove, Ron,
Vic Bravo Rove. Nick though,
Bro, Croatia, my friend.
Uh, while you're checking where the
hell I'm contacting you from, uh,
let me jump you with invitation.
Invitation to my country. Slash. City.
I run brewery and we are in debt at the
moment. So don't expect this is money.
Interesting invitation.
This is opportunity for you to check
out crazy side of Buckland's and getting
hours and hours of future material.
By the way, you're funny. Well,
thank you sir.
Uh,
that read like a fucking ransom note from
eastern Europe and I would be lying to
you if I wasn't a little
afraid to go to your bar.
I need a couple of those in there. You
know, while you're checking where, oh,
he got the hell.
I'm contacting you from letting me jump
in with an invitation that be jumping
with invitation. Uh, you, you
fucking talk like Ivan Drago.
Um,
listen buddy,
I'm going to try to get as close to
done Bruv nick as I possibly can.
I wish you bar was making more money.
Uh,
and I'd love to go in there and help
you out with your fucking monthly rent.
Buy Booze and my face off.
But I don't,
I can tell you I don't think I'm gonna
make it there. Uh, eastern European tour.
Jesus Christ.
If this is all I'm getting,
this is all east eastern Europe
where Eastern European tour,
dear Billy Bald Burger. Oh, come on now.
That was feeling I was
feeling good about myself. Uh,
I'm a huge fan of your comedy and F is
for family is my favorite thing on next
flicks. Well, thank you
very much. Therefore,
I am very excited that you were
thinking of visiting Prague,
Czech Republic comedy scene in Prague
is pretty much nonexistent. Oh,
Gigi. So I'm sure you would kill
with your knock, knock jokes. Um,
if you are interested, pint of beer cost
between one to $2 and it's delicious.
You also have to try
traditional alcohol drink
slip Bovis it's made from distilled
plums and has about 51% of alcohol.
Okay,
I'm in.
You can visit the Czech hockey hall of
fame or you could go to cr mayor or play
some second division hockey.
Oh, that would be cool as shit.
I'm probably only gonna
be there for a night.
I think this is going to be a a bunch
of one nighters here. A while back,
you mentioned you saw the movie
anthropoid about a checklist of Akian
paratroopers assassinating high ranking
German Nazi official. I loved that movie.
The movie ends with the
final shootout in the church.
You can actually go to the crips of the
church and see the bullet holes from the
injury incident.
I'm fucking doing that.
I hope you decide to come and share
your Moroccan wisdom with us savages.
Thanks. And Go make love to your
lovely wife. Oh, thank you. Bless you.
Go Fuck your wife. You fucking ready
it. Prick Eastern European. Tori.
Hey Bill.
I've just wanted to say that I know a
lot of people waiting for you to come to
Poland.
Oh Great.
I guess your agents already figured out
that Warsaw's seems the most logical
place to do your show as it's
the biggest city in the capitol.
It's located somewhat in
the middle of the country,
so most of the people from outside boards,
so like me,
will be able to come and see you live.
I'm 100% sure you'll sell
out all of the tickets.
Plus Warsaw is a great place to visit
because of its history and of course all
the cool stuff going on there.
I guess people from the states think
you'll see white bears and trams and horse
drawn carts in the street, but that's
not the case. I didn't think that.
I just thought I'd see four people
trying to screw in a light bulb. Sorry.
Just like everywhere else. We've got
hipsters in Starbucks, moderately fat,
lazy fucks in shopping malls and generally
people wasting their lives on social
media. Yeah, yeah. That's, that's
a reoccurring thing. Anyway,
my friends and I can't wait for your
show. Thanks and go fuck yourself. Yeah.
Everybody's staring at their phones is
a big thing and I do that all the time.
Uh, persistent colds. You
may have walking pneumonia,
go see a doctor when you get
back to la. I need a doctor. Some
soft tires and Nazi symbolism. I
love this guy. This guy's just,
he's just doing the whole gamut,
isn't he? Um, running the gamut. Hey,
let's look that up.
Let's see what the fuck that means.
How does that expression come about?
All right.
Run the gamut.
Origin meaning the entire range.
The word Gamet traces its origins to the
Middle Ages in a system for designating
musical notes around the turn
of the second millennium.
But fuck you mean the second millennium?
I thought this was the second
millennium. 2000, right?
Isn't a millennium a thousand years.
I'm an evil monk. Developed a system.
Jesus fill I, you know,
just gets to the point like,
I try to be informed.
Thank you.
The second you going to bring up a
fucking monk around the turn of the second
millennium, Guido of our, our Xo.
A medieval monk.
Yeah.
Developed a system of Psalm Ization.
I designating musical
notes by syllable names.
While today we are familiar with
the Sung syllables do re Mi fa.
So La ti back in Guido's time,
he died in 10 50.
They had a hex tonic scales six note
and he used the symbol earth re me fa,
Sol and La
and the represented the lowest note.
Oh,
it's be far. So at La and uh, I can't,
I can't, that's why I
drums and tell jokes. Uh,
ut what represents the lowest tone
recognized in music theory at that time.
The second g below middle c. What the
fuck? I don't give a fuck about Wayne.
So what is the gamut?
The range of notes. Okay.
Building on this denotation
detonation, I dunno.
Gamut eventually came to mean
the whole musical scale. Oh,
so you're running the whole fucking
scale. Okay. Jesus Christ. Alright.
Hey Belton soft tires and Nazi
symbolism by the way. Hey Bill,
I think I can answer both of your
questions from Thursdays podcast.
I'm in law school and a motor
sport fanatic. So the questions,
these questions are right
in my wheelhouse. All right.
[inaudible] you were in law school.
What, so you know about Nazi symbolism?
Do you prosecute hate crimes?
I hope a number one.
Why the soft tires in Moto
GP? Uh, principally you,
you're right. I know the tires to
grade towards the end of the race.
So it makes sense to use harder
ones to get consistent performance.
Especially now that's slightly sliding.
The bike is the quickest
way around the track.
How the fuck you learn how
to do that is crazy. I mean,
I've seen people do that in cars,
you know, drifting. But you know,
you're on four wheels.
Like the level of balancing scale though,
be ability become one with the Macheda
judge on their all with a work of art and
Germany. Lorenzo used a soft front
tire while Marcus took the hard one.
Uh, for the rears. Lorenzo was on a
medium tire in Marquez on the soft.
Marcus is a special driver and tends to
get a better feeling for the bike with
the hard tire. Um, the sidewalls,
some simply don't wobble around too much.
Lorenzo's bet was to use the
superior pace of the soft tire,
more grip to build enough of an
advantage to win. This is fascinating.
Mark has meanwhile expected a tight
field and wanted to nurses tires while
keeping with the pack.
Thus having enough tire left for the
last lab and a final attack for a wind,
which is exactly what he did.
Simply put the drivers have to decide
between an early pace advantage and
therefore superior track position was soft
tires and the consistency of the hards
add, add changing conditions, different
writing styles and bikes to that.
And you'll see how hard it is to
pick up a winning package. Well,
my thing is,
is there a way for him to know what
Mark Marcus is going to be running
considering he's the best writer
out there as far as I can tell,
no disrespect to Jorge Lorenzo. I know
he's one of the couple of times, but um,
the championship, I believe
he's won two of them. Um,
no matter what tire you're going to have,
you're not going to open up this
like
insurmountable lead.
So I just think eventually that soft
tire is going to fucking wear out.
And then mark has his behind.
He's going to overtake you and then he
then can ride hard for the first time in
the race.
It beat the shit out of those tires.
But by the time they get fucked up in
the race is going to be over before that
happens. I don't know. But
thanks for that. That is,
that is fastened.
Cause everybody says you watch Reishi,
she's blind people driving around,
driving around track,
driving around in circle stock, car
racing. You're like, do you need to know?
Go turn left. Um, yeah,
that's all he needs to know.
Band Nazi symbolism. Um, I'm
enrolled in one of the best school.
I love how people are too
dumb to understand racing
and then they sit there and
they shit on it.
Uh,
I'm enrolled in one of the
best law schools in Germany
over here displaying Nazi
symbolism is punishable with up to five
years in prison in the context of the
whole legal system. It's quite an
unusual article of the law usually.
This is amazing. So you, cause
you're a lawyer in Germany,
usually the political background of an
opinion is irrelevant to the criminal
repercussions to avoid discrimination.
Usually objective factors are
used instead of political ones.
It was discussed whether it banning and
punishing Nazi sympathetics displays is
constitutional. It is an infringement
on the freedom of speech. Yes, it is.
Um, and also let you know
who the Nazis, ah, uh,
the one argument that
won in court was this,
this was the historic significance in
Germany. Uh, the constitution with,
by the way, I'm loving all these,
these letters from around the world.
This is fucking incredible. If I
could just get some women to write it.
I know I'm off putting ladies.
But you know,
that kind of gives you an
opportunity to put me in my place,
which is one of my favorite things.
You hear when my wife's on here,
she shits all over me. I love
it. Giggling like a schoolgirl.
The constitution was put into place in
1949 while most cities still look like
downtown Baghdad,
circa 2004 a and when the ovens
of Auswitch had just cooled down,
Jesus,
uh,
the content of the con constitution is
an answer to all this shit that went down
between 1933 and 1945.
Yeah.
Because most of those lunatics
died or were put to death.
And then some more rational
people were like, hey, yeah,
let's try to prevent that happen.
And again, I look at the city. Yeah.
This is amazing.
You can see all the way to the other
city because there's no cities left. Um,
anyways. Um, so the constitution
is the answer to, that's really,
I know you don't see a lot about Germany
other than 1933 to 1945 or the show
shit about, you know, World War One,
but they don't show about the steps
that they took afterwards to ensure that
this wasn't going to happen again.
Uh,
I'm sure there's a nice book on it that
I could sit down and read if I wasn't
such a moron.
And he was denying support of that
regime is part of the constitution is
inherent character. I agree with that.
The problem, it doesn't change anything.
It's symbolism. We can now point at
our laws and tell other countries,
see we learned and what
do the neonazis do?
They use fucking code,
which is not forbidden,
such as 88,
I guess that means Heil Hitler or
Hkn K R Z shirts,
which in German is recognize is saying
Hakan Kreutz which equals swastika.
I swear to God,
those fuckers parody the run DMC
logo with HKN space R Z shirts.
I had no idea.
Wow,
thanks for the podcast.
They keep me laughing during exams.
Looking forward to your German European
tour, you freckle con, you know,
that's gotta be the most fascinating
Shit I've heard about Germany since,
you know, the same shit that
they show a zillion times on,
um, on the history channel. Me obviously
you got to show that. So, you know,
hopefully that never happens again.
Um,
but they should probably shine a light
on this to know that that is going down.
I Dunno. It's hard, man. I, I
believe looked like the Nazis.
They kind of like a fucking
think I used to do a bit on this.
They're kind of like a band that had a
bunch of hits like fucking 40 years ago
and now they're coming back and it's just,
you know, there's no original members.
They don't have the magic. Any wishes it's
over. It's over. It's, it's uh, you know,
it's like, uh, you know, some,
some bands it's just their name
becomes toxic after awhile,
you know.
Although sometimes they're so bad that
they come back and people love him again.
I don't know,
it's probably a bad analogy,
but that's pretty frightening
that that shit's going down,
that people still like,
you know,
I dunno, I've never really been
to a Holocaust museum. It's just,
I just don't think I could handle it.
You know,
knowing that people are capable
of that level of fucking evil.
Just literally separating,
you know,
it's Shit and slavery the Shit at the
board to separate parents from their
children to sit there and fucking do that.
I don't,
I don't give anybody a pass.
Even the fucking kid down
there like, this is my job.
Quit your fucking job.
I'm not fucking doing this.
Like, when do you, when
is that Kid's screaming,
crying voice gonna leave your fucking
head for the rest of your life. Oh my God.
Especially now having a kid and
no one like how much they need.
Like my daughter just came in,
she was like whining and all that.
For whatever reasons she wanted to
hug me, you know? I don't know why,
but they need just to take that away
from a kid at just, it's fucking,
you know, over some, I don't
know that this guy, you know,
there's gotta be another
way. Right. Anyways, uh,
you sent my to the hospital.
The fuck are you talking about?
Can I legally read this
without getting all right? Hey,
Billy broke killer. My brother and
I went to your show early years,
your early show in Minneapolis a couple
of weeks ago. And as we were leaving,
he was complaining about his back and
shoulder hurting being the Douche. I am.
I assumed he was whining
about the uncomfortable seats.
So the next few days he started coughing
and hearing a rattle in his chest. Yeah.
Okay. We'll go to the doctor. He went
to the doc and as we were cautioned,
it turns out at some
point during your set,
his right lung made like the
Falcons and Superbowl 51 collapsed.
Well, if that's not from laughing, that
was like, you know, you went there. Yeah.
This is probably everything he
did up until that point. Um,
he spent,
I would love to take credit for any
joke being funny enough to make somebody
lung collapse, but I think
you're, uh, thank you. Uh,
yeah. You're looking at the asset
of the problem there, buddy.
He spent the next six days in the hospital
and had to get a tube stuck through
his rib cage, like Carl weathers,
destinies, death scene in Predator.
Then they hope that shit up
to a dustbuster sucked out
the air that was outside
of his lung and sold the whole shot.
That's fascinating.
He finally got out of the
hospital and is doing fine,
but I just thought you'd appreciate
knowing you're at the level where your
comedy caused someone's Oregon to explode
like the Goddamn deathstar keep this
up and you'll be well on your way to
fixing the overpopulation problem anyways.
Can't wait for you to get come back to
Minnesota so he can finish the job and
get his left lung. Hope all is
well with the family. Thinks. Ah,
I'm glad you guys came out and I'm glad
your brother's doing all right. Um,
all right. I think that's the, uh,
I think that's the podcast here,
uh, for this week. Um, all right. I
think there was a formula one race today.
I'm taping this Sunday night.
I got to sit down and watch that,
but I got so much shit to do.
Um,
is that it is, do I
have anything? Oh yeah.
This weekend I'm going to be with
Nate Kraig and Houston. All right.
Houston, Texas in July as
a bald, redheaded male.
And then I'm going to be in Dallas.
I didn't know how many shows I'm fucking
doing here. Let me check it out here.
All right,
so here's the deal.
Thursday I got a show at
revention music center in Texas.
Friday I have a show at prevention
music center in Houston,
Texas. There's still tickets
to Thursday, Friday sold out.
And then I got two shows in,
uh,
the pavilion
up in Dallas at the Toyota music factory.
Um,
also I added a show right before
the rough and rowdy in Rochester,
New York, right outside of Buffalo,
which I haven't been to in a Zillion,
um,
Rochester,
former home of the Rochester royals that
then became the Cincinnati royals than
the Kansas City Slash Omaha
kings than the Kansas City kings.
And then the Sacramento Kings.
Hey Bill, why would they,
Kansas City and Omaha King spoke cause
they used to split their home games
between both those cities.
Seeing which town gave a fuck more.
Kansas City didn't have any
college football. Omaha did.
While I guess it's the
Lincoln, Nebraska, right?
Where is the University of Nebraska?
I only went to a fucking game out there.
I always forget what it had said and
then they became the Sacramento Kings.
I'm into that shit.
I'm going to pass tissues.
You want to do a couple of cool
ones? All right. Here's a good one.
Kansas City Scouts,
NHL team moved to Colorado,
became the Colorado Rockies
and then moved to New Jersey,
became the New Jersey devils. Okay.
I can't do all your homework for you,
but I can do some of it. All right.
The original Washington senators,
1901 to 1960 they left and became the
Minnesota twins and then the senators came
back briefly in Washington,
almost like they retain the name like
the Cleveland browns and it was a second
incarnation of the fucking Washington
senators and they also failed and then
they moved to Texas and
became the Texas Rangers.
All right.
You want to hit some more?
What else do I go? All right. The New
York Yankees. Who were they originally?
The Baltimore Orioles.
1901 to 1902 then they became
the New York islanders,
1903 to 1912 then they
became the New York Yankees,
1913 to present now the
Baltimore Oil Oreos.
I knew they were the
old Saint Louis Browns,
but I didn't realize they were the first,
they were the Milwaukee brewers in 1901
then they will then that Saint Louis
browns in 1902 to 1953 and from
1954 till now they became the Oreos.
All right, that's it. Ken, I want to
talk to you guys anymore about this.
What the Oakland A's, is that, is that,
is that what you were asking about? Well,
they were the Philadelphia athletics
in 1901 to 1954 then the Kansas City
athletics to 1955 in
1967 and then they will,
the became the Oakland A's 1968
to 1986 and then the Oakland,
Oakland Athletics 1987 to present.
I don't know what that means
as far as I'm concerned.
They've been the Oakland A's
or the athletics and 68 but I,
that's what this fucking thing
said to me. You know, and you know,
I learned about all of this shit.
A lot of teams have passed
through Kansas City started there,
have gone through there, and
then they just fucking, you know,
Kansas City Scouts,
Kansas City kings,
Kansas City athletics. They've had a
lot of people come and go, you know,
and there's only one
solution that I can think of.
There's a lot of constant Kansas
City. All right, go fuck yourselves.
I'll talk to you on Thursday.