Hey, what's going on? It's bill burn.
It's time for the Thursday afternoon,
just before Friday, Monday morning
podcast and [inaudible] just check,
get in on you. Checking into CIU
weeks going by before I get started.
This is going to be a special podcast.
So I have a couple of special
amount announcements. Uh,
Steven Adler is back together with
Adler's appetite and they are going to be
playing at the, uh, the Rose
in Pasadena on August 23rd.
And then he's going to be in Vegas
at the Golden Nugget on the 24th.
And on the 25th.
This is August,
August dates at the Canyon
club in Santa Clarita.
If you want to see one of the best
drummers I've ever seen in my life,
check out Adler's appetite. Um, we'll
have a link and all that type of stuff.
Go on and go check out Jesus if you've
got to promote a couple of things.
All right. Uh, number one,
I'm going to be at Madison Square Garden.
November 7th for the New York comedy
festival. Tickets are on sale now.
I believe that's a Wednesday Hump Day.
Everybody.
Um, and uh, I didn't read
the one read. I had Hubble.
Everybody. Do you have eyes? Do they
not work as well as they should?
Do you like spending less money on
things more than more money on things?
Do you know what the Internet is?
If you answered yes to any or all
these questions than visit Hubble
contacts.com, uh, motivate your audience,
choose one or two. All right. I
guess these are positive things.
Talk about how you've been wearing
humbled contacts for the past 25 years.
I have it before I didn't see things and
now I see I didn't wear those fucking
things.
I don't have context.
I have no idea. I don't want
the same. These guys make
contact lenses and they're,
they're fucking great.
How was that? With humble,
you'll get a fresh pair of lenses for
every single day for less than 60,
for less. 60 contacts for
33 bucks. Do the math.
That's barely a dollar a day. This is
way more affordable than other brands.
Go to Hubble contacts.com and get
your first two weeks for free.
Hubble sells directly to you.
So they can offer context
at a more affordable price.
They can send you to an optometrist if
you don't have a prescription featured in
vogue, Gq, tech crunch, Mashable,
and now the Monday morning podcast or
Thursday afternoon just before Friday.
Um,
so do what I evidently did 100% and go
to Hubba context.com and get your first
two weeks of lenses for free.
Uh,
that's Hubb Ellie contacts.com.
And with that, the other announcement I
have to make, I have a very special guest,
a long time waiting,
long time in the coming for
whatever fucking reason.
We've hung out a million times.
We never thought to do a podcast.
I didn't want to infringe
on the man's talents. Um,
please welcome Mr Tom Rhodes.
Yay. What's going? Yay from me.
What's up brother? How are you brother?
Um, I'm doing good man. I'm so psyched.
You're on a podcast. You're one of
the, one of the best comics I know.
I've known you for like,
I know I've known you for like 20,
I don't know how many years,
a long way back in la.
And I would say I was living in
New York like 98 99 was that it?
I think, yeah, maybe that was what it was.
I thought I met you in like 95 or
96 out here in la. He's out here.
Maybe briefly,
you probably walked by with your
romantic novel hair that you had back up.
Romance,
novel haircut.
I meet with my red Afro Two hacks
passing in the night. Right.
Trying to get better. And then, yeah.
And then I think the first time I like
officially kind of met you and was
hanging out back when we
both had folic strength. Yes.
And I was very excited that you knew who
I was because I had seen you at eating
it of all places, which is why I
became a huge fan of your standup.
I've told you this story before, but I'm
gonna tell the listeners where you were,
uh, you were talking about some sort of
extracurricular activity that you were
doing. I had done mushrooms in
Amsterdam and vulnerable park. Yes.
And I just remember you were describing
the whole fucking trip of it.
And I just remember you just at
one point you were just like,
I was running through the
grass summit tippy toes.
And it's just something about
that was like, you know,
there's w with alcohol,
there's nothing worse than just seeing
somebody who's like completely fucked up.
But like with mushrooms,
there's like a oneness with the world
where you literally watching adult become
a child or something. I just thought you
described it. I've never taken mushrooms,
but like from what I've seen when
I've seen people tripping and I'm a,
I was there with,
with Nia way back in the day when
we were still boyfriend girlfriend.
And we would die in laughing.
And that became like, you
know, like one of the, uh,
a catch phrase for us.
You know,
we would just be walking
around the apartment and one
would be in the other room
and we just, we're just yelled that out
and run into the grass on my tippy toes.
We both would just start laughing.
That's the greatest compliment.
You could get one like a,
uh,
a joke or a sentence from a joke becomes
part of somebody's vernacular, you know?
Oh yeah, there's been a few.
There's the Dave Chappelle,
Dave Chappelle had a bit
about, uh, how, you know,
he likes eating chicken
and he's a black dude.
So there's that weird sort of stereotype.
But he's like, but, but I like it.
He goes, but I won't eat it
in public because he goes,
I'm afraid there'll be some white people
around going look at him. He loves it.
So just like the encyclopedia says,
it wasn't that the last line of that bit.
I don't remember. But I just remember
to this day, I know I can't eat this.
Thinking of that line. Well to this day
when me and Nia or hanging out, uh Oh,
if we're eating food and F if she go as a
taste, I go, oh, that's good. I like it.
And she'll just go look at him. He
loves it. Like it just, it's just,
there was a few of those. Yeah. Now
I've got to go through all of them.
Sarah Silverman,
Sarah Silverman said something about how
she prac bought condoms or something.
I forget. I just remember that was the
punchline was cause I do a lot of fucking
neo was watching that we're in this
little one bedroom apartment is everything
is in New York little and I was shaving
in the other room and I just heard that
I didn't even really even here the setup,
which probably why I can't remember it,
but I just burst out laughing while
I was shaving. So, um, anyway,
you're part of my mount Rushmore
of lines that just never, it never,
it just never left my, my, my,
my head. I don't know why. So.
And furthermore other, you know,
I would say either you or Doug,
Stan hope have probably put the most like
stand up miles on the odometer as far
as the places that, that you've
played, how far you've gone. Um,
but I mean you might
have to be the king man.
You were telling me that at some point
in this podcast you are going to start
rattling off your dates.
If actually you sat down here looking
like you didn't have a care in the world
and you just casually mentioned to me that
you're off to Mongolia tomorrow. Yeah,
yeah. I would be a fucking wreck going
like, oh, I, what am I going to forget?
Something I would have to check 50 times
to make sure I have my passport and I
would stick it in the bag and I would
zip it shut and then look to make sure
that I would zip it shut again and then
I would still have to check it before I
left the house in the car on the way to
the airport before I started talking.
That anxiety down because I used
is my, um, Genghis Khan
biography to reread on the plane.
That's it. Is that how you
say it? It's not gang. Yeah.
I played in Mongolia last October and
it was freezing. It was in the third.
So this is the,
you're the only guy I know.
Not only is Benda Mongolia over
notice that he's return engagement was
triumphant return to Mongolia.
You asked him the Comedians,
they're wonderful guys.
I mean in Mongolians are beautiful and
they look like the people in the Avatar,
but without the blue. And, uh,
five of the low f five of the local
Mongolian comedians met me at the airport
when I arrived and they chow,
they cheered when I came out.
I'm like the most famous comedian
that's ever played in Mongolia,
so they'd like bend over
backwards showing me, uh,
Ulaan Baatar and we drove out to the,
uh,
the world's largest Genghis Khan statue.
And Yeah,
they taught me that it's a, it's Genghis
Khan not getting gifts and those, those,
well, I like a, you're not
obnoxious with that information.
You could be really conti at a party.
Uh, excuse me guys. I don't interrupt.
It's Genghis Khan,
Huh?
Yeah.
And Americans and other people say though,
they call those white round tents a Yurts,
but they actually call them GIRs
in Mongolia. So what's, what's the,
uh,
I don't know anything about it other than
it's just sort of spoons with northern
China. It's between them and Russia
and China and Russia. And, uh,
so I liked it so much and um,
I wanted to go back in summer and see it
when it wasn't, um, bone chilling cold.
So it's kind of, um,
uh, vacation. So I mean,
I'm going to do a gig there,
but I'm going to go in and I'm
going to spend like four days there.
These guys are going to take
me way out into the country.
We're going to sleep in a girl,
one of those round tents. Um,
shoot life, shoot some
arrows, do some, uh,
do some Mongolian warrior activities.
And then I got a Gig.
You've got to tell Rogan about this.
Rogan sounds like he would be all
over the country. Would love it.
I'm sure you would love it.
It's um, you know, that's the,
I've shot some arrows in my time.
I went,
I went both fishing and some by you down
and fucking hour with o was somewhere
outside of New Orleans.
It's a great thing about being a comedian.
I remember I was in Alaska years ago.
I did a Gig in Ketchikan and I met the
perfect Alaskan Guy who took me fishing
on his charter boat and
then took me skeet shooting.
I obviously feel like
when you meet those guys,
there's always some sort of like raggedy
plane you get in first that lands on
water or they put snowshoes
on bottom of it plays
upon tune. Um, so let's see. Uh, you know,
you're the only guy I know
that it's played Vietnam.
I love Vietnam. You know, my, my,
you're the, I know that watches like
Ken Burns documentaries. Like, yeah,
I've been there. I've played there.
Yeah, I know what it looks like. No,
I've done all of that.
Um, I, you know, well,
I did that special for comedy
central in 1995 called Viva Vietnam.
I W I got to go to Vietnam. You've
been going there? I was over the years.
Yeah.
I was the first comedian ever to have a
development deal with comedy central and
so I could do whatever I wanted. It was
like being a junior filmmaker almost, so.
Oh. And they were sitting 94. Bill
Clinton lifted the travel ban on Vietnam,
the way like Obama lifted the travel
ban on Cuba and my father fought in
Vietnam. He flew helicopters. He was
shot down everyone in his helicopter.
Can you tell that story?
Uh, yeah. Quickly. Yeah. So,
and this is why Vietnam has
always been a really important,
it's a been a big thing in our family.
Um,
so my father flew helicopters
in Vietnam in 1969.
He was stationed in play cool. And, uh,
he, there was, there was all these
soldiers stuck on the ground.
They're surrounded by, uh, the
north Vietnamese soldiers in there.
They're just getting slaughtered.
So my father had to fly in and rescue
these guys. How old was he? Um,
he actually joined my, my dad was one
of those knuckleheads, so he was 30.
His,
uh,
his buddies in his unit
called him Methuselah because
he was like the oldest guy
there because everybody else was 19.
You know, he just thought, you know,
he grew up on John Wayne movies.
He thought that, you know,
he was one of those guys that thought
you have in your country needed you,
you know, so, uh, they made, he made,
I got the letter from the army,
uh, and all his metals, um,
after he died.
Uh,
so he made three attempts to
land to save these guys and was,
it took so much heavy fire,
he had to lift up,
circle around and on the fourth attempt
he gets down and there's like 20 guys
down there is still alive
and it's life or death.
So they all like jump on the
helicopter and as he's pulling up,
you know, and these just getting
rattled with so much, um,
fire machine gun fire that the helicopter
nose dived down and everybody died in
the helicopter except for him and his
copilot who was knocked unconscious,
he unhooks him, drags him across
the field under heavy fire.
And then they had to wait there for
like an hour or two before someone could
come in and rescue. Was he shooting back
at them or what? Well, it's funny, he,
cause he, you know, he, my dad, uh,
would laugh when he tells his story
because he always had this pistol that he
would take with him when he,
when he was flying.
And then the one day he forgot it, he gets
shot down. So he wasn't shooting back,
he didn't have a gun. So, um,
my dad was a decorated war hero and he,
um,
he got like five medals for
the men over your house. He,
uh, Tom has it framed. Yes.
The letter and, and
there's like, you know,
the little from the army is saying what
he did from his commanding officer and
there's almost not enough room in the
frame for all of them as like five,
there's like six medals,
but five were from that one incident.
He got the distinguished
flying cross and, and, uh, my,
my father, um, is buried in Arlington
national cemetery as they should be.
And you gotta be a bad ass to get in
there. You know, I would say he qualifies.
So my dad, uh, probably be
buried across the street.
I'm like sort of a seven, 11.
I want a viking funeral pyre.
Um, so, so my dad,
every year he would get,
he would have a reunion with his Vietnam
veteran helicopter buddies. It was like,
um, big thing for him. Uh,
and uh, and, and you know,
my dad also loved stand up comedy.
My Dad loved prior and my dad's the reason
I'm a comedian, you know, you yet all.
I remember driving around with it as a
little kid listening to Richard Pryor
with my dad. So as he thrilled that
you became a comedian. Oh yeah.
My Dad drove me to my first open
mic night. My Dad, my dad, see,
I looked at him and Tommy,
so my dad stand up comedy was always
revered in my family and well especially,
you know, because my dad and he just, uh,
my dad wore shipped prior.
He had a Bob Newhart records
and JC great taste too. Yeah.
So I, I, um,
I think those were like my two
biggest influences as a kid.
And then my family is from Washington
DC and my uncle did open mic nights for
one year in 1978.
I'm 11 years old.
My Dad took me to see my uncle perform
at this open mic night and it was a club
called El Brooklyn's in DC.
And the entrance was next to the stage,
the shows in progress.
We walk in,
I'm wearing a Washington Redskins jacket.
The comedian on stage pulls me on
stage and he starts interviewing me.
Like I'm the coach of the Redskins and
I'm like, I'm 11. I'm mum's a bashful,
dopey kid. I give you one
word answers. Yes, no,
but I'll never forget standing on that
stage and seeing all those happy people
with their heads thrown back and laughter
and all the teeth in their mouth.
And that moment changed my life. And
I, you know, and I, I just, I can,
I can still picture it. You know,
it's, I, you know, um, you know,
black people, Latin people,
white people, like Asian people,
just the flavors of humanity.
And I just thought that that was the most
magical place in the world to stand on
stage, making people laugh. So, um,
I became a student of comedy after
that and would keep notebooks.
And then I started when I was 17 with
a fake idea. You still have all your
comedy, like you like your,
your apartment, first of
all, it's cool as shit.
It's also like this,
uh,
it's the Smithsonian of your life and he
has his dad's helmet from Vietnam when
he was shot, the one that he was wearing.
Um, I got chills looking at that thing.
Yeah. Like that's like a imagine like
you brain when he was aware of that. Yes.
And you had told me the story as we
were sitting there smoking a wonderful
cigar.
Uh,
and you told me this story and then to
New York and I still have the helmet and
I was like, Oh wow,
man, I couldn't believe.
And then to walk in and see it and
after and just the heaviness of it once,
it's like a story attached to it. Like
if you just got a helmet and it was like,
yeah, this is like, uh, you know,
some memorabilia thing. This is,
and you have to wonder what
have to actually know what
happened while that thing
was. I mean I'm into that type of shit.
Like I got that weird thing of like,
um, if I know the story behind it, which
is why I have to be careful because I'll,
I'll just fill my house up
with a bunch of shit like that.
And then I have all this fucking anxiety
that I have no place to send anything
down.
You know,
I can't have this thing cause I kinda
grew up with semi hoarders that just would
not fucking throw anything out, you
know, 40 years of magazines and Shit. Um,
no, that's a good thing about, you know,
I had everything in storage for 10 years.
I just traveled the world.
I decided not to live anywhere.
Do you think can see that. So I got to
preserve all these great things, you know.
But do you think,
you think your dad being in Vietnam
and then you learning about that,
is that how you got the travel bug
to the level you that you're on?
Like some Tom Brokaw level shit?
Yeah,
maybe. And my mother's from Argentina.
Um, so I don't know. I mean,
I had performed everywhere in
the United States, you know, 20,
30 times and I wanted to
branch out. Um, but, but,
but,
but back to Vietnam,
I mean that was a really special
thing for me to go there.
And I filmed this hour special called
Viva Vietnam for comedy central.
I was like a travel log type of thing.
Um,
did the Jane Fonda workout tape in Hanoi
with some old women in a park when that
Denang China beach setup a slip.
CIA people about why Jane
Fonda is funny for that. Uh,
Vietnam veterans hate Jane Fonda's
guts still to this day. Veterans, um,
at those Vietnam reunions,
my dad would go to,
they still sell the Jane
Fonda, um, urine, uh,
the thing for like a urinal
guard with her picture on it.
You know what I'm saying? A
urinal cake. Yeah. It was a no,
like the little plastic thing
on it. Oh yeah. Okay. Um,
and so at the height of the Vietnam war,
Jane Fonda goes to Hanoi.
The, um, uh,
the capital of the people were having
a war with and she's antiwar and,
and,
and they took pictures of her own,
like anti aircraft artillery and,
and then she met the POW [inaudible] and
one of them slipped her a note and then
she, uh, apparently, if I
remember the story correctly,
she gave that to the Vietnamese
prison guards and Oh God,
who was tortured extra for, I'm slipping
her a note. Oh God, that's fine.
That's has to be the ultimate,
uh, stupid celebrity moment.
Yeah. Where you're, you're
just so like, you know,
sucking the Dick of your
own fucking ego that you,
you go and do something like that to just,
well, I think being against a war zone,
okay, that's fine. Do that.
You'll go to the Capitol and I've watched
enough war movies that my heart would
be in my fucking throat. The second
you get the note, you're like,
do I got to put this under my
tongue and put it up my ass? Like,
what do I gotta do? I gotta do it. I
know this is like some top secret shit.
Shitty. Yeah. Um, but so
in, in 1990, we filmed it,
it was me, guard came at you mad,
slipped me a note.
Um,
he'll need extra bamboo
under his fingernails. Uh,
so 19 September [inaudible] 94
we filmed it and like Americans,
it was only like, that's, that went there.
Like it hadn't become like a tourist
place yet. So, and this park in,
in Hanoi, a old women would gather
and do Tai Chi in the morning.
So at the time in [inaudible]
94, beginning, early nineties,
Jane Fonda was making these exercise tapes
and we set up a television with a VCR
and we brought the tape
and 1994 technology,
we had to run an extension
cord like five blocks to,
to set this up in the park.
And these old women loved it.
They took to it and they started doing
it and she was, I turned it as she goes,
now turned to the right and I'll say,
I'll say she turned to the right. Did you,
did you see,
uh,
can you imagine her fucking agent
when she was telling them that,
I'm going to go to North Vietnam?
He's just sitting that Jane,
I've worked so hard with you
to get you to this level.
I'm imploring you not
to do this. Oh, Marie,
the a bed bed bed.
Uh,
Mary Tyler Moore episode. Um, God,
what a fuck he sort of like
the first Dennis Rodman.
Like when by the time Dennis did it, it
was just, just been so much. First of all,
they didn't have our guys, you know,
in, in p and W. Yeah. Yeah. And uh,
well, I mean, you know, um, what
was that guy's name? Otto warm beer.
It was a guy that I have no clue who
that is. Did he played for the Bengals?
I'm the only one who remembers this
guy's name. I think he was from Chicago.
He was there. He went to North
Korea and vacation a few years ago.
And he stole a banner out of the basement
of a hotel. Yeah. And they sent him,
sentenced him to, you
know, hard labor for life.
And then they came back a year later.
They sent him back as a vegetable.
There was in a coma. Yeah. And he died.
Yeah, he died. It's heartbreaking stories.
So yeah, he went up, he went
in there and like, yeah,
it took that poster, whatever, which
is, you know, something you don't do.
I remember somebody on, on,
on the Internet, it was like,
as you example of white privilege,
oh my God. It's just like, even this,
you have to turn into that. Yeah.
Can't we all just be like, wow,
that's somebody's son. Yeah. You
know, can't, can't you just do that?
Do you have to turn it into like a
fucking Hashtag, uh, social justice,
whatever fucking moment. Everyone's
being dehumanized. Yeah. I mean, I dunno,
that was one of those six months or so.
I can understand why anybody
would go to Vietnam on vacation.
They killed so many of our, she knew
so many people that died, you know,
and I went back in 2014.
Hennoi was my favorite.
It's French tree lined boulevards.
It's really, uh, the lake.
The John Mccain was shot down
in, uh, in the whole town.
Has Swan boats now has now has swan peddle
boats. No, it doesn't. I told you that.
Did you tell me that? I did tell you that
was just use my Boston background. Yeah,
you can rent couples.
Go there and rent swan paddle boats.
See that's why I don't watch people
stand up specials because things stick in
years.
I forget cause I was sitting there like,
oh I'm going to throw in the swan
joke thing from when I got back.
So I went in 2014.
This English guy who runs the Gig there
and annoying also gives motorcycle tours
of the north in Vietnam.
So I went back April of this year and um,
I went on this,
if it was my,
my dream to go on this motorcycle journey
and we were 45 miles north of Hanoi
going up a mountain,
a little winding road,
and the bike went out from
under me and I wrecked and say,
how good are right around you.
I was the fourth time I've been on
a motorcycle and I've been afraid of
motorcycles my whole life. So it was
something I wanted to do to break my fear.
And, uh, just wearing a helmet.
My head bounced off the road,
but I was fine. And, uh, took
a lot of skin off my elbow, but
I think it just taking the safety course
out here, we ride around a parking lot.
My wife's brother,
my wife is from Holland and her brother
teaches motorcycle lessons in Rotterdam.
So last summer when I was in
Rotterdam visiting her family, uh,
he took me out and, and he and I
did that in the parking lot. Okay.
So I did
then how long between that and then
just writing up a fucking mountain in
Vietnam? Uh, what,
eight, 10 months later I do this.
I took my ground school and,
uh,
didn't fly again.
And eight months later I decided to fly
in fight or a dirt bike when I was a
hurricane and I like tore a tendon in
my arm and I missed a baseball season,
which was a big deal when you're
14. Yeah. And uh, and then I didn't,
when I lived in Amsterdam and
I had the, uh, worked, uh,
for this Dutch travel show for a year,
I got to do a highlight on Peru
and we went to the Nazca lines.
You know those lines that people
think are alien landing strips.
They weren't discovered until the 1920s.
That shit on
not cover that Zeplin box
set. Uh, you're talking about,
cause I really dumb guy here, dude.
I don't, I don't, that's weird.
You'd like talk in English, but half of
this shit you're saying I don't, I don't,
I'm just like, I don't know what that is.
I'm just, this is taking me back to the
cool,
well I'm just like,
there's these desert drawings and they
weren't discovered until the 1920s when
aircraft was um,
first flying over Peru and one's that
Condura one's a monkey and then there's
the, looks like these landing
strips in between it and um,
yeah.
Why would you make it like that if
everyone didn't know how to fly back then?
Right. Is that what they, they asked it
like a thousand years old.
It's,
how could they have done it
unless aliens helped them?
Maybe just, maybe that's the theory. They
develop some sort of hot air
balloon before anybody else.
And then they all perished in some
sort of a plague and there, you know,
everything was biodegradable back then.
How you're going to find
the hot air balloon. It can,
it doesn't always have
to be aliens doesn't,
yeah. I used to do a line years
ago that a, the Incas did cocaine,
I guess that explains why
they were building, uh,
alien UFO lending strips in the desert
all night.
Um, tell me about a couple
of things I want to ask.
One of my favorite podcast episodes ever
was the one that you did with the late
great John Fox, who was, I never met him,
but I heard all of the
stories. He was like, um,
road viking. I mean, he, like every, he,
he created the cliches.
Like he was kind like,
uh, the like, I don't know,
the Elvis or like, you know,
the early days of rock and
roll where there was no, you
know, go out and go create
it and create what the fuck
this is going to be. And he,
he kind of did that as far as
every fucking cliche now, um,
that guy was,
and listening to that podcast with him,
because I'd only heard of him
and I never really, you know,
there's all these short little clips of
him on the Internet just to get like an
hour, an hour and 10 minutes, however
long it is of him telling stories.
And then just hearing the
stories in his voice like that.
I that crazy laugh he head,
oh my God.
Oh my God. Like, uh, amazing.
How did you get like everybody on my,
on my buddy Paul Versey met him
and was like, man, that guy was,
he was a fucking sweetheart and verse.
He met them right towards the end and
he actually who they are working like
Milwaukee or something and he watched
his set and actually gave him a couple of
tags, encouraged him and all of that. And
I don't know if he was sick yet, but um,
he just was all mad. He was like the
nicest guy and all of that type of stuff.
So I'm so glad that you did that episode,
but how did you get to meet John?
Um, I worked with him when I was
really young. I think I was, I,
I was 19 when I worked with
him in Jacksonville, Florida.
There used to be a punchline there.
It was a great room and I used
to do the comedy zone down there.
This was way before that. You know, the,
the Atlanta punchline in the, in the boom,
in the late eighties there was punchline
comedy clubs all over the south.
And the one in Jacksonville was one of
the best and the guys that owned it,
it was like four guys and then they
all got like Mercedes and BMWs and then
they're breaking in so much money.
They moved it to a bigger venue.
They had like 150 seat room.
Then they moved it to a 500 seat room
and the place was never the same.
And then it went out of business.
But at one time that was like one of the
W it was one of the greatest clubs in
the south. So I worked
with him. And you know,
John Fox was legendary for kind of being
a womanizer, coke freak, booze hound,
all that. Chan I check he liked me. Um,
because I I could drink heavily and um,
I I was row relatively cute and um,
you track some late would attracts
some ladies. So he still had,
he was on one of the first
right, right. That is,
that is next level like getting pussy
where it's just that remind me of Pedro
Martinez when he lost the
heat on his fast ball.
So he developed a couple other pitches
and he was able to stay in the league at
a high level.
So he's sitting there crushing ass cause
he was a good looking guy when he was
young. Right. Blonde hair had
the mullet, which was the look,
the whole Miami vice oak he
could pull up was crushing as,
and then all of a sudden he starts
[inaudible] loses a little heat on his
fastball is like, here's a good
look. You look looking young fella,
I'll bring him along. That'll keep
bringing the ladies up to the light here.
That's the thing. Yeah. I think
people don't remember, don't think of
when they think of him when he could.
He was on one of those early
Rodney Dangerfield young comedian,
and he looked like a California
surfer guy. He had blonde hair,
Tan, he's a Tan, great shape.
And then he got older and Pudgy and
he looked like an older white guy,
alcoholic dude. So, um, the
life caught up with him.
He helped me get in.
He loved me and he helped me get in with
Chicago xannies where he was the man
and you know, that was his hometown. He
was from Waukegan, Illinois. But, um,
he was mister Chicago,
so he gets me work with him in
Chicago, booked like three weeks, uh,
the downtown room and a couple of the
suburban rooms for a couple of weeks.
I'm 19. I'd never been to Chicago, uh,
and it was sold out every
night and he was the man, uh,
Saika one of those porn star came
and he took me to the blues brothers,
had a bar or doing cocaine after
hours off to the pinball machine.
He took me, he took me to a cubs
game. He took you under his wing.
He took me under his wing, but it
was great. I mean, uh, you know,
I'd only been doing comedy for two years
and now I'm in Chicago playing and sold
out rooms opening for this guy.
But he took me to see
the cubs and he was a,
he was kind of a Chicago celebrity back.
Yeah.
And he was buddies with Steve
Stone and he actually took me up,
we got to go up into the booth when
Harry Carey's saying take me out to the
ballgame. And like, Harry Carey's
like, you know, half in the bag,
leaning out the window and,
um,
the had to hold his belt so
he didn't fall out. I mean,
who lead a better life than that guy
gets to announce baseball while he's just
catching a buzz. And everybody's thought
it was hilarious that he was like,
he was literally drunk. Yeah. On
the, yeah. In the afternoon there.
So, um, yeah, so I mean, you know, uh,
John Fox was really nice to me and I
knew him through the years and then, uh,
the trials and tribulations
and bad relationships and
years of booze and excess,
uh, it was kind of sad what, I mean,
he was kind of the cautionary tale of,
you know,
you don't want to be this road guy who um,
is just chasing women in partying
and stuff forever because it,
uh,
it was really a sad end for that guy.
And then he lived in the
apartment building next door
to the apartment where the
xannies puts the comedians in
Chicago. It's an old town. And,
uh,
there's the old town Ale House,
which I remember him taking me there
and all these, that area in the,
in the late eighties was Graham a kid.
And it was, you know, it was so much fun.
And then, uh, he was kind of like sad,
lonely drunk guy at the old town. Alehouse
towards the end or was towards the
end, like when, when
did it start becoming,
when did it sort of shift
where the industry wasn't,
he stopped getting work and,
um, and I, I sat in the night,
Nah,
I can't remember.
I can't remember what year I
did that recording with him.
I don't think it was the nineties,
cause when I was, no, no,
it was asked early thousands. Yeah.
Cause when I was in the nineties,
when I was starting to get out
there on the road, it was, uh,
I would hear legendary stories about him.
And then everywhere I had just been,
it seemed,
Doug Stan hope was there and had some
sort of debauchery in the fucking green
room. And I remember the first time
I met Doug Stanhope, uh, you know,
I instantly loved the guy,
but before I met him I was like,
who the fuck is this Stan Hope Guy?
What the fuck can he, you know,
do all this shit outside of the Goddamn,
uh,
the comedy condo and a, but I
would always hear like, oh my God,
the Atlanta punchline, they,
they used to have stories.
I know there's a couple of
guys who was still alive,
so I don't want to fucking
put this shit out there.
But there was like a couple of guys on
that Mount Rushmore of like the wait
staff would be so excited
that they were coming to town.
And after like maybe a night and a half,
like that Sunday night show seemed like
three years away and they would just
like,
I don't think I'm going to make it.
Because there was those guys
that came to town and they just,
they were like this pied Piper
in the entire fucking wait staff.
They had this charisma. All the
bartenders, the club owners, they,
he would just take them on
a crawl night after night,
after fucking night. And
yeah, and like, I mean, I, uh,
this other guy that I know of,
well I'm not gonna mention his name,
like he had a nickname and all that,
and you would pick up the phone and he
would just, he would say anything like,
Tom, like Yanni bills, it's so and so.
And the running joke was you would just
scream in horror knowing that he was
coming to town,
he was going to stay with you and that
you guys were going to be hitting a
bottle or two every f it would be
like trying to keep up with Lemmy,
some of these guys.
That reminds me of something like
the Lemmy Motorhead stories, um,
that you hear him so
well. You don't have the, um, the,
the albums in the
following to fall back on.
Like I remember anything John Fox
when he was still like surfer,
good looking guy.
Uh,
I remember he would walk by the
waitress station and he would go, um,
he would just announce
fuck me before him famous.
He would say that out loud to the,
to the way he never would have survived
the me too movement. Oh my God. Wow.
But so when he was so
towards the end and you know,
and I always had a soft spot in that
from a hurt for the guy because he helped
me when I was a young comedian. And, uh,
so I did that interview with
him. And, um, the thing that I,
that stands out for me on that interview
that I did with him. Oh, so there was,
there was one when it,
when it got sad for him,
I remember there was some
turbulent, he was in and, and uh,
he was falling apart and as a,
as an alcoholic and he's in this
terrible relationship and the girl had
scratched his face,
like really bad.
And so he had all these scratch
marks on his face. And uh,
there was a story in Atlanta about him
breaking down on stage and crying and
just some really sad stories
and shit that happened to him.
But the thing that stands
out fucking movie. Yeah.
The thing that stands out for me about
that interview was did he still believed
in love?
He's talking about,
and he had been through all this shit in
his life and you know, he's, he's older,
Pudgy,
alcoholic guy past his prime and he's
still talking about love and it's like
raging bull. But the stand up version,
like the narrow back in the day Co,
he could've played John Fox like the
John Fox story. It's the same thing.
And in the end he ends up doing stand
up in raging bull. Yeah. Jesus Christ.
Um, well you, uh, you, you
cleaned up your act how long ago?
Uh,
I've been so good.
We're four, almost five years.
That's fucking amazing. I've been a,
I finally kind of cleaned up my act.
I don't like,
I don't think I would ever
not do it again, but like,
I drank like the last day of
June and then I drank, uh,
August 7th,
and I'm not going to drink again.
Select October now I sort of drink like
the way I smoke cigars or I should say
the way I would like to smoke
cigars, which I like, you know,
a couple times a month or every other
month or something like that. Uh,
you know, um, I'm trying to
like, you know, I've got a kid,
I'm a super old fucking dad to have a kid,
so it's just like I have to
fucking be around until this,
my kid has it figured out.
Yeah.
Every,
every warrior needs to move onto
Wiseman and I can't be out pounding it.
And, uh, one of the greatest things ever
happened to me was given up the booze.
And I mean, and I have feasted from
the banquet of life. You know, I, I,
I mean I lived in Amsterdam, you know,
uh, hosted a talk show over in London.
You would like the Dave Letterman late
night talk show for two years on Dutch
television. But, um, you
know, I went through, uh,
some pretty hardcore tragedies.
My Dad, who I adored, um,
was killed by a drunk driver in
2009 through the irony of that,
when you see that helmet,
that surviving Vietnam,
all of that in the metals and all that.
And then just some jackass in Anaheim,
which, you know, we've all
fucking done. So I can't put like,
it's just fucking unbelievable again.
And then my little sister,
who I was really close with, um,
died of breast cancer in 2011, uh,
my wife and I actually got married
at her hospital bedside, um,
the day before she died of cancer
cause I didn't want her to miss it.
So that was 2011. So 2012, 2013,
I had stopped drinking for pleasure,
saying I would just like numbing
myself because I was so heartbroken.
And then, um, January 1st, 2014, uh,
in Philadelphia, I blacked out
and busted my head open and, uh,
the next, and I got like six stitches
on my forehead. I had a black guy.
The next day I looked in the mirror and
I saw so much ugliness and, uh, and I,
I knew,
she didn't know that was the moment
when you look in the government.
I had been thinking about it and I just
thought the main, I mean vanity was,
was a big reason because, um, I, I
saw so much ugliness in the mirror,
but also I knew it was
holding me back as a comedian.
I knew I could be a better comedian
if I stopped drinking every night.
And, um, you know, and I
didn't go to any AA meetings,
which a people always get
offended when I say that, but, um,
I just, I just had had enough and um, the,
for the first, the first, first couple
of weeks, you know, you're a little,
little bumpy, but uh, you know,
you can get through it just pictured you
look into the mirror with the black guy
in the car and just be like,
all right, you went, yeah, yeah.
When I'm a fucking doing this.
Well,
what happened was I looked in
the mirror and I just thought,
I want to go one year when I looked in
the mirror, what I said to myself was,
I want to go one year
and see what it's like,
not be in drunk every night to be,
to see what I could get done.
And I got so much done, uh,
writing jokes and, you know,
working on my book in different
projects and stuff. Uh, I,
I, I, that's what made
me stick around. Yeah.
Well mine to having a kid now too. It's
like it's every, every dad told me,
he said, Oh yeah, I have a kid that'll,
that'll curb your drinking cause they
don't give a shit or have any sort of
concept of what being hung over his yeah.
And they wake up with like,
they're there on a full tank.
Like the whole body is brand new,
nothing hurts and they're ready to just,
it's just like that Duh Duh Duh.
They get right in your face. Ha. He's
yelling and shit and it's just like,
um, it's actually, you know,
I'm finding if I'm going to go out
and do stand up, I have to make the,
I have to be out the door by
eight o'clock, eight oh five,
I'm going to fall asleep.
It's just one of those things like she
gets up at like a quarter to seven in the
morning. And uh, that happened to
me last night where I was like,
I'm going to go out. I think it was
actually, I was going to go see a mission.
Impossible. Cause I'm wanting to watch
Tom Cruise, speaking of helicopters,
find that helicopter. And um, I just, Oh,
the next showing isn't until 10 or 10 30.
And I knew I was like,
I'm gonna fall asleep in the middle of
mission and possible Tom Cruise Action
Summer action movie. I am so fucking
tired, I'm going to fall asleep. So, uh,
plus I want to take my, uh, Neil
long to go see it in like Imax,
get the whole thing before, uh, the whole
experience before it goes away. So, um,
let, let me see. Ah, let's, let's promote,
so you're going to be in Mongolia.
What else do you got? Like I don't
know if I have any listeners there.
That was such a great story about
how supportive the comics where,
because I did a Gig in India and
like most of the crowd was comedians.
I was so happy that I didn't realize
that because I would've been like
intimidated. Like, Oh God, they're
all going to be like, well,
what's the next joke
structure? And afterwards we
all hung out and it was like,
it was weird.
It was like I was hanging at a comedy
club on the other side of the world in,
in like total. They're called, but it
was the exact same fucking questions.
Did you write on stage? You do that? Yeah.
Don't you think this guy is overrated?
And they would say shit like
that. I was like, oh my God,
it's the exact same physical, the guys
they're repelling over there. Um, uh,
emulating your, uh, gestures and
stuff cause they hung out with, no,
but I actually do,
what I found was people in India are
fucking hilarious that just, they're a,
there, it's kind of that same vibe of
like when you go to Ireland and Scotland,
when you just meet like, like, yeah,
this is why I love the most, you know,
the fraternity of it, you
know? Yeah. They're like, uh,
people in Australia funny. They're just
fucking funny. I don't know what it is.
And then other places you go, I'm not
going to mention is I want to shit on any,
he just go in and they're just like,
these people are polite and then
you go to these other places.
It's just like you just is the
second you walk into the airport,
you just start seeing
characters. He's like, all
right, this is to be a good show.
These people are cool. So I'm so
glad you went to um, that, that um,
storer in Paris and on your podcast,
you wouldn't give the name of it.
Oh yeah.
Cause I turned you onto it.
I knew I didn't want to live emails.
What's the name of that Patisserie?
Cause I was picturing you go in there
the next time standing in this line,
you know, you're all excited.
Like that fucking asshole bill.
Set It on his podcast all get to stand in.
But there's already,
the word is kind of what people already
know. And when people come up to me,
I tell him like, like what it is. And
I actually liked the sandwiches better.
The sandwiches are amazing.
I remember what I,
what I told you what I tell everybody,
get one of the sandwiches
because they're incredible.
And then buy one for later from when
you're walking around Paris and you think
to yourself, damn, I wish I'd bought
a another sandwich for later. Yeah.
And it doesn't overdo it. It doesn't, it's
just makes you want to keep going back.
So, um, you know a lot of, uh, that
mission impossible. I heard he's in Paris,
shot in Paris. Yeah. I gotta
check that out, but I keep
trying to get to your data.
Okay. All right. Funny Bone
in Mongolia. No, no, no, no.
It's called the UBI.
Ulaan Baatar is called a,
they call it ubi city. So it's
the you, you be city comedy club.
Um, okay. So check out this schedule
I have for the rest of the year.
Uh, August 22nd, um, in
Ulaan Baatar, Mongolia.
August 24th, I'm in Beijing,
China. August 25th, Shanghai,
August 30th through September 2nd,
um,
at levity live in west Nyack, New
York. Are you driving to these gigs?
No. Wait, you're doing, so
you're doing this quick little,
it's that even Southeast Asia,
Southeast Asia in the April of course.
Um,
this is Maharaji Butterfly
in a couple of gigs.
So I could have an excuse to go back to
Mongolia in summer and in check it out,
you know.
So September 4th through the
ninth of it Janie's in Chicago,
uh,
12th through the 16th.
I'm in Rosemont Adzenys September
27th through September 30th.
I'm at the punchline in Atlanta.
I love that place. October 4th,
I'm in Porto,
Portugal doing a comedy festival
as you do a October six Lisbon,
October 12th and 13th in Paris.
The 16th through the 20th is Oslo,
the 25th through the 29th. It was a
funny fucking people. I Love Oslo. Yeah,
it's great. Then they're really
like the fun fucking people.
I think it's my favorite
place in Scandinavia, a 25th
to the 29th, uh, Galway,
Ireland during that comedy festival.
And that's your potential.
If you could live anywhere in the world.
You told me that would live in Galway.
It's one of my favorite places in
the world. Uh, the 31st is Dublin.
November 1st is Belfast.
November 3rd, Berlin.
No,
this is
such a fucking interest and get you want
the most interesting people I've ever
met because how do you
not, you know, well,
I guess there are mouth breathing
more on set could travel this way and
[inaudible] reading. Sorry.
Now we're with fucking, uh,
and their worldview wouldn't fucking
change, but yours does. Thankfully.
I'm interrupting here. Continue.
What else? Uh, yeah, but you know,
I was trying to make that show where I
would be the Anthony Bourdain of comedy.
Um,
but whatever.
It'd be November 8th to the
11th at the Improv and Addison,
the November 12th through 18 Las Vegas.
Uh,
November 23rd through 27, Tokyo, Japan.
November 29 two rotate second.
I'm at the Improv in Pittsburgh.
I'm actually really excited
about and my wife, no, I've,
I've never been to Pittsburgh. So, um,
she used to travel with me everywhere and
now she's selective where she wants to
go. She wants to go to Pittsburgh
because we've never seen it.
I can tell you you to
get was a per Manny's.
You've got to get one of those sandwiches.
Yeah.
They're Italian section with all the,
uh, the Gaba, Google and all that shit.
Joe Barton, I converse, he
brought me through the, they,
they went and got it through.
Pittsburgh is one of the, uh,
great cities. This country has one
of the great, the old Basset America.
I've never performed one of the go,
go to a pirates game.
That view with the bridges.
It's, it's believable.
It's one of my favorite cities.
And when you come from the airport,
it's the greatest skyline you're going
to see because it's not like you see it
and it just keeps getting bigger
and bigger. You can't see it at all.
And then you drive through like
this fucking hill, this tunnel,
and then you come out and just
Boehm and says, panoramic elicits,
it's like all of these bridges does the
ballparks and everything to the left
Heinz field, uh, um, [inaudible]
pirates play. It's gonna say pac bell.
It's where the giants used to play.
I forgot what the fuck they call it.
They change them every year. And then, uh,
then the skyscrapers and though they just,
there's so much to do there.
The food is unbelievable. And the, uh,
you should be like [inaudible] you should
give out little stars for Comedians
that, uh, that work
ever. He used to do that.
What do Willie Stargell in 1979,
they called him pops.
Yeah. And they had those, there's
flat hats back then. Yep. The old,
he used to give out little stars to the
his teammates that he thought whenever
they did something. Great. All
right. So on the back of their hats,
they had all these stars. Do you remember
that? Yeah, vaguely Kent to call them.
It was like a really cool thing about the,
I saw him on one of the last time,
one of his last public
experience, uh, to Colby,
the side arm throwing no
appearances. Uh, I saw, uh, yeah,
but I saw Willie Stargell when he was old.
He was sick.
He could tell he was dying. And I was at
three rivers stadium and I was watching,
uh, the cubs first, the pirates and
Sammy Sosa was still out in right field.
You still look Cuban, you know,
before, if you've seen them now. No,
he's whiter than, you know. Yeah. Um,
there was some big story about him. Yeah,
I read recently. Yeah. He's, oh,
he's living in Dubai and he's, um,
he looks, yeah, he looks
like John Fox. Yep.
Now that's what Sammy Sosa looks
like. Okay. So, uh, yeah, what?
Pittsburgh?
November 29 to December 2nd,
I don't think the pirates will be playing.
Then we go to Heinz field and then, um,
December 10th to the 17th,
I'm in Israel doing this Israel tour.
Uh,
and then where haven't you remembered?
20th through the 22nd I'm at the Improv
in Orlando, Madagascar. What have we got?
I've never been Antartica Hulu.
I've never, the only con I have not,
the only content I have not
performed on is Africa in Antarctica.
Okay. Yeah. Dude, there's gotta be some
sort of expedition. So the, the, uh,
they're writing the comedy Igloo as
soon as that opens, when the, uh, yeah,
the 40th anniversary of the thing,
when they, when they all go down there,
you gotta a,
you gotta get that thing to going to
dial back the international travel next
year. Well, I want to,
how I do it is I, I, I'm,
I'm overdue to go, go to Australia and
I just sorta like as I get the new hour,
I just have it in my head were what hour
I did the last time I was there and I
always go and, uh, have a great time.
It's a lot weirder now that I have a kid.
So we set up this east level.
Australia to Sydney is one of
my favorite cities in the world.
All of those cities are great.
Brisbane, Melbourne, Perth. Yeah.
I came to Perth on Australia Day.
Fucking lunatics.
Who Do the El Camino was still popular,
so popular.
They love those fucking things. That a,
what's the, I forget what they call it.
It's a, I remember going to Australia
for the first time. I'm like,
what kind of cars?
Yet?
There's this, this automobile brand
called Holden and they still make those,
um,
yeah, cars, they're great. People
would get more fucking shit faced.
Drive it all around. I've
told you this shit. I saw,
I went to Bon Scott's grave and
somebody went to Bon Scott Scott Miller,
genuine draft bottle on there and I
wanted to remove it, but I was like, oh,
out of respect for the person that put
it there at bond probably would've drank
and he wouldn't give a fuck.
But, um, all right, let's, uh,
let's wrap this up here. So
I, I just got to say you,
you're one of my favorite people, one
of my favorite comedians. And, uh,
this has been one of the best podcasts
I've done as far as just like fascinating
fucking store. I mean, everything we
had life death here. What'd he say?
Heroic behavior here arisen.
Is that a word?
Heroism. Heroism. Ben?
I've been to a lot of countries too and it
just doesn't seem dumb luck, man. I, uh,
thanks for having meall a man. I, uh,
you're one of my favorite people to
hang out with every time you and I get
together and we just like hang out as
buddies. I always get material out of it.
You know,
I was telling you that story about a,
because I pronounced so
many words incorrectly,
I was just gonna say,
I can't imagine how many,
how many fucking countries I've been to.
And I still sound like
I've never left my block.
Oh mean, it's just so great. Um,
I was telling you about arguing with my
wife because she wants me to clean the
toilet and like, I don't, I
don't want to clean the toilet.
Right. And, um, you know,
a lot of thoughts go through my head
during the day, you know, watching movies,
sleep on the couch, call a friend,
cleaning the toilet is not one of them.
And we live in an apartment building.
So this is what it's like to argue
in an apartment building. Uh,
you make a valid point.
Now lower your voice,
because I don't want
everybody in my building,
no one my business and I'm in the
laundry room, folding clothes.
Some guy walks in there. I
know you, you're the dude
who don't clean the toilet.
So like I've been doing that.
I've just started doing that
like in the last two weeks.
And that comes from having a conversation
with you on my balcony smoking
cigarettes or cigars cause yeah,
you're one of those guys,
you're always spitting out material.
You realize that you've got to go,
don't waste that on me.
You better do that. Yeah.
I used to get an argument with me.
Neva was still living in an apartment.
We used to, uh, she didn't give a fuck
and she calls it, she's passionate.
So,
uh,
this is when she would occasionally throw
shit at me or punch me in the chest.
Um, this is back her younger wilder days.
And I remember, uh, we would get into,
and I would lose so many arguments because
she didn't give a fuck about volume.
And I would always be going like, all
right, do you have your bait to point?
You don't got to help the whole
fucking world know about it. I said,
they get loud.
She would just be like,
so then what's worse as
you start whispering,
so only your shit is coming out and all
the names like, oh my God, he's horrible.
He's not even arguing.
She's so fucking right.
That's where they get ya when they get
allowed on. Yeah. Well anyways, uh,
so greatly you finally came
on, finally. Got You on.
I think it's cause we also love
smoking cigars and telling stories.
So it's like why would we have a
podcast get in the way of that? Um, um,
I'm so glad you came on. You get
to, uh, promote your dates here.
So go see him in Mongolia. If not, you
can see him in Pittsburgh, Atlanta,
west Nyack, Orlando. Yes. You know,
I still, I still play everywhere,
all over the states.
And you have a great life.
I majored in like radio communication
where you got a great radio.
I wish somebody would give me a voice
over gigs. Huh? You know, this town is,
you've got to take it.
I'm running through the
grass on my tippy toes.
Um, definitely check him out.
He's going to be everywhere,
and if he's going to
travel that fucking far,
you can travel a little bit to go see
him. Uh, the great Tom Rhodes, everybody,
thank you so much for coming on. Here's
a little music for you. And then we get,
we have a bonus half hour of a greatest
hits from a Thursday afternoon podcasts
from earlier this year, years ago. I
don't know. I don't decide. All right.
Have a great weekend and
I'll talk to you on Monday.