[inaudible].
Hey, what's going on?
It's Bill Burr and It's time for the
Monday morning podcast for Monday,
February 15th, 2016 hello. How are you?
How was your world going on this Monday?
How was your Valentine's Day? Huh?
Did you get her something special?
Um, if you're a smart son of a bitch, um,
you're either not in a relationship or
you're not taking her out until, uh,
tonight or tomorrow or whatever.
Whenever the prices go back down again,
you know, and by the way,
if enough people start doing this in the
old fucking restaurants get wise to it
and they start making their prices higher,
Valentine's Day prices a few
days before, a few days after,
then fucking wait a week, wait
a month, do it a month earlier.
Um,
okay.
It's the biggest fucking rip
off probably of the year,
other than probably what's
going on to Bernie Sanders,
but I don't really understand. I guess
she has some super delt delegates,
you know? Oh,
fucking Hillary Clinton's got the super
and she already has the super delegate.
She already had a hundred. She
only needs a harder, the 20,
whatever the fuck that is. Jesus Christ.
It's like, it's like playing bridge,
trying to keep up what's
going on. I have no idea.
All I know is I liked that Bernie looks
like an old dog trying to eat a meal
when he's talking [inaudible] the fucking
job was going and the weird thing said
his fingers do I like it. I could
look at that for four years.
Um,
I got to admit that as much as I don't
like all the racist shit Trump is doing,
I do love some fucking jerk off
yelling at other politicians.
So that part has been
enjoyable. You're a liar.
There are that, there weren't any
mass weapons of mass destruction.
And they know it may sound like
he's quoting some podcasts.
Um,
I have no idea. At some point I'm
going to start paying attention.
There's gotta be some even
keeled so-and-so out there.
I have no fucking clue.
I have no clue.
And last week I said that I hate him
when people in the public eye talk about,
uh, politics. You know, that's not true.
I hate when they fucking tell me why
I should vote for somebody. Oh Shit.
Were you the guy from a interview
with the vampire? Oh yeah.
Who should I elect for
leader of the free world?
It was like when Tom Cruise was talking
about psychology. It's like, Oh yeah,
you pretended to be a shogun
warrior in a NASCAR champion.
Let me by by all means, let me listen
to you talk about a modern medicine.
Um,
as long as you preface it with
like, I'm a fucking moron.
I don't know what I'm talking
about, but I, here you go. You know?
But when you really start believing
it, that's when you get in trouble.
And maybe I believe it,
and maybe this is the way I'm
just sort of soft pedal on a team.
I'm playing the more on it as
I'm fucking feeding you my,
let's putting a little, a ringworm and
you're fucking ear or whatever people say
there with the fucking ear worm, right?
Some song you can't stand gets
in your fucking head, you know,
it's kind of a weird ones. What a
song you like gets in your head.
And then you don't mind. And then you
drive everybody nuts around you. Like, uh,
um, Steve Gorman from Steve Gorman sports
sent me this, this link to this, uh,
this country star that's been, um,
that's been struggling for a long,
long time. And he finally got a big break.
I believe he's a distant cousin
of Roy Clark. I'm not sure,
but his name is Wheeler Walker Jr and uh,
he sent me a clip that
I'll send you guys. Uh,
it's a great fucking song for Valentine's
Day if you are not in a relationship
for a man or a woman. And, uh,
the hook is just been stuck in my head
and I really want to sing it to you,
but it's gonna ruin it for you.
So go look up a wheeler Walker Jr.
Uh, well I guess the song kind of ruins.
It's called a fuck you. Yeah, bitch.
And it's really catchy and it's a,
I dunno, it's fits rich, kind of
poetic. I really think the, uh,
the chorus really sums up what you
feel when somebody breaks your heart.
So, um, you know, country music,
those country music stars,
they can do that t every once in awhile.
And it's nice to see someone
go to the left, you know,
those fucking country singers.
So those poor bastards for all
these fucking years, you know,
they've been abused
and drugs and you know,
going to clan meetings and beating
the shit out of their women.
But when they get on TV, they got to
do that family values thing. You know,
they got to [inaudible]. Yeah. I just
want to thank Jesus who I'm just,
I just feel blessed that y'all just,
you take me into your heart, you know,
hey y'all, he wants you
on some potato salad.
That stupid phony fucking southern thing
where if you're from up north the first
time you see it, your heart and melts.
When you hear that Twang and you just
think that dig the nicest fucking person.
Nobody can stick the
fucking knife in your back
like a fucking southerner
with that fucking k y'all.
How'd you hit all mts work?
And they downplay it. They play dumb,
but blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
And next thing you know,
you're laying in a fucking pig trough
about ready to get fucking eaten alive.
That's how it goes down. All right,
now guy from fucking 50
snatches and 40 smoking barrels,
that's where we got it from.
Okay. Not from that content.
You know, I don't know where the
fuck I'm talking about. Anyways,
I watch a brand new TV
show last night and uh,
I was really fucking disappointed,
you know, I fucking turned it on.
I needed a new shelf and I thought
it was going to be the one, you know,
I was like, this is gonna be it.
It's Valentine's Day night. Okay.
Me and the lovely Nia,
we're not going out.
I had a fucking one of those Tomahawk
steaks frozen in the freezer.
The fucking
phrase, right? The frosted
dead bitch all day.
I watch like 30 youtube
videos. His had dude sat,
do you know what you're going
to do? [inaudible] on Youtube.
And I watched like 50 of those fucking
things and I just sort of like,
I took a survey with temperature and
time flippage in all of that stuff.
And I went down the middle and, uh,
I got a little impatient
with the big green egg.
My temperature is a little
higher than I wanted,
so came out of the medium
rather than a medium rare,
but it was still fucking delish and I,
there was a new series at that that I
tried to get into last night and I put it
on and, uh, it looked
good. The acting was great,
but the dialogue just wasn't there.
And I tried to fucking fight it
out for the first 20 minutes.
And then I just looked over
at Nia. Nia did one of those.
Yeah. You know, big inhale in the
fucking eyes, like, yeah, this is a,
yeah. And then I was just like, well,
let's shut it up. She's like, no,
you know, we gotta at least watch
the pilot episode, you know,
which is how she ended up marrying me
because I believe 20 minutes into our
relationship, she was like, yeah,
but she fucking stuck it through night.
She kept panning for gold and she found
a little nugget and she stuck with me.
I didn't, I was just like,
fuck this. I'm out. And uh,
by 40 minutes into it, I was
imitating people in it and, uh,
the whole thing just went down
the shitter. So once again,
but you know what it, you know,
I'm finally gonna do I think I'm finally
gonna start watching game of Thrones
now that they're fucking five, 10,
15 fucking seasons into what I've been
trying to watch it for the longest time.
But, uh, Nia is just
not into it. You know,
she doesn't wanna see a bunch of white
people running around chasing dragons.
It's just not what she's into. And,
uh, I'm not really into dragons either,
but like, if you're going to cut
somebody's fucking head off, like, um,
you know, you got to do a lot to
lose me after that point. You know,
I dunno. Maybe I don't know
who the fuck knows. Maybe I,
I remember watching the first one and
there was some sort of spooky thing going
on and there was some little kid that
was supposed to watch a beheading and he
looked away and then his,
I forget what his dad did,
put him on the rack or
something. I don't remember. Um,
but then I don't,
I don't know what happened and that
just kept it kept going and you know,
it's like a train that was coming right.
And you could have ran and caught it,
but I, but you don't, you just stand
there and you watch it disappear.
And in that moment when that train
disappears and you realize you're late for
work in that fucking moment,
you question everything that
you're doing in your life.
Why didn't I run for that train? Because
I had this job that I don't like.
What am I doing in this
relationship? What happened to me?
What happened in the last six
years in my fucking life? Right?
It's a critical moment there where you
have to beat all those thoughts down,
bury them, and go back to
being the Zombie that you are.
Which brings me to the
walking dead now. I'm kidding.
Anyways, I want to thank everyone
who came out in Cheyenne, Wyoming.
I kept doing a southern accent the
entire time I was out there and I was
addressing it, but, uh, I don't know
what Wyoming people sound like. Um,
Cheyenne, Wyoming and Denver,
Colorado. I went out with, uh,
Dean del Ray and uh,
we had the great fucking
time to play this, um,
the Cheyenne civic center.
How cool does that sound?
And had all this amazing woodwork inside
of it that really look like one of
those log cabins that either an oil man
or a fucking Hollywood starlet goes and
buys. You know, like when people like it,
a huge amount of success pretending to
be other people at some point they have
to get out of La. Then they always
end up in like Wyoming or Montana.
It's fucking hilarious. And they buy
what looks like a log cabin, sort of.
It looks like a log cabin and like a
fucking resort all at the same time,
you know? And then they go out there
and they buy, they're a designer.
I'm a fucking cattle rancher wardrobe.
And then they do the
fucking interview, right.
With their big stupid cowboy
hat on and older, wiser,
so and so steps back to a evaluate
the last six years of a whirlwind,
whatever the fuck it is.
Right. You know what I mean?
And then they pretend that they could
live this little fucking life out there
before they go nuts after three days
and they call up a chief [inaudible] to
pick them up and take
them right back, you know,
and they end up back down to
chateau. Right. The Chateau Mall.
I'm doing blow in a
bungalow. That's what you do.
You find in a little
bit of balance. Um, oh,
speak in a fucking [inaudible]
before I go back on that shit.
Speaking of fucking
sick ass houses. I was,
I went on this Paul Newman kick, you
know, he's my favorite of all time.
You know, a lot of people go, Steve
McQueen. I like Steve McQueen,
but Paul Newman's my guy. Um,
he's my fella. I just, I dunno,
once I look into those blue eyes,
I just, I melt to say anything.
I believe it or are you a
pool shark or you a lawyer?
Do you play hockey? Um, I watched, um,
well I guess the first thing
I watched, I watched, uh,
the man with the golden arm, which d,
which Delray was telling
me to watch, which was a,
a movie about a Frank Sinatra
playing a heroin addict who,
uh, you know,
comes out of jail and he gets clean and
he plays the drums and he wants to get a
gig playing drums. And, uh, I
watched a great fucking movie.
There's some brutal,
brutal over acting. Um,
you got to you, I don't know. I would
definitely recommend seeing that.
So once I've finished that, you know,
it's like the next thing that was coming
up was, uh, somebody up there likes me,
which I had always heard
of when I was growing up.
And then once I saw it was Paul
Newman, I was like, all right,
I'm going to watch it.
And it was him playing out rocky
Graziano the rocky Graziano story.
And, um, and I literally forget
what I was talking. Oh that's right.
That's right. So it just got me on
this, this, this Paul Newman thing.
And you know what's funny
is, uh, this is thing,
actually Steve McQueen is in that
movie for fucking two seconds.
And uh, it's right as, uh, Graziano
was getting out of some fucking, uh,
you know, juvenile detention
home that he fucking escapes.
So He's going around the
neighborhood, tapping all these guys,
all this tough guy, friends on
the shoulders to be like, Hey,
I'm back in the neighborhood.
And all of them turn around like,
who the fuck is this guy? Right?
Cause cause at Tufts street kids,
so fucking, uh,
fucking Steve McQueen is shooting pool.
They rocky taps them on the shoulder.
And he fucking turns around with
a knife out, just two seconds.
And then he realizes it's
reads like it's rocky, a rocky,
and he does this stupid fucking thing
with his hand that I don't know who
fucking,
there's certain things in movies that
the first guy who plays that guy does.
And then it's this weird fucking thing
where every other actor after it starts
fucking doing it. And you
know, nobody ever did it,
who's actually the guy
that they're playing.
But then it's done enough in fucking
movies that the people who are actually
that guy, then they start fucking doing
it. And that's when it becomes a circle.
And you don't know who the fuck it
is. It's this fucking thing like a,
it's almost like say you were getting a
mannequin right and you want it to dry
off your nails and you do it just exactly
a rocky and he's doing this stupid
fucking thing with his
hand. Um, I don't know.
I'm going a really long way here to
tell you what I really want to tell you.
But like one of my favorite things is
to watch actors during that era playing
Tufts street kids. Um, like it's just,
it's fucking cringeworthy that
fucking movie that Marlon Brando did.
He's on the motorcycle with
the fuck was that one called?
It's not the wild bunch. That was a
cowboy movie. Rebel without a caught.
Now that's James Dean. I
can't remember, but just the,
the have to sit there
and watch that shit. Um,
how fucking brutal it
is. That west side story,
which I don't think I've ever seen.
I'm just going to throw that in
there cause I need three of them. Um,
I dunno. Whatever. So I
started watching that.
So then I finished that one and
then the next one that came on,
I can't even remember the name of
it. Fuck, hang on a second. Now.
I gotta I MDB fucking Paul Newman. Um,
he just has the bluest eyes. Paul Newman.
I am the fucking be filmography.
So anyways, I think it
was called not Hudson.
The long story was this
next movie comes on, right?
And in the beginning,
he's driving in this car and
he's clearly in Los Angeles,
which was one of my favorite fucking
things ever to just see old footage,
black and white or color of La.
And you just get to see like you can
usually tell by the Hollywood hills and
sometimes the highways and shit
kind of where they are. And um,
you'll see like train tracks and shit
that they ripped up those fucking cons or
you'll see 'em you know, you'll just
see how less populated as all right.
Here it is. Harper Harper's the movie,
the very beginning of the movie,
he goes into a house and uh,
Lauren because in there Lauren Bacall
who married a Humphrey Bogart bogey and
Bacall one of the great couples
in Hollywood history and uh,
you know, Humphrey Bogart,
somebody that Frank Sinatra
stole a lot of his swagger from.
They were also the first rat pack
Humphrey Bogart and all his fucking crew.
And uh, not only did, uh,
Sinatra steal a lot of
Humphrey Bogart swagger,
he actually ended up fucking Lauren Bacall
later on after Humphrey Bogart died,
which is really fucked up. But
anyways, I digress. So at Harper,
he pulls into this fucking house
that I could not believe and uh,
I actually looked it up and it
still exists. Look it up right now.
If you're at work, pretend
that you're doing, uh,
that you're doing some sort
of, I'm busy work. It's,
it's on one zero one
one north Beverly drive,
10 11 Beverley drive. And uh,
this fucking house, I think it's
just called the Beverly House,
it's in Beverly Hills,
probably has one of the sickest fucking
pools I've ever seen in my life.
It's like a three tiered thing.
The first two tiers I believe
are just considered a waterfall.
And first of all, it has like a
half mile driveway that he did.
He comes up around in what's Hilarious,
which will looks like the first
year they had the Porsche,
which at this point by
1965, when they shot,
it was just considered a piece of
shit. Who would know that years later,
some baby boomer would play
like fucking 900 grand for it.
So he's driving up one of, you know,
one of the fenders is like that fucking,
you know, what's that, that paint
that they primer and all that shit.
So he pulls up in his fucking house.
You've got to see the backyard of it.
So actually I looked the fucking thing up,
I found out where it was and the next
time I fly a helicopter I'm going to
fucking fly over the house and
check it out. Um, it's actually a,
just a little bit north of
the Beverly Hills Hotel,
but you got to check this
fucking thing out. Um,
one of the great things about living in
Los Angeles, a lot of people, you know,
always shit on living in
la, but one of the main,
I think la arguably has some
of the most amazing homes,
um, in the country, just for the
simple fact that for whatever reason,
I don't know if it's the weather out here
or what, they haven't been torn down.
Um, so many of them, um, you know,
other places that I've been to,
but they have like craftsman's houses
out here and then they have all the, the,
the Spanish, the Mediterranean
style ones they have, uh,
they got, it's just incredible houses.
So you've got to check this one out.
This house is actually kind of
ugly, you know, when you pull up,
they shut the godfather part two
there, but I'm part one there.
This is actually the house
where, uh, the horses head scene,
um, spoiler alert if you,
if you're one of the two people
have never seen that fucking movie,
they shot that scene in there and JFK and
his wife Jackie had their honeymoon in
this fucking house and I just saw it
recently. The last time it's sold,
it's sold for $135 million.
And all I'm doing looking at it after
by in my old ass house that was made in
1923 all I see is fucking 50,000 square
foot of galvanized pipe and cloth wiring
that they're going to have to somehow
fucking read through where all sections of
it. You know, there's a little
bit of copper pipe here,
a little bit of wiring that
was done correctly. Um,
but anyways,
that's another cool thing about these
fucking houses out there is that they've
been around so long and if they're
in a desirable area in Hollywood,
like the stories of like the people
that live there, like how cool. I mean,
that's $135 million house. Obviously
it'd be a fucking amazing house.
But how fucking amazing would be
to have that house and be like,
he didn't see a movie.
And you're watching Paul Newman walking
across your fucking terrace that you now
want. I don't know. I think that
Shit's cool as hell. But, um,
you know why you're at it.
You can check out a lot of those and
also just look up famous Hollywood homes.
Um, I told you there's a house about,
okay.
Not even like, I dunno,
maybe a 15 minute drive away
from me in, in, in Los Angeles,
15 minutes is a big fucking
deal. Sometimes just, you know,
15 blocks, it can go one way or another.
It can literally go like to,
I'm going to get stabbed to how the
fuck can you ever afford to live in hi.
How many people did you steal from to
get this fucking sky's got a moat around
his house. Let's, let's wait. La
Is, it's like really like patchwork.
So like a 15 minute drive
away from where I live. Um,
my neighbor told me there's a
house that went up for sale.
I think I told this story before and um,
it's an old ass house. It's
pre-prohibition. And Basically, uh,
when prohibition came around, this
House had a pool and then it had a,
a Cabana and in the companion, this guy,
he built a bar during prohibition and he
had illegal booze or I don't know if he
was making beer in the bathtub, whatever
the fuck he was doing. But he used to,
he used to have all these famous people
come over there and they would just
booze it up. And, um, he,
anybody who came over there
and drank that was famous,
he would have them carve their
names into the bar. And, uh,
evidently according to my neighbor
who went and looked at the house,
even though he couldn't afford
it, he just wanted to see the bar.
He went and looked at it. And it's one
of those things, if you buy the house,
it's that bars obviously protected by
the historical society is some shit.
But you go in there and everyone from
like Louis Armstrong to like fucking
Humphrey Bogart have, have carved their
names into that fucking bar. So, um,
whatever, that's some sort of nerdy
Los Angeles. How shit. But um,
yeah, definitely. Uh,
rather than work today,
just go on Google earth and just look
at some of those fucking houses. Um,
or just Google, like famous Hollywood
homes too. This homes where like,
you know, when I was watching that, you
know, somebody up there likes me. Uh,
right. I should really know the
name of the fucking actress,
the one who plays Paul Newman's love
interest obviously is an absolute,
uh, fucking knockout. And
I had never heard of her.
So the fact that I never heard
of her, I'm like, ah, fuck. I,
I've looked up enough of
those, those old movies,
like I got this creepy thing that I always
look people up like an older person.
Like, all right, that
person's definitely dead.
Let's see how long that
they lived for. Right.
Or you try to find a cast
where like everybody's dead,
you know, which is a very
difficult thing to, to, so anyways,
so I started looking up, you know, the
people that were, you know, this woman,
I hope I say her name right. It's
p, I. E. R. Is it Pierre? Pete Pier?
I don't know. And Jelly. I have no idea.
I looked her up and I was
immediately going like,
she probably died of pills cause back
then like, I dunno, like getting,
giving people pills,
like it seems back then every guy either
died of a heart attack in his fifties
and sixties,
or he died at cancer and like 90%
of the women died of an accidental,
like barbiturate overdose because
back then, like, you know,
the woman came in and she had
some emotional issues, you know,
the doctors are like, for God's
sakes, get all to yourself.
And they would just give
her some pills to relax her.
It was like in that movie airplane where
they will just slapping you and giving
you a backhand and shit. So, um,
she was just gorgeous, amazing actress.
And then of course I looked
it up and um, you know,
she died accidentally. Um,
some people say suicide,
some people say accidentally
at 39 years of age.
And then I look it up and
sure enough, the place was,
she fucking overdosed is still there.
That's another one of those
things. It's a really fucking you,
I would see the coolest,
creepy, all these fucking
houses that people died in.
There's another actor in there. This
guy's Sal Mineo or whatever. Um,
I swear to God, who's a dead ringer
for Ralph Maggio. He's in it.
And uh, he ended it. He got
fucking stabbed to death
in like the mid Seventies.
It's fucking on real man. Like a lot of
people, a lot of stars back in the day.
They didn't make it. They
didn't fucking write it out.
It seemed like just crazy
shit happen to them.
And I guess what I'm saying is that
a lot of these houses still exist.
And if you're sort of, um, I guess
I'm becoming morbid in my older ages,
I realize, you know, you know what
I mean? You're your mortality.
You start looking how long this person
live? How do they live? How did they die?
Fuck. Is that going to happen to me? You
know, that type of ship. I don't know.
All right, let's, let's read the street.
A little fucking advertising
here for the week. Oh, JJ,
would you look at their MVMT watches
movement watches this company,
Ladies and gentlemen, was started
by two college dropouts. Uh,
with the idea to make quality watches
that don't break the Goddamn Bank.
They started just 95
bucks. They're sold online.
So they cut out all the
bullshit retail markup, uh,
movement watches sent some over
here and I gotta tell you, man,
you throw one on your wrist and nobody
has any idea that it's not a really
expensive watch unless they sell watches
or they come over and they touch it and
they realize it's a lot lighter. Um,
quality materials and sleek designs.
The perfect everyday watch. It's easy
order online today for free shipping,
free returns and a 24 month warranty. Um,
joined the movement and saying no to
big brand retail markups and say yes to
great styles. Checkout MVMT,
watches.com/burr and you'll get
15% off your entire purchase.
That's MV t, watches.com/burr.
I'm all right. The next one, dollar
shave club. Everybody, you know,
lots of players will be sporting playoff
beards. Now that the postseasons here,
they got update this. Um,
leave that to the pros kickoff the a
year right kick off your year the right
way. Sorry with a fresh blade shave.
That's why me and millions of others
have joined the dollar Shave Club have
joined dollar shave club.com. You don't
realize about me reading out loud.
My fucking mouth is like of sentence
and a half where my fucking eyes are.
Slow it down.
Bill Dollar Shave Club knows the key
to getting an amazing shave is simple.
One.
Use a fresh dollar shave called blade
to use that Dr Covey's easy shit.
That's it. Dot.
Dollar Shave Club delivers amazing razors
right to my door for a third of the
price of those greedy mega corporations.
That means listeners who switched now
can afford the luxury of shaving with a
fresh blade anytime and
save hundreds this year.
And when you combine the fresh blade
with their Dr KVCC shaved butter,
it just glides. It's unimaginably
smooth. I'm telling you,
if you're not, it's not your average
shave foam. It won't dry out your skin.
The all natural ingredients.
Leave your skin feeling soft,
smooth and moisturized after
every shaved shape. Sorry,
take it from me. I'll take it
from somebody else, but whatever.
Don't take it. Do whatever
the fuck you want to do.
Use a fresh dollar shave
club blade with duck you.
Kathy's easy shave butter if you want
it. The most gentle shave imaginable.
Dollar Shave club.com/bar
today. That's dollar shave
club.com/burr. Um Oh by the way,
I'm doing my first solo flight
through a bravo airspace.
So if you're still on the map, if
you're still on the Google Earth math,
I love looking at this shit,
right? And you go on to a,
you go on t. Um, what do you do?
Where you clicking on the
fucking globe there? All right,
now go over to the ocean. Okay,
follow Santa Monica Boulevard
over to the ocean. All right,
right where it says the 10.
Now go down a little bit and you'll
see something that kind of looks like a
tree, but it's made out of water.
That's Marina del Ray. All right.
Now if you're flying south,
that's where Bravo airspace begins along
the coastline. And when you're there,
you have to be at 150 feet
or below at or below one 50.
And then you transition
the bravo airspace.
If you go a little bit further
south, you'll see lax. All right.
And that's to the south of
it is to five, right in two,
five left and to the north there's
two five, right? Two five left,
those two runways. And those are
where the big boys are taken off.
So you fly underneath those guys
or ladies and you stay at or below,
um, 150 feet until you get two.
And then you got to zoom in a,
the Manhattan Beach Pier and, uh,
which is almost a beam
as they say, the, uh,
comedy and magic club
down in Hermosa beach. Um,
so you want to be, you want
to be right down there,
150 fucking goddamn feet.
Um, now wait a minute,
wouldn't it be Hermosa?
Yeah, no, I'm sorry.
Hermosa beach pier is where the comedy
clubs that, but the Manhattan Beach Pier,
that's where you want to be. You got
us from, from there to Marina del Ray,
you're going to be at or below 150 feet.
So if you come out here and
you're on the beach as a tourist,
you see these helicopters
flying by really low. Uh,
they're not buzzing the beach looking
at your or whatever they are. Uh,
they are transitioning the bravo
airspace. So I'm going to be doing that.
Um, I don't know on one day,
but that's my big goal this week
with the helicopter thing there. Uh,
but anyways, let's get back to the,
uh, skip back to the podcast here. Um,
where is it? What else did
I want to talk about? Oh,
how about those Boston
Bruins. Now I know we lost,
I know we lost to a, the Redwings. I
didn't get to see the, uh, the game yet.
I have a taped, I'm a game
behind. I watched, um,
the f I'm actually game and two thirds
behind. I watched the first quarter of a,
of us beating the wild and Brad Marshawn
scored again his 12th goal in 12 games.
And I actually looked up the ticket and
I saw that he scored his 13th fucking
goal. And, uh, in 13 games,
the guy's on fire. And, uh,
I saw his goal in the, um,
the Minnesota wild game,
um, a shorthanded goal, just
a beautiful pass and uh,
and it was fucking awesome. And he's
gonna have like guys, he's on his way.
He's gonna have like 40
goals his fucking year. Um,
and I got to say just the Bruins and
the Celtics this year, both of them,
I was just going to be like, this is,
you know, after all the moves they made,
you know,
I just kind of felt that neither one was
going to be that competitive and it was
going to be tough to watch.
And this year, and, uh, I am,
I think they're both over achieved
and it's been fun to watch them,
although for some reason my fucking
recorder stopped taping the Celtics Games.
I was really getting into it
watching Isaiah Thomas and, um,
Crowder, uh, Jae Crowder and, uh,
who's the jam band guy that
finally learned his fucking name?
They're a Kelly Olynyk. Right.
I was enjoying watching it and our young
coach there who I still don't know his
fucking name cause I always taped the
games and they talked to them and I just
fast forward through all of that
shit. And then they just show him,
I think his name is Stan Steven,
something with an s Shawn, I dunno,
but he looks like a baby man.
The guy's like fucking 15 years younger
than me and he's coaching the Celtics.
He's doing a great job. And evidently we
got a couple of number one draft picks.
We're in a great fucking position. Um,
I missed the all star weekend stuff.
I saw some of the dunking
stuff and Kevin Hart,
did anybody see Kevin Hardy or he
went up against some other NBA guy.
I can tell, I don't watch the fucking NBA.
He went up against a
professional basketball player
and a three point contest.
Um, should I give you a spoiler
alert or should I do that?
The clickbait and the results will
surprise you and it gives a fuck.
He actually beat the guy.
And what I loved about it,
besides being a big fan of, uh,
his stuff and everything was when he went
to start shooting his three pointers,
they were playing disrespectful music
underneath them. They were playing this,
I'm always in this like,
oh, it's adorable. Or is it,
it's silly that this little man is going
to come out here and try and beat one
of our professional athletes and a,
okay.
They were right through the first two
racks and then he fucking close strong.
And I think he might've beat him on
the last ball. You got to see it, Matt.
I mean, it's a, it's pretty fucking
impressive. If I remember correctly,
in long time ago, he was telling
me that before he was a comedian,
he went to a a, you know,
he went to a basketball camp that had a
young unknown Coby Bryan and that type
of shit. So, um, but still, man, you
know, it was a long fucking time ago.
Since then,
he's gone all the way to selling out the
eagles football stadium doing standup
comedy. You'd think that his basketball
game would drop off a little bit,
that maybe he'd be a
little rusty at the y.
Forget about being able to beat a fucking
NBA player in a three point contest.
It was pretty, pretty God damn impressive.
Um, so anyways, let me get back.
Jesus Christ, Wyoming, Cheyenne,
Wyoming. So I go there and um, you know,
this was the last of
the 50 that I had to do.
So of course I'm reading all up on Wyoming
and all that type of stuff and I see
that Yellowstone park
is right in the north
northwest corner of it.
And I'm like, Oh fuck.
I gotta go up there and go do a gig in
the middle of nowhere at some point.
And uh, maybe I'll do a nice run through
Montana, Idaho and all that shit.
The Dakotas, um, you know,
I get into all that fucking nerdy
shit, right? So we do the Gig,
we have a great time. It takes some
pictures with some people afterwards.
And when I was on stage,
I was saying, hey,
where should we go tonight if I want
to go out and have a pot? Right.
So of course everybody's yelling out
everything at the same time and I can't
hear anything. So I'm like
one at a time, one at a time.
And then just in the back, this
guy yells out the gray door,
said to go to the green door, and then
the whole crowd just goes, ah, like,
you know, don't go there.
And I was like, I was like,
I didn't even need you guys to say that.
The green door just sounds like some
creepy serial killer place. So I go,
I'm not fucking going there.
So then somebody said,
I forget the fuck it was called
the Cadillac lounge or something.
I took a picture of it. So, um,
I, uh,
I decide, you know, all right,
that's where the fuck we'll go.
We'll go over to this thing.
I'm actually looking at the picture
right now on my, uh, uh, my phone here.
Um,
yeah,
come on. Come on. Where is
it? Where is it? There it is.
The Cadillac Cadillac ranch. Sorry.
So we go in there, you know, there's a
big American flag lit up on the side.
I'm like, all right, here we go.
Let's fucking go in there and
see what this place is about.
And we went in there and
I gotta tell you, man,
it was the most diverse group of fucking
people I've ever seen in my life.
And I think for the simple fact,
there was no other place to go.
So there was like a group
of bikers. There was,
there was soldiers. Um,
there was like ranchers,
there was a group of lesbians and then
it was just filler people that you
couldn't really tell what the fuck
they were. They was older, younger,
the whole fucking thing. So we're in,
they're like, wow man, this is fucking,
this is nuts. And then it had a
real like cowboy kind of feel to it.
Yet there was like a fucking DJ play
in like modern music. It was this,
it was fucked.
So we're in there and dean for whatever
fucking reason is just pointing at Shit
and people going, look at that
fucking guy. Look at this shit,
look at his fucking bar. And
I'm sitting there going, Dean,
stop pointing at Shit. Stop
Pointing Shit. You know?
And Dean's been sober for like 20
fucking years, so he's got no excuse.
He just kept pointing at Shit.
Um, and then finally, you know,
I had a, you know,
I was talking to a couple of the people
in there talking to this guy that was in
the middle of taking a
two year welding class,
which of course was really interesting
to me. I was talking to about that shit.
I was talking to some other people. And,
uh, then at one point somebody said,
hey, you wanna a whiskey. So like, um,
my thing now when I go on the road
and I drink, I have a beer and a,
and a and a whiskey or a scotch, and then
that's it. I call it a fucking night.
And it's been working out great
for me, you know what I mean?
So I have a nice little taste,
but then I don't get hammered and then
I'm fine the next morning and I kind of
work out and shit. Right. So, uh, this
guy offers, you know, he comes over, hey,
you know, I've got gotta buy a drink.
I said, well, I'm just getting a beer.
And I said, all right, well, you know,
I was going to get a whiskey too.
He goes, what do you want? He goes,
we got a local fucking Wyoming
whiskey. I was like, all right,
when in Cheyenne, let's
fucking do it right?
So he gets me this fucking shot and
he brings it over and it looked,
it was almost like see-through.
Now I don't know if they did
whiskey and water or what,
but I fucking took a sip of it
and they had no bite or anything.
I was just looking at him like, dude,
what the fuck is his? He goes, he goes,
well, it hasn't been aged at
all. I've got to tell you, dude,
it was the worst whiskey I've ever had
in my apology to the person who bought me
the shot. I couldn't finish
it. I looked, I said, Dina,
go look at this fucking thing.
And he was just like, yeah, dude,
that looks like piss. So, um,
and then at that point I wasn't looking,
but dean was saying that the bikers
people were mean mugging everybody and he
goes to, let's get the fuck outta here.
So we get outta there. And, uh, oh,
as we were driving over there, I
noticed that there was a drive,
there was a liquor store with a
drive through. So I was like, Oh God,
I gotta get a picture of that. So I
get pulled over, I get a picture of it.
And then I'm just like,
dude, I gotta do it.
I gotta go to a drive through liquor
store. So I fucking pull up. We actually,
I posted video of this and I just wanted
to get one beer and the guy goes, well,
I can give you like the 24 ounce.
So I got like a Budweiser and
I'll repost the video on the,
uh, the, the Monday morning
podcast, Twitter page. So I went up,
I ordered a fucking beer.
And what was really cool was it had the
old fucking remember the old air hoses
when you would pull up at
the, the, uh, the gas station.
And it would ring the bell like, Dang,
Dang is your, is your car pulled in?
It was so fucking cool. And um,
okay,
well he was sitting there and then this
dude just sort of walked into the place
or whatever. And as we drive out,
there's an Arby's across the street,
which I never fucking eat, you
know, fucking fast food roasts,
roast beef. I mean, I like to
think I'm a courageous person,
but that's just a little, that's, that
gets a little too shady for me. Right.
I'd rather eat the pink
slime. Um, so anyways, uh,
del Rey's going like, hey man, it
goes, let's hit the Arby's. I'm hungry.
So I go, all right, so we go into the
Arby's, right? He ordered some shit.
Then I ordered like some chicken sliders,
which I shouldn't have fucking got.
They were fucking disgusting.
It was like eating the heel of some
chicks fucking boot boot, you know,
just the way they were shaped like
clogs. They were just fucking gross. So,
um,
okay.
We go around to the drive through and
this is right across from the drive
through liquor store. And I look
across the street and I read the sign.
And what does it say?
It says the green door.
So the drive through liquor store is part
of this shady fucking teddy bar called
the green door.
That urban legend said that there was a
one legged stripper and now the younger
me would have been like, I got
to go in and go see that shit.
The older me goes like, oh my God,
that's somebody's daughter. So, um,
so technically I kinda did go to the green
door. I didn't, I didn't go in there.
I just fucking pulled up
or whatever. So I'll, I'll,
I'll post some pictures of that shit. Um,
let me see if I actually took him. So,
and then the next day we got up right.
And we wanted to go to some
local place to get a, uh,
to get breakfast. And we
went to this local place.
And I don't know if the
regular chef was out of town,
but I ordered eggs over easy
and I cut into them. Dude,
they was so under cooked,
like it came out clear,
like the white part of the egg
was still clear. Like, you know,
when those people drink like
egg whites, it was like that.
And so dean's eggs were
the same way and uh,
I just never sent food back, so I just
stirred him in with the fucking Hash.
I mean,
they should've just served the eggs in
a glass like fucking rocky Balboa and I
just suck it down. And I noticed
a woman diagonally from me,
she sent her eggs back to, and
then in the end when I went to, uh,
I went to pay, she was just like, how
was it? And when I said it was great,
I kinda stumbled on when
it was great. It was great.
And then she goes and that she me
looked up, she goes, is everything okay?
Is Everything okay? So I'm
just guessing that the,
the normal chef was out of town, so I'm
not gonna out. This place is being a,
a as being something bad. But, uh,
it was pretty rough. It was one of the
worst breakfasts I've ever had. But, uh,
when we, when we came back down,
um, we'd drive down to Denver.
I Lu feel like a little kid right now,
like I'm just telling you every
moment of this fucking this tour.
But a dean's a big motorcycle
guy, he's been Ryan for 30 years,
so they had this huge fucking Harley
Davidson dealership right on the 25 as we
would come down. So we
stopped in and I didn't know,
but Harley has a new bike that's
just right out of my childhood.
It's called the 72. And it's
got the big spoked front wheel.
It's got the handle bars. It's like
fucking Arthur fonds and rallies bike,
which obviously was fucking, uh, from
the s the, you know, the 50s or whatever.
But um,
I haven't written in like a year
and a half and uh, I dunno man,
I think I gotta ride that bike. I think
I'm going to rent it just one day.
There's a park up around where I'm at co
rented on like a Sunday and just go up
there in the morning time and just
fucking ride around and bring it back.
I'm too much of a pussy to ride
all the time cause a, you know,
I got too much to fucking lose and um,
okay.
Oh my God.
They had one in this black and
gold metal flake was fucking gone.
It's just perfect man. As
much as I loved the road king,
like every one to be motorcycle rider
who watched a couple episodes of a
whatever that fucking show was.
What was that fucking show there
that everybody watched about it?
About the bikes. Um,
okay.
You know like every fucking want to be
bad ass who doesn't have a tattoo and
it's not a motorcycle guy.
Like del Ray took a picture of me on
the fucking 70 to 72 and I just started
laughing. I was like, how much,
how much am I not a motorcycle guy?
Like do you realize if what a fucking
nerd you have to look like to sit on a
Harley and still look like a fucking
still look like somebody you could bully.
I look like every fucking just
white dude having a midlife crisis.
They're like, you know who watched
it? What does that fucking show?
What is the fucking show that was all
about the motorcycles that everybody
watched. I never got
into it. Um, goddammit,
it's the perfect reference for
this shit. But, um, anyways,
I might have to rent one coming up, uh,
might go ride a dirt
bike and get my fucking,
my skills back up to the ridiculously
low level that they were.
I just go to a local park out here and
I just drive this loop around and around
and around. It's actually
good because, uh,
there's a lot of downshifts
in that shit. A lot of turns.
You gotta look your way through all
this shit that I learned in the safety
course and everything.
But like I told you guys the one time
when I rode a motorcycle down sunset all
the way out to the beach, just
like I wanted to just thinking, ah,
this is gonna feel, you know,
freedom man America. Right.
And I was going to see all this
shit, dude, I didn't see shit.
I was fucking terrified. There
was just too many fucking people.
And I'm, you know, we
went later than I to go,
I rode with Dean and dean had done
spots, so he didn't get up to like 10,
so we didn't get on the road till like 11.
And I wanted to go at like seven in the
fucking morning when there was nobody on
the road and really just be able to
relax a little bit and not have somebody
right behind me. Um,
and I just remember getting off the bike
and I was like shaking and I was just
like, I had to have that fucking get
out of your ego moment and just be like,
Bill, this isn't in you. You
don't have this in your blood.
You're not a motorcycle fucking guy. He
just not, so don't be that shit head.
And, uh, I immediately sold the bike or
got rid of it, whatever the fuck I did.
I don't even remember. But, um, I don't
know. I think every once in a while, if,
you know, I smoke a couple cigars
a month, I got that under control.
Every once in a while I run a motorcycle
and I know everybody's going to fucking
be like, oh, [inaudible] Jewish, cause
you're going to be fucking rusty r right.
Taking all the fun out of
everything. Um, all right. Oh also,
uh, this week, um,
I got back into like drinking juices and
shit and there was this fucking allergy
shit, which was disgusting
when I drank it.
But I felt amazing afterwards
and I'm trying to, uh,
you know, like Dean said, you know,
it's a good addiction to have.
Like you get addicted to
shit. I realized that.
And if you're addicted to like
working out and good stuff,
that's obviously a much
better thing for you. So I'm,
I try to get back into that
type of stuff. But anyways, um,
this, uh, this past weekend, on
Saturday night when I got back,
I went to a, uh,
this music music cares event. And, um,
every year they honor somebody
and whoever they're honoring,
everybody comes out and I'm just,
does this person's music.
So say they wandering ACDC,
a bunch of famous fucking musicians that
are into ACDC would come out and do all
their songs and switch them up
and do different versions of them.
So is Lionel Richie,
right? Oh, what a feeling,
right? So I go to this fucking thing and
it was unreal. It was
like Lenny Kravis usher,
who I couldn't believe how small
he was. He fucking crushed it. Um,
John Legend, Stevie wonder. All right,
all these monsters and then Stevie wonder,
and I knew Dave Grohl was
going to go on and I'm,
I kind of fuck is Dave
Grohl gonna follow us?
Is he going to play drums and saying,
is he going to do the come out
with his blue guitar and sing?
And he just went up and just
sang a song. That was it.
He told this fucking
story about, you know,
when he broke his leg or he fell off
the stage where he broke his leg.
He was talking about all the
outpouring from the fans and all that.
And then one day he just got this
giant fucking basket of muffins.
The biggest basket, I guess
ever. This fucking giant thing.
And there was no note or anything on,
and as he's telling this story that
the band sorta just playing, you know,
some music underneath it and he's
telling this story and he's got people
laughing, but they're listening and all
that shit. And then like two days later,
I guess he got a, he got a,
a a call from his manager
who said, yeah, uh,
Lionel Richie,
Lionel Richie just called up to see
if you got the fucking giant basket of
muffins. And then he just
goes, uh, so I just, you know,
I forget how we fucking ended
the story. I'm butchering it now,
right as he ends the store and you
realize that it was Lionel Richie,
they kick into that his song, you
are a Dave Grohl just crushed it,
you know, let's argue you are this
something and you are the rain.
And he just was up there
singing it, fucking crushed.
It went on after Stevie
wonder and crushed it.
Um, so I, I got to, I got to do
that. You know, it was funny was, uh,
I, I went down there and, um,
you know, I'm not a suit guy,
but you had to wear like a shirt and
tie dude. And I swear to God, like,
I dunno, just like me when
I was on the motorcycle,
when I had on that suit and tie,
dude, I don't know what I was.
Sometimes I look all right. But, uh,
the thing about suits is if you, if you,
you got to buy them, like they
go on a style really quick.
And this one was like
three, four years old.
I just gotten a dry clean to some
show the last time I wore it.
And I put this fucking thing on. And,
uh, I was talking to Nia, I was like,
and I just kept going. I look like an
asshole right there. I like, she's like,
no, you look fine. I guy. Yeah, I
don't think so. I look like an asshole.
So the whole fucking night, um, you know,
anytime I would walk into the bathroom,
you know, it was a long fucking,
I was like a four hour fucking
thing, you know. And, uh,
anytime I would go in there
and I would wash my hands,
I would just sit there and I would
look at myself in the mirror.
I just kept laughing. What a fucking
jerk off I look like. Uh, I don't know.
It wasn't a good scene, you
know, I don't like hate myself.
It's not a good place for me to be say,
I think it's time to retire
that suit. Um, all right,
let's get into some of the, uh, some of
the fucking questions here for the week.
Um, ah, here we go. A judge Scalia,
bill listener from Virginia here,
the death of Judge Scalia brought out
some jokes on social media and a lot of
people took the angle that
they were happy that he died.
Now I'm assuming this is somebody on
the supreme court because I don't pay
attention to shit,
but I did see some stuff about this is
the first time the supreme court won't be
conservative. He goes,
what's your position on making
jokes about being happy people died.
Thanks for, for, for that.
Laughs. Thank you. Me.
Thank you. Thanks for the laughs. Um,
my position on making
joke about why, yeah,
I think you got a B. Uh,
I think you gotta be like a dictator
for people to do shit like that. Yeah.
I mean PR I wouldn't say don't do
it cause there's always a joke.
I mean, some day when I die, there's
going to be a joke. I mean, I'm,
I know if I'm hovering around as a
ghost, I'm going to laugh about it.
What the fuck do I care? I'm a ghost at
that point. Right. I didn't go to hell.
All right. I'm floating around. I
could deal with this. Uh, but yeah,
I don't do that. Um, well look,
if you just make a joke joke, that's fine,
but if you're doing it because you didn't
share like their political views, uh,
yeah, I'm not into doing that type
of shit. Like, you know, some,
some shit head. I'm going
to start doing this.
Like this shit had tweeted the week,
somebody sent me a text today telling me
that I needed to distance myself. Bill,
just to let you know, you need to
distance yourself from so and so.
Um,
and then sent me a link and this is
somebody that had been friends with for 20
fucking years.
And then I see this link and it has to
do with being a vegetarian or eating meat
and the name of the video is
so and so is an ignorant moron,
which right there I love,
like that's your angle,
like to get someone to listen to
your opinion. Um, right there.
I just look at it like this is just,
this is just somebody trying
to make a name for themselves,
trashing somebody that, that has
made a name for themselves, you know,
with some over the top
title. First of all,
I love is an ignorant moron.
Like that's like redundant,
you know, he's a stupid, not smart person.
I'm like,
I need to distance myself from say from
someone who's been a great friend for 20
years because of their
dietary decisions, you know,
because they talk about food and nutrition
in a way that's a truth that they
believe in all of this, you
know, like, and then anyone what,
you're a fucking genius, you know?
And it's just, you know, I don't know.
I don't know why people do shit like
that. So that kind of ties into,
and I would never, obviously,
you know, that's, I dunno,
I would never tweet
it. Somebody like that.
You need to distance yourself from this
person because I don't agree with their
workout regimen. And the same
thing with like that, like if I,
I wouldn't be happy that somebody died
because I didn't like their political
views, you know what I mean?
I always have that in my head.
They had somebody's dad, somebody's
husband or some shit, you know, whatever.
He was a gay judge. That's
somebody's boyfriend. Right.
I had a fucking dumb I, yeah, I don't
do shit like that, but if somebody does,
you know, I'm not the comedy
fucking police. Um, all right,
summer home,
Phil. My wife wants to own a
home by a lake in New Hampshire.
That's fucking awesome.
I'm trying to convince her that it's
cheaper to just rent a sick house every
summer for a couple of weeks instead of
paying 15 grand a year in taxes on top
of the mortgage. Help me sort out this
business. Please go fuck yourself. Well,
what I would say is, you know,
you can rent out your house,
your summerhouse, you know,
this is what I would do.
Okay. I would,
I would buy that house on the lake and
then I would just rent the whole fucking
thing out. And then
whenever I wanted to go,
I would rent some other
place. You know what I mean?
And this is how I'm weird because I
wouldn't want to go into a place that I
owned knowing that
everybody fucked in my bed.
I would rather go to a place knowing
that a bunch of people fucked in somebody
else's bed.
It makes no sense. What you should do
is buy it and then rent it out. I mean,
buying property is always great.
However, if you're having a rough time,
like I'm a big believer in no
paying down your first house,
um,
you should really pay that thing down and
get it under control before you go and
get a summer house. And I do
know that in relationships,
when it comes to money,
there's usually one person understands
it and the other person doesn't
understand it and they
want everything. Yesterday,
and you might be a little
more conservative, which
is what you sound like. So,
um, I w you know, I would just sit
down and just say, look, first of all,
you're in a great position because it
doesn't sound like she can just go out and
pull the trigger herself. So I just say,
listen, I definitely want to do that,
but we need to, we need to pay down
this house a little bit or, you know,
if we can't afford it,
let's buy it and then we'll rent the
thing out all the weekends that we're not
going to be there. Um, I
think that's definitely to,
it's definitely a smart way to do
it. But, uh, I would just sit down,
okay.
And write out all the points that you
want to make and then draw a smiley face.
This is what I do when I'm being a smart
person because I know how short a fuse
I have. And, uh, I
write all this shit out,
everything that I want to
say and all that stuff.
And then I draw a smiley face
reminding me to not lose my temper.
Reminding me that other
people are entitled to have
different opinions and uh,
you know, and not to be a cunt.
I didn't do that a couple of days ago
and ended up having a big stupid fight
over the, the, the
bathroom sink. You know,
I'd gone on the road and it did start,
started to clog up and I didn't
have time to fucking fix it,
but you know, we can't drain
up. So I figured, you know,
my wife would fucking handle it and I
come home to brush my teeth and I turn it
on and within fucking two seconds
it's already filling up as a puddle.
It's completely backed up
and you know,
it's usual shit, usual shit in a
relationship. You say to somebody else,
did you notice? No. You had noticed
and in your head you're like,
how the fuck did you not notice this shit?
But what I learned in that argument is
I have to understand that this shit that
she's looking at me at
looking at me at about like,
how the fuck do you not
notice it? And it's just,
cause I'm just not wired like that.
And that's why you get married.
Hopefully you're a yin and a Yang. I
finally set him right. I didn't say it,
Yang and Yang. I said, [inaudible] why I,
and I think this the first time publicly
I've ever said it right. Um, yeah,
they're going to be good at this
shit that you're not good at. And um,
actually had a great
day with Nia yesterday.
Like I didn't do shit for once and
we just hung out all day and um,
you know, we watched some movies and shit.
You made a little bit of food
and I always forget that,
that every once in a while you guys,
you gotta hang out with each other rather
than just being roommates to remind
yourself like, oh yeah, that's right.
We actually really love each other.
I forgot about that shit and I don't,
the amount of times I've had to fucking
learn that, you know, she get married,
you really start doing the
math. Like, dude, fuck do shit.
I don't need anything. I will
literally give her everything.
I will fucking just give you fucking
everything and I will walk out with the
shirt on my fucking back and
I will start all over again.
Like I think that that's
the way to fucking do it and
just walk down the street
after it like Johnny
fucking apple seed. And um,
because I really think you just get
into having all of this fucking stuff,
but if you just let go of all
of it, then you don't have it.
I think getting divorced could
be a really light feeling.
This is how far I went over and argument
over a clogged up sink before he came
to my census. I was walking down
the street with the, with the stick,
with the Bandana and a peanut
butter and jelly sandwich in it.
Then I was just finally like,
what am I doing? You know,
stop being a fucking idiot.
All right, let's get to some advertising
here. All right, me undies, everybody.
Oh Gee, I got to sing this quietly because
we have company over here right now.
Podo poop. Poop me and eat me
undies. No more sweaty nuts.
Badu do.
Do me on these BMDS keep a dry with
your butts when that doesn't make sense.
Ah, I said nuts. I was thinking bus
would rhyme. I, you know what I, I've,
I've got to retire this fucking
song and he's a new fucking,
I need some new bits on this goddamn
thing. All right. Mandy's all right.
This year don't be predictable and show
up at your Valentine's Day dinner with
some last minute box of chocolate or
bouquet of roses. Bouquet bouquet.
I don't want to say that are going to
die in a week anyways. Uh, give the gift.
Everyone's talking about me.
Young Ds me on days
taking care of your taint.
Poodoo to do [inaudible] me on these.
Your balls will say your a
saint. Uh, show your special day.
That fucking guy up there
either. Can you shake
[inaudible] is dry over.
Show your special someone just how
much she care with the present.
You're both love. A gift that
looks great and feels great.
Something that says you deserve the
best. I have to tell you right now, you,
if you give somebody underwear for
a gift, you better be fucking them.
Are they better be your kid? Cause
other than that, it's fucking weird. Uh,
you know, give you kid underwear.
You know, you're, there you go.
Jesus Christ straighten up and fly. Right.
You know,
I have a little respect for yourself,
you know, and then if you, you know,
you're with the person intimately,
you can give it to them, you know,
there's no fucking way actually
is a joke. You can do that.
You know,
you know,
I was actually thinking the other day
when I went to buy my wife a Valentine's
Day card, you know,
I was looking for the blank ones cause I
hate the fucking Valentine's Day cards.
You know,
they're either over the top gross or
they're just fucking like too distant.
You know, it's very hard to find that one.
That's the nice balance of I love
you, but let's not be gross. Um,
so I was looking for the blank ones and
I came to the sympathy cards and, uh,
I just was thinking like, you know what,
I really want to stand up with Joe de
Rosa again and then send him a sympathy
card afterwards. You know,
telling them I hope he feels better and
everything and just basically, right.
Joe, I saw your set last night. I know
you're going through a rough time.
Okay.
I don't Dunno. It was funny to me.
Anyways, let's get back to the,
he's saying treat yourself and your
boo to a matching pair of me on these.
The most world's most comfortable
underwear. Uh, this company,
this underwear is
comfrey is it gets me on.
These are made of micro
modal, modal fabric,
meaning they're twice as soft as
cotton and they don't just feel great.
They look great to me.
Undies comes with tons of cool prints
and styles and new designs come out every
month. You won't want to
Miss Miss February's limited
edition designs from the
legendary Keith Herring herring.
This retro design is inspired by love
making it the perfect Valentine's Day
gift. Well, it's over.
Grab yourself a pair and celebrate the
holiday sporting matching under it.
Where? With your sweetheart,
how do you do it?
You go to [inaudible] dot com slash burr
now to get 20% off your first order,
um, that's 20% off at [inaudible]
dot com slash burn all right,
stamps.com sometimes it feels
like there aren't enough hours.
Sometimes it feels like there's not
enough hours in the day. You know what?
You're just flustered even when
you're working past the nine to five.
So if you're still making time
consuming trips to the post office,
you need a better way.
You stamps.com with stamps.com you can
get the postage you need the instance you
need it.
Buy and print official US postage for
any letter or package right from your
computer or in printer. You'll
save money with stamps.com too.
It's just a fraction of the cost of
one of those expensive postage meters.
Plus you'll get special postage discounts.
You can't even get at the post office.
I use stamps.com to send out all my
posters. I'm a if I can figure out
how to do it. So can you right now,
sign up to stamps.com and use my last
name [inaudible] for this special offer,
four week trial plus $110 bonus offer
that includes occludes postage and a
digital scale. Go to stamps.com before
you do anything else, click on the
microphone@thetopofthehomepageandtypeinburburthatstamps.com
and to
burn.
As always, if you want to
contribute to this podcast,
I'm next time you're going to buy
something on amazon.com just go to my a my
website bill bird.com. Click on the
podcast page and there's a link to Amazon.
All it does is take you to Amazon.
It doesn't cost you any more money.
I just get credit for driving traffic
to the site. All right, trash man.
Everybody a Billie bubbles,
barely bubbles in the rain.
Um, I went to high school with
a guy who picks up my trash.
I get along with them and I always
wave and sometimes if he's not rushing,
I'll have a short conversation with them.
Last week I saw my neighbor
yell at him. He wasn't a,
he wasn't a jerk back, but
he wasn't a dick either.
What? He wasn't a jerk back, but he
wasn't a dick either. Later on that day,
my neighbor came over and asked me if
I'd make a statement about the issue that
he harassed her. I saw the whole
thing go down. He didn't harass her.
She yelled at him for coming a day late
during a week when a holiday pushed
everything back a day in terms of
sanitation pickup. Uh, what a comment.
She said that even without my statement,
she's going to press charges
and file a complaint.
I'm going to call the town or police
and let them know what's going on.
I'm so livid that she would ruin
this guy's life. He's a great dude.
Thoughts on how he should handle
this? Should I report her for lying?
APP's a fucking lately and I would take
time off from work to testify that she's
Elian Whore App's a fucking Luli.
Who the fuck yells at a trash man?
The service that they're providing. Fuck
her. Fuck her. Do you know something?
I would 100% do it and I would,
I would even fucking tell her that
you're going to do it at some point.
Not Not in the beginning because
you don't want to. We can his case,
but I would do it without a doubt. And
when the whole fucking thing goes away,
I would let her know that you did that
and I would let her know what a small
person you think she is and that she's
disgusting and to stay away from you and
anybody else that you love
because she subhuman there.
I was at the limit dilemma, Dear Bill. Oh,
what a fucking whore. He came in
day late and then you harassed me.
Gee, you know what? You know
what she I, you know what?
I bet she does for a living.
She sounds like a blogger,
always playing the fucking victim and
always going down and just trying to get
somebody in trouble and try and fuck
over their, their ability, you know,
to earn a living. What a
fucking Twat. Alright, dear.
Would you rather have to live
in an air balloon for a month?
Never having set down or would you
rather live in a submarine? Never
breathing the surface for a whole month.
Both scare the shit out
of me for a whole month,
but I think I choose to submarine
seems more natural. Yeah.
And there's also a bathroom. I wouldn't
want to have to shit on people.
And P why would obviously wait
until I was over a, a rural area.
Okay.
Yeah. Plus you, you'd be inside, you'd
have a bed p when you're in the summary,
you have a blanket, you know,
you get to be down there
with all the fellow of, Hey,
I'm no man. I mean,
I think it would be cool to fucking look
out the window and see all the fucking,
uh, the sea life and all that shit. I
would go fucking nuts down there. But,
um, I don't know.
Fucking up there in an air
balloon gets cold or hot.
You're really dealing with the fucking
elements when you're up there and starts
fucking raining. Um,
yeah, I dunno. I W I would be a, I
would get over that really quickly,
but I think being in a sub, you know,
you're down there, you could flake cards,
you could fucking break each other's
balls or whatever. I Dunno. Yeah,
I definitely would take out
a much rather do a sub. Um,
and if I had to die the way,
I'd rather die in a sub.
I'd rather have it just fucking, you
know, if you're going to die in the sub,
it's going to be quick.
You know, it's just over,
right? Yeah. I don't know. Yeah.
I don't know if sometimes maybe it might
not be quick. They close that door.
Yeah. Those are two terrifying
things I got to go with you.
Gotta go with you on that. Um,
yeah.
All right. Dilemma Billy bully. Uh,
if you had to choose which holiday to
get canceled and never celebrate again,
would you choose Valentine's
Day of President's Day?
Who deserves more recognition,
your girl for doing what you do all year
without a holiday. That's hilarious.
Yeah. We don't get a holiday.
Um, no, maybe I read that wrong.
Or presidents who may or may not be
horrible people who hurt the country.
I canceled president's Day because
I'd rather keep the one that involved
chocolate being around. Oh,
that's a good reason for it. Um,
if I had to get rid of one,
I don't think anybody really
celebrates president's Day.
I don't really consider it a day
off. It's kind of like flag day,
you know what I mean?
Or a buttermilk pancakes day isn't
there one of those fucking days to um,
Jesus, do you want me to cancel a holiday?
Uh, I wouldn't cancel Valentine's
Day just cause women like it so much.
Believe it or not, I am a consequent.
I'm not that fucking bad. So I,
I'd keep that one. Yeah. You
know what? Fuck President's Day.
All those guys have
bought and sold anyways.
You've seen it with Hillary
Clinton and Bernie Sanders.
You've seen how the Democrats had just
going to pick her because going to play
ball,
they are all tied into
the fucking, the fucking,
I dunno what you want to call it. Did she?
She that Bernie Sanders
is too fucking radical.
He's going to switch shit up too much
and then they're not going to work with
them. Even if Bernie Sanders
gets fucking elected,
they're not gonna work with them.
They're going to show their fucking
true colors. They're a bunch of that.
Just a bunch of, they're all bought
and paid for it. They thought, well,
how the fuck do that? Clinton's got $3
million to throw their kid a wedding.
You know what I mean? Let
me have fucking break.
Because you went out and you gave
speeches to all the people that fucking
financed your campaign and then you
hooked him up and look the other fucking
way. I swear to God, I swear to God.
Do you want to how the
fucking pharmaceutical
companies and the people who
fucked up the food supplier able
to do it and there's nothing,
there's nothing behind it. It's cause
they fucking paid everybody off.
I swear to God. All right,
I'm on my stuff on my I,
this is why I always vote for that
third party guy. And everybody goes, Oh,
you throw it away. You fucking vote.
How is throwing away my fucking vote?
Voting for somebody who's a decent fucking
human being? I sweat it. Got People,
they don't want to try to do what's
right. They just want to win.
They want to be like,
oh my God. One again.
See that every time I sit there and I
trashed people for fucking given their
public opinion, then look and make
the gummy. I do the exact same thing.
I am what's known as a hypocrite.
The HIPAA count. Um, all right,
that's the a, the podcast
for this week. Um,
I wanna thank everybody that
came out. Cheyenne, Wyoming.
I know there was last second,
but uh, I had a great time.
Had a great time in your,
uh, your state capitol. Um,
Joe was just a really, really cool fucking
town and I had a great time in the,
uh, Cadillac ranch there.
That sounds, I swear to God,
like the fucking bunny ranch. It
sounds like a fucking whorehouse,
but it wasn't. Um,
it was cool talking to the people there
and thank you to everybody, you know,
that bought me a beer and a shot and
all that shit. Thank everybody Denver,
by the way, which was just
a fucking insane show.
Um, that was another special one. Just
cause I've done so many fucking gigs.
Yeah. Colorado in the middle of nowhere.
I always bring up Arapaho community
college. I'll never forget that.
Nooner where they had me standing in
an area where three hallways met right
before class ended. That
was a fucking nightmare.
Next to a popcorn machine and five
people scattered out about 40 chairs,
empty chairs. There's, um, anyways,
that's the podcast for this week. Uh,
I'm going to try to watch some Celtics
and get caught up on the Bruins games,
um, and keep drinking my juice.
All right. Go Fuck Yourself.
I'll talk to you later on this week.