Hey, what's going on? It's Bill Burn and
It's time for the Thursday afternoon.
Just before Friday.
Monday morning podcast and
Ahhh,
just checking in.
Just checking in on you,
seeing how you're doing. How are
you today? Huh? Are you upset?
Thursday afternoon, Thursday
night football. What happened?
What happened during the song this time
that made people upset and decided that
they were going to get all up in arms
about their corner of the fucking world.
Yeah.
Unbelievable. I'm so fucking,
I'm going to be the guy talking.
I'm so fucking listening to people making
that thing about what they want it to
be about. It's like, that's not
what the initial protest was about.
If you would like to
discuss police brutality,
I'm more than willing to listen to what,
I don't want to hear
your fucking Soliloquy,
you know all those people who are like,
you know, want to be the reverend,
like I don't even care. I don't even
he, yeah, of course you don't care.
It doesn't fuck what they're talking about
doesn't affect you. So then about you.
Okay. Who gives a fuck? It's one
moment at the beginning of the game,
commenting on something that people
are trying to fix. That's all.
That's all my biggest complaint about
tonight's game between the bears and the
fucking packets is they stopped the game
because there's potential of lightning
God for fucking bid.
Somebody gets electrocuted.
It's unbelievable.
It's unbelievable how important human
being still consider other human beings.
I just don't it. It really isn't
about that. It's like folk,
do you think the NFL gives a
fuck about you? They don't.
They don't give a shit about you.
They don't want you to get electrocuted
because then you can't go out and buy
another jersey or another
ticket or NFL Sunday ticket.
That's what they care about and somehow
they're going to get blamed, right?
Because everybody in the crowd,
he's going to be like, well,
they should've known that
God was gonna do that.
You should have known what the weather
was gonna be. You know, there's no more,
Hey, fuck, oh, you went
outside. You know what?
South side lightning and you
went outside and God dammit,
lightening found you and that's
your own dumb luck. Guess what?
You're going to have your own Wikipedia
page. Now you don't have one now.
Nobody knows who the fuck you are,
but you get struck by lightening.
Tommy's going to find you on Wikipedia.
Maybe you won't get your own page.
You might be on a page that's just a list
of people struck by lightening in 2017
or in or in whatever the fuck
would call in this decade.
It has to be an extraordinary
circumstance.
When you get struck by lightening
for you to your own Wikipedia page,
you have to get struck by lightning
and then something else happens.
You struck by lightning,
you catch on fire and you run into
a paper machine factory. All right?
With a bunch of children there who's
make a wish was that they could go to a
make a fucking paper machine factory.
Then you run in there and and then it all
goes up and all those little kids died.
Then now they need to have to share it
with the kids and it's a tough thing.
It's hard to get struck by lightening
and get your own Wikipedia page,
you know? You know, it's funny
as if that actually happened.
You got struck by lightning, you had a
nice afro going, you catches on fire,
you run into a paper Marshay factory.
There was a bunch of make a wish kids
in there and then they all fucking died.
The funniest fucking thing about all that
is how much shit your relatives would
get. You know what I mean?
Saying, Oh, you know that guy guy,
he's one of those Wilson kids.
Yeah.
You know his fucking brother gets struck
by lightening instead of just die in
laying there burning the
fucking asshole content.
He is runs into a paper machine factory
and kills a bunch of kids that were
already dying anyways.
You know
that everybody treats them like shit.
Like you can keep your wits about
you when your head's on fire.
The bottom line is, is uh, I
dunno what happened to football.
I don't ever remember it being
stopped because of weather used to be,
they'd play in all kinds of weather.
Right.
And you had the ice bowl
up there in green bay.
You had that game when all the locust to
send it down on the Kansas city chiefs
when they played the
fucking, uh, New York titans.
I'm just making up shit at this point.
I don't know what happened to the game,
but now any time is going to
be a little bit of crosswind.
What if it blows somebody's sunglasses
off and goes into somebody's eye?
I mean, Jesus Christ, those, those
people that, that's Wisconsin,
the amount of layers of clothes and
blubber you have to go through after the
lightning strikes them to even like,
you know,
rattle a few fillings loose of the
average person in Wisconsin. These are,
these are, these are wholesome
people up there. Okay?
They get that ll bean catalog and
to those people that is formal,
where do you understand that? You know,
when you get married in Wisconsin,
you can actually show up, you
know, you know, like everybody,
you're going to wear
tails with your Tuxedo.
They ask him if they're going
to wear those fucking, you
know, those rubber pants.
It was fucking rude.
The suspenders when you go trout fishing,
somebody was saying there was some
fucking guy, he walked out into the ocean.
I don't know why the fuck he was in a
river, some sort of water, a watery area,
and he walked in there and this wave came
in and washed into his fucking pants.
They'll come tipped him over and he
couldn't get up because the combination of
the weight of his ass and his legs, those
rubber pants and all the water in it,
it just fucking a, he drowned.
I don't know if that's true,
if that sounds like something
a fucking old lady with Tyson,
all this fucking old lady when
I was a kid, you know backwards.
You know parents didn't watch their kids
like parenting back in the day you woke
up, you gave him fucking, you
know the multicolored cereal.
He opened the door and they went outside
and they just met other kids and with
your kid brains,
you figured out what you were going to
do that day where there was this old lady
who lived around the corner and she still
always tell us all these crazy fucking
stories. She had terrible candy to where
you'd still show up. I don't know why,
and she's be one time now. I mean, she
may and Jeremy on when you get your guy,
any, hey tried to stomp his foot down
on the brakes to stop showing it,
wouldn't go through it and stop shining.
She said that his leg went all
the way up into his body and his,
and it was like six inches shorter
in front of the rest of his life.
He walked around and he couldn't get him,
you know,
and I used to come home and I'd repeat
the stories to my mother. Right.
I'd be like, mom, he [inaudible]. Yeah.
You know, one tiny, I was a guy, he,
his leg went up into his body and she,
one day she finally,
I think it was listened to me,
she just looked at me and she goes,
who told you that? Now it's like, oh,
the lady down the street. She goes,
tell listen to her. She's crazy. I
don't know why my mother talk like that.
I needed to do a different voice.
She doesn't smoke.
I don't know what the
fuck I'm talking about,
but what would you expect from
someone who forgot it was Thursday.
That's how awesome my life is.
I forgot it was Thursday.
Now sometimes he can forget it's Thursday
because your life is fucking terrible,
right? You Rhonda, right?
You're on a fucking bender or you're,
you're like,
I don't know what you're fucking,
um,
I dunno. You're fucking,
you're a political prisoner.
You forget what date is your in Shawshank.
All right.
Sometimes you fight them off.
Sometimes you don't.
You're marking off the days he
got Rita Hayworth on the wall.
You don't know what fucking data's not.
Even if you're Andy do frain and you're
good with numbers, you lose track.
And the only other people
that lose track of that,
of people who work for themselves, which
I don't, I work for Netflix now, I guess.
I don't know. I just, you know, after
awhile you just said what fucking day is?
I don't know. Another day.
Live in the dream day. Um,
anyways, okay. Football Sundays
coming up. [inaudible] boom.
I'm going to start doing my
gambling pick of the week,
my gambling pick of the week.
All right.
I'm guaranteeing you that
if you gamble on this game,
money is going to change hands either
out of your pocket or into your pocket or
it might be a push.
I'm guaranteeing that he called me
up at one 800 freckles fat that,
that um,
the giants getting three and Tampa Bay,
that giants,
the Oh and three giants.
Everybody looking at him like that washed
up for getting that Eli Manning has
won two super bowls against the
reigning super bowl champions.
They beat bill Belicheck two times. Um,
guys got two rings, you know, he's got,
he's got two rings, he's got no respect
and he's got half an offensive line,
but I think this week to get in three,
they were underdogs.
They did find fine against Philly
last week that came back late.
But who gives a shit? They still scored
27 points. I didn't really pay attention.
Right?
And then they lost on a 61 fucking year,
right?
Some fucking dude from nine oh
two one o came walking in. Right.
They just fucking kicked the goddamn
thing, like the end of a Hollywood movie.
All right.
Ain't going to happen. They're going to
go down to Tampa. Okay. First of all,
nobody respects the Tampa Bay Buccaneers.
You know why?
Because they have a giant pirates of
the Caribbean ship inside their stadium.
I don't know what they're trying to do.
I don't understand how
the Oakland Raiders, okay.
Who have like a pirate on the side of
their helmet are able to achieve the
baddest, baddest fucking uniform in all
the sports. As far as I'm concerned.
They, when they moved to Vegas and
they have the white home jerseys,
they better go back to the silver numbers.
[inaudible] my name is it Billy?
Fat tits. Alright. Tampa Bay Buccaneers,
I don't understand is what is
a buccaneer. Exactly. Okay,
let's look this up.
Because judging by their colors,
I feel like it's more like the
musical theater sort of pirate.
It's much more,
let's just go out and have an adventure
rather than raping and pillaging.
Okay.
What do we got here? All right, and
then fucking Buccaneers lost last week.
34 to 17 so they're coming off a big loss.
That's always a concern.
What the fuck is a buccaneer? Buccaneer.
All right. Buccaneers were a kind.
Yeah.
Okay.
A privater or pirate.
What's a privater private tier?
Yeah,
a private tier was a private person
also, they keep to themselves. Well,
that's not really good
in a team sport is it?
Or ship that engaged in maritime warfare.
Okay.
Under a commission of war.
All right.
Well it did it very officially.
Okay.
Particular to the Caribbean Sea, yet
pirates of the Caribbean. That's right.
Originally the name applied
to the landless hunters of
wild boars and cattle and
they largely uninhabited areas of tor
to Gha and Hispaniola the meat caught.
They smoked over a slow fire where
the fire, what are we talking about?
Something about jerk me or Jerky.
Why should we fear these people?
You know what?
This is just a whole bunch of reading
that I don't want to do it when caught by
anti pirate English authorities.
Seven. Alright. You know,
what I needed to do was to do
between a pirate in a buccaneer. Oh,
what's the difference?
What's the difference
between a or aid in Oakland?
Read and a buccaneer? I
would say about 30 pounds,
judge. I've been, well,
I've never been to the Tampa stadium
going to be there in a few weeks, so yeah.
Okay.
Yeah.
Buccaneer verse rate or
what's The difference?
This is why you've got
to love the Internet.
I'm not saying they have a right answer,
but they always have an answer.
What's the difference?
A buccaneer is a synonym
of Raider as nouns.
The difference between a buccaneer in
a raider is that buccaneer is an is
nautical.
Any of a group of Semen Jews?
No.
See men who cruised on their own account,
on the Spanish main and in the
Pacific in the 17th century,
similar to pirates, but did not
pray on ships of their own nation.
While the reader is one who gauges,
engages in a raid,
colon semi-colon, a plunderer. Well,
what the fuck is a raid and what is a
plunderer? See this. This is what you do.
You have fucking
plunderer.
The plunderer is a fictional character,
so they leave.
They don't even exist that
I don't want this fucking,
that was actually a superhero.
Daredevil fought the plunderer.
Plunderer come on, man. Come
on. Give me something. Give
me something here. You cons.
Plunder.
Wikipedia is just such a one trick pony.
Sometimes they just keep guiding
you back to the same fucking
yeah.
T to plunder the public treasury to
take wrongfully as pillars. Yeah. Okay.
All right. You know, I don't even
give a shit anymore. How about that?
All they know is whoever fucking drew
the Raiders logo did not draw the
Buccaneers logo.
That first one at least and less.
He was a raider fan.
It was like these for these fucking
guys saying that Kinda like us.
We already took this name.
Let me see. Tampa Bay.
Yeah.
Fucking ears.
It's be like a porno logo.
Yeah.
What do we got here that's sort of a
pirate? [inaudible] they kinda ripped off.
They're trying to rip off the old fucking
Oh,
trying to rip off the Raiders here. Well,
let's see. They're fucking original.
Their original logo was just like,
I think it was Tom Selleck.
I don't know what it was. No, not really.
Tom Selleck sort of winking at you.
Yeah.
Tiniest of knives in his fucking mouth.
There's the one I remember right there.
The cream sickle.
Yeah.
Yeah. I don't know what that was.
He looked like a three musketeer.
You look like a good guy.
I think that that was the problem.
Was there a point to any of that? I
don't think there was. Um, anyways,
this is one of the,
this is one of the greatest times
of the year in United States sports.
And who's kidding? Our sports are
the best if you don't believe it.
If you don't believe our athletes
are the best, I'm telling you,
you need to watch the Olympics.
Okay.
All of our white athletes
dominating all of those games.
Well, maybe we do. We do well in the
Winter Olympics that we know we don't,
we lose to the fucking Canadians.
We beat the Canadians in like the juniors.
We always beat them because anybody like
our age is already made it up to the
fucking Nhl, you know? But you got
to give those Canadian something
hockey. They got you. They that
you gotta let them have hockey.
Even though the Russians are kind
of slowly taken away from them.
A lot of European players,
the game is slowly being taken away from
their sticky served fingers up there.
Okay. We all understand this. All right.
And they're going to hang on for
dear fucking life. Cause if Canada,
God forbid ever was to lose hockey,
what would they be left with?
Huh?
What would they be left with
that shuffleboard on ice that they play?
What do they call it?
Do they call that? Uh, what
the fuck is it? New slide.
He just let that fucker go right.
That big
sort of a wheel, isn't it? It's a rim.
Kinda looks like a rim off of a jeep that
they turned into a giant hockey puck.
That's what it says. An obese hockey puck.
What the fuck do you call it? Curling.
I don't know why they call it curly.
There's no hooking.
There's nothing like that, you
know, fucking, I have no idea. Um,
anyways,
you have playoff baseball's coming up.
Who is going to start hockey's going to
start college and pro football's going.
The CFL is getting close to the Grey Cup.
All right.
I mean just what else could you want?
Okay.
The Formula One in Moto GP, I'm going to
be wrapping up here in the next 40 days.
Mrs. Exciting fucking times. Let's check
out the baseball standing. Shall We?
Everybody. Who Do, we got here,
those Boston red sox
hanging on for dear life,
three games ahead of the New York,
the New York Yankees.
Um,
Tampa Bay devil rays,
soon to be Montreal Expos.
Spoiler alert. Um, I've been
tell you guys that story.
I must have told this story.
The time I went to the
Montreal Expos game by myself.
I was doing this Gig in upstate
New York and um, you know,
I was trying to go to all the fucking
stadiums. So I was like, all right, well,
you know, let's see this Montreal.
Yeah, they got a fucking games.
They had a game the next day.
So I went up, I did this kick,
I think I did the Lake Ontario playhouse.
I know I've told this story before,
but what made me,
I've got a few listeners maybe from
somebody from Chechnya is listening,
maybe somebody from Romania.
Um,
anyways,
so there was a game the next day.
So I ended up trying to cross the border
into Canada. Uh, this is pre nine 11,
by the way,
in a very weird spot by myself.
So I get stopped at the border and the guy
tells you, guy asked me, he's like, oh,
it's well, what are you doing there,
fellow Canadian dude? And I said,
I'm going to an expos game now. The Expos
had lost probably about, I don't know,
like 120 games at that point
during the season. And it goes off,
you're meeting some friends up there.
And I was like, nope, go on by myself.
And he was like, Oh hey Paul,
would you mind are pulling
over right there for a second.
So he asked me pull over and like two
more of these fucking guys come out and
they start ripping apart my car and
they send me inside and I'm like,
what the Pfizer,
some sort of random drug search.
And I'm just sitting there watching
them and they're ripping it apart and
ripping her apart. And then if fun
suddenly fucking dawns on me like,
what kind of a fucking loser? I
mean, I was like two hours away.
I was gonna drive two hours out of my
way to go up there to go to a Montreal
expos game by myself.
This guy could not fathom
than any human being.
Even one that looked like me would have
that much of a pathetic moment in their
life. He was convinced I was some
sort of drug mule or whatever.
I guess drug mules was that
when you have it up your ass,
but they never checked my ass.
They just checked the fucking car.
So it suddenly dawned on me that they
thought there was no way that I was that
pathetic. But I knew the real
answer was yes, I was that pathetic.
So it just struck me as funny and I
started laughing and I couldn't stop.
And I remember the cop looking over at
me and he saw me laughing and I think he
thought I was laughing. Like he
couldn't find the drugs, so they,
they were out there for
like a fucking half hour.
And then once I knew that
they thought I had drugs,
then I was just kind
of acting like a dick.
And I had a shitty and grin on
my face as I came walking up,
smiling and they will, the guy was
getting mad, like I was smiling,
like he didn't find it or whatever.
And uh,
then I went up there,
I went up there and this fucking
French [inaudible] acted like he didn't
understand what I said when I asked him
to take my picture because I didn't have
anybody to take my picture
because I was by myself.
And one of those disposable cameras,
it just,
the story just keeps getting worse
and worse. Um, when I called him,
a conti laughed and walked
away. Um, so anyways,
I was sitting out in
like fucking left field
and uh,
it was such an old stadium. I
don't know when, just under budget,
I think it's socialism up there,
you know,
and they just don't step on the
poor the way we do up here. Um,
out in the outfield. Your seat only had
one arm rest. That's what I remember.
Even on the left or on the right,
I can't remember what,
and I was sitting out there and
all the fans not paying attention
to the game, the fans that
showed up and they would just
sing in Ole, Ole, Ole, Ole,
that soccer fucking song. And
I was watching, I swear to God,
I saw this guy and I'm like,
I watched this guy steal home plate
and I'm way out in left field.
So I jumped up and I was like,
yeah,
when he stole home plate and nobody
else jumped up with me and it was really
quiet in the stadium. So
then I was like, oh fuck.
Maybe that was something else.
Maybe, I don't know. Maybe
he's a pass ball. Maybe a,
it was a Bach.
I didn't know what,
so I fucking sat back down and felt
stupid cause everyone's looking at me.
And then later on that night I was back
at the fucking hotel and I was watching
TSN. That's their ESPN up there.
And they're like, they're like, oh,
it's something you don't see everyday.
And they showed a guy stealing home
plate and I was like, you know,
that's my expo story. Not Riveting,
but not boring. All right.
Then you've got the Cleveland
Indians crushing it, crushing it.
One 22 winters of 22 in a row. Um, I
feel like they've won like maybe what?
Like, like 25 of their
last 30, not 27. Um,
they're in. And who else?
The Houston Astros. Ah,
wow. Well look who's finally
in the American league.
Finally put on your big boy pants
and you get stopped playing.
Hit and run and get yourself nice and
roid it up and try to hit it over the
fence. Huh? Um,
the Washington senators in first place,
I didn't fucking know that the
cubs looking to repeat the Dodgers.
I went to the dodger game last night.
They went fucking 10 to nothing. Uh,
had a great time.
We sat right down on the field,
like terrifyingly close.
Like I tried to make sure I watched
every God damn pitch and uh, you know,
I'm not boozing. So, you know,
that's also scary if you're booze
and you know, you're all relaxed,
your heads like fucking foam
rubber, you know what I mean? It's,
you just bounces off at one app and
whether, you know, you don't know,
you order another fucking
round. Right. But, um,
I'm stone sober sitting there, so
actually realize what the fucking happens.
I was staying right on it.
What a great stadium.
That is just a great stay in great
fans out there. You know what I mean?
As long as you don't wear a different
colored Jersey and you don't sit on the
bleachers, you know what I mean? As
long as you not with your kids. Um,
it's a great stadium. It's a great, as
long as you're rooting for the Dodgers.
It's a wonderful time. And I went
there, had a pretty good time.
I had a great time, I should say.
I meant to say I ate pretty good.
Eight pretty good. I got a little off my
dial diet when I was in fucking Toronto,
so I think my calf is healed up.
We're going to try to hit the elliptical
tomorrow. Hey, guess what? All freckles,
all freckles is playing.
Um,
the Monte Carlo tomorrow in Las Vegas.
it's going to be great.
Bunch of people from Memphis
for family are coming out on,
a bunch of writers are
going to be at the show.
So I'm hoping I'm going to have a
good one. I'm very to play that one.
That's the one from um,
uh, not river Phoenix.
What was the name of that fucking movie?
Ocean's 13 or 1215,
whatever the fuck it was called where
everybody's still all those good looking.
He stood out there,
right? Looking at the uh,
okay.
The uh, what was it though? The
phones. The phone shoot enough.
You guys saw them over? Yeah, that's
stick casino playing that one.
I've always wanted to play that one.
And we said it was the cleanest
and classiest looking one,
at least from the outside. You walk in
and the things they all look the same.
But anyway, so let's, let's get
onto the, um, it's going onto the a,
what do we got here? A little
bit of a advertising here.
Oh, draft kings, everybody.
Draft Kings. Okay. And I
said, I see, what did I say?
Giants getting three giants getting
three on three. Ready? Alright.
Draft Kings football season has begun.
What are your political prisoners?
You don't realize that,
but it's not too late to get closer to
the game you love with draft kings one
week fantasy football.
This draft kings is hosting a 100,000.
Sorry, this is capitals. I screamed.
Capitals. It takes give to Abba capital.
I'm going to scream it.
Dollar contest.
That is totally right to enter
when draft with draft kings,
there are many ways to play,
but only one way to,
we choose between public contest butts
with big cash prizes or private contests
where you can compete against
a group of your friends.
No saying mean stuff in here.
Let's make this a safe place.
Draft kings also has a beginner in cat.
Oh,
you're a big boy.
Did generate and casual contest.
Will you play against people of a similar
skill level and you'll never burn up
the waiver wire trying to replace injured
players because you get to pick a new
team every God damn week.
That's the beauty of one
week fantasy at draftkings.
She'll get to graph kings.com now,
now and use Promo Code Bar to play
in draft kings free contest with a
$100,000
dollars in prizes this Sunday.
That's Promo Code Burr to compete for
your share of a 100,000 a hundred thousand
dollars in prizes.
The contest is totally free to enter.
Why wouldn't you try draft
kings that game inside the game?
Eligibility restrictions apply.
See draft kings dot coms for details.
All right.
Oh look who's back by [inaudible]
me undies,
me undies taken of fucking knee.
Do do too.
Beyond ease beyond ease from
seed to fucking China and z.
Why people say it means this?
Black people say it means that Bob,
we all could wear nice,
comfortable underwear with the
guts hanging over our ball bags.
Uh, me undies. You want to look good
and your underwear and be comfortable,
right?
But that perfect balance
is hard to find every day.
One of your balls is hanging on a little
bit more to the right than the left.
Well, don't sacrifice style
or comfort or your nuts.
Checkout me undies.com and find the
best pair of underwear in the world.
Talk about why me undies is the
best underwear you will ever own.
I'll tell you why,
because they're the only underwear
company paying me right now.
Me undies has an exclusive offer just
for my listeners and probably a thousand
other podcasts.
Get 20% off your first pair and free
shipping and me undies is so sure you will
love their underwear.
They even offer a 100%
satisfaction guarantee.
You order a pair and if you don't love
your first pair, get a full refund.
This is a no brainer.
Had tried 20% off free shipping and
aren't percent satisfaction guarantee.
What are you waiting for?
Huh?
To get 20% off and free shipping
and their 100% satisfaction, Karen,
she and get the best price and
softest underwear you will ever own.
Go to [inaudible] dot com slash bar this
is a limited time offer that I've been
reading for like fucking a year now.
So what are you waiting for?
Start wearing the best
underwear of your life.
Don't you think your clam and nuts
deserve it? It's changed my life.
Evidently it's time to let
me undies change yours.
Go to [inaudible] dot com slash
burr right now. All right,
last one lastly,
but not leastly legal zoom.
Everybody.
Ya know when you run your own business,
you know that time equals money.
It's not just an old saying,
it's a fucking fact.
So why waste your valuable time dealing
with issues that legal zoom can help you
with?
Huh?
You may already know that over 2 million
people have used legal zoom to start
their businesses,
but legal zoom services do not end.
They're running a business
comes with taxes, contracts,
hiring employees, changing the filter
and the air conditioning system.
Basically a lot of fine print.
That's why legal zoom built a network
of independent attorneys licensed in all
50 states.
They can provide the advice you need to
get through the daily grind of running
your business.
And you don't have to worry about billable
hours since legal zoom is not a law
firm.
Instead you can count on upfront pricing
and clarity and invest your time and
money and growing your business and let
legal zoom help out with the legal stuff.
For special savings,
be sure to enter Promo Code Bur bur
in the referral box at checkout.
That's Promo Code Bar
for a special savings
only@legalzoomdotcomlegalzoom.com.
All right, there you go. There
you go. Um, somebody asked me
do a bent benefit today folks.
Well,
they
doe Rico, those poor bastards are
still without power or you know,
after you have to get
hit by that hurricane and
everybody's over here talking
about somebody taking a knee.
I actually think taking a knee is more
respectful than standing up, isn't it?
Christ the guys on his fucking knees.
Um,
so hopefully I'll be able to do that.
Hopefully people stopped focusing on
the song and start focusing more on the
heroin epidemic. Right. I'm on my soapbox.
The fact that we're feeding cows to
other cows and cutting the beaks off of
birds that are walking around doing face
plants because their breasts are too
fucking big.
You know,
you can't even give him
a big to fucking land on.
That's like that Max at get smart episode
where they put them in the Gurney and
they strapped him in and then it was only
one of those fucking rotary doors and
they stood him up.
You haven't seen that one.
They push them through and
he does the fucking face
plant. Oh, that bit killed me.
I loved it back in the day.
Can you tell them a huge meat TV fan?
I've been taping the twilight zones over
there and not only is the twilight zone
great. What's awesome about it
is afterwards I then get to do,
my favorite thing is Google to see
how much of the cast is dead and I was
surprised.
I watched the one that was the bewitched
pool and the both of the little kids is
still alive. They're in their
sixties the mother is still alive,
still alive and kicking like 89 years old.
However,
the dad fucking dropped like less than
10 years later in the early seventies had
a heart attack. You know what I mean?
That was a big thing back in the day,
guys died of heart attacks in women
died of accidental overdose overdoses.
You know, cause anytime they
got air quote hysterical,
they would give them black beauties
and all the guys get a Holly itself,
you know, they'd get slapped around and
the doctor's office and then you know,
to make sure the swelling went down,
they would give him these relaxing fires
for their cheeks in their, in their,
in the rest of their body. If something
like that, and I forget how it goes,
but that's what I do.
Like I watch Hawaii five o just about
every night and the other night they had
this episode called to hell with
Babe Ruth. And that was a big rumor,
right? That back in the day.
Back in the day when I was young,
I'm not acute anymore. They used to, um,
hello,
but come on in.
Turn the KNOB.
Oh, I thought you were coming
in. So back in the day.
Um, oh, it's the lovely Nia. Hi.
Hi. Hi everybody. I can't stay though.
Well,
yeah.
Why'd you come in that dinner?
Oh yeah.
What are you ordering like,
um,
like Armenian for like, you know,
Middle Eastern food, like lamb and rice,
that sort of thing.
Lamin right. All right.
Well in that I already ate for the
evening and another to bully salad with
chicken.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah. Diane is
fascinating. So I'm gonna go order dinner.
Hi. I've, I haven't seen you in so long.
We were supposed to have
a date night tonight.
Yeah. And you blew me off. Not that blew
me off. I didn't blow you off. I just,
Papa, Papa, Papa, Papa. All right.
To hell with Babe Ruth. Okay. This
is a ledge allegedly. This my time.
Is it over officially done?
Yes. Okay. You're being
dismissed. You know what, Nia,
you're fired.
No Am I,
I'm at the end of the podcast here and
I was telling them about that to hell
with Babe Ruth thing.
Remember the Hawaii five o I was showing
you when they had the white guy playing
the Japanese guy with an but
then the lady, he was with boost.
I don't know if she was Japanese,
but she was definitely Asian. Yes.
And so she's got to sit there and look
at him with this fucking white guy,
stupid thing. And then they put
this awful makeup around his eyes.
This is 50 years ago.
Yep.
There you go. I don't know what to say
about it. I'm just bringing it up. Yeah,
that was terrible. It was. It was half a
century ago. Come on the podcast again.
Okay. No. [inaudible] dokey.
So anyways,
um,
okay.
Allegedly during the, uh, World War II,
when the Japanese soldiers
would do Abunzi charge,
which is fucking a suicidal
charge, I guess, or whatever.
Like Japan was not fucking around.
There was no quitting.
Okay. There was no, everybody
gets a ribbon. All right?
They would just,
if you fucking,
there was no surrendering
to your fucking enemy.
So during those Buns, I charges allegedly,
I don't know if this is propaganda,
they would yell either to how with Babe
Ruth or Fuck Babe Ruth is what they
would yell.
Right?
So Babe Ruth got wind of it and
there's a quote in the New York Times,
I got to get this right. I don't
want to misquote the sultan of Swat.
The only man who ever had a ballpark
built around his fucking abilities. Um,
let me see if I can find this. Uh,
you can't. I can't find it. Um,
he basically said, he goes, any
JAP that says that I hope they,
I hope he gets shot.
He goes,
and while we're at it goes to hell with
all the Japs that was written in the New
York Times.
You know,
you could never do that in 1969 by the
time that episode of Hawaii five o came
out.
But what you could do was have a white
guy with the worst makeup ever around.
I'm going to fucking,
I'm going to post the picture.
I've got a post a picture I was, I don't
know if I'm going to do what either.
I just want to make sure I just got
a picture of John Daly in a fucking,
in his sweatpants.
Fucking
make a chocolate shake from himself in
a glass that had the Arkansas razorback
thing on it.
Is there anything about John Daly?
That is an awesome anything.
Um,
so anyways,
I was watching this episode and this guy,
I'm watching the whole time going, that
guy is not Japanese. What the fuck?
I was looking, there's something
wrong with his eyes or whatever.
And I finally looked up the actor.
I don't know what he was,
he was first generation something
around that. But it was not you.
You should just see these, see his face.
His whole face is fucker white features.
And then he had this, like he was
sort of squinting his eyes though.
I was just was horrific. Felt
bad for the lady across from, I
can't imagine what she said when
she came home and just be like,
he didn't even look good.
So anyways,
I guess what I'm saying,
it's about time we make a
world war two movie. You know,
we actually have Japanese
people play Japanese soldiers.
Can we at least do that?
Has it been done? I don't
know. I watch sports. Okay.
And there is no fact checking
whatsoever when it comes to a,
when it comes to his pockets.
Guys,
I ordered the greatest
fucking motherfucking cock
sucking fucking whiskey glass
you will ever own in your fucking life.
And it's so awesome that I know when
you see it, you're going to want it.
All right?
This guy's got a small operation,
so I'm not going to tell you who it is
until I ordered some more and get my
order in.
And then I'm going to let you
know on Monday, Monday, Monday.
I can't be that much of a cunt.
This is a great gift.
If you have a fucking person who loves,
hang on a second. Who loves to drink with?
All right?
And the holidays are coming up,
please guys.
Name on fuck.
Hang on a second. God dammit.
I gotta give you the name.
These are the greatest
fucking whiskey glasses ever.
There's this guy, he, uh, is
this, does this sound right?
This sounds kind of perverted.
He blows his own glass,
was a bad time to pause in that. He
blows his own. Three, two, one glass.
Um,
Nate Cotterman,
n a t e c o t t e r m a n Nate
cotterman.com, um, can make
you all kinds of things.
I actually fucked up my order.
I called the number up and he,
the guy just picked up, he's like, hello?
I'm like, ah. Yeah. As night there, he's,
I guess night. I'm like, yeah,
dude. I ordered the Riaa.
Put an order for eight glasses.
I ordered the wrong ones.
I wanted the ones with the square Cuban.
He goes, hey, I saw that. All right,
I'll take care of that.
How'd you hear about us?
I was just looking at wicked whiskey
glasses is what the guy does. All right,
for all you guys out there and you
drink the top shelf booze, all right,
you're a self made man or you were
born into it. Give a fuck. Right?
You got you a woman in line?
No. Um, and you've got,
you've got a top shelf bottle of
booze and you respect the booze.
You respect the artists,
artists who fucking whatever the fuck did
whatever he did to make it as mute and
his in his,
in his tasty God,
this is gonna make me go right off the
wagon and it's tasty as it is in and you
what you want to Colt, you know, so
there's all these different things.
There's these giant ice cubes you can
put in there, these big square ones,
but eventually towards the
end, you know, that's the,
the water's going to start
leaking into the booze.
You gave me talking tap water
here. Okay. Like beavers,
shitness stuff is mixing in with you.
God Damn Booze. You can't have that.
The, the aroma of duck feet
is, is, is coming in d two,
your pristine firewater here.
Right?
So then they also have, they
got these metal cubes or
whatever, but then you know,
no matter what, there's going to be
some sort of metallic, maybe blah, blah,
blah blah, blah. This
guy, Nate, all hail Nate.
He makes a whiskey glass and then he makes
a a square glass fucking ice cube and
marries that to the Gla.
It becomes part of the glass.
Then you take the whole fucking glass,
you stick it in the fridge,
the freezer or whatever, and
then everything's called. Okay.
And then you pour it in there.
Okay. The Bose has nowhere to hide.
It's surrounded on all
sides by nice chilled,
frigid glass.
But none of it leaks into the booze.
So you can drink it neat
and have an ice cold.
You can have your fucking cake
and eat it with these glasses.
I cannot say enough about them.
I absolutely love these fucking glasses
and I haven't even used them yet.
They got a little weight to them too. So
if you, if you limp wristed or you know,
if you're, you know, I
don't know if you, you know,
back in the day you got an old
roller blading injury and you've,
your pro both your risks. These
might not be for you. Okay.
But I fucking love these
glasses that you and, and,
and the coolest shit they caught him
in with the c. All right. That's it.
Enjoy the music.
And uh,
we've got another half hour shit
coming up from a Thursday afternoon,
just before Monday morning podcasts
and a Thursday gone by, you know,
possibly early this year.
Maybe it was from a three years ago.
I don't fucking know. I don't pick
them. All right. Have a great weekend.
You can cuts. I'll see you
in Vegas. And uh, that's it,
right?
Yeah.
[inaudible]
oh, you know what, I didn't
even get to that fucking,
you see that report or that died.
Let me get to where the
hell is that story here.
This writer for rolling stone,
which I have a subscription to one of the
magazine's few magazines that actually
read every episode,
every installment.
Um, Michael Hastings, uh,
he had a horrible death. He fucking was
going down, I believe it was Highland,
just south of Melrose is Mercedes
was traveling at ridiculous speeds.
He hit a fucking tree and the whole thing,
we exploded,
bursts into flame and they had to
identify him by his dental records and uh,
allegedly this guy knew,
I guess he wrote some fucking article
in rolling stone where he was over in
Afghanistan talking to some higher ups
in the military and they was saying some
shit that they thought was off the record
and he put it all in the article and
there's people conspiracy there is
trying to say that his car was cyber
attacked.
Now I'm not even gonna get into that,
but toot how fucked up is the world
getting if like that's actually something
that somebody could do. I'm not saying
whether it was done by this guy or not.
I have no fucking idea. He might've
been hammered. I have no idea.
I have no fucking clue.
I don't know anything about it,
but I'm just saying that the fact,
okay that somebody can hack into your
computer and cause your car to speed up
and there's nothing,
you can't shut the car off.
This is why I don't know that.
I don't believe that.
It's just like his evil is that
is we got to eliminate this guy.
Isn't there a zillion other ways
to kill them without doing that?
Like what if he slammed into like a
fucking minivan with the [inaudible],
you know, a married couple in
their three, four kids, you know,
it's gotta be, you know, can't they
just spray some mist on him? You know,
just walk up to them in a mall like hi
sir, would you like to try this fragrance?
You just spray it on him. And
then the guy like, you know,
10 minutes later we just trying on
some slacks, he just keels over.
You can't just do it that way.
But anyways, is this true?
Is can they actually do that shit?
And this makes me feel glad that you know,
half my time out here, I drive
around in a classic car, you know,
because not like I'm any sort of a
threat. But what I'm saying is if that,
if I just would think if you
had the ability to do that,
some fucking nerds would just do it
just to do it. Cause it would be funny,
just speed you up for a second and
slow you down just to freak you out.
You know,
like do you remember back in the day
when this is like pre Internet fun?
What you would do is you'd take
your garage door opener, right?
And you would drive around
the neighborhood and he'd
pointed at every garage
until you found somebody
that had the same one as you.
And back in the day they just had
a, like, it wasn't sophisticated.
So not only yours open, not only
yours, it opened the other ones too.
So you'd,
you'd eventually find somebody that had
the same garage door brand is you when
you could open and close their garage.
So at least you could my fucking
neighborhood. So you just find,
you use drive one person nuts.
You just drive by and you just fuck it.
And every once in a while we just open
it and I don't know why we would do it.
We were assholes. But so using
that, if you could fucking do that,
um, with cars wouldn't, wouldn't
like these people like,
you know,
hack in to steal like credit
card numbers and shit. I mean,
wouldn't that be somebody just doing
that just to do it like you're bored.
It was just the,
was this the dumbest part of the podcast?
Everybody did I stick the landing starting
off with ignorance and then a why,
why wouldn't they? Well, we'll
fuck you know what the reality,
if I ever book a commercial,
I'm going to be,
you know that commercial where the adult
sits there with all the kids and they
go, you know, what would you,
what would you do if you had
a zillion dollars and it,
the kids that I could buy an
island made out of candy. Yeah,
we could have hot fudge waterfalls and
shit. I would be sitting there right with,
except it wouldn't be like
the basketball one way.
They were like making fun of
the fact like I would be like,
you don't have to say I'm saying I'm okay
buddy.
[inaudible]
I'm all right for the birds. Hey
Belk, I've got these two parakeets.
My problem is that these
little dudes don't like me.
Uh, I've tried whistling
petting them. I don't know.
You can pet a bird and
squirting them with water.
Um, do they like water? I'm
guessing that that's a good thing.
Parakeets like water.
I don't know.
Why don't we ask the fucking Jimmy's
guy to write a fucking nine pages on it?
I love all I'm upset with that guy
because he actually did the research as
opposed to me who were like, oh yeah,
I overheard this in a bar. So anyways,
this guy's petting his birds.
He's fucking, he getting
them with the water hose.
He's whistling Adam.
Whoo.
I'm all to no avail.
I know there are only birds,
but I feel they hold a deep resentment
towards me where yet clip their wings and
you stuck them in a cage. How would you
feel somebody cut your fucking nuts off,
came by, started whistling at
you and throwing water at you.
You know,
I got an idea. Why don't you leave
him alone? She opened the cage,
right?
Why don't you take him to one of those
car Dashi and doctors and I get a little
botox in their fucking
wings and let them fly away.
When that'd be annoying to
you if you are in a cage,
your arm's cut off at the fucking elbows
and somebody came up and rather than
whistle and they started speaking English
or you speak in English at you. Um,
he goes, I think it's because I
yelled at them. Oh, here we go.
Because I think they respect
me because I yelled at them.
Yeah.
What did you, what, what,
what were they doing?
Okay.
Uh, I said no with one
during my shoves. Uh,
basically I had to scold them
for pooping in their water dish,
but I had their best interests in mind.
Two.
Do you understand how fucking insane you
are that you feel like you can talk to
a bird?
You know,
why don't you like not
stick the water dish,
you know,
underwear that was underneath the swing
or what I would do is I just get a
bigger cage.
I'd get a bigger fucking cage.
I put the water in the center that
isn't near any of those trapeze bars and
hopefully they won't be at the top of
the cage and still shit down on it.
Or I would accept the fact that
it's a burden to cage and that it's,
you know, basically anything
at the bottom of the cage,
miners will be the city address.
Right.
I would just take that as part of it. I
wouldn't yell at the birds. But anyways,
this guy, he had to scold them
for pooping in their water,
but I had their best interest in mind.
I heard if they drink contaminated water,
it can cause a disease that makes
all their feathers fall off.
While you could also read up on it,
as opposed to me who just repeats
shits that they, here he goes,
I do a lot for those little guys.
But putting jackets on nude parakeets
isn't one of them. Even if I wanted to,
I couldn't, they don't even let me
pet them, let alone dress them. Dude,
you're not a bird guy. You should
have got a dog. Uh, he goes,
when I originally bought them,
I imagine I would have one pair
of keyed on each shoulder. Why?
Hanging out around my house.
But whenever I approached the cage,
they freeze in horror.
Every time they do that,
I can't help but remember my brother's
face when he fell through the ice,
we had to pull him out. I thought maybe
if I bought them more toys, they would,
that would somehow help. Two
birds. Motivation isn't more toys.
Their motivation is
you not have an energy.
Like I'm gonna fucking twist you head off
to their wings are clipped so they can
escape. You got them stuck in a cage.
They're terrified and you yelled at him.
I would say more than on one occasion,
you yelled at them.
All right?
Um,
you need to fucking relax.
All right,
listen to this.
Would you,
would you want to be like your
job to be in a cage all day?
You know,
and then some,
you know,
I dunno.
Some giant comes home and puts you on
his fucking shoulders and your whole job
is to enhance the giants fucking life.
You don't even have a little bit
of empathy for the fucking birds.
What I would do is I would just have a
totally relaxed energy and hope that they
forget that you're screamed at them,
treat them nicely.
Don't try to pet him. Just don't fuck
with them. Every time you come over,
they'll graduate and be like, Oh, this is
the guy who feeds us. Scale brings water.
This guys on our side,
you know,
as opposed to the mixed
messages that you send them.
MMM.
Yeah.
Birch don't give a fuck about toys.
Do they? I don't think
they do. Uh, he said,
I bought them a new toy every Friday
on my way home from work and it's a
ridiculous amount of toys in the cage.
And here's the kicker.
They haven't played with this
single one. Not once. Well Do,
do you look at the birds outside?
They're, they're not out there. If you,
you leave your toddler's toys
outside. They don't go, oh good.
They left and then they go down. They
start playing on his fucking tricycle.
He goes, they just stare at
me. I took him to the vet,
but he spent more time looking at
his phone than the birds. Anyways.
Any advice would be greatly appreciated.
Um, I think you should find a bird lover,
sir.
And uh,
give the birds away and then, um, I dunno.
I think you should get your temper in
check and before and before you do that.
Yeah. Get your temper in check.
And then if you want to get a dog,
it seems like you want more
interaction with the pet.
Most people get birds because they can
have an interaction with an animal,
but they don't have to walk it
down the street and it's very,
a lot less interaction with them.
You seem like you want a bird to
act like a dog slash a little kid.
Like, Hey, daddy's home. I
bought you a fire engine. Oh boy.
Look at that is the bell work. You know,
somehow you want the bird to do that.
MMM.
Yeah. Please stop yelling
at your birds. All right.
They can help with they shit in the water.
You know the birds,
they're not supposed to be in cages.
They fly around and they shit as they fly.
They shit when they're on branches,
when they have to go, they go,
they don't have any stress,
they don't have any shame and
there's water all over the place.
So now you've got them in this fucking
cage with little confined area water.
You know, what are, what are they
supposed to do? Whoa, Whoa, whoa.
What do I know about the restaurant?
[inaudible] [inaudible]
[inaudible]
hey,
what's going on?
It's bill bar and this is the
Monday morning podcast for a Monday,
September 28th, 2009. Um,
my voice is a little raspy
this morning cause a,
I did a lot of shows this
weekend getting ready for my, uh,
my next hour special that's going
to tape in December. And uh,
somebody actually sent me an
email questioning when, where,
and all that type of shit. And uh,
we're still solidifying all of that.
So the second I know,
I will let you guys know the chosen 14
listeners that I have on my podcast,
which I know at this point
it's more than that. You know,
I've checked out some Google trends and
saw that I think I'm up to about 17.
I have no fucking idea how many people
listen to this and I could give a shit.
All right. That's it. I mean, I, I give
a shit. I want people to fucking listen.
But, um, I don't do this
thing too. Uh, I dunno.
I don't know. It's weird. I don't fucking
hype this thing really. If you find it,
you find it, you fucking
cunt. Um, all right.
So this is my deal. It's Monday
and I'm still in Addison, Texas.
Why do you ask why bill? I
thought Monday was the day, uh,
you went back to Hollywood and tried to
pursue your dreams of getting into a,
uh, a fucking movie here
or there. Well, I'm,
I'm hanging around one more day cause I'm
going to the cowboys game tonight on a
Monday night football cowboys playing the,
uh,
the fuck are they playing the Carolina
Panthers? I'm kind of out of sorts.
And you know,
you're not getting this podcast and
where you'll listen to and it right now,
and it's Tuesday morning.
And I'll tell you why he didn't fucking
get it is because he's fucking assholes
at the hotel, a rape and me
on the Internet. And you know,
I feel about corporations.
I don't fucking like them.
This is what these fucking assholes do,
right? You sign up for the Internet.
It's 13 bucks a day at this fucking
hotel, right? 13 bucks a day.
That's already ridiculous. All
right? But I'm on the road,
you know, whatever, I'm making some
money here. I'm doing all right.
And I need to fuck, I need the internet.
I lost my fucking blackberry. So I'm like,
I fuck it.
I'll pay it.
So I sign up for this shit at about 10
o'clock at night after I had flown in
Wednesday night and the next, you know,
the next day, you know, I signed up for,
for, for fucking day, 24 hours, right?
My world a day is 24
hours. All right? So I,
um, you know, I wake up the next day, I
do the morning radio. I hide my shows.
I have a great fucking time. I come back
in the afternoon, I say, you know what?
I think I'll go on that.
That their new fangled internet that
the kids are talking about, right?
I go to go on the Internet
and Lo and behold,
I'm not on the fucking Internet
anymore and I'm like, wait a minute.
Even though I went to
fucking summer school,
just about every goddamn year
in high school because of math,
I know how to fucking ad.
All right?
Is that Algebra Shit and geometry and
Algebra two and trig and all that shit.
That fucked me up because I'm,
you know,
I'm not into shapes.
The second they started drawing
those triangles on the ball,
I just didn't give a shit. It's
just like really, you know,
there's certain things in
life you just fucking, no,
you're never gonna use it right now.
I know that you know a lot of the things.
I'm probably fucking the sitting in
this room right now because of geometry.
Look at all his shapes. When I
look around the wind, no fuck.
I look out the window.
That's a rectangle.
My doors are rectangle. Where's
the fucking triangle? Well,
that's a right angle on the
doorway. Hell, there's four of them,
right? Is that geometry? I
don't know what the fuck it is.
Is there an Isosceles triangle over by my
phone? I don't fucking know. All right.
But I know, you know what I mean? He
just fucking know some stuff. You know,
you just going to suck at.
So whatever bill, get on Con,
we're gonna stay on fucking track here.
Right. So anyways, so basically it was,
it had been about 14 hours since I
signed up for the Internet and all of a
sudden I'm not on the
fucking Internet again.
So I go back online to figure out what's
going on. And right after you'd signed,
you sign up for 24 hours. It says in
small print in parentheses that it,
it expires every day at noon time.
So basically I didn't sign up for
24 hours. What I signed up for was,
yeah,
14 hours.
I paid $13 for 14 hours
of fucking Internet,
eight of which I was
sleeping. Okay. So yeah,
they fucking raped me.
They came up with a new little fucky
fuck charge new little, you know,
they just sit around like these fucking
money grubbing little comments to figure
out some little fucking way,
you know,
that they can just somehow squeeze it.
I mean the,
I'm sure if I sat down and
tried to figure out the map,
the math of like when people arrive in
a hotel and when they usually check out,
like how having it expire every day at
fucking noon gets them a little bit more
money, you know, so they can make
their yachts just a little bit bigger.
So you know what it was the
usual shit. What do I do? I
call the front desk, right?
And who do I get?
Do I get the head of the corporation that
runs this Internet scam? Of course not.
I get some fucking 25 year old person
who fucking majored in transportation or
fucking, I don't know, hotel management
and now has no fucking benefits in,
is working the front desk and I'm
pissed. So I say to them, I say, hey,
that chippy, this is bill burr calling
and fucking room one zero one eight.
Niner I don't know why I
just wanted to get military,
their alpha red nine or
68 cross power trip, do whatever
the fuck you call it. Anyway,
so I fucking call this guy up and I go,
look,
I just signed up for a fucking day and
now it shuts off at noon and the guy goes,
yeah. And I, um,
we don't have anything to do
with that here at the hotel.
The Internet is a
complete separate entity.
So even though you're in the hotel and
you're currently having their dick firmly
in your ass, we don't have
any responsibility on that.
If you'd like to see in,
and you know how I can fucking complain,
I have to go back on the fucking Internet
and pay another 13,000 fucking dollars
to complain to these assholes.
So you know what? Fuck them.
Okay,
fuck them fucking assholes. You
know what? You're dumb fucks.
You could have got 80 bucks out of me.
I was willing to pay 13 a day,
even though that was a total fucking rip
off it because you little fucking conti
attitude. Now you only get 13
bucks out of me. All right.
I don't understand why they do
that. Why they just, I mean,
do people just give into it
trying to find the name of these assholes?
What is it? I see h or something like
that. I didn't know what the fuck it is.
What gives a shit,
right?
I'm just having one of these fucking
weeks and now I don't have any questions
because I haven't been on the
fucking internet this week,
so I'm just basically going
to have to wing this podcast.
But fortunately I have plenty of stories
from my wonderful stay out here in
Addison, Texas. Um, here's one for,
I'm going to be on the road
for the next three weeks.
So that's obviously putting a
strain on my relationship. Okay.
So I'm thinking maybe I'll do something
nice for the fucking two days.
I'm going to be home over
the next three weeks. And uh,
I'm a big fan of the core vet.
Everybody. Do you like the core vet?
Are you a middle aged American man like
me who never got married and doesn't
have kids? So now for some, that's
what it ends up. That's when,
and that's when that car starts
appealing to you. You have to start,
they start thinking that
shit. You know, maybe I'll,
maybe I'll get myself a corvette.
Maybe I'll go hang out at an Applebee's
and start hitting on somebody who's at
least fucking born three decades after me.
No, I fucking love Corvettes.
I think they're there.
I just loved the look of the
car. I think it's, uh, you know,
it's an American made car. I think it's
a great value. You know what I mean?
I think, you know, they've got core Becca.
I was like fucking 200 miles an
hour now a grant. And I know,
I know that one's like six figures,
but you can get a corvette.
Can't you get a corvette for like
65 grand? I mean, all that and all,
it says a shitload of
money. But, uh, you know,
I realized halfway
through this, I, you know,
how much a Porsche cost is it Porsche or
Porsche? I don't even know how to say.
That's another car that I fucking love
that, uh, that, you know, I can't afford,
you know,
how much money I'd have to make a fucking
year to justify blowing basically a
house on a car, house, money on a car,
house money granted it in fucking
Arkansas somewhere, but still,
you know what I mean? Um, so anyways,
I think the way to go is rather than
fucking going out and spending all that
fucking money on the car,
you just go rent one for a day.
So one day I landed in fucking Burbank
airport and I'm driving by Hertz rental
car. What do I see? I see a fucking
yellow corvette sitting there.
I'm not into the yellow, but it's still
a corvette. And I'm thinking, you know,
I want to use it. Why don't I just
fucking rent one for one day? You know,
I'll rent one for one day. What's that
going to cost? Right? 300, 400 bucks.
That's a fuck load of money, but
it's, it's way less than 70 grand.
75 grand. What the fuck? Why
not rent one of those things,
you know,
I'll take my girl out,
we'll go for a cruise up in
the fucking Hollywood hills,
will tip it over,
will die.
Just like that fucking dude in the 50s
who look like Fonzie, but that's not him.
What is his name?
Johnny was his name.
Johnny was in every fucking
bad boy named Johnny back then.
Do you ever notice that shit?
One of my favorite things to watch,
um, is old. Like those old
black and white movies,
whenever that they're doing
movies about gangs, you know,
and it's always a bunch of white
actors and half of them are gay,
just flaming homosexuals and they're
trying to act tough and it's fucking
hilarious the way they flip
up their collar and they,
they pull up their sleeves.
But the fuck that I watched the other
day was one of the worst fucking movies
ever saw in my life was
a Marlon Brando movie.
That one where he's on the motorcycle
and he stops into the town.
If you want a fucking, yeah. Do you
ever get embarrassed for someone?
Like somebody is doing something so
douchey that you just feel yourself just
wanting to crawl underneath the fucking
hotel bed and lay next to the dead
hooker that you didn't
even realize was there.
You know what I mean?
There is a scene in that movie where
they are in this bar and these two guys
start talking in this street slang and
the old bartender just can't keep up with
it and they go like, Hey Daddy.
Oh Hey, if I can't even do it,
it's so fiery. Even got an, I cal get
embarrassed to even trying to recreate it.
It's fucking horrific. So, uh,
the fuck am I talking about? Yeah. I want
to rent this God damn car, right? Some,
I'll rent it for one day,
right? A for one day.
I'm going to tell you some right now,
la during the day,
especially during these hotter months,
it's fucking horrible.
It's like living in a city.
Let's write outside of God's stove and,
and you know, it doesn't even
make sense or trying to, you know,
I was trying to say that the
joke I was trying to do is like,
you have a heat up an oven.
Sure. We all have. Ah,
at some point you tried to cook a fucking
Turkey. Oh, fucking remind me. I've got,
I tell you about a great youtube video.
Y'All, you know what? I'm going to forget.
Let me get back to the stove thing.
Thanksgiving's coming up, everybody.
I now I'm all over the place.
I'm going to fucking finish Brando thing.
I'm going to finish this stove thing and
I'm going to get back to the corvette
story,
but first I'm going to tell him gonna
I'm gonna take a little break for the
holidays. All right. Over here in America
for all you people overseas, Bu, Bu,
Bu, Bu, Bu, Bu, Bu, Bu, Bu, um, I was
supposed to be ladies and gentlemen,
all the ships at sea. Um, we have,
we have a holiday over here called
Thanksgiving where we give thanks for the
fact that our founding fathers,
uh,
committed genocide and gave us
all this beautiful land out here.
Fuck you.
That's how the world works.
You knew we will come and you
saw our cutlasses, you know,
that's how the world works. Smash Mouth
Football, the black and blue division.
That's how it fucking works.
The Norris. Um, no it isn't.
I don't advocate that shit.
But you know what, what, what
it happened. But you know,
they've got their casinos. We named
a couple of golf courses after him.
You ever noticed that shit?
That's what I like about white people.
We fucking slaughter people. Then we
named Shit after him. Once we feel bad.
Oh, we'll call this a WAMPA tuck.
This is the one Pathak grocery store
and this is the last in the mall.
He can call the SAC. Um,
anyways, Jesus Christ. Bill. Yes.
So I saw this youtube video
Thanksgiving's coming up or right.
And one of the big things is a man is
you have to know how to carve a goddamn
Turkey.
Okay.
And as much as all you fucking guys out
there want to act like you know how to
carve a Turkey most see a fucking don't.
But you're too afraid to ask because
you're worried that someone's going to
question your sexuality because that's
what it's like to be a man. Basically.
If you don't just somehow
know shit without ever having
any explained it to you,
that evidently means that you, you, you
want to have sex with another man. That's,
that's the laws that I learned
growing up. Um, so anyways,
there is a fucking youtube video out
there that of course I can't check because
he's concert charging me $13 every
fucking an expires every noon.
But there just go on,
go on to Youtube, right?
And just Google how to carve a Turkey.
There is a fucking dude on there, man.
I'm telling you, you, it's,
it's unbelievable the way he takes
his bird apart. It's masterful.
Okay. And don't make the mistake I made
last year because I carved the thing up
perfectly, but the problem was my
knives, we're a little bit dull.
Go get your knives professionally
sharpened this month. Okay.
And Jesse eat spaghetti until Thanksgiving
so you don't fuck them up because I
swear to God, I've tried with that
little sharpener that you get.
A lot of people just
take out that sharpener,
that a little knife thing and they
just go week, week, week and there's a,
you have to fucking hold the thing and
as a at a certain angle and you can
actually be making the thing dollar if
you don't know what the fuck you're doing.
Trust me cause I did it.
You know I watched a couple of the
three stooges things and I saw them,
I saw curly look, hey look,
I can't even fucking do it.
My fucking voice was so trashed.
Anyways,
there's this killer youtube video man.
And it's like literally when this
guy is done with the thing you got,
you got the drumsticks,
the wings in the dark meat,
everything's lined up like that.
And then you've got all the white meat
with just a little bit of skin on top of
it,
lined up like a fucking deck of cards
and you come out with your serving tray.
I mean, if people faint,
it looked so good,
that fucking carcass is just,
it's a macula. All right,
so definitely check that shit out.
If you're going to make a Turkey,
and if you one of those people too,
who wants to deep fry a fucking Turkey,
make sure you put the Turkey
in the deep fryer first. Okay.
And then fill it up with water so you
know how much fucking grease to put in
there.
Evidently that's what people do is they
fill it all the way up to the top and
then they dropped the bird in there
and then it overflows. Catches flame,
lights their deck on fire and
they burn down their house.
And that's not thanksgiving.
That's not even Halloween.
Anyways, let me get better.
And what if I got to back up here?
So anyways,
this fucking podcast is a mess.
Um, to fuck that God's oven,
this is what I'm talking about. You have
a heat up, a fucking oven, you know,
and then you're checking
on whatever you're cooking.
And rather than opening it
and letting the heat come out,
and then looking down with your face,
you opened the door with your face right
there and you get that fucking heat
furnace blast. That's what summer
is like in La in July and August.
But I'm a tell you at night, it's
absolutely gorgeous. I'm telling you,
you should do it at some point. You ever
come out to la? Fuck the Hollywood sign.
Fuck going on sunset.
Fuck all of that.
Go up on Mulholland drive
and drive through the hills
late at night and look at
the valley and I, it looks like
Christmas, man. It's amazing.
So that's what I wanted to do.
I was going to get this fucking car
cruise around up there and uh, you know,
have a couple of drinks, wrap it
around a tree, runaway from the scene,
blame it on a minority. You
know, I'm fucking with you. Um,
you know, I was kind of, have a good
fucking time. It's what I wanted to do.
So I call these fucking
assholes up at Hertz.
I call him up cause I wanna rent this
car that's going to cost me 350 bucks.
I'm going to throw a fucking iPod
right in the trash for one fucking day.
A fucking taken some s turns
up there in the hills, right?
So I call him up and I say, yeah, listen,
I want to rent that corvette you got at
the Burbank airport. And they go, ah, oh,
first of all, I had to fucking get
through their stupid, uh, they're stupid,
a whatever, the, the, the,
the computer thing. And you
know, of course they have this,
this automated voice and you can
tell the person to do the voice over.
They told her, just smile. When she did
it, it says, this is the tone. She goes,
thank you for calling Hertz rental car.
You can actually get a better deal
if you go to here. It's dead king.
He this big stupid fucking grin on
her face. And it wasn't bugging me.
I actually enjoyed it the first
time through because I'm like,
I'm going to get a corvette for one
fucking day. I'm going to live the dream.
I'm going to live the fucking dream.
I'm going to live the American fucking
dream before they collapsed the dollar
and combine this with fucking Canada
and Mexico and put a microchip in the
middle of our fucking forehead.
I'm going to do it.
I'm going to get this God damn
corvette, right? So you know,
he wanted to fucking have a toothbrush
shoved up your ass. Press one.
If you want to fucking do a cart wheel,
press 19 so finally up,
you get up to 20 if you
want to make a reservation,
I fucking hit that button and then
write again. Giggy wiggly here.
El Pais date, right? It takes me
like fucking 20 minutes, right?
Press or say cunt, right? I'm going
through all that shit. So finally,
I'm just like screaming operator.
Yeah. Into the phone. Right?
So finally I get someone and I say, you
know, listen, I want to rent, you know,
saw this car corvette you had at the
Burbank airport. And God damn it,
I'd like to rent it.
And they go, okay, um,
let me give you the number for the Hertz
rental car location and they can help
you with that, sir. And I said,
okay ma'am. And she gives it to me.
All right.
So I hang up and what do I do?
I called the Hertz location out in
Burbank and what do I get again?
That same computers,
smiley voice.
Diggy recalling her GB anal
care. Yeah. Help eggs. Right.
Okay.
If you know the extension of the person,
how the fuck would I know that?
How would I know what fucking extension
would like to have football players and
they have a hall of fame career and I
know fucking Brett Farve is extension four
out of fuck what? I know
that shit. So once again,
operator screaming into the phone,
I want to fucking talk
to a goddamn person.
But of course I can't talk to a person.
What are they doing the entire time?
They keep steering me to the Internet,
basically saying in not so many words
that this would be a whole fucking lot
easier if you just went on the
Internet. Yeti hurts Dad Cam, right.
If you could just help us
eliminate more fucking jobs
so we can eventually replace all of
you with fucking robots, you know?
So I'm like, fuck this, I want
to talk to a goddamn person.
So finally I get to the stupid,
you know,
all I get is if you want to leave
a message, you know, I'm like,
I don't want to leave a
message. Right? And then they
go, well you didn't, you know,
they come on like I didn't
make a decision. I have to
make a fucking decision.
I did make a decision. My decision is
I don't like any of the decisions you,
you fucking gave me to make.
So I think if you went Moria
pins play sport, Smiley face.
So I press four and then basically
if I wanted to talk to a person,
I could basically schedule a phone
call when they could call me back.
I could leave my phone number
or I could wait a half an hour.
So I hang up and I'm like,
you know what,
I've just wasted a half
hour of my fucking life.
So I call these fucking assholes
back again at the national thing.
Thank you for calling her to be anal care.
I'm back in that shit again and I'm
screaming operator to the phone and I get
somebody and say, listen, who do
I talk to to make a complaint?
Cause at this point I'm like, I'm not
renting this fucking car from there.
I know there's other places where they,
they,
they rent these exotic cars
is that column that, um,
I was like, fuck it. I'm just
going to go through them, but I'm,
but I'm going to make sure that
I complained to somebody. Okay.
And I'm not going on the internet
and sending a fucking email. Right.
So I actually get a person and they
go, okay, well let me transfer. Okay,
I'm going to transfer you.
I'm sorry to hear that sir.
I'm very sorry to hear that. Sorry. Um,
let me transfer you to our complaints
department. I go. Okay, thank you.
She clicks it over.
Yeah.
Thank you for calling [inaudible]
I'm fucking back in it again.
Yeah,
right. And they, and they just fucking
tell me if I, if I'd like, I can't get,
I can't get to a fucking person. So
now I'm, I'm, I'm, I'm, I'm determined.
I'm going to get to somebody I call
back again. Can give you going here.
It's go to the operator, go through
the bull shit again. When I say listen.
Okay, you sitting down, person
on the other side of the phone.
I would like to make a complaint.
I don't want to fill out a form.
I don't want to make an email.
I want to talk to a person.
I do not want to be
transferred into your national,
he vaguely here fucking thing again.
I didn't say fuck cause they could've
hung up on me. National System again,
I would like to be transferred
directly to a person.
I believe you call it a warm transfer
in the creepy corporate world.
So can you do a warm transfer,
meaning something alive to something
else alive that can communicate with me?
She goes, yes sir. I'm sorry. I'm
sorry. Having this difficulty.
I'd say I understand lady.
I understand you're not on the yet.
You're not on the yacht.
You're on the dark.
Getting screamed at by guys like me every
day. That's why I'm not yelling at you.
All right, fucking, I'm on hold
again. She can't get to anybody.
Then I go back to her and then she hits
me with the form. What is your name, sir?
What'd they did? None of your fucking
business. You don't need to know my name.
What do you need to know my name for so
you can stick me on the hostile caller
list? Because I had the
audacity to complain about
your country fucking system.
I'm not giving you my fucking name. I want
to talk to a person. Okay, sir. I just,
yeah, I just, okay. Just following
protocol. I understand that ma'am.
I'm not mad at you. I didn't say
that country. That fucks stuff.
That's what I was thinking, but I
kept my God damn cool. I kept my cool.
Just like fucking Steve McQueen in that
movie where he eats the deviled eggs,
get mad at damn eggs.
So anyways, I fucking,
I fucking
finally get to a person.
All right? And I just say really
calmed me. I just say, look, you know,
I've been on the phone for 40 minutes
trying to give you guys 350 bucks,
okay.
And for the life of me,
I can't do it because I keep talking to
computers and they keep sending me back
into national system. Now, ma'am, I
know you have nothing to do with this,
all right?
But I want to know what is the best way
that I can try to complain so I can get
to the inner hive, the inner layer of
the hive here and actually get to that,
that person who's sitting there in those
loafers without any socks on sunning
himself on the deck of his yacht.
I want to get to that guy,
the guy who made this policy. Okay?
I like talking to people, man.
I enjoy the fact that you still
have a job. Okay. That's what I,
that's what I like here.
My phone buzzing in my phone,
buzzed and hang on one second. Hey Paul,
let me call you right back. All right.
So, uh, you know what? It actually worked.
So basically what they did was,
is I got an email and they go,
you can send an email and I go and let me
guess. No one's going to call me. Right?
Someone's going to email me back and
act like it's the actual frigging person
that I'm talking to. But really it's going
to be an intern who's being, you know,
who's working there for free.
And also parttime reads those books for
Oprah's book clubs so she can come on TV
and acts like she fucking reads a foreign
a page book every fucking week. Right?
Is that, are you going to give me too?
Cause if that's what the deal is I want,
I want somebody up high.
So basically they gave me allegedly the
email of the vice president at Hertz
reservations, Dad Cam, um, and
I actually have the guy's name.
Now, whether this is true or not, I dunno,
but what I want to tell the guy is
that I was trying to fucking rent
that fucking flaming yellow corvette
that they have out there in Burbank,
California for the life of me.
I couldn't do it and now I don't want
to do it and I'm going to bring my
business somewhere else and I
would appreciate it if you know,
just hope against hope that maybe you'd
give some human beings some jobs because
my experience with your
company as you may be at best,
have six people fucking working there
because you just,
you just keep trying to steer the herd
onto the Internet and all you dumb fucks
out there who are just constantly
helping them to get rid of people's jobs.
You're out of your fucking mind because
those people are going to need jobs and
eventually they're going to be willing
to do your fucking job for a lot less
fucking pay.
And considering we've sent 90% of our
factories out of this fucking country now.
So now the American worker going to have
to fucking compete with sweatshop labor
to make some fucking track shoes.
You know,
why don't we try to keep
the jobs that we have?
I'm not going to hertz.com you try
to pay me off with better rates.
Go Fuck Yourself. But some fucking human
beings in there the way you used to.
And you know what?
You'd be $350 fucking rich.
Or I'd be driving a corvette and
everybody would be fucking happier.
You can put some new varnish on your,
the deck of your fucking boat.
You fucking assholes.
So whatever.
I know there's gotta be a private place
out there in la that I can call right up
and they'll probably charge me
even more money. And you know what?
I don't give a fuck because
I want to go in there.
They'll probably give me a little piece
of champagne or rug gimme a fucking foot
massage. All right? They
probably won't do that,
but I'll talk to a person and that's
what the fuck I want. That's all I want.
A little fucking human interaction San
asking too. God damn much. All right.
So anyways, there's that story. All right,
and I'm going to tell you another story.
They want to just tell you guys
some stories this week. All right?
Why don't you put your pajamas on?
All right.
Get a fire going in
your fucking apartment.
If they haven't boarded the
thing up because they're
worried about getting sued.
Um,
wasn't that great?
Back in the day where if you started a
fire was your fucking fault as opposed to
the landlords as opposed to what? Why
did you have a fireplace in there? Well,
they had a fireplace in there
in case it got fucking cold out.
Or maybe you want to have a romantic
evening with your girl and you want to
light a fucking fire. That's why there's
a fireplace in there. It's a fireplace.
It is a place for a fire. Now, if somehow
you burned down the fucking apartment,
evidently you didn't understand what
place to put the fucking firing you.
Dumb fuck who doesn't
not to use a fireplace?
Evidently there's enough fucking people.
So they need to be boarded up.
Boarding up a fireplace.
Jesus Christ.
Why didn't you put Santa Claus in
jail while you're at it? All right.
That was a little big. Okay. I'm just
saying, you know, I like fireplaces.
I like a crack of the fire.
I don't like those fucking gas ones.
Those fake fires may technically
it is a fire, you know,
I don't know.
What am I talking about?
Let me tell you a fantastic fucking
story last night. All right,
so I'm working the road with
Joe to Rosa Young Joe de Rosa,
the fucking teen idol from the opiate
Anthony Show who is actually going to be
on the cover of teen beat this,
uh, this month in, it's actually,
I saw a little bit of the photo shoot.
He's doing a tribute to a
Annette Funicello and uh,
that other fucking guy was it Tony Curtis,
who the fuck she used to make those
beach movies with or whatever.
Joe is going to be there shirtless
holding her surfboard and knock. He needs,
he's never look sexier.
Um,
so, uh, the fuck am I
talking about? I Christ,
I don't even know anymore. Um, yeah,
so we go out last night, right?
We're doing the show is these two big
titted horse sitting in the front fucking
row. All right. So we're like,
Oh wow, look at these girls.
These girls would probably be fun, right?
And I'm in a relationship, but you know,
I like being the wing man. You know,
I love being the wingman. I'd love it.
I love talking shit. The
girls, I love hitting on girls.
I fucking do it all the time and then I
try to pawn him off to wherever the fuck
I am and uh, you know, so I don't
have any goddamn guilt, you know.
So anyways,
so long story short,
we're talking to these broads and it's
clear that there's some sort of strippers.
I don't know what the fucking deal is.
Okay.
So we meet everybody from whatever I'm,
I'm gonna stop naming names here. Okay.
So a huge group of us from the show,
from the crowd and everything.
We go and we head out
to this bar, right? So
one of the strippers is cool,
the other one has a voice that could
literally crack a flatscreen TV.
All right?
So the cool one shows up.
First she sits down, I'm like,
Hey, are you doing, you know,
I like at the end of the week, I hang out
a by around for some people, you know,
I'm in a great mood. I had a good
time. I'm on my way home, you know,
up by some people, some drinks. So I say
to her, hey, what would you like to drink?
She's like, I'll have an Faq and gag at
Google, one of those fucking chick drinks.
So you know, so I get her a drink. I buy
young Joe to Rosa fucking drink, right?
Everybody's having a good time.
And then this other person shows up who
I knew and she was a real nice person.
I said, hey, what do you want
for a drink? And she was like,
I'll get a vodka red bull,
right? I got my $20 bill out.
And then the strippers like, yeah, make
it tell right. And I was like, wait,
what do you mean make it to you
haven't even finished your first make.
Don't be ordering off my money. You've
finished your first one there, young lady.
All right, stand the fuck down.
You're not working right now.
Not some dipshit getting a
fucking lap dance. All right,
finish your fucking milk and
cookies first. So needless to say,
the conversation called
between the two of us,
but I didn't give a fuck man. I was
having a good time, but whatever.
It was still kind of, you know,
whatever, just talking shit.
We were talking sports. The bartender
was cool, you know, we, everything,
everything was going great.
So with chilling out and all
of a sudden this fucking, uh,
the other fucking stripper girl
shows up out and was so fucking,
it was just such classic female shit.
She's got a tits hanging out.
She's got the fuck me pumps on
and she comes up, she goes, hey.
And she sees her friend with the drink
and she knows goddamn well she didn't pay
for it. So she looks over
at me as less. It's like,
well that must have been the
SAP who fucking bought it.
Right? So she looks at me,
she goes, Hey Belle. And
she's like, she's like,
what are you Jane Can Right? And
I know what she's doing. I'm like,
I'm drinking one of those
Sam Adams Octoberfest
and is leaving like that nice and awkward.
Right?
Cause I know what she's trying
to get a drink out of me. Right?
So she doesn't know what to do.
She's like, ah, is that good?
I'm like, why? Yes, yes
it is. At this point,
Derosa knows what's going on. I don't
know that he knows what's going on.
So she looks at me like, okay, well
evidently he's not buying any more drinks.
And then she looks at Jo,
she's like, ah, Hey Cho,
what are you tracking? And Joe gets
his shit eating grin on his face.
He goes, why? I'm drinking a bud light.
Why would you like to buy me one?
And she didn't know what the fuck to
do. She's like, uh, I, yeah. Again,
he goes,
you know what?
I think you should buy me a bud light
and you should buy my good friend bill
burr here, another Oktoberfest.
What do you think about that?
And at that point I'm fucking
dying laughing. The other
stripper girl next to me,
she's laughing her ass off
cause she knows what happened.
And then the fucking grow with this
screechy voice is sitting there.
She doesn't know what the fuck to do.
We fucking nailed it.
And then wait and then like she's going,
she didn't know what to do.
And Joe's just going,
yes,
why don't you pay it forward for all the
drinks that guys have boughten you and
that you've drank. And then immediately
turned around and fucking walked away.
Why don't you for once by a Goddamn by
a couple of drinks for a couple of guys
and she's a high in, you put
it that way. Fine. I, well I,
well I might a fucking drink and
Joe's like, how bout some shots too?
And she just was, I don't know what
her fucking ego was that she goes,
final fucking do that too.
So we actually got to strip it up
by his two bears and two shots.
So we're feeling like the kings of the
world and then all of a sudden we found
out from this waitress that on the slide
she tried to put it on her boyfriends
fucking credit card.
What a scumbag. Right?
So we buster and we all win.
And when this big commotion breaks out
right before the fucking bartenders are
about ready to swipe the boyfriend's
credit card, we were like, don't chill.
Joette I just like an
officer and a gentlemen.
I got nowhere else to go.
Right?
We get him to stop and they take out her
ATM and she had to fucking pay for it.
And it was a done deal.
We had two drinks,
two shots from that
fucking person who knows.
Never paid for a drink since
she got her fucking tits. Right.
And this was the best part. The second
we got our drinks, we set thanks a lot.
And we both got up and we walked away.
Oh, it's tremendous. Tremendous.
It was the best night ever,
and I'm just standing
there drinking my drink.
Like 20 minutes later I'm milking it for
all it's worth this free fucking beer
than a stripper bought me,
which is awesome. Right?
And Joe was talking to some girl across
the way and you're looking at all of a
sudden I just yelled over, I go, Joe.
And he looks over at me and I did.
I did the Robert De Niro line from when
he was eating at Joe Pesci mom right
before they hacked up Billy batts. Right.
He looks up and he's like, what's up?
And I just pointed at the beer,
this stripper at bought and I
just went delicious. Delicious.
And that was my evening. And
that that, there's another
story for you. What are we,
35 minutes. Then you got any more
stories? As a matter of fact, I do.
What else did I do this
fucking weekend? Oh, I know.
I took a trip to the cotton bowl.
What is the cotton bowl bill? Well,
cotton bowl is a stadium that's been
around, I believe since the twenties,
and it's the first place that the Dallas
cowboys played in and the Dallas Texans
in the old AFL. And God dammit,
I found out it's still existed.
So I wanted to go fucking
take a look at it.
So I went down there and lo and behold,
they were having their Texas there.
Dallas, Texas state, motherfucking fair
that they have every goddamn year.
I got a new text message,
I hear my little 16 year old phone
call me when you wake up,
I want to please you asshole. Um, anyways,
so I go to take a tour of this thing, Mesa
first place, Tom Landry, coach, you know,
the first season of the Dallas cowboys,
right? Dallas cowboys team that I love,
which was basically the Tom Landry years.
And I never gotten to the Jimmy Johnson
ones because watching Tom Landry leave,
I mean, it was like watching
Johnny Carson go, you know,
no disrespect to the next people.
It's just, it's just not Johnny.
It's not Tom Landry. You know what I'm
saying? So, uh, I never got into them.
So like this, you know, it was a big
deal to go check this out. So I go to,
you know, go to this tour and it was the
worst fucking tour ever took in my life.
It wasn't bad. It was an awesome
tour, but just the lady was cute,
but she just didn't fucking know anything
about the stadium. She goes, uh Oh he's,
you can see on either side. They
added some seats, they added thethe,
all the shiny silver ones. Those are
the new ones. And I was like, how many,
how many people? The place is fucking huge
guy. People People's this place holds,
she's like, I think like 23,000, 23,000.
I know you guys aren't
into sports the way I am.
23,000 is like a little hockey arena.
You know, you have a hockey game,
you sell at a hockey game,
23,000.
This is where fucking Texas longhorns
in the fucking Oklahoma sooners play.
All right.
College stadiums do not hold 23,000
at the Division One fucking level,
especially Texas, Oklahoma. You
know what I mean? So I'm like, ah,
I think it's a little more, I guess
like 45,000. I didn't fucking know.
And she looks, and she goes,
yeah, I think it's 23,000.
Then she looked at it a little pamphlets.
She goes on, sorry, it's 97,000
and I got to tell you right now, right
there, the stadium tour is fucking over.
It's over.
I don't want to hear another word from
you because that is the first fight.
If you're doing a tour of a stadium,
like if you want on the family
feud and the in the, in the,
the first question was,
you know,
you're standing there with one arm
behind your back so you can't cheat.
I don't understand why you have to
do that on the family feud. Right?
Like what if your lunch with two hands,
you're quicker diving in
like fucking Pete rose. Um,
anyways, if the, if the
question was, um, you know,
you've taken a tour of the stadium, what's
the first question you're gonna ask?
And you fucking slam your hand down.
The first thing you would say is how
many people does this stadium hold?
How many people does this stadium
home fucking number one answer.
That's what it would be.
That it's just chick acted like I asked
her what the fucking consistency of the
concrete was for the of the stadium.
She had no fucking idea.
And then she tried to say
that that back in the day,
the cotton bowl,
B o w l like a cereal bowl
was open ended on both sides.
Think about that for a second.
A stadium that's called the,
you ever seen the Rose Bowl?
The rose bowl is an open on either side,
is it now?
It's shaped like a fucking bowl.
She tried to say that the cotton bowl was
open on both ends for a while and just
in 2002 they closed it off.
What they actually did was they put an
upper deck and as far as I could tell,
they knocked down the end zone,
lower level. And they just,
they rebuilt that and
they put an upper deck,
but she was trying to say that
it was open ended until 2002.
And in my head I'm going,
I don't think that that's right.
I don't think that that's right either.
And then we went into the
media room and Lo and behold,
they have a picture of the
cotton bowl in 1958 and closed.
You know, I, you know, and I, I just,
I don't know, but we've got to go down,
stay in right down near the field,
come right down where all the
players came out. And uh, you know,
was asked me, Len Dawson Hanks,
dram, Bob Lilly, chuck Howley,
you know, all that shit right up
till now. All the modern day players,
Ricky Williams played there.
Who else played on the long horn?
So many fucking guys, that
guy, Vince young, all those
fucking dudes. I don't know.
Billy Sims, Earl Campbell, you
know, it was a fucking great time.
Then I walked out of there and they
and I went to, I walked around.
The little state fair
isn't a little state fair.
It's actually a big state fair that they
have and evidently down here in Texas,
what they do is,
and you people overseas who hate on
Americans are going to love this shit.
It's just,
this is classic here.
What they do down here in Texas is every
year they fry something every year with
fry, something different.
Last year was Oreos.
Year before that it was Twinkies.
We Fried Coq one year fried pizza.
I'm not even lying. They fried
all of this shits. I mean,
he told me they fried Coca Cola.
I don't know how the fuck you do that,
but they said they did it. I don't know
how to do it. What do you freeze the coke,
Huh?
And then
fucking rolling around in some fly.
I don't, I have no fucking idea,
but all I know,
you know what?
Evidently they're out of fucking ideas
because this year, you know what?
They were frying.
They will frying butter.
I swear to God,
they were selling fried fucking butter.
And I'm like,
why?
That is the most disgusting fucking
thing I've ever heard in my life.
God dammit. I have to
try it. I got to try it.
I have to see what it is.
Like I made a little fucking
youtube video. Actually,
I got to have the kid I was with made a
little video of me trying that little,
uh,
yeah,
delicacy, that little
Texas delicacy. Dude,
it was the most disgusting fucking thing
I ever had. I've asked, the guy said,
all right,
well,
first thing I want to do was get the fried
Oreo because evidently that was a big
hit. That kind of made sense to me.
Fried Oreo is fucked up is that is,
I would figure because it's fried,
it's going to be salty,
but then you've got the sugary cookie
to kind of offset the two. You know,
it's Kinda like,
you know,
you did some lines and now you're drinking
some alcohol to even yourself out.
Same fucking thing. Just in
a food way. Right. So, uh,
I went over to that one first and I go,
yeah, let me get in. The guy's like,
I don't, I'm like, yeah, let me get
one of those fried Oreos, Oreo cookies.
And he goes, ah, I'm sorry. We can't,
we can't cook yet until the
health inspector comes up and, uh,
and gives us the,
okay,
the Elton Elton Health inspector has
to inspect our booth first. So my law,
next logical question was like, well,
how do you think you're going to do,
I know, locked into a restaurant,
like, hang on a second.
I loved my having given sandwich.
Let's just have the health inspector
go through first. Let's just see a,
we have an acceptable amount
of roaches. So I said, fuck it.
And I went straight to the fried butter
and evidently they had already been
inspected. And I said, all
right, hang out. And he goes,
well, how can I help you?
I go, I got to get some of that fried
butter. And the guy goes, all right,
what do you want? You want original? You
want something else to something else?
And I go, let me get the original. And
he goes, all right. And he goes, uh,
uh, he, yes, he said that your
choice of toppings. I forget
what the fuck they were,
but I went with the Welch's grape jelly.
I know this is disgusting.
You know what's funny is probably as
somebody working on treadmill right now
listening
to this feeling a lot better about
themselves. So they basically,
they look like these little Dino's
Duncan Munchkins or doughnut holes.
That's what it looked like. Okay. And
then there was like the grape jelly,
there was, there was the uh, the Great
Jelly, sorry, my phone keeps ringing.
Um, so I dip it in the grape jelly
and I took a bite out of it and do it.
It was the most disgusting fucking
thing I've ever tasted in my life.
It tasted like a flavor list doughnut.
And then you know,
that awful gum that has this squirting
inside that was like the inside,
except it was butter. It was just
a little nugget of like butter.
It was fucking gross.
And it was so disgusting.
I had to have another
one because you know one,
you know one for each ventricle
over ventricles, you get,
I forgot more than two.
Maybe that's why I'm still fucking living.
I don't know what,
but I had another one just to be like
is was it that bad and a yes it was,
it was a
okay.
It was wrong. It was just,
that's all I can say.
I was just fucking wrong and
should not be done. And uh,
yeah,
I'm just gonna leave it dad.
I think I'm gonna end the podcast right
here cause I'm out of stories and a
Jesus Christ, my fucking phone wants
to, I got it. I have a voicemail,
I'm going to New York next week and I'm
going to get my blackberry when I get a
new blackberry again. I didn't get one
out in la cause if you do it out in la,
they can't give you a New York number,
you know?
And I want to keep that number just
because at this point I've had the number
forever. You know, I don't want to
have to call fucking 9,000 people.
Okay.
I Dunno. I Dunno what the fuck
I'm talking about. All right.
This has been the Monday morning podcast.
I Apologize I didn't have any a,
they didn't have any
questions this week did I?
I don't have anything cause I couldn't
get to my email. I had a couple,
this is September 24th.
Um,
all right, I'm going to read one here. Um,
this is actually a commenting
on rugby and women. All right.
Here we go up bill, after hearing your
show this week regarding rugby, um,
where you asked whether or not any
rugby player has played in the NFL,
I decided to do some research on
the subject. Uh, what I found out,
yeah.
Um,
is that there have been several rugby
players who have crossed over to play in
the NFL.
Many of their names won't ring a bell
because it appears they are all kickers
and punters. The two names that came
up the most often were Ben Graham,
a kicker, who I think
played for the jets. And
Mick Luckhurst was also a kicker who
played for the Falcons from 1981 to 1987.
What I found funny was that the rugby
guys who attempted to try out for other
positions such as linebacker or running
back or often considered too small,
too slow or too weak to do damage on
the field against a much larger NFL
players.
Um,
now I know a lot of people in England
are going to flip out about that shit.
Well,
you know what?
They say that all the time that American
football players are a bunch of pussies
because they wear helmets
and all that type of shit.
Well,
I got news for you.
There's a great article in Gq magazine
that I actually read and I never read Gq
because a,
it's kind of like the male cosmo where
you just open it up and there's a ton of
articles,
not articles as a ton of advertising.
You can't find where the fucking
articles are and it smells like Cologne.
I swear to God it does. It's really
a fucking, it's a really, uh,
awful magazine. But I got
to tell you this, there was,
there's a woman on the
cover of this magazine,
Olivia Wilde might be the most beautiful
woman I've ever seen in my life.
She's just ridiculous. And I was like
I have to read this article about this,
this,
this female.
And it turned out there was an article
in there about concussions and above
football players going crazy
and killing themselves.
Professional football players.
And they were talking about Mike Webster,
the center for the Pittsburgh Steelers.
It's an unbelievable article.
It's a Olivia Wilde is on the cover.
And basically they were saying the helmets
cause that's the number one thing I
hear these English guys can say anything,
you know American football players or
pussy cause they were like the helmets in
the pads. Evidently the all the
helmet does is it protects the skull.
It doesn't protect the brain cause
the brain sits in like fluid and moves
around. So when you get slammed in the
side of the head and not only mentioned,
they were saying the way they build these
helmets is back when they had leather
helmets. You know, back in the
days, the three stooges days,
if you watch the guys play football,
they didn't lead with their heads
because you'd get knocked out.
But now in an effort
to protect their heads,
they were basically saying what they've
done with these helmets is they created
a weapon. And these football players,
especially the Lyman, every play,
if you watch them, they just slam
into each other with their heads.
And I have a deadly, they're doing
unbelievable amounts of brain damage.
And Mike Webster's brain,
he basically,
he went crazy and he couldn't
fucking remember shit. So
they, during the autopsy,
they removed his brain,
they sliced it in half.
And he had lists all [inaudible]
f I don't know that this plaque,
I don't know what they called it,
but it was like a,
they said it should have been the brain
of like an 89 or 90 year old guy in this
guy died at 50. So, uh,
I'm not saying that rugby guys
are pussies or anything like that.
I was just giving people shit or whatever,
but I'm just defending American
football players saying that, you know,
just cause they have that fucking
helmet on. You know what I mean?
I find that really interesting.
Like,
cause I used to always watch
guys riding motorcycles.
My duty out of your fucking mind.
Do you realize the brain damage you're
going to get if your head slams off a
curb like Gary Busey did and uh,
evidently obviously you know, if
you're wearing a helmet, you know,
you protect and you know from literally
putting a hole in your head so you
should wear it.
But you know,
I'd never really dawned on me obviously
because I'm a comedian and not a fucking
that just be, you can have a
helmet on and your brain can,
you can have just as much, I think
basically just as much brain damage.
I think what you would have to have
is some sort of like hard shell in the
middle and then like 80 feet of nerf
on the outside of our spongy fucking
material on the outside.
So you would have to start to slow
your head down before it came to the,
to the, uh, what am I trying to
say? I think beyond a certain speed,
it doesn't make a difference whether
you have a fucking helmet on or not,
because your brain is going to slam
against the inside of your skull.
So fucking hard, uh, that is not
going to matter. And they go,
that's coming from a comedian. So, you
know, it's, it's medically accurate.
All right, let's move on here. Um,
and once again, to those people in,
I have no disrespect. It was rugby
guys are fucking tough sons of bitches.
I have no, but no, no,
uh, questions about that.
But you really have to stop saying that
American football players are pussies
because they have pads on
those fucking guys. You know,
you wouldn't want to play rugby against
them. Put it that way. All right.
All right, let's plow ahead here.
Alright, Bill. Uh, you also stated some,
some ways you can tell when you've
won an argument with the woman. Um,
stuff like the crying
and when they begin to,
to switch your words to talk about past
topics in the middle of an argument.
Yeah. They bring up other shit that you
did because they're losing the shit that
you're talking about right then and there.
I guess guys do that too. But anyways,
let's plow ahead here. He said, well,
I have a better one on my way to work.
My wife and I were arguing over me hurting
her feelings because I came home from
a 10 hour day at work and three and a
half hours of night school just wanting to
go to bed. So even though my sexy
Latin woman was in, it was a,
was ready for some action,
I simply took a shower,
crawled into bed next to her and went to
sleep. Needless to say, she was pissed.
So this morning we were
fussing about it and she says,
that really hurt my feelings,
um,
because it felt like you didn't
want me. And he said, um,
and I don't know what, what came over me.
But instead of being an angry black man,
I simply smiled, grabbed her,
grabbed her hand, kissed it,
and commonly said in a soft voice,
now you know how I felt last week
and she said absolutely nothing.
She just stared at me like she wanted
to start the waterworks but she couldn't
get it going.
I dropped her off at the office where
she kissed me and actually apologized.
I smiled the entire way to work.
Wow.
I actually thought she was going to get
mad because that was kind of harsh the
way you said it. That's like stand
up, applause, break, stand up comedy.
Well now you know I fell
last week if fucking Twat.
That's how I would have delivered it.
But I guess you said it nicely and calmly,
but yeah,
you know that is kind of fucked up.
That's one of the things that I have
found like in relationship is, you know,
you've got to watch out because
for the most, I think I would,
I would venture to guess without
doing a survey as always,
I would venture to guess
that 92% of relationships,
women control the sex because guys
will do it basically whenever.
I really sound like a hacky comedian guys,
we don't give a shit woo woo,
but it seriously, and then
women kind of use it as a, uh,
they start using. Yeah, he's still
a bit about that as a reward.
You took out the trash here at good boy
and you get like a hand job. You know,
you can't do that if you really
want to equalize, you know,
the whole sex in your relationship.
You why you gotta you gotta continue to
rub one out every once in awhile so that
way you know, if they don't want to
have sex and you're like, all right,
that's cool. You know and then,
yeah, keep it. Keep eye on any,
then you're creating a war
because I would say then what you do
is next time they want to have it,
then you act like you don't have it.
That's not the way to go about doing
it because then you start playing games
with each other. What you probably
should say is a, I don't know,
just basically what I've said to
women, which is, Oh yeah, bell,
we should say exactly what you said cause
you have your fucking life figured out.
You fucking single 40 year old
psychopath. Yeah. Once again,
I want to say don't ever
listen to what I say on here.
You know I am not a trained person and
I'm worried at some point someone's going
to take my advice,
they're going to get punched in
the face and I'm going to get sued.
So you've got to understand that you're
talking to a comedian here who's may be
read three books in his life. Two of
them had pictures on every other page.
All right. That's, that's what you're
dealing with now. She, I'm telling you,
the big thing with women is if you want
to get your way, is not to get mad,
not to play a fucking game with them.
You just have to tell them
how what they're doing is
making you feel they can't
get around it if you have a legitimate
complaint, you know, let me see.
I got something ridiculous like,
Hey,
I want to put it in your
ass and you won't let me.
And it's really making me feel like
you don't trust me. I mean, that's,
I think you're going to lose
that one. All right. But um,
oh Jesus, I'm sorry to get back on
track here. If you fucking, you know,
like some serious like that where
you just like, look, you know,
I feel like anytime you want to have sex,
I'm willing,
but there's a lot of times I want to
have it and you don't want to have it.
And that was so now I kind of feel like
this thing that we're allegedly sharing
together,
you totally control and uh,
that doesn't make me happy.
Thoughts,
whatever you put flour the fuck you say
it. You said calmly without saying, fuck,
and I'm telling you,
well, what can they do?
They got to sit there and answer
it and I can guarantee you that'll,
that'll work out good for you for at
least three fucking days before it slides
back to normal again. It's a
never ending fight. All right?
But what you gotta do is
you've got to have the fights.
You got to have the fights
and protect your real estate.
Or are you going to spend,
you're going to spend your entire
time and goal line fucking d.
That's the worst fucking relationship
you've given up so many fucking the whole
time.
It's fourth and goal first and goal.
What am I talking about first
and fucking goal, right?
And you just jumped off side. So it's
half the distance to the fucking go.
We got it built. You're in
a bad situation. All right,
that's all I'm saying. Okay.
That's the end of the podcast. Thank
you everybody for listening. All right,
here's what I got coming up.
I'm going to be at the stress
factory in New Brunswick, New Jersey,
coming up this Friday,
Saturday and Sunday. Well, what
are the dates, bill? Well,
why don't you hold on a second
and I'll get them for you.
God knows I can't go on the fucking
Internet. Um, that's going to be a Friday.
Um, October 2nd. Oh my God.
Where is this year going?
Saturday, October 3rd
and Sunday, October 4th,
I am going to be, um, at the stress
factory in New Brunswick, New Jersey,
fans of the OPN,
Anthony and little Jiminny
Jiminny radio program.
I'm going to be on there on a Friday,
September 2nd,
and I believe Monday, Friday,
October 2nd, and I believe Monday,
October 5th,
uh,
those two days I am going
to be in studio with, uh,
my best friends of all time in
radio, the OPN, Anthony Show.
Really excited to see them,
sons of bitches again. And um,
after that I am going to be
at the Improv in Pittsburgh,
Pennsylvania on October 8th,
October 9th and October 10th.
And I will be,
um,
with Randy Bowman on DV for
all you Pittsburgh people.
I will be on the morning radio program
on October 7th, eighth and ninth.
So please listen. And, uh, and that is it.
I appreciate all you guys
listening to my podcast.
I apologize that I had to put this one
up on Tuesday, but I'm fighting the man,
man. All right. I'm fucking with
you. You guys all have good week.
God bless all of you.
Take it easy.
[inaudible]
beep,
beep.
[inaudible] [inaudible]
[inaudible]
[inaudible].