Hey, what's going on? It's Bill Bur and
It's time for the Thursday afternoon.
Just before Friday,
Monday morning podcast and
just checking in on you.
What's going on now?
Why Ya? Um, I'm fucking,
ah, I didn't want to get into
it. We're up to episode 10.
I have no life. I'm trying to fucking,
and I'm trying to get in a quick workout
before I go to work because I am,
I'm fucking right back up to where I was
last year when I was like a buck 86 one
87. I am, I f you. It kills
me. I've been working out.
Why do you walk out? You still put on, um,
you know, it is, it's late night. I'm
coming home. I'm eating like a fat chick,
you know, meeting like some sad
fellow doesn't like himself.
I just come home and I'm fucking fried.
I get home at like seven o'clock
at night and I go, ah, fuck it.
That's what I say. I get all
the way to my street going,
I'm going to get a salad.
I've got to have a protein.
I'm going to fucking eat the
bag of beans or whatever,
and then I just drive into my
driveway and I go, ah, fuck it. Right.
And I order a fucking
pizza or burger, you know,
or I have a beer or something like
that and MIH had, that's it. That's it.
I go to my looks, I got them on my
fucking second trimester right now. Oh,
is this my wife the other day
and went to a fucking mall,
which is something I never do. Go
into a fucking mall. Right? You know,
people go to a malls, people
with children. I get it.
You get them out there,
they fucking watched the trolley go by
and you know Santa Claus is there. Right?
Just fucking sit there waiting for
you to put your kid in his lap.
You fucking Weirdos, right? Hey,
let's keep the lie going to the point we
put our child in some fucking perverts
fucking lap. So they think he comes
down, the Goddamn Chimi Mija gets,
is there any wonder? So many people
end up in cars they don't want to be,
and that's, that's how you start out
their life. You know, some fucking dude,
we don't know, you know, don't really
talk to sort of Godlike, you know,
sort of culty right? Charlie Manson hair,
all fucking A's fucking coming
in and everything's cool.
You go sit in his fucking lap, but
don't talk to strangers. Right? I don't,
I don't fucking,
I'm just so whenever we go to this
fucking thing and we're walking by the
fountain, right? There's a trolley and a
fountain. This is like the fucking gay,
his place you could ever go to. And I
don't mean gay in like the homophobic way.
I mean, the way it used to mean
like the 1890s, the gay nineties,
as in, Oh my God, could a
decade get any happier? Right?
It was everything but fucking
showgirls coming down, you know,
like the end of the family guy song.
That was the only thing that was missing.
And it's, I just was like, what is
all the excitement? We're fucking,
everybody's here buying pants. Why
are we having a fucking parade?
You know? So I went in there and
I, I took her to go see the, uh,
the lives of pets, which I really
enjoyed. Cause you know, I'm a dog,
right? I love fucking dogs. And
you know what, I was curious,
what does my dog do when I leave?
Evidently they have quite the adventures.
Yeah,
that was a fucking really
good movie. I liked it.
And that was a bunch of kids in there
screaming and yelling and that's what I
wanted. You know what I mean? And
I went to the matinee show and,
and just have a bunch of
kids screaming and yeah,
I wanted the full effect of watching
that fucking movie. You know what I mean?
It's like when you go to a horror movie,
you gotta go see it and there's going
to be a bunch of people yelling at the
screen right at either that, that's
part of the fucking experience.
If you want to go see a movie, when
everybody shuts the fuck up, you know,
you got to do it in your house.
Maybe slap a few people around before
the movie starts, you know, set the tone.
Daddy ain't putting up with this
shit. All right. So anyways,
long story short and I dressed up a little
bit when I went down there. You know,
I've been working a lot, so
I'm going to take out my lady.
So when we're walking out, we'll
go and buy the fountain, you know?
And there's like all, you know, like
the plane, like fucking Tony Bennett.
If I ruled the world every day would
be like the first day of spring.
Every douche would have such a wonderful
song to sing. If I ruled the world,
what a wonderful world it would be.
And everybody's just
sitting there mesmerized,
eaten this fucking ice cream
and shit. Yeah, bide pants.
It was fucking weird, man. It
was like, when you go to this,
you go to some of these fucking malls.
It's like you're in a Christmas special.
I'm telling you, I wouldn't be surprised
if they got a fucking Mesta right.
And they're putting some sorta like,
like little little dopamine in the air
and you get like this fucking high and
all of a sudden you're
like, you know what?
I already have fucking nine
pairs of pants. Uh, one more.
I'm in the double digits seven days
in the week. I want the overlap.
I'm going to go over the bar line, right?
Like Vinny call Yoda in a pet's way.
Um,
okay.
So anyways, so I go, all
right, I'm, I'm gonna,
I don't know what had came over me. We
walked by the fountain. I said, I need,
let's get a picture.
She's like [inaudible] she
couldn't fucking believe it.
I was going to take a picture next
to, in front of a fountain at a mall.
This is not me behavior. Right?
Of course she's all over it.
Women love that tie. Oh my God.
That'd be so nice. Right. You just,
it just makes you want to start crying
like, oh, what happened to me? Right.
So all I want to do is take a fucking
selfie. Right, right. You know,
get up fucking heads in it.
My head taken up three quarters of it
cause it's so fucking big and some Douche
has to come along and be
like, oh, you will all,
we'll take the parish before you.
And I'm thinking, no, I want you to,
I don't want to prolong this moment.
You fucking asshole. Where's your guy?
Cold. Of course my wife goes, oh
my God, that would be great. Right?
So what does he do? He
fucking takes one. Oh,
let's get one more for
right. Takes another one.
Oh my God. And I look at this picture
in the fucking horror that I see.
Okay.
My fucking stomach pushing out the
bottom of my button down shirt.
And then when you really just know
you're just getting fat is that fucking
button right? Uh, right
on your breast plate.
It looks like it's doing the iron cross.
Just trying to hold both parts
of the shirt together. And uh,
I looked so fucking bad. I
almost got mad at my wife.
Like you letting me walk around
looking like that. It's like,
I get that you love me, but you know,
how about a little bit of tough love?
You know, how about a little,
hey, fatty cakes, you know,
you really going to have
waffles again this morning.
Exhibit a right? And you're bust
out a fucking photo you took of me.
Nothing will make you lose weight. Like
a bad fucking photo. Huh? Jesus Christ.
You know, it's bad enough when they
catch it in your own backyard, you know?
But I'll tell you, you
take a photo in public,
in front of a fucking fountain at a mall
that has a trolley while Tony Bennett's
playing. I mean, I'm glad I didn't
look at it until I got home.
I would've fucking jumped in 10 a sailors
dive right into the bottom of that
fountain.
Okay?
Yeah. I'm too vain to kill
myself. I'll just hang around.
Make everybody else miserable. That's
what you do. That's what you do. Um,
oh, by the way, I w I finally, I
watched the, uh, the record of the, uh,
the British Grand Prix, um,
fascinating fucking race with all the
rain there who's gonna go in and change
the tires? Who's going to keep
going? And by fucking lap seven,
everybody changed their
fucking tires, right?
It kinda seems if you get Paul position,
you're basically going to win the race.
These guys are so good in the cars
are so equal. You can't, I don't have,
I've never seen nobody does this stroke,
a race thing where you're way in the back
and all of a sudden you know your past
three people and you do the
little Zz top fucking ole move.
You know, remember fucking movie. He's,
he goes by three cars that are all fucking
in line drafting each other and I've
watched enough NASCAR who has to scold
bearing the Harry Gant car, right?
Darrell Waltrip, Cale Yarborough.
I watched enough of that shit to know if
two people that draft and they're going
to slingshot around you, I'll tell you
what, not when Burt Reynolds is there,
I don't know what he did. Did
he take off his two pains,
stick his head out the window and
make himself a little more fucking
aerodynamic? Is that how he went
by three cars? I don't know.
Fastest chicken in the south. That
shit does not happen in Formula One.
If you're not one of the top three
fucking drivers of the Illuminati,
you're basically, as far as I can tell,
the five races I've ever watched
from star stat to finish,
you're not going to win
the Goddamn race, you know,
unless the two guys up front don't like
each other and they smash into each
other. Jesus Christ,
Louis Hamilton and Nico Rosberg
right at the end of the fucking race.
Lewis Hamilton wins it, right guys from
fucking England, everybody island man.
What? Everybody's going fucking
nuts and a, as I mentioned before,
those two don't like each other
though. He smashing into each other,
so in the end they always show the green
room afterwards, after somebody one and
okay.
It was just like they didn't
say one word to each other.
Fucking meow fellows.
They didn't say one five.
I think the fucking Todo Guy.
All I want to do and I wake up in the
morning is feel your ass. When he fell,
he fucking set the two of them down. He
goes, listen, you [inaudible] all right.
I know you went out there and
you watched stroke arrays.
I know you watch that Kenny Rogers
movie where he adopts the six kids,
but never really legally, and nobody
had a fucking problem with that.
I know you watch days at thunder.
All right? This ain't that.
This cost real fucking money. Stop
smashing into each other. All right?
Yeah,
no, I'll take you back to Germany and
I'll reopen the, I can't go that far. Uh,
Oh, the Germans, you know,
I'm telling you right now,
if you take out about 10 years of their
history, they're great people. Um,
anyway, you pick one wrong guy. That's
what's so scary about this fucking,
this election.
I think that they should make Trump
and Hillary both put on a Hitler mask.
Matt on the mask,
put on a Hitler fucking mustache
and whoever looks the closest,
you vote for the other person.
Okay?
You know what? The results may surprise
you. Somebody make a clickbait. Fucking,
I'm a clickbait fucking whatever the
hell you call the meme or the, the,
the, the fucking vine. You know,
we put both the presidential
candidates in a Hitler Mass,
a Hitler mustache. Why can't I talk
this morning and Hitler Mustache,
the results may surprise you.
Okay.
And just, you know, whoever you're for,
you just make the other person, I guess.
Yeah, I don't, I don't know how you, I
don't know how you bring that one home.
You know all you kids today. Oh, you
fucking internet superstars. You know,
I went into a place the other day to get
some lunch of fucking salad with some
chicken, right. Desperately trying to
fucking bring down the belly. You know,
fucking Moba Day is what it look like
right now. You know, shaved head,
fucking ghost, white body. You know,
there's a lot of blubber on me right now.
You know, if I was to swim in the ocean,
my biggest fear would not be sharks.
You know,
it'd be some hipsters out there fucking
whale hunting cause they thought,
you know, they were taking it back. Right.
Get fucking Harpoon there. Um,
okay.
The fuck was I talking about? Oh yeah.
So I went in to go get this fucking salad
and I'm standing there and there's a
guy in line wearing a fucking Versace
robe, gold, Versace robe. And slippers.
So I text my wife going, there's
a dude in here, you know? Yeah.
Do you want me to take a picture?
You gotta see this guy, right?
So I fucking take a picture of the
guy. And she was like, oh my God,
my friend knows that person.
He makes these vines, right?
So then I clicked on his youtube page
and the guys now, whatever Twitter page,
the guy's fucking hilarious
and I'm just sitting,
they go is this fucking guy?
He doesn't need to be in a writers room
while he's has his own fucking show.
And he gets to walk around his bath
robe and slippers all day making cooking
videos. God bless him. I don't
know what the point of all this is.
I think the point of all this is I need
to get back on elliptical soon so I
don't have a fucking heart
attack before I go to, uh,
I'm going to say the Middle East
before I go to the fucking, um,
go over to England. Uh, anyways, so yeah,
I gotta fucking knock this shit.
I gotta knock off this
podcast and then I have a,
okay.
Actually I have some people coming over
here because our kitchen's all fucked
up. You know what's wrong bill?
What's wrong with the kitchen? Oh,
I don't know whether you put on
the hot water or the cold water.
The hot water still comes out, you know,
problem. I fixed fucking nine times.
You've got to shut off the fucking
hot water. The handle comes off.
Cupboards are all falling apart, you know,
everything else in the
house is pretty much nice.
I probably shouldn't even say
that shit. So, um, I got this,
like the final fucking thing I
have to do. You know what I mean?
Cause I fixed up the rest of the house.
I'm hoping it's the final
fucking thing I have to do.
But if for the most part I
fixed up the rest of the house.
And so now like the kitchen has
become like this ice I saw, you know,
it'd be like if you bought a brand new
suit and they had these old shitty shoes,
you know, and people looked down and
they were just like, you know what,
I was going to get in
business with this guy,
but what the fuck is with
those shoes? See you.
What are you fucking Willy Loman
there? You fucking Willy Loman.
Um, so that nightmare project
is about ready to start.
People coming over today with
their ideas. I have an idea.
Like what if we just took
everything out and put new stuff in,
in the exact same place except for a
couple of things and it costs you fucking
three zillion dollars. How about that?
I could be rustic yet
modern yet postmodern,
but kind of our deco ish,
but doesn't compromise the
integrity of the structure.
All right,
I'm signing up for that shit again.
Um, but you know what though,
you know that they can probably put
it into six weeks. In other words,
in about nine months, I think
it ought to be done breathing.
And a bunch of dust. I'll have
fucking, um, coal miner's daughter,
lung, whatever the fuck they
call it. I have no idea. Um,
we don't have any Goddamn, um, I
don't have any questions on this one.
And I also don't have any
advertising. You know,
I will do some advertising here. Uh,
Tuesday night I went back
to the troubadour and I saw
wheeler walker jr right.
You say it's over. Pack up your stuff.
Something, something you've had enough.
I'm that fuck you bitch.
You broke my heart.
Fuck you Franz. Tearing us apart.
Fuck your dog open. Never comes home.
I saw that guy fucking live, man.
It was what? I wonder
what a fun fucking show.
I'm just great in the bands killer.
The Bass player actually plays in
one of my favorite fucking bands,
truth and salvage company.
He's on the road with them,
had a killer band and the dude comes out,
wheeler walker jr he fucking murdered
it. Absolutely fucking murdered it.
Um, I didn't know what to expect
when I went down there. You know,
when somebody goes down there, they're
doing funny songs. You're like, go,
I don't know what's gonna happen here.
Is this going to be like a one joke
song and then you fucking like still
standing there for another
45 minutes. It was,
it was great and he was fucking
hilarious in between songs,
his band or what the crowd,
what I'm saying is if you get a chance
to see wheeler walker jr he's coming to a
fucking club near you
theater near you arena.
Fucking a amphitheatre
a a car port. I don't know.
I'm trying to think of every
structure I can think of.
Definitely go out and see him. He's, he's,
he's absolutely worth the money
and uh, and the band sounds great.
And he had, uh, on another
band open up in front of him,
two ladies with guitars. They were
great just to fucking kill a show.
And I ran into a bunch of
comics when I was there,
ran into Doug Benson and all these other
guys. Look at me dropping names here,
dropping fucking names and I sat there
in the back of the club and I just drank
water all night cause I'm fucking fat.
All right. I'm not gonna lie to you.
I had one whiskey, you know,
you've got to have one. You know,
even John Wayne would have one, you know,
before he ate half a fucking
cow that he barely cooked.
Isn't that what happened to him? You
know, that's what, you know what happened?
All those guys back in the day,
they just kept eating red meat because
back then it was all about, Whoa,
you know, why would I eat hamburger
when I got steak at home? Right?
Isn't that what they said?
And weren't they literally talking about
food considering what most of them died
of? I know that was
about their ladies. Um,
but anyways, uh, back then, right,
if you will like a guys guy, you are
eating steak. If you were fucking,
if you were successful,
it was considered the highest
cut of fucking meat and all that.
You didn't realize it was tearing apart
your fucking guts and back then there's
no way you let another man fucking look
in your ass to make sure you weren't
going to die of ass cancer. Right?
There's no fucking way you could do that.
And then get on a horse
and call yourself a cowboy.
That's not what it was about. All right.
He kept eating steak then.
Yet when you, when you would,
your wife was done making the steak,
you fucking fucking wrapped it with the
frying pan. I said, clean it up, right?
Then you went over and you put butter
on the steak and then that was it.
And I think it was better for
the environment back then.
You know what I mean?
Women were being beaten,
so they were drinking themselves to death.
So they died earlier and guy's fucking
ate themselves to death. And you know,
people got out of the way and there
was only like fucking a couple billion
people on the planet. Now look at
everybody. Everybody's doing yoga.
Nobody's beating their wives, right?
Everybody's having a fucking salad.
And now there's seven and a half
billion people on the fucking planet.
You know? And I think it's high time
that we go back to the way it was,
you know, oh, whatever. We'll
let Hillary becomes president.
And at the end of her 48 year run,
then it goes back to
the fucking dark ages.
We go back to a feudal system,
the real one, you know,
where you're actually aware of what was
happening rather than now where it's
just banker's fucking silently sucking
the life out of the fucking middle cloud.
Jesus. Bill, you're going to get on a
fucking, you know, fucking kills me.
Bernie Sanders,
arguably the scientists from back to
the future fucking endorses Hillary
Clinton. Get it. Can
you fucking any of them?
Can any of them just fucking have a
point of view and just stick with it?
They're always like,
this is what I'm above.
You could vote for me because I'm
above this. Right. And then the second,
all of a sudden they start taking on
water or this or the thing that's working.
Speaking of water. Do you know
there's more shark attacks than ever
and they're doing fucking stories about
what should we do about this? It's like,
well, you know, you could not
swim in the ocean. You'd dumb con.
There's plenty of fucking, there's
plenty of lakes. You know what I mean?
You know, Shit, fill up your bathtub, you
know, have make a day in it, you know,
but a snorkel on it. Stare at your
balls. I mean, do whatever you gotta do,
but don't go in the fucking water. Right.
Why do you think there's more shark
attacks now? Well, two reasons. One,
there's more fucking people until
we're eating all the fucking fish.
So the menu is becoming more
limited. You know, back in the day,
shark could be like, oh look at that
fucking surfboard. Or Eh, you know,
like the fucking bore gets between my
teeth. It's not that that tougher mate.
You know, he's still in politeness.
And I had quote and I'll look at that,
the school of tuna, Toro, Toro, right?
I'm going to go over there
and fucking have some total.
All those options aren't there anymore.
And these people still go out there
and that boogie boards, right?
If you've got on a boogie board,
you're like a slider, like children,
children on Boogie boards. That's
like a slider now for a fucking shark.
And then you get to the a, you get
to the bigger people. You know,
I'll tell you right now how fat I am.
There's no fucking way
I would go out there.
They'd think I was a fucking sea lion,
an albino sea lion that got shunned
by the rest of the herd. You know,
is there anything worse than watching a
fucking animal on one of those animals
shows getting shunned by the
rest of the herd. You know,
animals are like super fucking racist.
I don't know what it is to second
somebody, a fucking albino.
They show a little bit a weakness. I mean,
they're really people and you
never hear Peter Bring that up.
Okay.
I mean sure they sit there and they talk
about how bad human beings are. Hey,
you know, guilty as charged.
You're looking at it. I'd be,
I've gone down to fucking
Kentucky Fried Chicken.
I've eaten their beatless
chicken. You know,
all walking around roided up like
McGuire and fucking Sosa fallen on their
fucking faces. Cause people like
the white meat more. You know,
I've eaten that shit
guilty's fucking charge.
But what they don't talk about
is how those fucking chickens,
if they were allowed to
keep their beaks, you know,
and not have chest so
big that they fell down,
they would be bullying the
fucking weak as hen, you know,
you don't deserve to have children, right.
Just go over and they'd pack her to
death and they never, you know, they go,
you know, that's just how they are.
Okay.
You know,
it's survival of the fittest and all
that shit and then all of a sudden human
beings start doing it, right.
Some fucking nerd gets thrown into a
locker and all of a sudden it's this
national fucking story.
I think when human beings is going
to turn it around as the day,
we just admit that we're just a
bunch of fucking animals. You know?
I have no idea what I'm talking about.
I just, I have not looked at any news.
I don't know what this fucking
Pokemon thing is about.
Everybody's talking about it. I
finally asked somebody at work,
I know that there's like,
okay,
I know it was a movie. I
know kids were in toward,
I guess just people running
around with their phones,
trying to find the pokemons to,
to capture them in the
middle of the fucking day.
We were in the writers room and these
kids ran up to this dumpster and it was
like a fucking Wednesday afternoon.
It's like, don't you have to go to work?
Shouldn't you be somewhere
right now? You know what I mean?
She'd be out there blaming
your parents for something. Um,
I don't know.
It's really making that pope Pokemon
things really making me feel old.
Okay.
Everybody like is going around.
A lot of people going around doing it
and then there's people watching people
doing it.
So it's like they're not doing anything
and then you're watching them doing
nothing. It's kind of
fucking weird, right?
It's like, I saw this thing
the other day, you know,
on roller coasters now that
some of the new roller coasters,
they're having people get on the roller
coaster and then you put on virtual
reality glasses, right? And it's like,
it's not enough to be on the roller
coaster and then you gotta be on the,
put the glasses on and you go up the
hill and then as you go over the top and
you had that big drop,
they make it feel as though you're
falling off of a building or something.
It's like, well, you know, you're
kind of doing that in real life.
Why don't you take them off and enjoy
it? I don't, you know what it is,
it's all of us just slowly but
surely working our way to robots,
you know, having a robot, mom and
dad and these fucking, you know,
I ran into some nerd the other day
that was into fucking robotics,
believe it or not.
Okay.
Did this benefit for a,
that tragedy there in Orlando, right?
Do you guys remember that tragedy or is
there have been 52 more fucking shooting
since then that people don't
even remember it. Right.
So we did a benefit for that and um,
okay,
I'm standing out in the alley afterwards
having a fucking cigar, right?
And this kid comes up, I call him a kid.
That means he was like 26 years old and
he was fucking talking about how he's
into robotics and all this type
of shit. And I was just like,
why are you doing that? What about
in way he wasn't in a robotics?
What the fuck was he into?
Okay.
It was into some shit that would just
basically gather information on the user
without the person really knowing
it. And it's just like, why?
Why are you doing that? You know? And
he's going, well, but blah, blah, blah,
blah, blah.
And I just kept hammering them with
the questions and hammer them with the
questions. And at the end of the day,
the only way he could defend what he,
what he was doing was he, he
basically said this, well, you know,
if I didn't do it, someone else
would right there. That's the devils.
That's the devil song right there.
Hi, how high? How if I didn't do it,
someone else would it does it
rhyme? Who gives a fuck? I hope.
Let's go fucking do something evil.
That's might've been the worst song ever.
If you have to justify your fucking
job by basically say, you know,
if I didn't do it, somebody
else would. What jobs are those
spying on people dealing drugs,
right?
Fucking, I don't know what
shooting porno, dropping bombs.
I mean, anytime. The only way to
justify your job is if I didn't do it,
somebody else would,
uh, you know, I dunno.
Okay.
But these fucking assholes
making these robots, man, they,
they're making them too good. I
used to do a bit about it. You know,
that basic, you know, I don't mind if
you make the fucking thing super smart.
Just don't have it be able to
run like fucking Bo Jackson,
which is what they're doing.
Cause they keep trying to improve it and
they're fucking competing with somebody
out some other con, uh, companies,
fucking robot and they're just making
the thing into the $6 million man.
It's like, guys, guys,
okay,
you're already stuck every fucking answer
to any question ever. And it between,
it's fucking non-existent. Metal fucking
ears, I guess. It has metal lists,
non-existent human years and now you're
going to be able to make it run a
fucking four 40 you know like this, this
thing knows the answers to everything.
Right.
You Know Anna, Anna can make the
fucking Seahawks secondary at that.
That's what the fuck you're building
and you don't think that that's going to
come back and bite us in the ass.
It knows the answer to everything.
So it basically knows how to do open heart
surgery and also how to load and fire
an AK 47 fly an f six stayed.
I mean it's limitless.
Like you remember those fucking action
movies where like the fucking, this the,
the hero, the movie. I don't care.
Kind of mode of transportation
of fucking boat and helicopter,
a motorcycle, this space shuttle.
This fucking guy knows how to use it.
No preflight, you just start
the fucking helicopter.
Ropy yanked the guts out of it. You know,
I took a ride in a fucking ace star
the other day and there's no fiber.
I wouldn't be able to figure out
how to fucking start that thing up.
I got over it. I got,
I got 120 hours flying a Robinson 22.
You stick me in an a star. It's
like, hey kids, a little help.
These fucking Rambo guys,
these Steven Seagal guys,
these muscles from Brussels
guys, Chuck Norris, right,
Eddie D's, all of them.
They just fucking ran up and could just
do it and used to always laugh going,
that's fucking bull. Anybody, you know,
if you had a boat, you'd just be like,
wow, what if, what do you know where the
fucking keys were? Just jumps right in.
The fucking keys are right there.
And he knows exactly where
the fucking throttle is.
He doesn't have to look around and get
his bearings like, hey, this is this.
That's that. He just fucking
jumps in like it's his boat.
And it always makes you laugh going, yeah,
that would never happen in real life.
Well, guess what? In 2016,
that's going to happen.
These fucking robots.
I don't know why they would be running
away and they're not going to be running
away from us. They're going to be
running after us. And, uh, you know,
they get sick of fucking
running, which why would they,
they don't have a respiratory system
as long as they're charged up like a
fucking Tesla. They're never gonna
stop, but it doesn't make a difference.
What mode of transportation,
what weapon is nearby?
That was another thing with those
action heroes, whatever. Fucking they,
they'd pick up a goddamn garden and hoe
and all of a sudden this spinning around
like Bruce Slick. It's like,
Jesus, we will you in band.
You when you were a major red too,
you went time to fucking
master all the martial arts.
Learn how to use not only
every mode of transportation,
every fucking aberration of that
fucking mode of transportation.
Is that the right word? You know,
every style of fucking boat.
I don't give a fuck if it's sailing.
If it's a submarine or
a fucking cruise ship,
you know how to get that fucking thing
going and to docket and tie it off all at
the same fucking time. Right?
These robots can do that,
but at least Rambo, at least ramble. Bled.
He had to take time to fucking sell
himself back up. These robots don't leave.
He completes. We can kill it.
The fucking robots don't bleed.
You know what I mean? And you know
these fucking nerds, you know,
back in the day you poured a Dixie Cup
of water on down their back, you know,
and they didn't do like a person lift
their shoulders up and go, all right,
they don't, they fucking short
circuit out and then they fall down.
So you know what these nerds are doing?
They're like, well, we can't have that.
You know, the competition's robot. If
you dump a little bit of water down,
it's back at shorts out and it goes
fucking a zillion dollars worth of
technology. You know, that they're making,
they're gonna make these
full fucking robots.
They're going to make them
be able to swim, right?
Do everything is going to be
just like that fucking movie.
Okay,
well that guy at all,
those fucking lady robots and he
was fucking them and shit, right?
And then the one kid gets locked in
the breezeway and he's screaming like,
I thought you loved me. And she
just goes away with the expression,
this look on her face. That's what
they're going to do. I guarantee,
I bet you right now, as I'm talking,
somebody somewhere is fucking a robot.
Yeah.
Then got the lab coat on and shit. So he
makes him feel like he's doing research
and there's a bunch of other scientists
watching him fucking the robot. Right.
And then afterwards he's going to give
the feedback. Oh No. You know what it is?
It's a fucking,
it's probably just some regular
person who has like Hep-c,
but can't afford that 1090 $5 a pill
to get rid of it or somebody's HIV
positive. So they go, hey man,
you want that fucking pill?
You got to come in here and
fuck this robot on film. Oh,
this is last thing I'll tell
you and I've got to go to work.
Did you fucking see, uh, have
you seen this? Evidently,
I don't know if this is fucking
true, but ever since Bentley,
the pharmaceutical lobbyists,
any states where weed is legal,
that going after, uh, the
legalization of weed because any,
any state where weed is legal, um,
the prescriptions go down. I
don't know if this is true,
but somebody told me it was and I
never looked up any information,
so I'm going to say it's true and I owe
a big apology to all the fucking weed
smokers out there. Evidently
you are right. Um, so anyways,
but I'm going to keep drinking. I'm too
far down this fucking road. All right.
I gotta get Outta here.
I gotta go to fucking work and knock
out this last fucking one for Christ's
sake. Um, that's the podcast should cons.
I will talk to you on a Thursday.
I'll check in on you. All right,
go fuck yourselves and
I'll see you Thursday.
[inaudible] when those
get to use it all to Cuba,
we have to
[inaudible]. [inaudible]
Hey, what's going on? It's bill.
And uh,
this is the Monday morning
podcast for the week of July 10th,
2008 is it July 10th? I have no idea. I
just got off a plane coming back from,
uh, from Pittsburgh,
Pennsylvania. I flew us there.
I sat in seat 18 a and.
M there were two people
about, Oh, I dunno,
19 rows behind me talking really
loudly. You know, those people, they,
they laugh at everything that they
say and they never say anything funny.
Four hours of that shit for fucking hours
of that. People just going, you know,
how many hours are left on the
flight? I don't know. Four and a half.
[inaudible] he just start laughing.
It was fucking killing me was,
it was torture the whole
flight. I ended up, you know,
I ended up doing, I got a new battery
from my, uh, made of wood laptop,
so I was able to watch good fellas.
Song's able to drown her out for
a w how long has good fellas? Huh?
So like two hours long or
some shit. So I had that on.
I had Goodfellas on cranked
as high as I could, you know,
we did, but we won it. We were wise guys.
I had that fucking crank is high
as I could to try to drown out
this Widdicombe plus group of people.
I don't know. I, you know what I mean?
Maybe it's me. Maybe I'm so
fucking miserable, you know?
Am I so miserable that I actually need
something to be funny to laugh at it?
You know? I mean, I was sitting
there and the end of it trying,
you don't want to, and they
finally, you know, I actually,
I didn't even watch the end of and
end up good fellows. I hate when he's,
when he fucking becomes a Druggie, you
know what I mean? He just pisses me off,
you know? And then he, then he feels
like all, he feels like he's the victim,
you know, 6,000 bucks for a life of work.
He gives me six grand.
You're lucky you didn't fucking
blow your brains out right there.
He told you not to fuck with the drugs,
the exact fucking thing he told you
not to do. You went out and you did it.
And then he ends up going to jail
and dying in jail. You piece of shit.
I fucking hate at the beginning
of that movie is great,
right up through the was the Lewenza
fucking robbery. That movie is awesome.
And then the second is second,
he gets that co core and
that flopped house apartment.
And then he's got that retard
with the attitude though the girl,
they're the fucking babysit.
And I got to get my hat.
I Dunno. I Dunno. So anyway,
that's what I was doing.
I was fucking listening to that movie
on 10 Janice Lassie as though I had that
fucking blasting in my ears. One
of my ears is ringing right now.
I already have tinnitus in one ear from
playing drums years ago and fucking,
it's going to be ringing even more
because of these fucking idiots, man.
It's just, I dunno, does anybody, you
know, you got anybody who does that shit.
They just, you know,
they come walking up and you know the
only be sit standing there waiting for an
elevator and they just go, hey,
how you doing? You're like, good.
And they're like, Eh, good. Yeah.
You know, if you go to anybody
fucking Lou does that at work. Just
discreetly leave a book on self
confidence in their little cubicle area,
something, you know what I mean? People
either do that or though they sit,
oh they hum songs. I think I already
joked about that about 28 podcasts ago,
but for those of you who are new to
my podcast, I used to work with a guy.
You have to work with someone who
uh, hums a tune that doesn't exist.
You know what I mean? Used
to walk around the office,
Eh,
boot or Doodoodoo
duty
all fucking day long. And I used to be
like, what the fuck? That's not a song.
Right. It's not a stuff sound like a
song when I hummed it. Yeah, exactly.
But that's a dead on rendition of
his fucking, you know, it just,
it went on forever.
Like one of those progressive
prog rock bands or Dave Matthews,
I saw him in concert and
fucking was this terrible.
Somebody hooked me up with
tickets and it was one of those,
those bands that you get after
fucking a song and a half.
And then there's a black guy playing
a fiddle, which is, which is weird,
you know, I usually like random
shit like that, you know,
like seeing a fat Asian, you know, just
don't see that too often. You know,
black guy playing a fiddle, you know,
she'll be like, she'll be, you know,
isn't that, but you think that he
would, he would do it the black guy way,
you know,
where all of a sudden he teaches white
people that have fiddle can actually be
cool as opposed to some, you know,
redneck instrument or a,
I guess in classical music it's cool.
But you know what I mean? I mean,
black people made happy birthdays,
make a cool sound, you know, cool song.
You'd pick it. You know? That's what I,
that's when I saw a black guy with a
fiddle. That's what I thought. Okay.
He's gonna, he's gonna,
he's gonna break it down.
I thought something was gonna happen and
he just was playing that skip to my loo
spin. Your partner ran to
a rat deck that that style.
I think the black guy who plays the
saxophone in the Dave Matthews band,
I bet he doesn't talk to the
black guy that plays the fiddle.
I bet he thinks she's a Cielo. Just
coming up some heavy show, you know,
motherfucker is bad enough. You'd
be playing a mother fucking violin.
You'd be doing that shit
every night in front.
All these motherfucking white people.
How do you think that makes me feel?
That was the worst impression of a black
saxophone player in a band that I don't
like, that I'll ever do,
but I don't give a fuck.
I let he just got off of Goddamn
playing, cut me some slack.
I listen to people laugh, you know? It
was like a nightmare fucking comedy show.
You know what I mean? Where
all of a sudden it didn't,
it didn't make sense anymore. Like
you just said anything like, Hey,
can I get up? I need to need to
go to the bathroom. Yeah. Okay.
All right. Anyways, let's get
on with the podcast here. Uh,
what do we got here? What
am I going to do this week?
And I'm going to start with the question.
It's not fucked in. I'm going to,
I want to height the
shit first. First of all,
I just got that the Improv in Pittsburgh,
unbelievable turnout and
99.9% of that has to go to a,
the Jim and Randy show on WTV.
Those guys totally hooked me up.
They let me come in on a Wednesday on a
Thursday and on a Friday I did like nine
hours a fucking radio with those guys
letting everybody know that I was going to
be over at the stacks, the
mall over there. And uh,
other than the fact that a couple people
got shot and one was murdered, um,
I think it was a good week over there
at the mall. Get an happen one week,
one night we were out drinking and uh,
all of a sudden we couldn't leave
the mall cause somebody got shot.
This is fucking unbelievable.
Stand within a stone stove.
We have a stone store, no pun
intended, a cold stone creamers.
That's not supposed to happen,
isn't it? When you, you know,
when you see a fid Rutgers,
right. I just don't,
I just don't associate that
with violence. But anyways,
I had a great week out there and I want
to thank all the guys over at a DV for
hooking me up and everybody
who came out to see me,
I'm also once again to remind you,
I have a one hour special coming
out on comedy central August 23rd.
All right. Set your Tivo six
weeks ahead. For some reason,
my fucking CD comes out before the
special, which makes no sense to me,
but I believe that's in
stores on August 5th.
And then the DVD DVD comes
out I think September 14th.
I know, it's bizarre. You guys are
going to be sick of me by mid September,
but anyways, please check it out.
I'm really proud of this special
we shot at ourselves. Uh,
tell your friends to
watch it and uh, whatever.
Hopefully they become fans of what I do
and then they show up at my shows and
someday I can afford
to take a private jet,
or at the very least set up in first class
where I can afford those Bose headset
where I can drown out people if they
fucking, uh, uh, laughing about shit.
That isn't funny. All right, let's
get on with the podcast questions.
If you new to my podcast, this is
what I do every week. I babble.
I bitch about people in
airports. I answer questions.
I riff about the Dave Matthews band
and I hide my shit. I'm, no, I don't,
I don't riff about the Dave Matthews Fan.
I don't even know any of these
fucking songs. I just know, uh,
I know crash into you. Yeah, they,
they, um, and then I come into you,
he really is like disgusting lyrics
when you really think about it,
but he thinks he thinks of nicely.
I don't like that little James
Brown fucking Jig. He does either.
When he's sitting in
with his Acoustic Guitar,
I never really noticed how much I
didn't like that, man. You know what?
I'm going to have to think about this.
I'm going to get back if you have
to get back to you guys on this one.
Listening. I'm stuttering. I'm so
fucking annoyed from that flight.
Maybe I'm really just pissed at
the people on the plane and uh,
I'm taking it out of the Dave Matthews
band. Misdirected anger. All right,
let's get into the questions here. People.
I got to make this one a quick one cause
I got a bunch of bull shit I gotta do
today and one of them is the fix my
attitude. All right, question number one,
Bill. Um, I have a question for you
podcast. Why don't you just ask it? Okay.
That's like, people go, let me
tell you something. He said,
he's just fucking saying it. I
said, I think I do that. All right.
I have a question for you. Podcast.
Being a comic from New York City,
which coast do you think is best
for stand up comedy? First of all,
I am not a comic from New York
City. I'm a comic from Boston,
Massachusetts who then moved
to New York City. I'm okay.
Uh, I will. What's the question?
Which coast do I think is
best for standup comedy? Uh,
Christ. I don't know. I ain't go,
how's that for fucking a bad
answer? Um, New York City,
if you just want to become a great comic,
there's nothing better than New York
City. It's gotten like 9 million clubs.
He can do like 10 sets a night. If
you want. Not 10, you could do 10.
But I think realistically
you do seven or eight.
Once you ran with all the clubs,
at least you could back in the day.
Just keep digressing with
everything I'm saying.
So I would say New York was
great. And then there's other,
other cities that are good to start
out in, which is, uh, Boston was great.
Houston's always have a good
scene. Denver, San Francisco,
Seattle's bunch of funny guys there.
Minnesota's got a great scene.
Um, yeah. You know what I mean? I worked
in Atlanta. I don't know if you funny,
just get your shit together,
but I guess you're asking me should you
move to New York City or la? Um, you,
I would visit both places before
you went out there because, uh,
I don't know,
New York City just felt like home when
I went there and when I went to La,
you know, the weather was
great and everything was
cool, but it was a, you know,
I stood in line for
fucking nine hours to do a,
a to sign up for a three minute spot at
the laugh factory and he had a fucking
sunburn.
I got there at nine in the morning for
a sign up that was at six at night.
This is no bullshit, right. Sat
right there on sunset avenue.
They take you guys down, memory
lane, some sitting there and uh,
I just remember there was these
two fat chicks and fucking Utah,
something that had really bad tattoos.
I was third in line by nine in the
morning. That's all I remember. And uh,
yeah, I, and then I wasn't
down there with anybody else,
so I couldn't leave other than
quickly to go take a bathroom break.
Like there was literally a whole system.
It was a fucking nightmare. Right.
Ended up getting a sunburn right
on my huge forehead and uh,
went home after I signed up,
it's six, went back to the kids,
a problem where I was staying,
showered really quickly,
came back down and had to do
three minutes of stand up,
which is practically impossible.
You know what I mean?
That's like trying to finish a bowl of
cereal and like two scoops, you know.
So I went down there and I don't
know how the fuck I did it,
but I went on stage and I absolutely
fucking destroyed for three minutes.
I did a tight three minutes
set that had a beginning,
a middle and an end probably cause I
only had like a half hour of material.
I knew I figured out how to do it. So
I'm sitting there going like, Oh man,
I got off stage. I was like,
that's it. I'm in at this club.
I'm going to get a manager. This is,
you know, everything's going to happen.
And then I went upstairs and uh,
I met the infamous Jamie Masada
who calls everybody body.
So I'm sitting there and he had his
table and I sit down at his table.
I'm thinking, this guy is just
going to kiss my ass. You know,
I'm some young buck. I went up there
fucking destroyed. I was better than,
you know, the two fat chicks from
Utah. This is it. It's over, right?
So I sit down, you know,
my ego's through the fucking
roof and he's just like,
I don't mean he set this
stared at me for a second.
He had his hands together like
not in a fist, but sort of like a,
he's doing the church and
the steeple thing set.
All these things are up and he had his
index fingers up on his mouth and he just
goes, you're very funny. And I was
like, oh, thank you very much. I'm like,
okay, here comes sit, comes here comes,
he's going to have to manage me. Right?
And he's like, uh, you
know, you, you, you talk,
you talk a lot about [inaudible]
about your father. Yeah. I go, yeah,
yeah. You, and he said, you should
do more. You should do mono, buts,
do modal Butts, your father. And I'm
like, Oh yeah, yeah. You know, I,
I got a ton of stuff about my dad.
I got some more stuff about my mom.
And as I'm saying that, he holds
my, his hand up to silence me,
at which point I literally shut the
fuck up and he just goes, you'll father,
let me ask you a question.
How does it make you feel
when your father yells?
And then he leaned back in his
chair, right? And it was like,
I felt like he was gonna
give me the answer.
So all my standup questions
in the form of a riddle,
and immediately I,
I began grabbing the legs on the back of
the chair because I was going to smash
it over his fucking head because I was
so fucked. I was so pissed. I was like,
you gotta be,
I just fucking killed for three minutes
and now you're going to act like you're
this standup Guru, you Jack Ass.
And that's exactly what he did.
He didn't ask to manage me.
He just gave me a little, how does it
make you feel when your dad yells, Jamie,
I hope you listen to this cause
I'm playing you club this week.
How do you think it made me feel?
Made me feel like, let me feel sad.
Is that what you wanted
to hear? Jesus Christ.
This guy came at me
like one of those guys.
You ever see those interviews when they
interview somebody after like a tornado
hit their house and killed
their favorite dog, you know,
and they sitting there interviewing them
and they want them to cry and then not
clients. And then they gotta ask.
They gotta sit there and
ask them questions to try
and make them fucking cry.
I think that's what he
was trying to do to me.
So I literally was grabbing the back
of the chair, the legs on the back.
I distinctly remember doing that and
I was like, fuck this guy. Fuck La.
I'm going to New York. That's
how I ended up in New York.
One three minutes set after
nine hours in a second degree,
sunburn on my forehead.
I decided that the east coast
was the place I needed to be.
You know what I mean? And a, you
know, I worked out well for me.
You know what? You know it's funny.
Somebody who's probably gonna fucking
tell Jamie than I actually said that shit
just so they can try and get a
three minute audition on Tuesdays.
So this week when I go down there,
Jamie's going to be like, buddy Bobby,
what do you, what are you doing
buddy? I actually love Jamie now man.
And I'm not kissing his ass
either cause I don't give a fuck.
But he said the funniest shit to me the
like three weeks ago I'm working as club
and I'm standing in the lobby
and these two gorgeous girls,
you know la to fucking gorgeous.
So I'm looking at him, you know,
I'm bugging out of my head and
Jamie's like, buddy, buddy, buddy.
Well what are you doing man? What
do you, what? What do you like?
What do you mind? I go, what do
you mean? What am I doing? My Go,
I'm looking at the girls. He
goes, yeah buddy, but what? Why?
Why are you looking at the girls? I
go, cause they're beautiful. I go,
why wouldn't I be looking at the
girls? And he goes, cause you're a fag.
I think I butchered that. He said
it even better. It was the fucking,
he said he totally set me up, son
of a bitch. And if you live in La,
I'm going to be down there
Tuesday night, Thursday night,
Friday night and Saturday night,
all on the 10 o'clock show and I'll be
having a good time down there. All right.
So there you go. See that? I Trust Jamie.
Then I tell a funny story where he trashes
me and then I hype his club and then
it's all good. Huh? Who the fuck's in
show business? I am. I know how to do it.
I know how to escape the fucking line.
All right, so that's what I would do,
son. I would,
I would go to New York and La and
figure out which one you want to be in.
All right. That's it. All
right. Question number three.
Have you ever had any thoughts about
doing a European tour of your show?
Absolutely. I feel that
I'm in conspiracy theory.
I feel like they're crashing the
dollar and all these corporations,
they're all going global, so
I'm going global with them.
I'm not going to be caught flat footed
with a pocket full of currency that isn't
worth the Goddamn peso.
So I'm actually setting up a European
tour for the beginning part of next year,
or at some point in 2009, I should say
I'm going to go over to England, Sweden.
Uh, I did some shit one time
in, uh, the Netherlands.
It's really disappointing when I went to
no Netherlands when I got off the plane
and the first thing I saw was
like a fucking Dunkin donuts,
you know what I mean? And like a
McDonald's, it just, it just really is a,
I understand why people find America so
annoying is because the urban sprawl of
our fucking corporations,
you know what I mean?
I literally think that I
could to like fucking Ah,
let me pick a movie.
Pick a fucking nice obscure country that
I don't even know where it is on a map.
Let me think of something. Bosnia. No,
I know why that's fucking eastern Europe,
Olivia and it was one of those
blah blah. That's in South America.
Whatever you go to fucking Bolivia.
You think going to go down there and
see that fucking that guy from the tee
shirt that everybody wears
che go viral, Gutierrez,
whatever his name is. Balance
Way Ala that fucking guy.
And you'd go down and
he'd get off the list.
The first thing you see Carl Sanders
on a big bucket of fucking chicken.
I think that's what you go chop is
his big fucking, I love that guy, man.
That guy is the shit. You
know what I mean? Those guys,
they remind me like Tony
Montana, that's what you go.
Chavez is stupid Chavez taken on the u s
knowing full well that we could fucking
Newcomb anytime we wanted to
talk and shit about us at the UN.
He's like in his early Tony
Montana years, you know, um,
for Jesus Christ is on annoying.
Even as early Tony Montana years,
like right before he a, he gets the, uh,
the Cadillac with the leopard
skin. You know what I mean?
When he's still washing dishes with that,
that fucking Robin
Williams Hawaiian shirt.
That's what Hugo Chavez is right
now. All right, question number four.
This is very, a little jet
lag here. People, sorry,
let me fucking blow through these and
they'll stop wasting your time. All right,
question. I'm a for a, Oh
God. This one has a backstory.
Yesterday I attempted to renew
my Norton Antivirus. I'm like,
I want me to sing a song about Microsoft.
I can't, I can't remix this songs,
dude. Unless they have a song. You
know what I mean? You gotta, you gotta,
you gotta pick one. You gotta
pick a product that annoys you,
that actually has a song,
and I will do a fucking puff daddy remix
of it that has the word continent and
it'll make you feel better. All right?
All right, question number five.
Hey Bill, here's a question.
Have you ever had people bring
their kids to your shows?
And I'm not talking 18 years old. I
mean like five years old. Absolutely.
I've had people bring babies and I've
been in the middle of talking about
something really, uh,
I don't know evil talking about going
to a titty bar and now I hate that,
you know, regular girls go
to titty bars now, you know,
cause they killed the
perverted vibe of the club.
I was doing that bit talking about how
strip clubs are for horizontally and then
I can feel comfortable leering at a
stripper when I'm sitting next to Melissa,
you know, doing that joke and all
of a sudden you just hear this baby
babies that's crying in the back
and then it, you know, something,
it's even more awkward when they
bring a kid that can speak, you know,
why don't I just say a five,
five years old or over rather than having
you guys picture mutes or something.
Yeah. I've actually, I've
had people bring kids,
I'm trying to think and
hasn't happened in a while.
There was a girl this week in Pittsburgh.
She laughed like a little kid,
so it was weird. She
sounded like a little kid,
so it was freaking all the comics out.
And then it turned out
she wasn't a little kid.
She was just an adult with
a really annoying voice.
And then she came up to me afterwards and
she had these huge titties and she was
saying, come on down to plush, which
is some strip club in Pittsburgh.
And she had that classic,
a Anna Nicole Smith.
I'm going to overdose in
a hard rock cafe voice.
So if she's listening, I
hope you're still alive.
He didn't. Oh d that I had
to tell you that story.
I played the same hard rock cafe,
the fucking in and Nicole Smith died in
and I gotta tell you something that's
been there for three fucking days. I
get it. I think she killed herself.
I don't think it was an overdose.
I think you know an accidental,
I think she did it on purpose because
a, that place sucks. All right,
question number seven, Bill.
I recently went to an open mic at my
local comedy club the first time just to
watch the club, just
to watch Jesus Christ.
Nobody puts capital letters
anymore or punctuation.
I just went right to
the next sentence. Bill.
I recently went to open mic night and
my local comedy club for the first time
just to watch the club only has
open mic night once a month,
which is gay, but I can't
do anything about it anyway.
I figure most of the, most of the
comments that got up with suck and bomb,
maybe a few would do okay.
But there were about 14 and 13 of
them ended up doing really well.
This was discouraging to me because I
figured most open micros would suck,
which would make me feel better
about myself and my comedy. Comedy.
Is this how open Mike was for you? Please
share your wisdom with me. Alright.
I'll show you my stories. Wisdoms
going a little too far. Yeah,
that's what it's like.
You go down there and there's people who
are still doing open mics, but they're,
they're better than being
open micros at that point. Um,
but they still need the stage time
and uh, you know, sometimes you know,
features and sometimes even a headline
on my drop and that's Kinda how it is.
And uh, yeah, your first few
open Mike. So lonely, but uh,
you just got to see the humor and it just
go up there the first time you do it.
It's not even about doing well whether it,
you don't judge it whether
you did good or bad.
The first time you go on stage is just
all about having the balls to go up there
when they call your name, you know, and
if you have the balls to go up there,
then you know,
you got more balls than 95%
of people in that situation.
So just take that as a victory tape.
You said keep it, you know,
lock it away in a safe and then
some day when you're good at it,
you can take it out and just laugh
your ass off at the shit that you,
that the, the shit that you attempted.
I wish I'd take my first one. I did.
I mean just to give you,
to make you feel better.
I was supposed to do five minutes.
I think I did about three.
I walked up there and the
second I saw the microphone,
I forgot everything I was going to say.
And I started in the middle of the shift
that I wanted to say and then brought
it back around to the front kind of,
I followed the same pattern of pulp
fiction. You know what I mean? Well,
they start with that. Oh
you mother fuckers get on
the ground on that bullshit.
And then he goes to the
beginning and then fucking,
you end up seeing that scene. Oh,
like Goodfellas. Same fucking thing.
That's how I, that's how
my first stand up set went.
Except unlike those awesome
movies. Mine was terrible.
So just picture, if they
was that the happening,
if m m night Shambhala Ama
Dingdong made that fucking movie,
the way they made pulp fiction that,
you know, that's the way my friend,
I'm trying to tell you, my first
set sucks, so don't worry about it.
Don't worry about it. Just go
up there and this. I get it.
You got to find the humor and bombing.
There's nothing funny than bombing.
It's fucking hilarious.
It's just something undeniably funny
about standing in front of a room full of
people and just putting it out there.
Especially if you're high energy and
you and your joke fucking bad at bat and
everybody's just fucking staring
at you this. Yeah. You just,
just, there's no other way to describe
what a fucking tool you feel like,
but everybody's been there, you
know, bring some water up there.
You're going to get dry mouth. All
right. And just, just do it, man. It's,
you know, you'll be fine. You'll be
fine. Fuck it. Alright, last question.
All right. Yes. It's actually a story, um,
which I actually find really
interesting. Kay. Hey Bill. And on,
what the fuck happened? My email last
week, a blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
All right, here we go. Okay.
A lot of damage related.
This is a real fucking long one. Let me
try to get to the meat of this thing.
Um, okay. This is an auto
damage related story. All right.
I must preface this story with the fact
that I find it very difficult to contain
my temper already.
I like this story with even I really
difficult to contain my temper with even
the most meaningless shit,
such as stubbing my toe or getting
cut off while driving. Anyways,
uh,
when something of actual meaning happens
to me having something of mine stolen,
let's say I really lose
my shit. All right.
A few months ago I had an expensive set
of knives missing from my kitchen and I
flew into a rage through
deductive reasoning.
I concluded it must've been
stolen by one of two people.
Now listen to the descriptions. You
can guess where this story's going. Uh,
it was either a, the sketchy
Jewish kid who lived upstairs,
or B, the Mexican
repairment who still had a,
had a key since I just moved in. Well,
the reasoning part of my tamper
tantrum was taking place.
A few racial slurs may have slipped
out and as one made to Deuce,
a temper tantrum is often accompanied
by loud screaming, oh, that's great.
They're okay. The screaming is
most often followed by regret,
usually concluding with
embarrassment. Anyhow,
the following day I went out to my car,
which was parked out front to
gather some belongings in the trunk.
When I got to my car,
I noticed that some thoughtful neighbor
who obviously heard my screaming the day
before notched a large swastika
in the center rear of my car.
After a few moments of
careful contemplation,
I left and decided to keep it
there for shameful posterity.
This swastika remains as a
painful reminder for me to
get a handle on my anger.
The steak knives were never
found. All right. You know what,
I find that fucking really
to be an interesting story
because the guy actually,
he seems like, you know, he's trying
to improve himself as a person.
You know, he knows he has a temper
and he knows what he did was wrong.
And uh, I would, this is a
question I have for you guys.
If somebody flies in cause you know,
they're, they always say that, you know,
I dunno like your, your real
thoughts come out in anger.
I don't know if I like 100 a
hundred percent believe that.
I think when you get angry sometimes
it isn't like you have this deep seated
hate. Sometimes it just, it just
trying to hurt the other person.
You know, like they get mad at some
you fucking cock sucker. I mean,
do you really think that they're out
there sucking dick? You know what I mean?
But then he got the other side is all
of a sudden when somebody goes into the,
in the actually, you know,
racial slurs that's like above
and beyond. I don't know. I don't,
I dunno about that one dude. I,
that's what I'm asking is, you know,
like if somebody, if somebody gets mad
at me, yeah, you fucking Dick. Like,
I don't think that they
really think I'm a dick.
I think that they're mad at me and
they called me a dick. Now there's,
does anybody think that it's possible?
Because this guy seemed like good dude,
he left this, wants to go on it. He
realized, all right, I'm a fucking ass on.
I gotta you know, keep my temper
in check. Does anybody think,
is it possible? That's what I
want to know to lose your shit.
And you start yelling racial slurs and
you still stick it in the same category
of like, I was just mad. It's he
just calling, just calling, you know?
I Dunno. I don't fucking know
work. You know what, be thankful.
You're not famous. You know what I
mean? You would ended up like a Kramer.
You wouldn't have to go on a, actually,
you wouldn't have gone on Al Sharpton
show you where I had to go on. Uh,
Jesus Christ, who's a
Jewish guy with a bad perm
to a Mexican guy with a bad perm.
You know how shocked would do a lot more
for his credibility if you would really
get rid of that pimp haircut.
You know what I mean?
I always felt he looked
like boss hog. Like if,
if they ever did like the black boss
Hog, you know what I mean? Need all that.
So that's like the hacky thing to do
in Hollywood. Like once you write it,
ideas, you just take, you
know, a sitcom like it's Alice,
but it's black. And then it'll was,
I didn't know what the fuck I'm
talking about this point. Anyways,
I got shit to do here. Okay.
There's a long ass podcast as always a
once again thanks to everybody came out
to my show in Pittsburgh, man. It's
fucking unbelievable. I couldn't,
last time I was there it was only like
18 people, so I really appreciate it.
And um, I got the comedy
works coming up in Denver,
Chug Dodge July 31st through August 2nd
and I believe I don't have my calendar
in front of me right now.
And also I'm going to be at the Improv
in Miami and in the middle of August.
And uh, that's it. I'll be
adding some more dates today. Um,
I think I got a month straight dates.
One isn't stress factory in New Jersey.
I think I'm doing umass Amherst
with Charlie Murphy and uh,
I think that's about it.
But anyways, everybody, uh,
thanks for listening to these podcasts.
I also got a new video I'm going
to be putting up on youtube. Um,
I add a new video last week. If
you miss last week's podcast,
it's right underneath the podcast
thing. It's entitled thank you.
Cause this is what that lady was yelling
at me after every fucking punchline.
And, uh, I'll be adding another one.
Just come stop putting random
shit up from shows that I do. Uh,
people seem to enjoy it and
it's a way to make you laugh,
show you some new standup without
burning any bits. So, uh, so that's it.
Once again, thanks to everybody, uh,
listen to these podcasts
and please remember to watch
my special on August 23rd
on comedy central. All right, that's
it. You guys have a good week.
Take it easy.
[inaudible] [inaudible]
[inaudible]
[inaudible].