Hey, what's going on? It's Bill Burr.
It's time for the Thursday afternoon.
Just before Friday.
Monday morning podcast.
And I'm just checking in our home.
You
what's going on?
How are you?
Yeah,
I'm in Chicago.
My kind of town Chicago
with my kind of town.
Chicago is
eating harder attack foods.
Your cargo is a great yeah,
place to put on 40 pounds.
It's my kind of town.
Yeah. Oh, they got steaks,
chops, deep dish pizza. You know,
remember that old SNL sketch and they all
dress like my ticket and they all have
in fucking heart attacks
and stuff. Yeah. Um,
this ends my sixth straight weekends
on the road and I gotta tell you
I was in such great shape at the beginning
of it and now I'm starting to go in
the wrong direction. So
it starts tonight. Uh,
just ordered a little bit of room service,
something healthy,
something not so healthy. But uh,
I'm fucking, I got two shows tonight.
I'm just going to go home and you can
tell them fighting off a fucking cold.
That almost ruined my show last
night at Madison Square Garden.
Thank you to everybody who showed up.
I had a great God damn town time.
The a sound was incredible.
And um,
I had a bunch of friends came out, saw
it and they all like, oh my God, we,
we really enjoyed it, which made me feel
good. Thank you to the people, you know,
some people gave me some gifts, you
know, I got some cigars this week.
Thank you to everybody.
Came out to theF is for family.
I'm thinking of Jig there
that I did at the uh,
Paley Center with Mike
Price and Peter Billingsley.
We actually aired the first episode
for the people that were there.
We actually got a great review from
Forbes magazine about our third season.
Say it's her best fucking season and,
and,
and we're one of the top half
hours on Netflix. I mean,
I am having a hell of a week.
I really am.
I'm enjoying myself,
but I'm eating like a fucking idiot.
So drinking this stupid
ass fucking vitamin C Shit,
you know, they'll just keep
drinking those packets. Psych. Well,
it's a thousand milligrams.
What to drink? Two of them.
That's why I drew went 2000 of anything
in me. That's just seems to like,
uh, like a lot. Can you o d on vitamin C,
you know
how many times can the cold virus kick
vitamin C's ass before we realized that
it really doesn't do anything.
Vitamin C over dose,
you know, somebody did
this. Okay. Four adults,
the recommended daily
amount for vitamin C's,
65 to 90 milligrams.
Now what do I got?
I got a thousand milligrams.
Uh,
and the upper limit is
2000 milligrams a day.
Although too much dietary vitamin
C is unlikely to be harmful.
Mega doses of vitamin C supplements
might cause diarrhea or nausea.
Okay?
And we can o d on it be fucking hilarious
if he gets so into health that you
fucking overdosed the ugly
truth behind the vitamin,
vitamin C overdose according
to Spoon University,
uh, that they'd like to snuggle when
they learn things. Spoon University,
I hate being sick and I'm guessing
you do too, says the article, uh,
blah, blah, blah, blah. Shamal see,
you've heard someone that you can
never take too much vitamin C.
Is that really to true or it isn't a myth.
Can we overdose on environment and
say, I don't care. I don't care.
[inaudible] I'm fucking, if I'm
reading, just say the answer.
Don't want to read an episode of a fuck
a television show that doesn't exist.
It's an old person reading a book. The
other day at the airport I was just like,
wow, that's fucking amazing. You know,
they just didn't give,
it wasn't staring at a fucking smart
phone like everybody else. Clued myself.
You know, I actually use my
smartphone to help me with my stress.
Whenever I'm stressing out,
I just play fucking solitaire.
You know?
It's got a nice fucking mellow
guitar thing. Wait, wait, wait.
Where when a bear all this fucking song,
it plays in the background and I just
don't give a shit and try to beat my top
score, you know? And I look
up, I'm stolen at the airport.
I don't give a fuck. I really
dumped. You know what I hate?
I hate when these who near the fucking
security line at the airport and some
fucking asshole behind you goes.
Can I just get through them so by my
flight's already boarding. It's just like,
okay,
well you fucking got to miss it then
now because you're late
because you're late,
you get rewarded for being late by not
having to wait in the fucking line.
Like the rest of us, fuck you.
Fuck you and fuck your flight.
You know, I'm sorry. Can I just
end this stupid body language?
They're trying to be all like a
submissive as they walk past you.
I mean,
what's to stop somebody from just saying
my flight leaves and fucking 10 minutes.
I mean that's the move.
If you don't have TSA precheck
or a global or a, you know,
if you didn't have your tape mapped,
whatever the fuck they're doing
now to get you on the plane sooner.
I mean that's the move I think.
Yeah.
If your conspiracy theorist and you
don't want them to have anymore formation
about you, but you don't like waiting
in lines, I would just show up to that.
Sorry. It might make my flight
leaves in 10 minutes. Can I just,
can I just [inaudible] yeah.
Some of these,
give those people the old
right there, Fred. Oh God,
I'm fucking miserable.
If I can do these two shows tonight and
not get sick if I can just fight it off.
MMM.
But anyways, I had the greatest fucking
night ever last night. Just wired a wire.
I just had a fucking awesome set.
MMM.
And then the after party was at Gotham
comedy club with the Mozillians who I've
known forever. And uh, they
made this incredible cake.
MMM.
I believe they got the cake boss to make
it. We took pictures, I uploaded a shit,
but it was uh, it was, the cake
was not only Madison Square Garden,
it also looked like a snare drum, cause
you know, obviously I played drums.
There was a helicopter on it.
And then they had this big figurine of
me wearing that fucking shirt I wore in
my last special with the
stars on it. And then, uh,
they had the John Bonham's green sparkle,
1971 Ludwig kit.
You know what, this little Seplat for
insignia on it. It was incredible.
Fucking cake was incredible.
And they let us,
well I can't see what they let us do
cause I don't think they get them in
fucking trouble. But you know something
they usually make you do outside.
They allowed us to do insight,
which was fucking tremendous. Um,
then that was it and it fucking went
home. And now I'm, now I'm in Chicago,
I'm in fucking Chicago.
I got four shows here at
the Chicago theater,
which arguably has the greatest
marquis in the country.
I feel, um, speaking of the greatest, uh,
Paul Versey special thanks to you guys
is a, it's one of the highest
rates specials, comedy
central sat in a long time.
It's fucking crushing. It has
over like a million views. Um,
so thank you to everybody
who went out and watched it.
It's still streaming on comedy central.
You can check it out.
It's great for Paul is great for
me cause he did it with my company.
All things comedy by any and all medicals,
you know, it's fucking tremendous.
That's the first one.
And you know what?
We got three more common you take Paul.
First he was was,
was the high watermark and
we're going to dip. Nope.
Everybody's just going to be
at the same fucking level.
It's all going to be quality. Um,
do I sound like Trump right now?
I actually watched a little bit of that
news conference, by the way. You know,
that childish fucking affair, Jesus
Christ. Everybody's yelling at each other
report a continuing to ask questions.
Is Trump saying I'm done with you?
Then he walked away from the microphone
to that whole fucking thing on both
sides was like embarrassing.
Um, and I'm not a fan of Trump,
but for people to sit there and act like
the media does not fucking absolutely
hate that fucking guy.
I've never seen. I mean,
I've never seen a guy get a fucking
attacked the way this fucking dude gets
attacked. It's like watching
a comic play a hell room.
It's just up there getting
fucking heckled. And he's like,
I'm not going to do my fucking act
that [inaudible] you fucking suck.
Um, I dunno. It's the worst
job on the fucking plant.
You can literally get blamed for
everything. You know? Why aren't they,
why don't they fucking have
a press conference with
some of these fucking piece
of shit? Corporations polluting
the water, stealing from people,
blown up the economy,
and then rip the rug out from everyone.
What we'll fuck about them. You
become president. You just, you just,
they're fucking stooge.
And you go out there and you stand there
and you just get yelled at by these
fucking nerds who think they're
in the paper. Chase is some shit.
Um,
I have no idea.
Another fucking bad story.
It's just a bad, you know,
I just put it on the TV and I saw that
whole thing about the fucking one of
those mass shootings things.
And uh,
it just makes no sense that
those things happen all the time.
Other than the fact that that's
all they fucking show on TV.
And there has to be some
sort of connection to that
because there's always been
a shitload of guns
in a shitload of people that had them.
And I,
I literally think like,
it's like the ice bucket challenge for
psychosis and they just fucked me over
that everybody's side.
We're doing the ice bucket challenge.
So then everybody had to start dumping
fucking water over their heads instead of
just giving money. I never understood
that. It's like what is the cause? Okay.
That's a good cause. I mean, I don't
have to ruin my shirt for delay.
Would you like some money?
I'm willing to give you some.
So
yeah,
I would love to see if
they could experiment, just
not giving it any coverage
and then it would just fade away
like an old pop star, I think.
You know, I dunno, that's my too,
because other than that that,
that I don't have any
fucking solution for it.
MMM.
Just fucking horrific. Oh, anybody
could fucking do something like that.
Um, but anyways, back to the
comedy. Back to the comedy. Um,
oh my God. This is one of these fucking
day. Some days doing a podcast is easy.
You know, it's like falling out of
bed. Well that's not it. Fucking,
it's the one thing is it's like
getting out of bed, rolling out of bed.
It's like taking that nap. Is that
an easy thing? We asked people,
a hundred people did a survey said name
the top five things, you know, bad.
I would suck on fucking the family feud.
I can't say the name of the show,
the family feud name,
something that's easy to do.
Uh, Mr. Byrd, uh, fall
out of bed, show me,
fall out of bed, back, Sullivan
family with a chance to steal.
I'd be that last family member.
You know what I mean? Fucking dude.
All the way down the end.
Yeah.
Yup.
Families only have so many smart people
and it seems when you watch the family
feud, it stops around three
is if five people on a show,
it's always the last to, you know, some,
he always just said something that sucks.
Well, you should really do. I
think, well, how would you do that?
It's almost like a batting
lineup with intelligence. Okay.
Did you got to have your lead off hitter?
You know,
you've got to have somebody's back and
clean up and then you get, you know,
you've got your pitcher,
bat and a knife. If we're,
if we're going by national league
rules here, right. What do you do?
Do you put the dummy up front when all
the answers are still on the board?
Name a word that begins with a
apple being number one answer,
right?
Or do you just leave that guy down the end
and hope that everybody else,
you know, does a good job?
I wonder if there's fights.
You know when somebody finds out.
Yeah. Hey, we're going to have
you all the way down to the end.
Basically the right field of intelligence.
We're going to be all the
way down the fucking end.
Now is the person too stupid to realize
that that's where the dumbest person is.
You know,
and everybody needs to get a hit.
Everybody needs to get ahead because this
motherfucker's going to get a strike.
All right?
Just put him all the fuck way down.
He's going to get the least at bets
in theory,
up, up, up, up, up. They should
have a fucking a week of,
of all those fucking people down the ends.
You know,
you just make super families
out of that last person.
Just the dumbest mother fuckers ever.
Oh, what'd you call it? Family feud.
A fucking dope week.
Who else that shows
it's still Steve Harvey.
He would probably run out of
looks to give the crowd. Um,
anyways,
so I'm hearing in Chicago this buckets
and I gotta I gotta I gotta get back on
my Goddamn Diet.
You know,
I was good before I did this six week run.
I had my whole fucking future ahead of me.
You don't fucking lyrics.
I'm going to the heart doctor next
week to get my ticker checked out. Uh,
the six weeks ago I've yet gay or
in phenomenal shape for your age.
And I was going to be like, hey, you
probably want to lose seven pounds.
I could do it though. I want to. I
want to be that. You don't want to be,
I'm going to be that fucking
guy that loses weight during
the holidays. You know,
he has only one way to do that. You've
got gotta be homeless. Nobody loves you.
Is that okay? How much of an asshole
you are when it's the holidays,
somebody is going to make cookies,
right?
Those stupid little tins. You walk
over with, you opening it up, you know,
is that voice in the back of your head?
What are you doing? What are you doing?
And then you shouted down with, you know,
I'm going to go to the gym in January.
I'm going to start the
year with a giant fucking
okay
steamship round for a fucking
torso. I can't do it, man.
MMM.
I'm disgusted with myself.
Look what you did, Bill.
You had a good thing going. You fucking
ruined it. I haven't watched any sports.
I don't even know what's going on anymore.
Right?
Red Sox won the world series and
I just been fucking flying high.
I haven't watched anything. I know
the lake. Uh, what about fucking Duke?
Just absolutely kicking the
fucking shit out of Kentucky.
And once again, once again, they,
they got it. They got another guy.
How do they fucking do it?
Duke Verse Kentucky.
Now,
how does that work?
Do they just have this shit just to like
for the ratings so they can figure out
who's, uh, who's the best
team? Is this actually count?
Is it like soccer where they
have a friendly shout up?
You know soccer is like the, you
know, we're playing but it doesn't,
it doesn't mean anything.
MMM.
That's 75 47 with 14 minutes to go.
Are you fucking kidding me?
They scored 75 points and a
half and like you just can't be,
it can't be
one 18 to 84 that's like
a fucking NBA score.
They still let up 84 points though.
I Dunno. I Dunno how to fuck
that works. But it did somehow.
I'll tell you what them Duke Blue Devils,
they put a whip in on that fucking
wild cats from Kentucky. Um, all right,
let me do a couple of reads here.
Everybody a Saucy,
everyone at some point, his wish they
could just have a, just have beer,
wine or liquor delivered while someone
finally decided to do something about it.
Introducing Southie,
the alcohol delivery APP,
Southie delivers your favorite wine,
beer and liquor,
right to your deal on
demand. Now, if you'll now,
if you live in Los Angeles,
the bay area, Chicago,
San Diego or Sacramento years,
I'll say order will arrive.
At your dealer in under 30 minutes.
Ready to drink now,
why didn't they say Los Angeles,
the bay area,
San Diego, Sacramento, and
then Chicago. This is long,
longer been on the tour. I'm
like, that fucking routing sucks.
I'm going to be mean. La. I go
up to San Francisco, Oakland,
then I go over to Chicago,
back to San Diego and up to Sacramento.
The fuck are we doing here? Uh, for the
rest of US Sassy, we'll deliver it. Beer,
wine and liquor to you deal with in
two days or less. Nationwide. Um,
there are no order minimums, no delivery
fees, no running to the steelworks. Uh,
if you got the saucy app,
you got a fully stocked by on your phone
and for a limited time you can get $50
off. When you doubt Wayne, I'm in Chicago.
They can deliver recepted ah,
kind of booze with saucy baby.
We don't live very to La and fuck it.
Saucy and fuck.
In the bay area, there are no
order. Miriam's, no delivery fees,
no running to the store.
If you got the saucy APP,
you've got a fully stocked bar on your
phone in front of limited time, you can,
you can get $15 off when you download
this saucy app and enter Promo Code Bar,
that saucy APP,
uh,
spelled s a u c y unit
to the Promo Code burpee.
You are for $50 off.
Get the saucy app today
and use Promo Code Burn.
Oh look who's here.
Bodo due to my young days.
[inaudible] fucking steak, dude,
dude, dude, do me on days be on days.
It's fall.
Grab a rake,
ate a bunch of pizza and
fucking fattening food.
Walk around like a Mustachio
dude cause you're in Chicago.
Block your arteries with all their
fucking delicious food and none of it's
healthy while your balls
roll around on felt.
Uh, Biondi is uses the coveted
micro modal modal fabric,
which is three times softer than cotton.
If you've never felt this fabric,
get ready to experience pure bliss in
underwear form men and women can choose
from four different cuts, all of which
are available from classic colors too.
Adventurous prints.
Speaking of prints this holiday season.
Oh the holiday season be on these.
We'll be releasing a new fucking
bread every God damn Tuesday.
That means you have no excuse to celebrate
the holidays right down to your very
own car. Uh, but why stop
at [inaudible] this year?
Me undies is launching their
holiday prince in lounge
pants in one sees as well.
Both are made from the same micro
modal modal fabric as their undies.
Seriously,
how could he get not,
but how can you not get you and your
loved one a matching holiday themed one z
this year
because it's kind of weird to be
an adult wearing a fucking onesy.
You'd be like one of those,
those adult babies, you know,
sit in a fucking crib cause
you can't deal with reality.
Well I guess,
you know,
that's just another segment
of the population they're
trying to make money off
of. So you know, God bless them beyond.
He's has a great offer for my listeners
for first time purchasers portraitures
when you purchase any meander,
you should get 15% off and free.
This is a no brainer.
Get 50% off the most comfortable undies
you will ever put on to get your 50% off
your first pair of free shipping and
100% satisfaction guarantee. Go to me
undies.com/bird. That's me,
undies.com/bar. All right, what's left?
Oh, butcher box. Uh, right butcher box.
That reminds me, I looked
up battleaxe today. This is
the fucking funny thing. Ah,
I try to make tucked in that fucking
battle ax over there. You know,
I always thought that meant an ugly woman.
It just means a woman who doesn't
take any shit and she's difficult.
All right.
You know,
I dunno.
I always thought like a battle ax.
It looked bad.
It was all fucked up looking
cause she went to battle on it.
So you've seen her face look like a
battle ax? I guess it wasn't though.
They determined. Let's look up
the definition of bad election. We
like a
call your wife that and see
what the fuck happens. Eh?
You fucking battle ax.
Yeah.
All right.
Battleaxe meaning is a term
generally considered a pejorative?
Do you how many times
I've looked up pejorative.
That's like when they said the Democrats
won the house. I was like, oh my God,
what does that mean?
Every election I have to look up.
What does the fucking house do
versus what does the Senate do?
Not that they're all, I don't think
all of this at the Capitol is one side.
The house,
the other side's the Senate.
I Dunno know you.
I just picture you go in there and all
you hear is the sound of loafers walking
on marble. All right. Expressing
contempt or disapproval.
Pejorative. Can you use it and
excel in a sentence please.
Oh, who gives a fuck? I don't
even care anymore. Right?
A battleax you fucking battle ax when?
Raise it.
Okay, so it's, well, what just
happened? Oh, there it is. All right.
A battle ax is a term generally
considered pejorative for an aggressive,
domineering, and forceful woman. Oh,
this is the female word for
cock sucker guys at Dick. Uh,
she's a fucking battle ax
and he's a fucking Dick.
Battle ax is just funnier.
The battle.
Axe is one of several stereotypes
found in nursing, a tyrannical,
fierce matron exemplified by nurse ratchet
or Haiti's shock in popular medical
dramas and comedies.
Why the fuck is,
why is everybody picking on nurses?
I Dunno.
That's kind of my goal this week.
I'm going to call somebody a battleax.
I would never call my wife that.
She's too fucking cute. Okay.
What's the worst thing
ever called my wife?
I don't call. I don't. I don't
do the name. Call it most of us.
Do we stop being such a fucking asshole?
Leave me alone.
Just leave me alone. All right. All
right. What's your box? Everybody?
Butcher box delivers healthy 100% grass
fed and grass finished beef free range,
organic chicken and awe.
Heritage bread.
Pork. Oh, do you owe it to yourself
to eat one of those fucking pigs?
The incredible quality of butcher box
meets start with the commitment to raising
animals humanely free of antibiotics
and hormones before they murder them.
Each box comes with at least
eight to 11 pounds of meat,
which is enough for 24 individual size
meals or one and a half meals for a binge
eater.
When I was little skinny Asian guys that
for some reason when the hot dog eating
contest, right, the big fat
dude can't kick get it done.
You can choose from five different
box types, all beef, beef and chicken,
beef and pork.
Mixed box or custom box.
Yeah,
which lets you choose your own cuts.
All right. Personal experience.
I already told you guys told you many
times that heritage bread pork mean it's
pure bred.
It's like it's the original pigs from
Europe for whatever reason they taste
better than the ones we got over here.
You know,
probably because our pigs are out
eating fucking Mcdonald's, you know,
grew up on peanut butter and
fluff it out or some shit.
I don't know what the hell these fucking
uppity goddamn heritage bread pork with
doing, but whatever they did it, they
taste fucking delicious. Anyways,
for $20 off your first box and two pounds
of free ground beef in every box for
the life of your subscription.
That's $20 off your first box in
two pounds of free meat a month.
That's a lot of fucking meat.
Quarterpounder right?
That'd be eight quarter pounders.
How many days there were not month?
Well built depends on the
month. All right, relax.
And for people who are already
butcher box subscribers,
you'll have a special deal on ground
beef you can take advantage of by logging
into your account.
Go to butch butcher box.com/bar and
enter Promo Code [inaudible] at checkout.
Once again, butcher box.com/burr
and enter burr at checkout.
Okay.
All right,
let's get back to this fucking bullshit
over here. Let me see. Let me see.
You know I'm going to look at this.
This just,
I like searching dumb shit like this.
Top 10 worst things you can call your
girlfriend. Here we go. I just popped up.
All right, let's see what we got here.
[inaudible] let's play the
feud. Alright, let's see.
My 10 number one would be
client number two would be bitch
a got gotta be in their slot.
Battleaxe Heifer. Uh, Jesus Christ.
That's all I got.
It's got to be something else.
What else could I call you fucking,
uh, I was kind of covers it, right?
Bimbo,
dumb, dumb. I'm just running.
Just becoming a fucking
second grader. All right.
The 10 worst things you can call
a female who may sis list what,
how did I end up looking this up?
What the fuck is wrong?
The 10 worst things you can
call a woman. Number 10, bitch,
this is probably the most common term
used straight into the point yet not as
degrading because of its
immense popularity in common
use. Well, it depends on, on,
yeah. Like I think if black women,
if you call him a bitch at me and it's
means more white women, for some reason,
white women really don't like cunt.
I think white people say cut a lot.
I don't know that black people say cunt,
which should be fucking hilarious.
Um, at least American black people
who I haven't seen it, you know,
not like I'm out here
doing a current survey,
but I'm just generally speaking
to people I talked to. Uh,
anyways, I find black
people will add, you know,
add to bitch stank bitch
or something like that.
But they never seem to
make the leap to cut.
Okay.
White people like bitches, just
sash. She's a bitch. You know what?
She's really being a bitch. She's a
cunt and that's how it works. Everybody.
All right, number nine cow.
Speaking of butcher box cow,
the only reason this is so low on the
list is because it never comes as a
surprise of fat.
Chick knows she's a fetch.
A Jesus Christ knows she's a fat chick.
In fact, sometimes they even embrace it.
So in rare cases, this can actually
backfire. Now I don't think,
I don't think this works. I don't,
I don't, I don't believe in that.
And who wants to be called a fucking cow?
That is funny though.
If fucking cow, a cow is funny
than pig. What'd you say?
You fat pig. You fat cow. There's
something about cow. Maybe it's the sound.
It says out, you know his hours in
there, it hurts. It's hurtful thing.
Slut number seven, horror.
Slash hope number six is slob.
Wait a second.
I didn't mind when you called me a whore,
but when you said I was a
Slob, that was it. Skank pig.
Bimbo, slut smut bag. Oh,
this is worse than my list.
And then cut. Yup, you do.
COMP was going to be number one. All
right. Now let's now, let's be fair.
Let's be fair to the ladies here.
Okay.
All right.
Top 10 worst things you
can call your boyfriend.
This is how you killed time on the
road as a comedian, by the way.
Okay?
Uh, all right. This is hilarious. Women
have 25 things that they call guys.
They really do talk more,
don't they? 25 wars.
Pet names for your lover thinks you
don't want to call your lover 50 horrible
nicknames for your significant of the 13.
Where's pet names?
What not to say to your
boyfriend? All right, here we go.
I would imagine when he takes his
dick out, they go. Is that it?
It tickles. Um, all right. Number one,
you're so much better than all
the other jerks I've dated. Yeah.
Cause that makes them a meal. Think
well, how much cock has been in you? Um,
can you really afford that?
This is just one of these classic things.
It's like, did they even ask guys,
can you really afford that? Can really
afford that? Uh, yeah, I can. Or No,
I can't thank you for stopping
me from making this bad purchase.
That seems like a concern,
girlfriend.
So we're running a little
late. Relax. All right,
so we're running a little late.
Comes with the territory.
But if there's a preemptive relaxed
before I flipped out, that would bug me.
Although I don't know if this
makes my top 10. He's a great guy.
You should be friends with him.
Yeah.
That means you guys used to fuck or
you're about ready to number five.
She made me promise not to tell,
but uh, it's not surprising.
None of you can keep your fucking
mouth shut. Clooten guys, number six.
Don't be silly.
I haven't done that in ages.
Uh,
I dunno what that means.
What are we talking about?
Okay.
You want some heroin? Don't be silly.
I haven't done that in ages. Okay.
Put it in your ass. Don't be silly. I
haven't done that day. Just like, yeah,
it's kind of a weird answer.
No matter what you were asked.
Would you like some cereal?
Don't be silly. I haven't
done that in ages anyways.
Number 10. Oh 10 sentences.
He be psyched to hear.
Number one, boring. Nothing helps me
wind down after a long day at work.
Like giving you a blow job.
Okay. That's never been said.
Number two, what does, what does
she became like Wacky Dick Jokes.
All right.
That was cosmo. Everybody. Um, all right.
I need to drink more fucking I guess
vitamin C, it's inevitable getting,
I got to do two shows tonight. All
right. Oh, freckles is going to get sick.
First call of the year. Didn't even
make it to fucking December, you know.
All right,
well thank you once again to everybody
who came out to Madison Square Garden.
Thank you to uh,
Gotham comedy club for the after party.
Thank you for to the west side comedy
club for helped me tune up my shit earlier
in the week. It uh, I think that's it.
Take it. Everybody showed up. All
right. Enjoy the music and a, uh,
continued special half hour of,
uh,
I guess greatest hits from a Thursday
podcast from earlier this year or 10 years
ago. I have no idea. Oh, by the way,
I got some great fucking
video to backstage that we
will be putting up on the
Patrion page, um, from the beginning
of the show at the end of the show.
Very excited about it. Um, that
is all. Have a great weekend.
You bitches. I can't say con
right? I don't want a fed. Yeah.
Alright.
[inaudible]
you doctor, listen to
podcast. The fuck yourselves.
[inaudible] [inaudible] away from me.
You couldn't see how
[inaudible] so close.
So close.
[inaudible] carried you books from school.
[inaudible] I was six when we came to me.
No, when you were Amy and your crew,
your private looked down at you.
You hit that one home. One
day. My son will grow the VMV
move.
Look at you now.
Just got your ass whipped
by a bunch of Goddamn nerds.
Yeah.
Hello.
If I was you,
I'd do something about it.
I would get up and redeem
myself in the eyes of my father,
my maker,
and my coach was just go dark.
Yeah.
Hey, it's bill burger. It's the
Monday morning podcasts for Monday,
November eight, 2010. I hope these
levels aren't too fucking high ahead.
Had to really crank that up so you could
actually hear that speech that I hope
there's actually some New
England patriots listening.
Well that goes out to
the New England patriots.
Everybody after that fucking
show lacking that rape,
but that they took at the hands of
the fucking hapless Cleveland Browns,
the fucking hapless Cleveland bronze.
Why are these levels so fucking high?
Hang on a second. Hang on, hang on. Hang
on. Let's go on on here. Hello. Hello.
Test one, two bill bar. Monday morning
podcasts. There we go. Is that better?
Is that better? Um, Jesus Christ,
we got fucking killed.
Absolutely fucking killed,
uh, by a white running back. Everybody.
You know something?
I'm going to go out on a limb.
I think the white running back or
fullback. Let's not get crazy now.
Let's not get crazy.
The fullback,
that fucking white dude
who just doesn't feel pain.
It put me fucking kill that guy.
That dude is back Mongo.
Remember that fucking white dude who
rode the bull in blazing saddles?
Put a helmet on that guy. That's who the
fucking Pat's went up against yesterday.
Jesus Christ. You should have seen
this fucking guy. He had a face mask.
His face mask look like the front
of a dodge ram pickup truck.
Look like the grill of that
dodge ram pickup truck.
The second you see his face mask,
you know what he's doing?
He's getting the ball.
He's going right up the fucking middle.
He's out running around the side
like some fairy fucking running back.
He's coming right up to fucking gut.
And that's exactly what that
guy did all God. Damn Day long.
He was stiff arming at defensive ends
like they were cornerbacks just sort of
throwing them aside.
It was,
it was one of the most dominating
performances that I've seen in awhile.
And,
uh,
so that was a little inspirational fucking
speech for my team because next week
we play in the Pittsburghs
add a, I was already worried
about that game, but uh,
this is the interesting thing about how
football works is if the Patriots went
in and actually beat the browns.
Um,
I was thinking that, okay, if we beat the
browns and then we go up seven in one,
we are going to get at what happened
in Cleveland was going to happen in
Pittsburgh.
But now for some fucking reason,
this is how it seems to work
that we lost in Cleveland.
We'll actually be way more competitive.
I still think we're going
to lose in Pittsburgh. Our
defense is fucking horrific.
It's horrific.
You know,
it's fucking frustrating to be going
through. You know, it's actually not bad.
We going through a fucking,
uh, a a a rebuilding year,
you know, and I know a lot of you guys
out there just cause it's the patriots.
You still think it's the
fucking championship team.
Go get yourself a little team roster
thing and look who's left. You know,
our whole offense is built around thrown
two rookie fucking tight ends and Brady
was off yesterday, kept
throwing everything through
the fucking roof, right.
I'm sitting there talking to these people
in this sports bar actually found a
cool one where it was kind of mellow
and there wasn't really a, you know,
there's like this insane one
around the corner where people,
it's just like you can't even go in
there with your team colors on because if
your team is losing that day,
you're going to want to fight somebody.
It's one of those places and it's
just not an enjoyable experience.
So I found this other one where
they have like nice, like, you know,
it's just nice. The decor is nice. It
doesn't have that fucking date rape vibe,
like a lot of sports bars.
Do you know that fucking awful vibe.
The pent up just fucking the,
the amount of fucking, uh,
just pent up, you know,
and then they got the,
those fucking girls always got to
dress like runaways. The waitresses,
it's just creepy. The whole fucking vibe
is creepy. I don't like it. And it's just,
yeah, this is awful. So I found this
other sports bar that was, you know,
actually way more mellow.
And I'm sitting there, right.
And I come walking in and by the time I
get there, it's already tend to nothing.
Cleveland and I sit down as this dude
next to me already drinking beers.
The game comes on at like
fucking 10 in the morning.
He's clearly on like his third beer. I
didn't realize he was shit face. I go,
Jesus Christ, they go 10 to nothing.
I go, I go, I go, what happened?
And he looks at me, he's like,
Cleveland is up 10 nothing.
I was just like, alright man.
Thank you. Thank you for fucking a
thank you for clearing
that up. You know, um,
and Jesus Christ and they just start.
It was awful.
We just got the living shit
kicked out of it. And you know,
it was funny was last week, this week I
got, I got a ton of emails from jets fans.
It was very surprising because last
week I didn't get any from, you know,
last week when they lost to the packers.
Nine to nothing at home.
I got like two emails from jets fans
and then this week it was weird,
you know, cause I was like, wow, did
do the jets fans not exist anymore?
Then this week all of a sudden I
get this whole avalanche that look,
I know all jet fans and all sports fans
aren't like that because a lot of you
didn't send me emails either fucking way.
But those,
those fucking sports pussies who fucking
lay in the weeds until their team wins
and then they get out and start talking
shit. You know, let me ask you guys this,
because I've been sitting here
trash in the jets all year.
Just let me ask you this real honestly.
Honestly,
do you really think you're going to win
the Superbowl at that team? You know,
cause I have such blind hatred for the
fucking jets after the shit talk and that
they did at the beginning of the year.
Honestly.
Do you really think that that team has,
what the fuck it takes?
All right,
set aside your hot seriously.
Eking out a victory against the lions.
You eked out a victory against the
dolphins and you eat one out against the
Broncos,
two out of three of those games where not
for a bone head fucking penalty by the
other Goddamn team.
You know,
you could have lost one or maybe both
of us to add to your two fucking losses.
Now, if I'm a jet fan, I gotta be
thinking, no, if I'm a jet fan,
I got to be thinking of the one
thing I got going for myself
is that nobody is dominating in the AFC.
Nobody is, you know, that's the
one thing that I would take.
I would take pride in the fact because
the jets have not really dominated
anybody.
Have they?
They kicked the shit out of the Patriots,
but that wasn't until the second
I'll actually was this second half,
second half of the second quarter they
did. But other than that, I don't know.
I'm not too impressed.
I think that they're fucking offensive
line might be the best in the league and
Sanchez just sits back there
in a fucking lawn chair.
But I think if they actually
go up against, I dunno
the giants, I, yeah, I just,
I don't fucking see it.
You know what I'm basically saying
is that when Joe Nemeth finally dies,
I hate to say it,
I think you guys are going to have to
get them stuffed and mounted so you can
still wheel them out onto the
field to get you to get that.
He's like,
you're newt Rockne and then he can stick
one of those things in the side of his
neck way.
Uh,
well you just pull the
fucking you Paulette and the
string and he starts talking.
I think the jets are going to make
a great play. I want to kiss you.
You just have it sorta half fucking
shit faced. Half inspirational speech.
Oh Jesus. So next week we play the
fucking Steelers in. Uh, I dunno.
I Dunno what's going to happen.
I think we're actually gonna have a
nice competitive fucking game with them
somehow.
It makes no sense,
which is why I have to stop fucking
gambling because I got to admit as much.
Um, I can't even say it really hurt cause
I don't give a fuck about Cleveland. Um,
and I also, you know, it's no
surprise that our defense sucks.
Um, the game that pissed me off the most
yesterday was the fucking Kansas City
chiefs game. The, this, these
were my pics yesterday. Okay.
I've got this thing going,
Paul Versey right. Um,
you got to pick four games a fucking week.
The end of the year,
the guy takes the pot, right?
So I got the cheat, I got the,
I got the bears against buffalo
bears given three. I tied that game,
right?
Then I picked Tampa and Tampa against
Atlanta getting eight and a half.
I fucking won that game.
I had green bay given seven,
whatever the fuck against the hapless
fucking cowboys, right to all in one.
Nobody's gone undefeated.
I had the fucking Kansas City chiefs,
those fucking assholes. One that Goddamn
game and just decided to give it away.
Oh,
I really want to blame the fucking but
it at that fucking Matt Cassel, he just,
he just drove me fucking nuts. Those
fucking receivers not catching the ball.
Oh, kip. Fuck the Kansas City
chiefs. Fucking Goddamn assholes.
Do you see that fucking call chief's fans?
You see,
you see that pass interference call the
end of the fucking game when the Raiders
were down by two. I can see,
this is why I think it's fixed.
And this is why I think I'm, I'm, I'm,
I would never gamble other than just
with a buddy. Like I don't, I honestly,
I don't know how you fucking gamblers
do it because the level of fucking
emotions that you go through when you
have money on the game is nothing.
Nothing compared to you just
loving your hometown teen.
All those fucking douchebags
Lou go out to the Raiders gains,
then they fucking dress like
spark or whatever the fuck it is.
Spock with like spikes coming out of
their shoulders as much as they think that
they give a fuck.
You know,
you don't give a fuck as much as
some guy who's not even from Oakland,
who's got money on that fucking game.
I'm telling you why the fucking levels.
So God damn low,
take it's time to get a new uh,
recording here.
People have been bitching a little bit.
Seeing the levels are a
little bit quiet here.
Got To make sure I forgot this shit
going here. Hello? Test one. There we go.
All right,
so anyways,
when that fucking ref called that pass
interference and then they show the
replay and the announcers are just like,
oh, let's see what's going on here.
Doesn't seem to be any CARTEC Lil g,
Mike, I'll tell you I didn't see anything.
And then they just continue on. Nobody
starts going, well why the fuck?
How the fuck do you call something
that didn't even happen, you know?
I mean I can see missing
some shit that happened.
It's like fucking 22 goddamn
people out there running around.
How the fuck he supposed to see
everything. But how do you call some shit?
That didn't even fucking happen.
I swear to God,
I think it's fucking fixed on some level.
Something fucked up is going on and
I challenged my listeners. I right,
you fuckers defend that. How is, you know,
I really do sound like something asshole
who lost money on a fucking game.
How do you call some shit that didn't
happen. I get it. 22 fucking people.
I get how you can miss something. It's
like standing in grand central station.
Everybody's going every which
way. Somebody, oh my God.
Do you see that then homeless guy
just took a shit on the floor.
Did you see that? Actually I didn't.
I was staring at that checks. Tits.
I missed it.
I get that.
But how do you call die?
Dare fucking 15 yards for shitting on
the floor and there's no shit on the on
the floor.
That's such a stupid fucking example.
This is how mad I was so fucking mad
when the refs missed that God damn call.
Thank gave it fucking didn't miss the
call. Just invented that fucking call.
Gave the fucking Raiders of
first down. No, I see that.
That fat fuck dude who got caught with
the date rape drug warming up his leg and
I know he can kick it
from fucking Siberia.
So items like this game's fucking over.
It's going to go into OT and I
shut the game off and I just, I,
I picked up the remote control and
I just started walking. Just, just,
just slamming it methodically.
Like that fucking Slingblade guy write
it down on Dwight Yoakam's fucking head.
Just, just, I actually, I got,
I got so fucking mad at [inaudible]
just courtesy to my girl.
I just, I walked, I grabbed my phone,
I have fucking Hoodie and
I just started walking,
started walking up the street like,
fuck, I didn't know where I was going.
Tourette's. Fucking God get fucking piece
of shit. Fucking reps. No fucking way.
Fuck you fucking costs something.
That didn't even fucking happen.
I should be three.
Oh and fucking book people walking by
with their pubs just staring at me.
I'm trying to act like I'm talking on my
cell phone. I'm not talking to myself.
I'm talking to that fucking ref, that
piece of Shit Raf. I swear to God,
if I was running the fucking
league and at the end of the game,
some fucking ref made a goddamn call that
that overtly affected the point spread
and he made a call.
It didn't even fucking happen.
That son of a bitch would be in
my office Monday fucking morning.
I'd have his phone built, laying on
the table, his visa, mastercard bills,
his fucking passport,
all of his shit.
And I'll be looking at his life and I
would figure out who the fuck this guy
owes money to that you can make
a a horseshit call like that.
All right, I'm back. That's what happened
to me. I fucking walked up the hill,
so God damn pissed.
I started walking into the Goddamn hills,
walking up to the street and
look, the sun's going down, right?
I get to the top of the Goddamn hill and
I realize I'm right at the foot of this
fucking park that has a bunch
of God damn coyotes, you know,
and I'm, I'm not there. I'm not
there with my fucking pit bull.
I don't have my security with me and
I'm just walking up there and then I was
thinking like, Jesus Christ,
what if I get mauled to death
by a pack of coyotes?
That would be the dumbest
death ever comedian, Malta,
death by coyotes because the chiefs
didn't cover against the Raiders.
And right there I was just like,
you know what?
This gambling shit is the dumbest
shit you can ever do to yourself.
If you've never gambled, don't
do it. Don't put money on a game.
It literally,
it ruins your football Sunday.
It fucking ruins it.
It's losing money on a game.
I'm telling you is so much worse
than just watching your team lose.
You know, your team loses, they
fucking lose, but you still,
you can still go out and go buy yourself
a slice of pizza. Right. You know,
maybe that key you had your eye
on. All right, that's enough.
That's enough with the sports
this fucking week I believe. Um,
so congratulations to the Co,
uh, the Cleveland browns fans.
I'm actually in some weird way.
It's Kinda hard cause you beat my team.
I'm actually excited that
you guys look like a,
maybe you finally pick the right
quarterback after years of, you know,
the Cleveland browns is kind of
like the Chicago bears or the East,
you know, where they just, I don't know,
they always get that Cade mcdowney Tim
couch or whatever the fuck his name or
they always get that guy,
that guy who was the fifth runner
up Heisman trophy guy, you know,
and they did it again this year with
Colt Mccoy and he, he looked great.
He fucking looked great. Stepping up
into the pocket, ran one for a touchdown.
He was fucking rolling out
throwing the ball on the run.
Like fucking Doug Flutie.
I Dunno, whatever.
What the fuck are you going to
do? God dammit, we got raped.
She got raped in Cleveland, uh, right
next to the rock and roll hall of fame.
Just to add insult to injury.
And then I got to get all these
emails from these jets fans. You know,
they were all laying in the fucking weeds,
just waiting for the Patriots to lose.
You know,
I was amazed at how quickly I got the
emails from them considering they had to
clean four quarters in one OT
of shit out of their pants.
Um, if you are going to,
if you are going to gamble,
I got to tell you that I met the, the cat
might be out of the bag, but there's a,
I love teams right now like Cleveland,
the lions.
Um, who else? There's was
one other one. The rams.
If those teams are on the road and they're
getting any sort of sizeable points,
uh,
I would go with those guys just because
they have competitive fucking teams.
Like uh,
they just lie in his head,
a great fucking draft and they keep,
they keep being like fucking five
point underdogs and that type of shit.
I don't know. Then they blow it in the
fucking, and that's the only thing.
Cause if they let up a touch them,
then you loo ads all fucking fixed.
How could it not be fixed? How do
you know, how do they pick the eggs?
The perfect fucking number. Every
God damn week. How do they do that?
You know,
if it's so fucking hard for me,
I don't get it.
Like literally be like if
I picked one game a week,
I should have a 50 50
chance of winning it. Right.
And after 1617 weeks with the
buy, I should be, you know,
501 game over one game under,
right.
I should be nine and eight or eight and
nine and it never works out that way.
Somehow you, you lose like 60% of the
fucking time. I don't get it there.
Any mathematicians out there,
they can fucking help me
out. I'm all goddamn years.
That piece of Shit fucking rough. This
is what happens too. When you gamble,
then you start fucking no in the names
of referees and that's when you have a
fucking problem. You start knowing
the names of backup punters.
I guess some people
know that shit nowadays.
Those fantasy football playing people
do that got him on my fantasy team.
Um, what the fuck on my questions
for the week. All right,
that was 20 minutes of sports. I really
good. Let's, let's talk politics.
Let's talk.
Let's talk politics.
The elections where this past week,
where are you guys excited?
Are you excited that we
took the country back?
How many times are we going to do
that in these elections? You know,
like two years ago,
I remember everything was the Republican's
fault and then they vote in all
democrats and people were like, yeah,
we took the country back, right?
Two years,
fucking later,
they voted all Republicans and they
say the exact same fucking thing.
This is the theme this week is
that everything is fucking rigged.
You can't tell me you, you
can't. You don't notice
that no matter who you put in now,
it doesn't really make a difference
that this sort of, this, this common,
that toe in this, the same line. Anybody,
anybody noticed that none of them are
talking about bankers and how they took $1
trillion. No one's talking about
that and just kept the shit.
No one's talking about that.
No one's talking about, uh,
how all these companies have fucking
taken all the manufacturing out of this
country.
We probably need to reverse NAFTA.
They'd probably be a good fucking idea.
No one's talking about that,
that Democrat or Republican,
the Algiers,
I think it's time to get
this country back to work.
Everybody starts screaming
like something's going to
fucking happen. You know,
Federal Reserve just printed another
$600 million out of thin fucking errands,
buying up bonds. It's, nobody's didn't,
nobody's talking about that shit.
Nothing,
nothing.
All they talking about is fucking family
values and getting people back to work
and a hard working Americans and
all this lip service, you know,
and then people vote Democrat
or Republican, right? Which
is your fucking right.
But then whenever I tell him I voted for,
uh,
somebody outside those two
parties who actually says, hey,
why don't we audit the Federal Reserve?
Why don't we figure out why there are
private corporation yet somehow print the
money for this country? They always
tell me that that's a waste of a vote.
So then you vote for fucking,
I don't get it.
I really don't fucking get it.
So I have one gives a shit.
This whole country's going
down the fucking shit.
Or everybody's just sitting
there yelling at each other,
fucking tea party screaming at people.
I fucking give it thought,
you know,
I just find the whole thing
unbelievably fucking a depressing.
I think the world is run by
sociopath's and who manipulate morons.
You know,
you've got this whole sea of morons
could fill up the Pacific Ocean with the
amount of morons,
you know,
tell me what to thank those people and
then the sociopath's tell them what to
think in. Whoever's the best at
telling them what to think wins.
Gi Bill. That was fucking deep. I know.
I don't know what the fuck I'm
talking above. You know what it is?
I just like the people who,
uh,
I don't know.
I got my me and explain it.
I just slides just like people who
just go, this, this is bullshit.
This is fucking fixed.
I like those guys.
I don't like people who go, uh, you
know, you know who are in the Jesus.
You know what?
This podcast went off the fucking
rails at least three minutes ago.
I don't even want him to say,
you know what?
I'm so fucking stupid that I don't even
realize that I'm one of those morons in
the Pacific Ocean.
That here I am trying to have this deep
fucking thought about politics and I
don't even have the fucking wherewithal,
the brainpower
to even convey my own thoughts.
So with that,
let's go with the obscure sports
stat of the week. This is a new,
this is for all the, the, the
sports nerds out there. Uh,
this is the obscure sports stat of the
week. This is a new segment. All right?
This is something I didn't
realize is how much, um,
teams from Massachusetts from
Boston have dominated St Louis.
Here's the tests. I was in Saint Louis
two weeks ago and somebody hit me.
Hit me with this stat. All
right, well, the last time
the St Louis Cardinals, uh, lost a world
series they lost to the Boston red sox.
The last time the city of
St Louis lost the Superbowl.
They lost to the New England patriots.
The last time the city is St Louis
lost a Stanley Cup finals game.
They lost to the Boston Bruins
and the most obscure of obscure the
last time St Louis lost in NBA finals in
1960 61 the St Louis Hawks
lost to the Boston Celtics.
We fucking own you guys.
St Louis. You hear me?
We've owned you since 60 61 and what
have you done about it? Nothing.
I'm all right. I'm bored shitless. Was
Sports too. Let's, let's move on here. Um,
what do we got here? Oh,
last week I asked you guys,
you know I was talking about that woman
who kept clearing her throat in a really
annoying way behind me on the plane.
And I presented this question to you.
I said,
what would happen if the most interesting
man in the world met the most annoying
woman on the planet?
What would happen?
And I asked you guys for your theories
and I got a bunch of them and I'm going
to try to read them now
and not fuck it up. Um,
this is what people had to
say without saying a word.
He can make even the biggest con shut up
and do the fucking dishes because he is
the most interesting man in the world.
All right. That's theory
number one. Theory number two,
most entering,
most interesting man plus contiguous
woman equals most miserable man.
That's pretty much yet bill.
Uh,
that is if your question implied in
inherent attraction between the two,
if it's just like a chance encounter,
like at a party or something like that,
the most instant interesting man would
probably just say it's such an annoying
cunt and he'd be on his merry way.
However,
if the two decided to form a relationship,
the most annoying woman would just siphon
everything interesting away from the
most interesting man chiseling him down
to a being that could equate her level
of unjustifiable existence. And then
he writes, wow, that's depressing.
Uh, someone should advertise
some pss or something.
There is no shame in a harrowing hunt.
So please do not settle for an annoying,
um,
brought to you by the people who hate
country throat clears allocated to their
immediate ear space. Um, all right,
let's move on with the
youtube videos for the week.
I'm going to blow through some topics
here just for some people cause I really,
I, I gotta I gotta tone down the
sports on this fucking thing.
It's just becoming the fucking,
uh,
beer and wings podcast here. Uh, youtube,
youtube videos of the week. Uh,
look at garbage day original.
All these, by the way, will be up
on the [inaudible] podcast.com. Uh,
look at garbage day original. And this
one right here, this one is from me.
And I think this is one of the
greatest fucking lines ever uttered in,
uh,
in movies ever.
Certainly in any sort of
teen movie that was a,
that's about teens rebelling.
This movie's called over the edge.
I believe it came out in 1979. Oh
yeah, that's what's over the edge.
1979 part nine. And, uh,
and just looking at that and you know,
I also started off with
revenge of the nerds.
That speech on this podcast that kind
of made me just think of some classic
movies could end bed. Ah, here's ALP.
Look up Al Pachino,
a great ass extended version.
Um,
one of the greatest actors of all time
with one of the worst performances I've
ever seen in my life. And,
uh, what else do I got?
Incident at subway.
Check that one out.
Some kid at subway wants to fight every
fight. Somebody behind the counter.
And Jesus, I didn't know
what's going on. Um, Nino,
uh, what else? Underrated. Overrated.
What happened to this podcast?
Something at 22 minutes happen at this
podcast in order to just as I went
outside and I'm still wearing my fucking
hooded sweatshirt and I think I'm
getting too fucking hot and it's
siphoning all the goddamn funny up.
But now I can't take it off because
I have my fucking headphones on.
So I gotta lay the microphone down
as they slowly take this fucking,
all right, here we go. Now I'm ready. Oh,
I remember what I was going to do.
I was going to tell you guys the
story this week. I did this awesome,
unbelievable fucking Gig. Um, it was, uh,
the Bob would riff fund whatever you call,
uh,
Jesus Christ.
I really thought that this story was
going to get the podcasts go on again.
What the fuck was it called?
The Bob Woodward,
a charity fund auction thing.
Bob Woodward was a reporter.
Uh, he was in Iraq.
He got hit by a roadside bomb,
made a miraculous recovery.
And this is the fourth annual one where
they raise money for his foundation.
That's the word I was looking for his
fucking foundation to raise money for it,
for, uh, you know, for troops who,
who've been injured in battle in that
type of thing. Just one of those, those,
those charities you just cannot say
no to. You have to do it. And, uh,
it was all the way back in New York
City at the Beacon Theater, uh,
for music fans out there.
They know that the almond brothers have
been doin the beacon run for like the
last 30 fucking years.
So already I'm thrilled to be there just
because I'm gonna be standing on the
same stage as Duane almond. And, uh,
and I showed up in the,
in the lineup that I went on was the
most insane lineup I have ever been on.
Um, in my career. This
was the lineup. All right?
Max Weinberg was there and he
put together this big band,
so they're out there fucking killing it.
Jon Stewart was the host.
He goes out and he kills it talking
about politics in a very funny way,
unlike the Horse Shit that I did on
my podcast, a, he fucking kills it.
Then he brings out Tony Bennett,
Tony fucking Bennet,
who sings two songs, absolutely kills
it, sounds as good as he did 40,
50 years ago.
Just kills it.
Then they bring out John Stewart
comes back out, does some more jokes,
kills again.
Then he brings out Bruce Springsteen.
Fucking Bruce Springsteen goes out
there and just fucking owns to stage,
sliding around, jumping up on the
piano, tells him, telling jokes,
just just fucking kills it.
Uh, then they had an auction,
at least fucking rich people's played
like 150 grand for one of Bruce
Springsteen's guitars, raised all this
money. Then the second half of the show,
they bring out Joel Mchale who had to go
on after Tony Bennett and fucking Bruce
Springsteen,
and he still somehow killed it.
Then I went up and then the final act
of the evening was Jerry Seinfeld. Well,
it's the do Jerry fucking Seinfeld,
the king,
the master.
Right.
And I'm on stage when I went out there
and my whole nervousness of the night was
not going on after those people was my
nervousness was the fact that nobody had
said fuck yet. And it
was a benefit, you know,
and people talking about tragedy and I
was going to go out there and my opening
bit was talking about,
you know, hitting women.
So I'm backstage just like mine,
fucking myself going on guys.
It's gonna be too harsh.
I shouldn't curse.
Jerry's going to get mad
at me the second I curse.
He's gonna look at me like I'm
not even a comedian, you know,
and I so badly want his fucking approval,
you know,
so I'm sitting there freaking out,
finally my age. It just goes, dude, gee,
you see what Springsteen just did? He
went out. He just does what he does,
jumps on pianos. Just go out there and
do what the fuck you do. I was like,
you know what, you're right. You're right.
So I went out there and I, I definitely,
I didn't say fuck as much as I
usually did, but I went out there,
I did my get hit by women, uh,
hitting women, all that type of shit,
a fucking killed.
And when I get off stage and
walking and is going on next,
so I'm walking off the stage
and there he is fucking Seinfeld
who at this point it's,
it's like,
it's like looking at Elvis Goddamn icon
is stand there and his suit just ready
to go to work. And I
walked by him. I'm just,
I'm just wincing when I'm waiting from
just completely blow me off or just be
like, why did you say
fuck so much? You know?
And I walked by him and he fucking sticks
his hand out and he just goes really
funny stuff. Really, really
funny stuff. And I was just like,
oh, thanks a lot. You know,
I try not to curse so much out of
respect for you going on, going on next.
And he goes,
well I don't care.
Then it felt like an idiot.
I'm sitting in me and I'll nervous
like a little schoolgirl now.
Just realize like, wait a minute, Jerry
has always worked totally fucking clean.
He came up in the late seventies,
right through the 80s with all these,
these barroom hack comics doing blow.
I mean,
the amount of shit that that guy had
to go on after working squeaky fucking
clean. He can't follow me. Well,
what the hell was I thinking?
And I would say that he couldn't
follow me. I didn't think of that.
He would be annoyed and a
then I stood there, you know,
feeling like feeling like I was 90
miles in the air because he said that he
thought that I was funny
or that it had good stuff.
And then I watched him go out
there and it just absolute, uh,
and not to bring up sports again,
but I guess I have to, you know,
any port in a fucking storm here.
It was like watching a, you know,
when somebody is just, just has
the, the, just the perfect swing,
perfect jumpshot their form or
whatever that that's what it was like.
There was just everything that he did,
there wasn't one wasted word,
one wasted movement. Every everything,
okay, you want to talk moves.
It's like toy story.
You go to see toy story.
It's like every line in the movie
just propels the thing forward.
There's not a line of fat in that
fucking script and it's just,
just like his act and he
goes out there and just,
just absolutely fucking destroyed.
And uh,
it was awesome.
The other than other night that I had
that ever compared to that was one night I
was down at the comedy cellar in the,
uh, in the village in New York City.
And,
um,
that's the club where if you want to
see if go out and see great comedy or if
you want to see a possibly somebody
super famous that's a comedian,
just drop in and do a set.
That's where I would go.
And it used to happen all the time.
And One night I was
down the cellar and uh,
give me name and a lot of names here, but
I, I never named names of the podcast,
but there's nothing bad about this story.
So Godfrey was hosting the show and um,
you know, I was supposed to, I think I've,
I think it was me. I was going on next,
but uh, all of a sudden, you know,
I am, I can't really tell the
story without saying the names.
This is basically just imagine you're
sitting in the fucking crowd. All right?
You just seeing no name hacks like me
going up and all of a sudden the host goes
, uh, hey everybody.
We've got a very special guest that
just dropped by wanting to do like five
minutes. You might recognize
this guy from the hit TV show.
Everybody loves Raymond.
Please welcome Ray Romano and ray
walks on stage and the crowd goes,
fucking not totally Fuck
Ray Romano, right? And um,
as he's on stage,
Seinfeld and Chris rock show
up and they also want to go on,
all right, this has happened once
in 20 years of me doing stand up.
This was the most unbelievable
night, right? So they go downstairs,
Ray Romano finishes.
So Godfrey goes back up and he kept doing
these great intros that was making the
crowd lose their shit. He goes, keep
going for a remodel. He goes, all right,
we got another special
guest just dropped in.
You might recognize this guy
from the Chris rock show.
Please welcome Chris Rock. And then
the fucking place standing ovation.
Holy Fuck. We got to see fucking
Ray Romano and Chris Rock.
And now at this point, every comic knows
that Seinfeld is waiting in the wings.
So we're all standing there,
huddled down in the little hallway
waiting to watch this crowd lose.
It's fucking shit like those soccer
moms on fucking Oprah, right?
Chris rock kills it.
Godfrey goes up, Chris Rock,
everybody crown is like out of breath
from fucking laughing. And then he goes,
uh, we had another guest
dropped by at this point.
People just like, what the fuck?
Right? He goes, you might recognize this
next guy from the hit TV show Seinfeld.
And I hear this guy go no fucking
way in the crowd. And he goes,
please Jerry Seinfeld. And that
like, half the crowd almost fainted.
He goes up and just fucking destroyed.
And like people,
I like elated. They have like, like
when he's done the everybody's faces,
like in pain from grilling and from,
from, from grinning. I swear to God,
this is true story, right? So
Seinfeld ends and he goes, ah,
I keep it going for Jerry Seinfeld. He
goes, all right, you guys ready for more?
Show the crowds like flipping
out. And they go, okay,
this next comedian and the crowd at
this point is so goddamn spoiled.
I'm standing there in the doorway waiting
to go on and everybody is trying to
look around my head for somebody famous
to come on and he's bringing up me.
He goes, please, you know, you might have
seen him on a VH ones. I love the eighties
MTVs apartment two F
please welcome bill burn.
I went on stage and there
was just, there was, uh,
a noticeable sense of disappointment at
that point when I walked up to the Mike
and the only way I got out of it
was I just addressed it. I was like,
that's right. Welcome back to reality.
This is what the fuck you paid for.
And then everybody laughed and
like, all right, he addressed it.
He addressed the fact that
we're disappointed to see him.
And at that point they kind of went along
for the ride and I swear to God in our
later Dave Chappelle went up
and he went up and that was a
dope. So that night and the
night I just did with the two,
two most unreal nights that I've
ever seen in a, in standup comedy.
I swear to God, that seller story,
I know it sounds like some bullshit.
I swear to God it's fucking true.
Um,
and I don't know why I'm
thinking that you're doubting it.
So if you ever go to New York City and
you just want to go out and check out
some fucking comics,
go to the comedy cellar right
down on a west third and Mcdougal,
right? I've said that like
9 million times in my life.
Flagging down a cab back in the day when
you could do eight sets on the weekend
every night,
flagging down the cab with the spot money.
Take me to west third and Mcdougal. Do you
want me to think the, the, the highway?
No, you fucking asshole. It's
going to cost me an extra $7. Okay.
There's a lot of traffic.
All right,
you Dick fucking take the other one.
You son of a bitch. What do I care?
What do I care?
Someday I'll have my own podcast and
I'll be selling ringtones at 99 cents a
whack. Just raking in the
fucking money. Um, all right,
let's get to underrated. Overrated
for this week. Um, all right.
This first underrated overrated that
I'm going to read is a, this goes,
this transcends the topic
of underrated overrated.
Because what you re not only did he
get to hear this person's underrated
overrated.
You get to see why having a tragic,
uh, childhood and I dunno.
I Dunno what, uh, yeah.
Basically that leads you to
be fucking hilarious because
all right, let me just
read this shit. This is,
this is from the same fucking person.
Alright.
Underrated your new girlfriend being
hotter than your ex-girlfriend.
Uh, that first face to face
meeting between them is priceless.
That's right. She's hotter and
skinnier than you enjoy the,
the eating disorder.
You can't.
So right off the bat you'd think,
wow, that's kind of harsh. The fuck.
Where does that come from? You learn
where this comes from in is overrated.
Overrated.
Your Dad telling you he loves you.
I heard you fag.
I'm not saying it back now.
Tell that fat bitch you left mom
for her to get me a fresh beer.
Now I'm gonna tell you right now,
if this dude ever did stand up,
he would be the guy that the comedians
hang in the back of the club.
Watching onstage is the crowds groaning,
laughing their fucking ass off because
they're relating to everything that he's
saying. Those are two classics. Those
are two fucking classics right there.
Um, I heard you the first
time fag. I'm not saying it
just completely walled off with the
emotions. Ah, that's fucking great.
That's a funny guy right
there. You already know it.
You know what? Anyways, um,
underrated modern horror movies.
Um,
being that it was Halloween last week,
every channel had a horror movie marathon
of some sorts and I watched some of
them. What happened to horror
films? They used to be scary. Um,
it might be that I have grown up,
but I think the real problem is that
they spend most of their time trying to
grow south. The audience. Have
you actually seen the movie saw?
Um, the first one was good, but after
that they just try to make you throw up.
I mean,
does the movie really need a two minute
sequence of a guy being injected with
acid and melting? Did that really happen?
That's kind of why I stopped watching.
I saw the first song.
I thought it was interesting and I started
to watch the second one and I'm like,
this is just gross.
This isn't really a scary,
it's like a, it's like
scary g, uh, like no,
it's like an even grosser jackass.
Right? Does that make any sense?
F let me just keep reading this Goddamn
Shit. Why am I trying this week? Um,
anyways, he goes on to say it would
be okay if they were unpredictable,
but they always make the killer
the most obvious choice choice,
which just makes it obvious. Did
that make sense? Yes, it did.
Why did you lose confidence in the
end? Um, no, I totally agree with you.
I think the problem with a lot of movies,
both action movies and horror movies
is that the special effects are so
unbelievable now that that's
what they focus on. This happens,
this happens,
this happens.
And then the fucking special effects
that they don't build any suspense,
you know,
and they don't really build the characters
where you give a shit about them and
you're rooting for them.
The amount of,
I just like mentally tap out of
most of them. And I'm like, well,
this guy is the lead,
so there's no way he's going to die or us,
the movie would be over.
So what's the fucking point of this?
And like I always bring it back to a
perfect storm. Like I could give a shit.
You know,
by the time they got to the wave,
I was like rooting for the wave because I,
I didn't care about their,
their pathetic attempt to try to bring
some nobility to these guys who went
fishing. They just so gloss over glossed
over the whole fucking thing I had.
I didn't even give a shit. So
I would agree with you sir. Um,
what else do we got here? A
underrated cane sugar. Seriously.
So much better than that. High fructose
crap. Pepsi throwback is awesome.
You know what? I'm going to try
it just because you said that,
and I'm not even a big soda guy.
I'm underrated going to a concert.
Most people I know have never been,
never had the full concert experience
of going to see someone you love and
seeing them live on stage, killing
it and leaving, uh, leaving def,
sweaty, tired, bruised, and
loving every second of it. Uh,
you're probably facing the same problem
with people going out to see stand up.
Actually, I've got to be at
Mit. I've been really lucky,
but lucky people have been coming out to
my shows. Uh, but anyways, he says, uh,
they think it's going to be the
same thing as watching it on TV.
I remember the first time I saw
you, do you stand up act? Um,
it was also the first time
I'd ever seen a comedy show.
I'm paraphrasing because I don't
know where I am in this sentence.
First Time we ever saw a comic
was you about four years ago.
And the live experience of seeing someone
who is good at their craft is just so
much better than watching it on
TV. Well, thank you very much, sir.
And it's considering you just gave
me a little bit of a pat on the back.
I want to thank everybody who's
gone out and is bought my DVD.
My DVD is killing it.
It's still last I checked still
in the top 10 on iTunes. Um,
I can't thank you guys enough this want
to sell and even better than why do I do
this?
Sold and I'm all the emails you guys are
sending me about that extra 21 minutes
of material that you didn't get to see.
Basically 25% of the special that you
didn't get to see on comedy central. Uh,
I read all of them.
I appreciate all the uh,
all the kinds of emails and all
that type of shit. It's nice.
It really offsets all the jet fans
giving me shit to read a nice compliment.
Now jet fans going to write, I love the
DVD and then I'm going gonna open it up.
Patriots suck. I already know you're
up to that. What do you think?
I'm a fucking child.
Um,
but seriously and Christmas is
coming up so keep buying those DVDs.
It's only like 10 bucks on amazon.com.
And as I stated before,
it makes a great stocking stuffer for
someone you don't give a fuck about,
but half to buy a gift for, go out,
bang out six of them for 60 bucks.
There you go. Frisbee around. There you
go. You cunt. Fuck you. Dickhead Pussy,
whatever. Up to six people, you know,
whatever. Just by the goddamn thing.
Okay. My ringtone was such a Goddamn flop.
People actually asking me to make another
ringtone and I feel like a band that's
scratching their head why they haven't
been dropped by their label yet. Um,
which actually segues us into some
of the questions for this week.
If I could find them. Somebody actually
asked me some drum questions. So bill,
I've got three questions for you after
I heard your drum battle on youtube and
you didn't suck a,
you seem like a relatively good drummer
and extremely good opinionator so I'd
like to ask your opinion
on some drum things. Um,
what do you think are some of the
hardest drum songs to play? Well,
for me it would be just about all of them.
Uh, I, I, uh,
the hardest ones I would say.
I would say as far as like for a look,
I'm going to get actually get into this
a little bit cause I really got hardcore
into sports,
you know,
not even remotely concerned about people
who could give a shit about sports.
So I'll get into this a little bit for
the musicians out there is I actually
found one of the hardest things to do is
to have the discipline to just sit down
and try and make what I
could physically play.
Actually sound good
because I think one of the,
one of the big things when you're learning
an instrument is when you physically
get something down, you move
onto the next thing. You don't,
you don't stay with it until you can
actually make it sound good and make it
sound good to somebody listening to you
play it. You just, okay, I got that down.
[inaudible] Pam.
Okay,
now I'm going to move on to the next
fucking thing rather than, you know,
if you learn like a drum fill, you
just get the fill down and you, yeah,
you play a couple of fucking beats and
then you just throw it in. Yeah, yeah,
I got that down.
You don't really have it down.
So one of the hardest things for
me was having a discipline. Um,
and it was something I learned when I was
watching Steve Jordan play drums and I
was listening to him play something
and I was watching it going,
I can physically play what he's playing
and what he's playing is actually really
simple,
but I could not make it sound.
1000000th is good is he's
making it sound right now.
Like he was playing a beat that would
actually be considered lame if I played
it.
And the way he played it,
it sounded unbelievably fresh and it
would make an entire arena just start
smiling and get into whatever
song was being played.
That was the fucking hardest thing is
far as trying to get halfway decent at
drums for me. But as far as, uh,
just songs that are difficult,
any of the shit by John Bonam,
his foot is just so god damn fast
and you can catch up with speed,
but you just can't play it
the way he fucking plays it.
And I've had unbelievable arguments
about people like, you know,
the coke and Pepsi argument with,
with White Rock drummers
is who do you like better?
Bottom or Neil Peart this is way
back in the day before all these,
these other kids came along and I just
fucking killing it and I always pick on
him. I didn't, I didn't think
Neil Peart was anywhere near him.
I thought Neil Peart was
like a fucking technician.
He played right on the beat and it was,
sounded very fucking robotic as opposed
to John Bonam who could play once again
the simplest fucking fill that I could
physically do but could never play it the
way he pleased that they just did.
This is the fucking shit.
It's like watching a great
actor, you know what I mean? Who,
who can just take like a really just
basic fucking monologue and make it the
most interesting God damn
like a Christopher Walken
or even John Goodman that I
was playing. Like I sometimes I forget
what a great fucking actor that guy is.
Um, I dunno, I dunno. So,
but as far as like songs that I would
say is difficult, I would say, uh,
the wanton song is ridiculously difficult
and I think most people play it wrong.
They actually leave out one bass drum
note where he's playing three in a row and
they only play two in a row at that
fucking tempo was fucking ridiculous.
Um,
out on the tiles,
that second fill that he does that ends
where he plays a fucking triplet with
one goddamn based Rome is
fucking ridiculous. And then
I also got to admit, uh,
that drum and bass shit and a lot of stuff
that like a, I love really into like,
uh, um, what's his face? A quest
love the shit that he plays.
He's another guy where I think he took
like the Steve Jordan thing to like the
next level. Um, and he, he does shit.
I don't even know what the fuck
he's doing, but I don't like,
I'm fucking stutter in here cause I
can't really think of any specific song.
I'll give you one here that I'm trying,
that I want to break out my double
pedal because I don't play double bass.
I just play a single bass drum.
But every once in awhile there's a drama
comes along that's so fucking good.
It makes me want to play double bass.
And um,
I've actually really, uh,
gotten into that band,
lamb of God and uh,
just to warn some of my older listeners,
uh,
this is sort of that, that Rah Rah
Rah Rah Rah kind of fucking singing,
but it's not as bad as some
of the other guys. But they,
they got this song called
break you and this,
there's a double bass pattern in the
end that I just think is the shit.
I'm sure all you guys who played double
bass, this is a fucking joke for you,
but this is something is the kind of shit
that makes me want to play double bass
.
Let's see if I got it.
Does here I can get this
just sounds ridiculous the way he's
singing. All right, here we go.
Listen to this fucking double
bass pattern. This is Chris Adler.
This is one of my new favorite drummers.
I think this is the shit right here.
Listen to this.
Here we go.
That shit right there.
That fucking machine
gun shit actually figured
out what the fuck he's doing.
But I that just amazes me that the entire
band can be on fucking point like that.
And I know you guys are gonna hit me
with a bunch of other double bass drum
players who are faster or whatever.
I liked their band because
the temple that they play at,
it's still fucking music to me because
some of those other bands I try to get
into, but it's maybe my
ear isn't ready to hear it,
but this shit is so fucking fast
dad.
It loses its effectiveness
that it stops being music.
It just sounds like a jet
that's like flying by but never passes
my ears. It's just sitting there
and my fucking ears. So, uh,
I guess that type of Shit.
Does that make any fucking sense? Why
did I do with it? What did I do? Um,
let's get to the next question.
Who are some of the best recent
drummers of the past decade? Uh,
I'll just tell you the guys that I like.
I like everyone from a,
whoever played with those original Chuck
Berry's, I like Ringo, Charlie Watts,
uh, Phil Rudd, Alex Van Halen,
Steve Gadd, Vinny, Vinny,
Kali Uda. Yeah. Uh, Steve,
Steven Adler, Chris Adler,
quest.
There's so many fucking guys.
Um, and I'm going fucking blank on all of
them. I really should have made a list.
You know what I'll actually
sense to the MM podcast.
I'll send you a couple of youtube videos
of some guys that I think are just
fucking amazing, uh,
amazing drummers. But, uh,
I don't know anybody who gives me the
fucking chills when I listened to them and
they know that that's
like the big thing that,
and they make me wish that I
could fucking do it. That's,
that's how I judge whether a
drummer is good enough, if they,
if they play some shit. And
it's so fucking good that
in might delusional head.
I start driving down the street,
fantasizing that I'm doing it, you know,
during the middle of the greatest HBO
standup special performance ever then then
, then that's, I get into a, I
get into that drummer. All right.
Number three is good times, bad
times, the only son that you can play.
I can barely play that side, but now
this, I can play some other ones.
I don't know. Did that bore the shit out
of you? Music people who gives a fuck?
'Em All right,
advice.
This is going to be the last thing and
I'm going to get on with my day here.
MMM. Advice. Bill, how's it going?
I hope that wherever you're at,
everything is going swell. Lol. All right.
It's kind of a question about a
relationship. Here's my story.
I'm 19 years old,
19 year old female who's been dating
a 2021 year old male and we've been
together almost five years old,
Geesh,
five fucking years.
And she writes fucking ridiculous.
Uh, fucking ridiculous. I know.
And our relationship has had its ups
and downs, like any relationship,
but lately I feel like I can't
stay in them anymore. Yeah,
that's understandable. You've been dating
him like half of your fucking life. Um,
I don't know what's wrong
with me or maybe it's him.
I don't know what's going on.
I have no fucking clue.
But he seems to have a really big
problem with weed. If he isn't high,
he can't think about anything else
but getting high. Oh God. Here we go.
His goal in life is to get high
as a fucking kite and giggle.
That's a peaceful, nice fucking
goal. Uh, she writes, what the fuck?
I don't want to be dating a
weakling who needs a drug,
like who leads a drug like that?
I want a man and I don't
know how to tell him that.
Every time I tell him I have
a problem with the weed,
we get into a huge argument
and I end up being the bitch.
I just want him to care about me more
than he cares about his weed and it's
hurting us financially.
We both only make 300 bucks a week and
he's spending 75% of his check on weed,
cigarettes and gas. I am the breadwinner.
I don't want to be the breadwinner.
I'm so tired of taking
care of his dumb ass. Um,
he doesn't even seem like he's willing to
change even a little bit. What do I do?
I know I probably sound like a complete
prude, but I'm not at all. Well, anyways,
uh, I really hope you read this and can
give me some good advice. All right,
ma'am,
you are dating a fucking loser.
Yeah, you're dating a loser, so you gotta
you gotta get out of it. I mean, the,
the only red flag in
there is when you said,
I just want him to care about me
more than he cares about his weed.
Now
the only question I have there as well,
what if he was really into playing guitar?
Would you then be like,
I just want him to care more about me
than he does about his guitar playing?
Because then,
you know,
that's actually a red flag with you
because you could be one of those awful
people.
Like one of the worst relationships
you can seriously be in is when you're
dating somebody who,
uh,
finds your passion to be a threat.
And then they systematically,
like,
they try to mind fuck you out of basically
either your dream in life all the way
down to just a simple hobby that you have
just because it steals focus from you
paying attention to them,
which I don't think you are in this.
I think you sound very rational. You
actually said, I don't know if it's me,
so I don't think you are being like that.
So I have to side with you 100% here.
All right, let's roll. Let's first of all,
we'll start with your
relationship and just,
just completely ignore the
fact that he's 21 year, 19,
you've been together for five years,
which means when you got together,
you were 14,
he was 16,
which means at some point he
was 18 and you were under 18,
so there was some sort of statutory
rape going on there, right?
Uh, we'll ignore all of that and
just get to the fact like, you know,
I've met a lot of my listeners would
probably think that I was going to trash
you for you saying that. I,
I am, I'm the breadwinner.
I don't want to be the
breadwinner, you know, and I,
and I would go out typical fucking broads,
you know,
they all talk about how they want to be
the independent Goddamn woman and Yada,
Yada, Yada, and all of a sudden they
got to take care of some fucking sponge.
Welcome to my goddamn world. I'm
not, I don't feel that, that,
that you'll like that. I, I know what
you see, a date and a fucking loser.
You're dating a future, a
subject on cops. It seems,
you know, you had, the way you describe
him, it's his he shirtless too.
This guy's a fucking loser.
He makes 300 bucks a week.
I'm not judging that aspect of it,
but he spends 75% of it on weed,
cigarettes and gas, you
know, right now, uh,
I'm picturing that guy that,
uh,
Matthew mcconaughey played in dazed and
confused just hanging around the high
school. Like, where are the parties,
ed man, you know, with his cool car.
Um, yeah, you got to get out
of the relationship, you know,
and there's nothing wrong as a female if,
if,
you know, I'm not saying that you go
out and just be a fucking gold digger,
but you want your man to be able to
provide. That's what the fuck we do.
We provide, we don't
provide, we're useless.
We don't have a womb right now.
Seriously,
but fucking useless. So I,
uh, I get it. Yeah, you got,
you've got to break up with this guy.
You mean, how many times can you already,
it seems like you're approaching
this guy on egg shells, you know,
he'd be really nice with you. You know,
if you just stop being a fucking loser,
you're pretty, you're not even saying
that you're being a nice person.
So if I had to give you any advice,
I would say you need to get out of that
relationship and considering you've been
in it since you're 14,
I think a,
you might be a little codependent and I
think you need to to break up with this
guy,
figure out who the fuck you are,
which will involve you staying single
for a significant period of time and uh,
and just know that you
don't break ups are painful.
Just prepare yourself for that so you
don't go running back to this fucking
loser and waste another five
years of your fucking life.
Cause you don't want to go through
six weeks of pain just, you know,
as they said and platoon take the pain.
All right?
Just get out of the fucking relationship
and just, just tell yourself,
this is going to suck for six weeks.
I'm going to wake up crying.
I'm going to feel lost.
I'm going to be wondering what did I
used to do with all my free time before I
was with this person.
You can have that bizarre feeling where
now you're looking back on somebody who
was a huge part of your life and
now they're becoming a stranger.
So then it just becomes this weird
episode. Like what was that? Who was that?
What the, was that my life that just went
into that fucking room for five years?
It's really busy. Just prepare
yourself that that's going to happen,
but every day it gets a little
bit fucking easier. Yeah.
Then one day you're gonna wake up.
You're not going to give a shit.
The Sun's going to be shining and uh,
and then just enjoy being single.
Your only fucking 19 years old,
there's no fucking reason to be in a
relationship that's serious for that
fucking long with the fucking loser.
So get out of it,
get through the pain. And then
after six weeks, you know,
just hanging out with your friends,
have a good fucking time,
but do not get into another relationship.
I wouldn't get into another
relationship for like a year.
Just be single for at least a fucking
year and feel how awesome that is to just
be single, to wake up, you know,
feel good about yourself,
but then not have to worry that someone
else is a Douche. So that drags down.
You're feeling good about yourself
quotient. Yeah. It just fucking be single.
All right. There you go. I said the
same thing 90 times in a fucking roll.
I realize it. And a, what are we going?
I'm a little over an hour
here on the podcast, so good
luck to Ya. All right. Uh,
that's it. That's the podcast for this
week. I will talk to you guys next week.
This weekend I am at the
funny bone in Columbus,
Ohio and uh,
Friday,
Saturday and Sunday are the dates
that I'm going to be there. Actually,
those are the days.
Here are the actual dates.
November 12th 13th and the 14th and on
the 13th I'm going to try to go to that
Ohio state, Penn state game.
You know, because I've,
I've been to Ohio state game,
but the first time I went,
they played bowling green and it
was like the middle of September,
one of those cupcake games and it sucked.
So I want to go there and get the
full on horseshoe fucking experience.
So that is it.
Thank you guys for all the emails.
Thank you so much for buying my DVD.
If you haven't bought it yet,
it's only 10 bucks. I swear to
God. Yeah, you're, you're, you're,
you're not going to be upset if you buy
this fucking thing and you're really be
helping me out because I will get another
deal to shoot another special that you
can then watch and enjoy.
See how it works. A little
surf and fucking turf here.
Beautiful. All right, I'll
talk to you guys next.
[inaudible]
[inaudible].