Hey, what's going on? It's Bill Burr and
it's time for the Thursday afternoon.
Just before Friday, Monday
morning podcast. And
ahhh
just checking in on you.
Just checking in on you.
I'm actually recording this
one's day before the game.
Seven Jeff fucking with Ya.
It's Thursday. I watched the game.
I know what happened. All right.
I got to say congratulations to the Saint
Louis Blues on your first Stanley Cup
Championship. Ever avenge Jake,
your mother's Day's loss was it
May 13th, 1970 something like that.
40 fucking nine years later. Um,
I'm not gonna lie to you.
I had a smile on my face
when I was watching all those
St Louis Blues fans going
crazy.
And one of my favorite things
in the world is watching,
uh, a franchise that hasn't
won it in forever when it,
but I feel like I got fucked
over because they beat my team,
so I couldn't fully enjoy it
the same way. Like I, you know,
I was rooting for the eagles,
you know, to win a Superbowl.
I just didn't want him to beat the
Patriots. So both of those, you know,
I felt like I would've enjoyed way more,
obviously if they weren't beating my
team. But like Jesus Christ, hats off to
the Saint Louis Blues Organizations, they
played a fucking masterful game seven.
It was such a great series where it
was really just the speed of the Bruins
versus this physical, we'll have
the blues, what was going to win.
And I got to say, oh, freckles kind
of called it, did he not, did he not?
I said,
the way to beat the blues is you got
a score first and pull him out of that
fucking trap defense that
they were playing, Eh,
which would open up the ice for our speed.
And that's what happened in game
like game three in game six.
Um, and when they went up one to
nothing, and I was like, fuck, we need,
we need to get this next goal. We need to
get this next goal. We can't have them.
We can't have them up to,
oh,
I mean I haven't seen the trap defense
played that well since the boring ass New
Jersey devils one,
three cups.
Some of the worst hockey I've ever seen
in my life as far as excitement went.
But what I loved about the way the blues
played it was as much as I was kind of
being a fucking cunt about it,
I actually in the end really
enjoyed the way they played. Um,
playing outside the lines a little bit,
but that is playoff hockey. And you know,
I lose looking up some hockey
stats before game seven.
The Bruins back in the day when the
Canadians would always be this, you know,
Don Cherry was our coach and
it's something I read was just,
he told him to have their sticks up high
around Gila floor and we still didn't
beat and Mckela Flora's whole fucking
head was swollen and cut up by the end of
this series.
So we've done shit like that.
So I would be a real fucking pansy here
if I was to complain about some of the
rougher stuff. And just
the bottom line was we, um,
I set it, dude. I said,
it said you don't want to go seven games
with this team because you're going to
be to beat up by the end. You
know, if you're the finesse team,
you gotta he gotta win it and five or
six or they're just going to weigh you
down. The way I saw him were down in San
Jose, which is exactly what they did.
And uh,
I was too hard on Billington.
I said he was astoundingly mediocre.
I was as hard on him is they have
been overly complimenting him.
All right? First Rookie
goaltenders I have a good 68 games.
It's like Patrick while only one 15
and 1986 because you could only win 15.
All right. The first round
was best three out of five.
So it's not his fault that he couldn't
have beat their ass and other fucking
game. Um, not to mention he won the cons.
My thing had a 1.92 goals against average.
My thing about Billington was this and
he had four fucking stand on your head
saves in a game seven so you can
never take that away from that guy.
But that guy was definitely a
different goal tender when he was down.
Okay.
When we win game six,
when we were actually fucking got a little
physical and we went up, you know, we,
we, we went up a goal,
you know, the same thing.
We didn't gain three.
All of a sudden the guy's given up five
goals that game and getting pulled out
of one game.
So last night what I was watching,
the problem that we were having,
and I've never seen a team for
check as well as the blue, uh,
and in recent memory
is the St Louis Blues.
What they kept talking
about their goaltender it,
I don't know what the fucking
game they were watching,
what the game was between
the goaltenders and like,
have you ever seen a fucking team?
Like
they stop like every fucking past we made.
There was like every time a Bruin
had a puck there was like a,
there was like a clock
thousand 1000 to get rid of it,
get rid of it or they would just going
to come up and just physically take it
away from you. We had the amount of
passes that we would like through the air,
like saucer pass try to do and they
would just bat it down out of the air.
Like they had like a fucking, I dunno,
like they had a goaltender's stick.
It was unbelievable how fucking
amazing they were at that.
I'm not good with the names cause I got
a kid now and I got to watch the game
with the fucking sound out.
But that number nine on the blues,
I can't remember what your first or
second goal and we, I think crazy.
Somebody had the puck and
he just knocked him down,
kept in in our zone and I was like,
and then you know, they're passionate,
they're passing that keeping it
in the zone the whole time ago.
If they score here, then that number
nine should get a fucking assist.
And sure enough they ended up scoring
I think on the tip shot or I can't
remember.
It was so sort of the partial breakaway
backhander that guy got by Tuco. Um,
but the big thing was to beat them.
You had to go up cause when you went up
then Billington came back down to earth
and the problem last night as we got down
and we got down early and then he got
to stay behind the cushy confines of the
way they were playing that trap defense
and we did not have a power forward
was what was lacking on our team.
We needed a guy in the slot taken the
punishment and we were to beat up and just
didn't have that fucking guy.
So what was happening is when we got
into their offensive zone, if you want,
we watched the game the amount of times
we had the puck in a good position and
we would pass all the way to
the other side of the ice,
go wing to wing and an NHL goaltender.
That's all day to go from post to post.
And we just didn't get any traffic in
front. And too many of our shots from,
we're from out near the Blue Line
where he had a wide open look. I mean,
by the time we finally got traffic
out in front and scored on him,
it took us six on five.
We had to have an extra guy so somebody
could stand out in front. And, um,
I dunno,
I love the blues aggressive style,
the way that they played and um,
and they knocked us on our ass and
we have to get bigger and stronger.
Congratulations that Bruins.
They went way further this year than
I thought they were going to. Um,
you know, we definitely got it. You know,
we got rid of too many like Sean Thorton's
and Luke chichis and Adam McQuaids
where we couldn't hit him back.
And that was really,
really hard to watch as a Bruins fan
because I've never seen us get physically
dominated like that. Um, but, uh,
I dunno. I Dunno. I Dunno.
It kinda ended up going the way
I thought I was going to go.
And I was honest the other day when I
said I had absolutely no feeling on which
way it was going to go in game seven,
which I don't know how you could,
because if you watch the Bruins and
game won a game three and games six,
you would think that the
blues couldn't play with us.
And then if you watch the Bruins
end game fucking two, four,
five and seven, you would've
thought we would've got swept.
It was such a fucking
weird series where it was,
it was almost like just whoever got out
front first like that was it and the
game was going to be played the
way they played it. You know, if,
if the Bruins got out front,
it was going to be a speed game and we
were going to win in Billington was going
to let up four or five fucking
goals or they got out front and,
and fucking, it was just going to
be this physical game and we were,
we were going to play 80% of the game
in our, in our own fucking end. But,
um, I don't know. I'll
tell you this though.
That's going to be a hell of a party on,
on uh,
on Saturday down there in St Louis. You
guys totally deserve it. We're really,
at the end of the day,
we're the better team.
I'm being a little cunty with your
goaltender and it has nothing that,
this isn't a personal attack on the guy.
I'm just so fucking sick of like
sports casters in sports networks,
the way they spew out stats with no sort
of historical perspective is the same
way a politician,
you know,
we'll fudge numbers and shit to make
this guy doesn't like babies. You know,
he voted no on this fucking thing and
they don't look at what's attached to the
fucking bill as to why
this person voted no.
Like this fucking horse shit where it's
just like this guy just had more wins
than Ken Dryden. It's like we can
drive and play and I think you needed,
he needed eight.
There was only two rounds of the playoffs
or you'd be watching like major league
baseball and be like,
I'll tell her,
here's a stat that just came in so
and so just pass babe Ruth the salt.
And the Swat for most
postseason play offs.
It's like there,
they're back in Babe Ruth played.
It was like whoever had the most wins
in the American league that was winning
the pennant. There was no play off. You
just immediately went to the world series.
So the best you could do is
play seven games in a year.
So now you could play, what is it?
The first round is the best of five.
You can play five and another four.
You play 19 fucking games in one year now,
so obviously you're going to start
passing these guys sit down and say, hey,
you know what I mean? He's
who's getting, oh, I'm April.
There's a reason why we're all sitting
there, right? Oh, hey, this kid right now,
he's got, I bet he's pinching
himself, seen his name up,
playing against eight fucker
guard to attack attack. It's just,
I don't understand that.
It's just like, well,
obviously if somebody is going to play
three times as many games potentially
every fucking year of their career,
they're going to start passing some
fucking amazing people. You know,
like Martin brought dirt.
My main memory of this hall of fame,
great goaltender was him stopping,
dumping chase passes behind his
fucking net. You don't have,
the best I saw was Patrick Wa.
That's the best I ever fucking soft.
So that's why being a bit of a cunt,
being a bit of a con,
it definitely fucking, um, you
know, it was fucking hilarious.
As I watched the game and a cigar bar,
I was so fucking sad when I left.
I forgot my credit card. I've got to
go back and get that today. But, um,
I, uh, I was in there. I'm in New York.
Nobody gave a shit about the fucking game.
I had to tell him to turn the game on.
And when the blues scored the first time
on the deflection,
the insult to injury was,
I was sitting there and somebody
just goes, oh, did they just score?
And then he's watched the
replay. He goes, Ooh, a ricochet.
It's just like, oh my
God. Oh, ricochet. Okay.
Um, anyways, but, uh,
and then the ones in New York fans
realized that I was rooting for Boston.
They started giving me shit
and I fucking destroyed them.
And then they all had to shut the
fuck up because they got nothing.
They got nothing. They got
fucking 97 fucking t. What do,
what are you going to chant that me kind
of what 2008 with the fucking Boston
Celtics, the fuck out
of here. Um, so anyway,
and then I ended up fucking leaving it.
Natus a slice of pizza. Like did you see,
I loved, uh, what's his face? Um,
El Pres there from fucking
barstool that video.
He took him just eating all kinds of bed.
That's what I did.
I went and I got to say,
I was watching the game with
Bobby Kelly and then I went,
he dropped me off when I'm staying
here in New York and I, uh,
went over and just got a slice a pizza
from the better famous race in the area
and I'm
just sat there by myself,
like that weird fucking feeling,
you know,
when you're that close and you fucking
lose and then it's the double whammy of
not only did you lose,
but that's the end of hockey for the year,
which by the way, thank you Canada for
hockey. Jesus Christ. I still maintain,
it's a fucking, it's the
best of the four sports. Um,
I was just sitting there eating that
fucking thing by myself. Gone at fuck.
And now I got to do the podcast and I got
to eat crow the next fucking day while
was fucking me. But I'm
over it. And um, all right.
So now that I've been a bit
of a cup of tea, a goaltender,
which he really doesn't deserve.
Uh,
so 1967 I'm going off the top of my head,
cause one of these mall where fucking
we know things took over my computer.
I have a brand new laptop
and they'd already it watch
out when they say you need
the new flash, whatever your
flash player needs to be updated.
I clicked on that.
So now I have to spend a fucking day
this week at the fucking apple store
figuring out how to get rid
of this fucking thing. Uh,
may all you fucking hackers
out there burn in hell.
All you fucking at the
fucking assholes who did this.
It's like you can't go after bankers.
You can't go after fucking real pray.
You got to fucking get some dumb bald
fucking redheaded contracts team.
Just lost the Stanley Cup final.
You've got to fucking take
over my computer so he can
make more money off of JC
Penney. You fucking assholes. So anyways,
sad sacks fans.
So this morning I got to go downstairs
into the laundry room of a where I'm
staying here and um, to
do my laundry here, right?
So I go downstairs to go do it.
You figure Thursday morning,
there's not going to be anybody here,
but actually most of the machines would
taken up. And fortunately I got one.
And um, so I ended up
going downstairs, you know,
after the Washington was done in this
guy sitting there and he's fucking
assholes who does his laundry
like once a leap year,
he's got all these bags of shit and he's
like taken up all the machines and he
starts going like a, yeah, I'm just
still waiting for one more, like worried,
like I'm going to take one. I go, that
one's mine. It's almost done. He's like,
all right. And the is mine is done.
He's like, you want this? You want this,
like trying to get me to take the basket,
you know, over. And it's just like buddy,
relax, right? So I take my shit out
and you know, the stuff, I'm going to just
let dry him the apartment. I fold that.
And then I put my socks and underwears
into the dryer and then all of a sudden
he comes around the corner with
this load of wet laundry and goes,
I'm just going to leave this here.
Absolutely. I'm like, what? He goes,
I'm just going to leave this here. I'm
like, what the fuck is he talking about?
Then I realized that was somebody
else's laundry. I'm like,
is that somebody else's
laundry? He's like, yeah, I got
to. Don't drag me into this.
He goes, what? I go, don't drag me
into this. That's not my laundry.
Don't ask for my, okay, look, I'm the
salting of the fucking laundry room.
Things like you have to say anything. I'm
like, you guys are fucking selfish cunt.
Right?
So I walk out just one of those
people you just want to get away from.
So I go out and I pushed the button and
I'm waiting for the fucking elevator.
Right?
And I look up,
I realized I didn't push the button
because I'm so still thinking about the
fucking game and what we could have done,
which is all futile at this point.
And I hit the up button and all
of a sudden he comes walking out.
So now it's like I got a fucking,
I got a write up with this asshole.
So I'm like, well, you know what?
I'm the first floor of apartments.
So worst case scenario, he
gets off on my floor. You know?
You know what this fucking asshole does.
You know what he does?
You know what it does?
It gets in the elevator
and he pushes lobby.
You fucking Billy. He got on my
elevator. Okay. Which is a thing.
My elevator is a thing.
If you get on it first,
it's your fucking elevator and if somebody
gets on after you and then fucking
hits a floor before you're getting off,
they interrupted your life twice and
they should apologize when they get off.
I do it. That's my, that's
my elevator out of kit.
Is there anything worse when
you're in a tall fucking building?
You come down and some fucking asshole
on 18 hits it and he gets on and then
fucking hit 17 it's like he
couldn't take the stairs.
Yeah,
yeah. Know you wear your wing tips.
We're going to get scuffed up.
Would you turn the corner? Oh, Bill,
what are you really mad at? Ah,
my team lost. God dammit. Um,
oh, I was going to say, this is off
the top of my head. The expansion six,
if I remember correctly,
was the Philadelphia flyers.
Pittsburgh penguins,
the Minnesota North Stars,
the St Louis Blues, the La Kings
in the California golden seals.
So the California golden
seals then I think became
the Oakland Seals in,
somehow they ended up in Cleveland
and became the Cleveland Barons.
And then they folded,
or maybe a few of them sort of
combined with Minnesota north stars.
I can't quite remember what happened
to them. So they never won one.
Let's see if I can do
this top of my head right.
The flyers won at first 74 and 75
then the next ones to win it.
We're,
well,
let's see here.
Would it be the Dallas Stop Minnesota
then be the Dallas Stars in 1999?
No, the Pittsburgh Penguins. They want
flyers. The penguins, the Dallas Stars
in [inaudible] 99, then the La kings
and then the fucking uh,
Saint Louis Blues when it last night.
So it took 52 years,
53 seasons,
um, for the expansion six, all
of those great fucking teams,
um, that added so much to
hockey, doubled the league.
MMM.
To finally had the last
one win the Stanley Cup.
Here's the weird thing about hockey,
right?
Let's say you had a 16 league and you
were adding another six teams who are
obviously going to be weak, right?
Because there are new teams.
Okay.
How would you divide those up if you're
going to make two conferences once you
take three of the original in one,
three of the new and three of the
original six and the other in three hockey
didn't do that.
They kept all the original six in one
division and put all the expansion six in
another division.
So the first round of the playoffs was
basically the Stanley Cup final between
the two fucking original six teams.
And that's why I believe we swept the
blues in 1970. Last time he played,
they were like go fucking
brand new franchise.
MMM.
So anyway,
is there anything else that I wanted to
talk about as far as hockey? I can't,
I literally cannot even go on my computer.
And what's funny is I,
I tried refreshing and clearing all my
web browser history and I lost all my
passwords. I can't even get into my
fucking email. It's a fucking nightmare.
Um, so now I'm going to
go over and, you know,
talk to one of the geniuses at the apple
store to see if they can fucking figure
out one of the evil geniuses who came
up with this mall where horseshit. Um,
I've now realized I'm not clicking
on anything anymore. Okay.
I'm done with this shit.
I'm going to get a rotary phone.
If you want to get in contact with me,
just fucking call me. Maybe I'll be home.
Maybe I won't be, I'm just
going to go back to old school
shit cause um, you know,
I was telling you when, you know, I have
these acting gigs when I go down on the,
um,
the,
uh,
the set there, you
know, in between setups,
I don't bring my phone or anything cause
I just feel like it just takes me out
of what little game I have as an actor.
I was actually down there and there was
a book on a coffee table and I actually
started reading it and I was like,
this is what I should be doing between
fucking, you know, when there was,
when there's a long turn around, like
it's going to be like a fucking half hour.
You don't want to keep doing the lines
in your head because then you can be like
a robot when you go out there.
At least that's how I'm wired.
But actually reading a book and old
man, Old Lady thing to do, it's fucking,
it's the shit that could believe how
enjoyable it was. It was actually,
it turned out to is Pete
Holmes's book, um, comedy God,
which I immediately thought
was funny. I'm like, all right,
is he just doing this thing where
he sleeps? Like overly bragging,
doing like a run burgundy thing?
And it was actually a lot of look forward.
I was skimming reading was a lot of it
was about like him being brought up in
religious and religion, overly
religious and getting into stand up.
And I read,
uh,
a couple of chapters of his book and
I was trying to find to see if he had
mentioned the first time I ever worked
with him just to see what his take was on
that weekend.
The first time I've ever worked with
Pete Holmes is I worked in at this comedy
club. I don't even if it's still out
there, was called Brewster's in Peoria,
Illinois. Hometown of the Great
Lake. Great Richard Pryor,
grace comedian of all time. And
um, we did this gig out there.
I just remembered it was like mostly a
bar and on stage it was sort of done up
like this old west kind of thing with
like these big whiskey barrels and looking
like provisions and shit where uh,
like we were going to go onto the
fucking Oregon trail or something.
We're up on the,
uh,
up on stage and I believe a long time
ago he actually posted a video of him
bombing during that weekend and we both
went out and watched the ring in an
empty movie theater was the two of us and
both got scared shitless watching that
thing and had a great fucking
weekend working with themselves,
trying to get to that part where
he first moved to New York.
But I actually read the part where his
marriage first marriage fell apart. Man,
that fucking guy's a great writer. So
check out that book. It'd be get a chance.
There's also another book.
MMM,
okay.
That just came out on Greg Geraldo,
which I didn't even know was coming out,
so I don't even know who wrote the thing.
I just saw Bobby Kelly
promoted it on his Instagram.
So I'm definitely going to
get that book. Um, you know,
I don't know.
I don't even know how to do with people.
I don't know what I'm doing. I'm fucking
devastated. I really am devastated.
My fucking beloved Bruins lost.
And I'm also oddly really
happy for Saint Louis,
you know, long suffering fans. It's
just the weirdest fucking feeling.
MMM.
I was actually sitting there with Bobby
and we just don't do you this fucking
bullshit. And I was just like, they play
or the bed, they're the better team.
They're the better team.
And when they raised the cop,
just seeing how excited the guys actually
had a smile on his face and Bobby's
looking and it's like, dude,
I fucking love this shit.
This is the best fucking trophy ever.
Um,
but I, I would be lying to
you if I am not fucking, uh,
if I didn't say I wasn't fucking
devastated right now. Jesus Christ.
And then, then that's it.
Thank God for Moto Gp.
Thank God I got into motorcycle racing
because took to go from the end of the
fucking NHL playoffs and
just the level of intensity,
you know, trying to
ease your way, you know,
into fucking the dog days of
fucking baseball. You know,
I,
I always equated it must be like what ric
flair felt like after doing a road of,
you know,
of run of wrestling and then cut trying
to come home to his family life and
trying to come down from
fucking woo styling, profiling.
I'll let Shane screaming.
It's like this fan version of that.
So thank God for fucking Moto GP and
I get to watch those fucking amazing
lunatics race those bikes
around a 200 miles an hour.
And I'm not shitting on baseball because
I do love baseball. Actually. Um,
you know, I've been so into the NBA
finals in the Stanley Cup final that,
you know, the other day when there was a,
there was a day off. I actually was like,
I have to watch some
sort of competition here.
And I watched the Yankees mets
game and I was able to get into it.
Um,
I prefer the Yankee feed over the meth
feed just because I'm more familiar with
that.
Michael K and all of that.
And I also love listen
Depaulo Neil and [inaudible].
But I was just sitting there. I
Dunno, I have to tell you this,
so let's, let's talk. So in the end,
congratulations to the Saint Louis Blues.
Congratulations to Billington
for proving me wrong.
I mean he had just forced stand on your
head. Fucking saves in a game. Seven.
I mean, you don't get lucky like that. I
think the kid is the fucking real deal.
All right there. I said it. Um,
but I've gotten so into uh,
this NBA final finals, Jesus
Christ, jumping back and forth here.
I was initially for Toronto and I still
really kind of am because of the Toronto
fans, but I have to play. At first I
was making fun of Drake. Now I love them
because I find myself watching him
when the ball's being brought to court.
Like he is so out of his fucking mind.
He's,
he's literally pacing the sidelines.
Like he's coaching the team.
Like I was watching them when they were
bringing the ball up and he was just
manically making this spread,
like spread the off fence
fucking uh, gesture. And
I'm going like, this guy
has, has, has lost his fucking mind,
like tease doing shit that I do in my
living room when I know nobody's watching.
He's doing this on television.
So part of me,
I don't want to run out a win
cause I want to see this again.
I don't want to see satisfied Drake.
I want to see longing for a championship.
Drake and a,
that last game watching,
uh,
the warriors show why
they fucking champions.
You know, and I, I'm not, you know,
I didn't get upset with Toronto fans
cheering when kd went down. That was,
that was fear more so than
disrespect. That was just like, oh,
thank God this guy is out.
All right.
Although there was that
one cunt in the front row,
you know, who was dressed,
sort of like, you know,
he looked like he listened to
fucking remember those awful, uh,
rap metal bands from
the early two thousands.
He looked like a fan of one of those
bands and he was like waving bye bye.
And it's just like, who the fuck
does that? Who does that? Right? Um,
so
this is what I think happens in
that series. I think golden state.
I know, but you've got Leonard
Leonard is just fucking ice water
when you won't even give a fist pound
to one of your own fucking players.
That's when you know you're in the zone.
He's like the fucking Marshawn lynch.
Like his attitude when he doesn't
give a fuck about anything.
Except when you saw that quote,
when they split it home and they were
going out to golden state and the, the,
I must set the teacher, the coach was
going, you know, we go out there, we did,
we get one, you all we to
do is win one game. And he
speaks up and said, fuck that.
Let's win too.
And then they did.
He's like fucking John Wayne in a western.
So I don't know. I don't actually,
I gotta be honest with you.
I will be happy either way.
MMM.
Watching this series, no matter
what happens, I will, you know,
in the end I think I want to see Toronto
went a little more just because they
haven't won a championship in so long,
but like the next championship,
I really wanted to see Toronto when it
was, I wanted to see them win a cup. Um,
you know, I, I will tell you
though, anytime I see Toronto
fans gathering outside,
watching something on a screen, I get
a negative feeling going. Like, oh,
how many times we've seen this,
they gradually start peeling off.
It's one of the saddest, slowest, um,
departures of a fan base you're
ever going to fucking see.
But God bless them because
they do show up. Um,
so I wanted to go seven games.
My gut feeling is golden state
comes out and wins game six and
then loses game seven in Toronto.
I just think Toronto might wear
him down by that point. Uh,
golden state is really banged up. But, uh,
I will tell you what would be fucking
sick as if Toronto goes into their
building and fucking ends their
dynasty in their own building. Oh.
Oh,
you know what,
that will take me back to 1985 when
Kareem hit that last fucking sky hook.
I never forget that. And he ran
down the court and he fucking made,
he balled up both his
fists like that's it.
We got these motherfuckers
and I was just like, ugh.
They finally beat us in the final
finals. All right, and with that, let's,
uh,
let's read.
Let's read a couple of
fucking advertisements here
for the podcast. All right,
we got butcher box. Everybody out. Do
I love these guys this much this month?
Munch, I'm already thinking
about eating this month.
Butcher box is offering
free bacon for life.
Sign up now and you'll get paid a one
of the best tasting bacon free in every
box for the life of your subscription.
Butcher box, Bacon is whole,
30 approved, whatever that means. I'm
cured nitrate and sugar free right now.
New members will get a package of Bacon
for free in every box for the life of
your subscription.
Plus you'll get $20 off your first box.
This is incredible quality of butch. The
incredible quality of butcher box meets,
starts with the commitment to humanely
raised animals that are never fed
antibiotics or home hor hormones.
They're shown Disney movies before
they're slaughtered that we mentioned.
It's delivered right to your door to
receive $20 off your first box and a
package of free bacon in every box
for the life of your subscription.
Go to butcher box.com/burr enter.
Burn the checkout at checkout. Go now.
Limited time offer. You
know, just to let you know,
my favorite is the
heritage bread. Pork. Okay?
That is just the best pork
chop I ever fucking had. Uh,
everything's high quality grass fed grass
finished free range, organic chicken.
A heritage breed pork is by, you're
supposed to say it. Um, I'm telling you,
that's the only, only the ad read I have
on my mouth waters as I'm reading it.
Thinking about that fucking good food. All
right. Oh look who's here. Do, do, do, do
[inaudible] Singh.
Enough fucking blues Doo Doo Doo Doo bid.
[inaudible] niece we lost.
Now what do you dues?
You aid your credit card and get us slice.
The other team won and that's not nice.
I'm gonna Cry Until October,
but he banaba do boop boop. Oh,
shout out to James Talent Harris.
Okay.
One of the New York kings of comedy,
one of the New York kings of
comedy acting like a sports queen.
No text message. When we won the
world series, no text message.
When we won the super bowl,
we lose the Stanley Cup final.
Typical New York fan
pops his fucking head up.
Jesus Christ. Surprised I
didn't hear from Rob Stapleton.
He's another fucking half ass fan.
Never around during the losses and
like they're whack a mole fence.
Then there,
then they're comedy kings on stage
when it comes to fucking sports fans.
They're fucking queens are.
I'm sure we'll be hearing from
both of them now. All right,
Mandy is there are two
types of dudes in the world.
Did Bobby Kelly did a,
those that go through the gate and
those that go over the fence will,
after all these years of research and
countless experiments with seasoned
underwear,
scientists be on these now has options
for both with their new boxer briefs with
a fly.
It took a while.
But now men from both sides of the aisle
can enjoy the world's softest undies.
Beyond these uses,
the coveted micro modal modal fabric,
which is a full three
times softer than cotton.
Not only will you feel like your
loins are being hugged by joy itself,
but me undies gives you multiple
style options for both men and women.
Men can try out the new boxer
brief with a fly, with a fly.
You're going to have metal
that close to you, Dick.
So I never understood people who go
fucking nature. Boy. You know what I mean?
Don't you wear, your balls are going
to get snagged in the zipper. Ah,
you never saw fucking I'm
gonna set my cousin Mary.
There's something about Mary a men cannot
not try the new box where you put the
fly. It's the same. Great. Cut His boxer
brief just with a hole for number one.
Be undies for number one. Fellows, do
not unzip that and try to drop a deuce.
You're gonna have a problem.
Me undies is more so than Tom
Hanks in that fucking movie. Uh,
Mandy's is also the goal
for the softest lounge.
Where is the Goto for the softest lounge?
Where on the planet hangout in they're
super comfy lounge pants in onesies. Yes,
me undies makes me a one onesies
and there they are. Incredible. Um,
Yancey says a great offer for my listeners
for any first time purchasers when
you,
when you,
when you any money me undies the
fuck they're missing words here.
When you order any undies, you get 15%
off free shipping. Get 15% off a fair,
the most comfortable undies you will
ever put on a to get your 15% off your
first pair of free shipping and
100% satisfaction guarantee.
Go to [inaudible] dot com slash burr.
That's me on [inaudible] dot
com slash burr. All right.
That sit at once again. Um,
lastly, but not leastly truly
from the bottom of my heart.
Congratulates the Saint
Louis. You guys, you know,
without a doubt where you
just were the better team.
You guys played fucking amazing hockey
and I really thought it was a great blend
of the old style hard style of play that
I grew up watching and the new style
and um, great franchise,
great fucking fans.
I'm sure a lot of band wagoners we'll
be there on Saturday for the parade.
But all you old school guys,
you know,
congratulate men and women who
watched that team. Congratulations.
God knows you fucking
waited longer. Ford, uh,
which makes it all the more sweeter,
right? And Joy. This fucking sad music.
I want up. They'll be sad music. I
have no idea. I don't pick the music.
And then we'll have a greatest
hits from a Thursday afternoon,
just before Friday, Monday morning
morning podcast when maybe I was a
little happier.
Jones, when was the date?
30 told the chest plate.
Mommy does cry in and everybody's
dressed up in black suits.
Don't wind up pay.
The last respects told the black true
is the question that we're Runda but
everyone knows that every day is a
different number. So what are your Tom?
Tom's just remember you'll always
have a place in this world as a member
expressively who passed away back in 92
best believe that all the boys in the
hood, it's got whatever we go,
whatever we be thinking of how we've
rung in the clubs smoking and now we're
missing out on a hood.
FICUS Amery Day back in the,
we had a good fight.
Everything has changed and people
are looking lonely as gold.
B strains in the new year.
Z without your home.
But a must have.
We can do except for group through
opportunity to make sure we dealt with and
[inaudible] hurts to save the boy. You're
broke bread with six feet in the dirt.
Hey, what's going on? It's
built burn. It's the Monday
morning podcast for Monday,
June 12 2011. How's it going? Eh,
get fuzzy on the damn man.
[inaudible] um,
yeah.
Why,
why do I keep doing these by my self?
I have the Star spangled banner is in my
fucking head because the NBA finals in
the Nhl finals have have never been on
the same night and I've been watching all
of them. So that's all I've been
hearing every fucking night. Oh,
C car and your c.
And then when you watch the fucking
NHL finals, you also get, Oh,
Canada do glory.
Pretty Major.
Both set up and hockey
and some fucking cash
boo.
The Alaskan pipeline and Fuckin
people who think they're from France,
um, just every fucking night. And uh,
you know,
start to fuck with me.
Can you guys tell that I have absolutely
nothing prepared for this week?
Nothing funny to say. Um, I don't,
I got nothing.
It's a minute.
23 in and I'm ready to pull the fucking
plug cause I've got too much shit to do.
I'm actually recording this on a Sunday
afternoon. A Beautiful, beautiful Sunday,
sunny Sunday afternoon.
Did you go to church below,
Geesh? Uh, no I did not.
Although when I was out in the forest,
I gotta tell you when I,
last week when I thought I was
going to get eaten by a bear,
I did pray to a higher power.
And I know what a lot of people right now,
a lot of you,
Jesus freaks out there.
A lot of you people who were into the old
Jay star are probably like, yeah, see,
see, you believe you believe. Um,
I believe in higher power. Yes,
absolutely. But I don't believe
in the, in, in, uh, the stories.
I don't think he's ever talked to anybody.
That's, I think that's what I believe.
You know,
like today I was in the car and my
girl was bugging me and I said to her,
you know what? You're really making
me want to slap you in the face.
You know what it is? She's held that on
fucking painting the Goddamn apartment.
I don't know why.
All right.
And I have to do a benefit tonight and
then I have to go fucking go straight to
the airport and take a red eye to Chicago
coming in a day early because I got
some friends out there and there, they
got some ice time somewhere and you know,
why not? I'll fucking come in a
day early, play a little hockey,
continue my Peter Pan Lifestyle.
So of course she's just like,
I want to pay to live and grow.
We have to get this done.
We gotta get drop cloth, we
gotta get some paid, Yadda,
fucking Yada. Right? So where did she
go? I go, all right, what if, where,
where are we going? Where
are we going? And she's like,
we have to go to home depot. All
right. Which I fucking hate home depot,
I can't stand it.
All right with that 900 foot ceilings
and they're two employees that they have
there and you finally run into
one and it's like, you know,
first of all you go win the fucking place.
And that same feeling I had when I walked
into the forest where I was like all
alone and I didn't know what
the fuck was going to happen.
That's what you feel like when you
go into these, these superstores is,
they call them and then you walk in there
when you finally fucking find somebody,
you know, oh that's not my department.
I just do window shades. You know,
back in the day when you
walked into a hardware store,
the fucking person knew the whole
goddamn store, first of all,
because it was only the size of
a, I dunno, I dunno. I've store
and I know all you guys out there who
get on your knees and slurp the corporate
cock are going to tell me, well,
you didn't have as many selections.
Go Fuck Yourself. All right,
swallow the load and kill yourself.
Because though the old school hardware
stores, they were better. You walk in,
there was some grumpy guy
there and you'd be like, yeah,
I need a fucking widget and a no, no,
no, no fucking shower curtain rink.
And he'd look up, you know from
some shitty was whittling on,
he tell you exactly what the fuck it was
and he continue whittling as a corner
of his eye.
He looked at you as you went in the wrong,
you written that down a on a bottom
bottom.
You were one of those guys. Now you've got
all those Douche bags out there, right?
People work at home depot,
basically people who couldn't get
a job at the apple store, you know,
they couldn't get one of those genius
tee shirts and now they get an orange
apron and then he'd just stand around.
You know, you're looking at their nails.
I don't know what. So anyways, we get
down to this fucking place and uh,
as we're driving there,
all right? Evidently,
whatever paint she wants to get, I
wasn't involved in this fucking decision,
you know? Um, whatever the brand is,
we're on our way over there, which I
really don't have time to do. She goes,
oh my God, I hope they have,
you know, Eddie Rabinowitz's,
eggshell fucking Robin egg white or
whatever the fuck she talking about.
And immediately my head, I'm
like, why didn't you call ahead?
Why didn't you call ahead?
So what do you think happened everybody?
What do you think happened?
We went into the,
the fucking monstrosity that is home
depot with their 40,000 fucking different
selections. Guess what? They
didn't have the Eddie Rabinowitz,
Robin Egg, fucking blue,
God damn coffee cream,
whatever the fuck it was called.
They didn't have it.
So immediately I get pissed.
So she looks for a silver lining.
Well at least they got drop cloth.
Um,
so then we got to get out of this some
shit I didn't have fucking time to do
anyways in judge. She wants me to stop
and Mcdonald to go get her a fucking, uh,
the lemonade frozen Frisbee or whatever
the fuck drink they have there.
And I'm like, no, I'm not
doing it. I don't have time.
So of course she starts pouting. So
what do I do? I give in like a fag.
I given,
you know,
and I was sitting there and
the God damn fucking line
and uh, you know,
Mcdonald's is hilarious now.
Evidently they're trying to go healthy.
I think the biggest loser
is really starting to fuck
with these fast food places.
Cause all these fatties are finally
realizing, Oh really? I can't have three,
7,000 calorie triple double
cheeseburgers with Bacon on it.
Evidently that's the reason why I have
this slab of shit that's covering my
knees at this point. Forget
about my genitalia. I think they,
uh,
the biggest loser,
I think that they've actually had an
effect because I went there and you could
actually get like a Waldorf salad or some
shit, some salad with like an apple in,
which was hilarious because you
know, it's sucks. It's still somehow,
and then they had like some
low fat yogurt with WWE is,
as long as Mcdonald's is doing it,
it's somehow still going to come
out to about 9,000 calories. So a,
what the fuck was my point here? Let's
talking about slapping her in the face.
Okay.
Oh, that's what I said. I'm a
slapping the face. Ah, Jesus Christ.
I was going somewhere with this.
The fuck was I talking about?
How did I get into this is
talking about going in the woods.
Ah, Jesus ain't no, I don't even fucking
remember. I'm such a long winded jackass.
What the fuck was I talking about?
There's something about slapped her in
the face and then I didn't do that and
that tied into some other shit that
I can't fucking remember. Ah, fuck.
Why do I try? Oh, it's
talking about church, right?
Why don't believe all that's right.
That's right. Church. There we go.
We're back on track. Everybody back
on track. So I said, I'm going to,
I really feel like
slapping you in the face,
this is when we want in the way of the
Mcdonald's. And she goes, you know,
obviously looking at him, looking
at me like, don't do that. So I go,
you know what I'm going to do?
I'm going to slap Jesus instead
because she's into rosaries, you know,
and she has it hanging from the fucking
rear view mirror of our stupid Prius.
So I'm gonna do, I'm gonna
slap Jesus. Anyway, so he's
sitting there on the cross,
of course, always in that
moment, look what I did for you.
Right?
So I just fucking slap them right on
the cross and he flies back and forth.
So she starts giving me shit.
Don't slap Jesus. Right.
And uh, yeah, that's when I
just kind of said, you know,
he really think that this
happened, that God, you know,
took out as giant fucking hire being
dick came into this fucking petri dish,
the size of a Jacuzzi.
Right.
And then took out some sort of syringe
in artificially inseminated. Uh,
what's her face there? Jennifer was
that was at his mom's name. Right.
Okay.
Do you really think that happened?
It didn't,
it didn't happen. Am I saying there's not
a higher power? No, I'm not saying that.
I'm just saying all these fucking
stories that they're telling you
are there that made up, this
guy did the, uh, you know,
we came out of a womb that
was never in a banged and uh,
then he died for you when the only way
to get into heaven is if you do what we
say and uh, give us some money. I mean,
how fucking dumb are you if you go
into that shit, I can't help you.
I can't fucking help you.
But if you want to talk about a higher
power, definitely believe in that shit.
But none of us know what it is. I don't
believe. I don't, I don't fucking know.
I don't know where you go. I
don't know what happens, but uh,
neither does anybody else
cause you read it in a book.
What happens when you die? Who
wrote it? Who exactly wrote it?
How dumb do I sound right now
at all? You, Jesus freaks.
Y'All rolling your eyes as you write with
your feathered pen to punish yourself
for some bullshit that you did.
Um, here's something for you.
I don't believe in ghosts either,
right?
We're just going to go right down the
line of shit that I don't believe in.
I don't believe in Jesus and I
don't believe in ghosts, but, uh,
I gotta admit this.
Some sort of paranormal shit been going
on in my fucking apartment lately.
All right?
We went on vacation,
we came back and all our forks are
missing except for two of them,
you know, and on two different
occasions I've been playing guitar.
I get up out of my little fucking
play pen area, slash, office,
and, uh, I walk in to talk to
NEA and then I come back in.
My settings are different
on my fucking amp. So, uh,
I think considering that the ghost stole
my forks in his fucking with my amps,
there's only one logical
conclusion that this spirit,
uh, died at a Scorpions concert.
That's what happened. All right?
And the only heavy metal fans got
debt. Remember that? That song,
there's no one like you and the
guy had the forks in his eyes.
Remember that Shit.
I think that that's what's going on.
So I'm going to be on the next season of
a ghost hunters and I'm going to sit in
there with some douche bag with a
video camera yelling at the ghost.
You have exactly four
minutes to show yourself.
Do you ever see that?
Have I talked about that?
How ridiculous that fucking
show ghost hunters is?
Those fucking idiots sit around yelling
at the, they always somehow, first of all,
they always know that ghosts name and
they'll just be sitting there yelling at
the ghost,
like threatening,
like threatening this
spirit that evidently is,
is hanging out in a
kitchen for all eternity.
You know Maggie,
we know you're here. Alright,
we're getting sick at this.
You got four minutes to show yourself
or packing up all our equipment.
Okay.
Right. And what do you think Maggie?
Sinking. We'll do it. I don't give a fuck.
This is the most entertaining shit ever.
Sit here. Frustrating you guys. How,
flicking the year, my little
ghosts, fingers on the way up.
You guys believe in ghosts.
Do you believe in that shit?
I was actually watching a,
there's some fucking channel,
I can't remember the names of anything.
It's called like Payola or something.
Pirelli that's a tire or they,
they have all these fucking unplugged,
uh, sets by these bands. That's
my computer making all that noise.
And uh, I was watching one. Uh, you
know, when you get to be old like me,
he w you just lose
touch with modern music,
but there's bands that you just,
you keep hearing their fall out boy,
and I'll fuck you while you young people.
Oh my God. That's like Thoreau, 2000,
whatever. I don't give a fuck.
I'm just saying they blend in.
So one of them was my morning jacket.
All right.
Now when I grew up, no one would name
a band my morning jacket. All right.
You'd name it something that had to do
with Satan or else I wasn't going to
listen to it. So whenever I heard my
morning jacket that just sounded like,
uh, you know, it was going to be like that
Jack Johnson's kind of stuff. You know,
that shit that like
women and hippies like.
Yeah.
Um, so I, I never listen to it, you know,
I just thought it was going to be more
like that fallout boy. Like that whining,
crying. I remember like the last
10 years, that emo shit where,
where was that song that, that
I, I made fun of that one week.
[inaudible] two.
Does
that sound like you're
going to win anything?
That sounds like you're already lost and
you're walking home crying to your mom
and you just talking shit cause you to
fucking embarrassed knowing you lost.
So I assumed that they were
kind of like that and uh,
I dunno man. I watched their,
if they're unplugged set,
they were fucking unbelievable and I
want to download some of their shit.
All right,
legally.
So let me know how's your latest album?
Because there was somebody else who was
on like leaky Lee was on before and I
watched her shit and I loved it.
And then I listened to it on
iTunes and I was like, ah,
the unplugged shit sounded way better.
Her shit was like singing through
all this distortion stuff. I,
which I can't stand after a
while, you know, it's like, bitch,
just sing the Goddamn song. Okay,
stop sounding like you're fucking,
I'm listening to it. Three
floors above you. You know,
if you're going to do some shit like that,
do it the way Jimmy page did it
and I felt like I was in on acid.
You know how he used to do that shit and
he and he would have it you back in the
day you would listen to
albums on headphones and bands
knew it and they knew you
were on drugs and they used to
try to enhance the experience.
That's how great rock used to be.
Okay.
That's how into drugs they were,
they knew you were on drugs so they would
make album and they were on drugs and
they would make albums that would make
being on drugs feel better and they used
to do shit where they would,
they wouldn't, whatever.
They'd have some sort of some sort
of effect going on and they would,
they would make it go from the left side
to the right side, just your speakers.
But when you had headphones on,
it felt like it pass through
your Goddamn head is tremendous.
I don't know.
I don't know what the fuck they do.
The yell into a bullhorn throughout the
whole fucking concert into a microphone
like that. That's the best you can
do. Who does that Shit, you know,
does that all the time?
Is that Guy Scott Weiland said his name,
the guy from STP velvet revolver.
He's big into that.
Singing through the fucking bullhorn is
he walks around in his a Nazi supermodel
outfit.
Anyways, this is the Monday
morning podcast. Everybody,
are you a new listener?
I hope you are. I hope we
continue to grow this podcast. Uh,
I do one of these every God damn
week and people send me questions.
They asked for advice. They send
me lists of underrated, overrated.
We talk about Youtube
fucking videos that we like.
I curse a lot because I don't read.
I'm not intelligent.
Um, all right. Speaking of youtube videos,
which I keep forgetting to talk about.
Um, I got a bunch at this point. Here's
one you got to walk on. These are all,
by the way,
all of these can be viewed
exclusively@theemmpodcast.com. Um, first
off, I did another tour of a, you know,
those videos I make where I do like
the tours of Los Angeles and show you
different parts of La. I'm actually,
uh, I did want to New York City,
um, and we just put that up so we'll have
that on the MLM podcast page. And, uh,
do you remember when I was sick a few
weeks ago and I felt like Shit and all
that, uh, this video was shot
the day that I was getting sick.
Notice when I'm on the subway, when
I'm walking down there, look at the,
the flop sweat on my giant forehead
as I'm starting to get sick.
Um, we got that and here's, here's
a video that has since blown up,
which pisses me off because
I've been meaning to talk
about this one for a month.
There's one a video called fan escapes.
Um,
I don't know if I talked to, I don't
think I talked about this one yet. Um,
it's basically some kid at an Astros game.
He jumps out of the stands,
runs across right field,
gives a great head fake to a
security guard, breaks his ankles.
He goes up and over the wall. He
just, and just fucking amazing.
He basically climbs up the stadium
and runs out the back of it.
And as far as I know,
he got away and uh,
I would love a lot of Europeans to watch
this. Who think every Americans are fat.
Fuck,
you should see this guy.
This guy does like a good four or five
pull ups and climbs up out of a stadium
from basically center field. It's
amazing. So definitely check that one out.
There's another good one out there that I
was watching called. Uh, it's basically,
uh, how to, how to talk to cops.
And this one's funny because uh,
you could live to people
who actually are doing it,
are actually complete dirt bags,
but they know their rights probably cause
they be getting arrested their entire
life.
And it's really fascinating.
I saw this video a long time ago about
how many rights you give up when the cops
pull you over simply because you don't,
you don't know the law and they just
ask you questions. Like in this video,
the guy goes, because the guy was
videotaping, the copy comes over. He goes,
when he videotaped me for, he goes, can I
see that camera please? Now most people,
90% of you would be like, yes officer,
here you go, because you're, you're,
you don't want to get arrested.
This guy was like, no.
And the cop goes, why can't
I? The camera goes, AH,
cause it's mine and you
need a search warrant.
And he just started rattling off this
shit. And the cops just like at fuck,
he knows the rule. I don't know if
he knows it needs a search warrant,
but you know, he needs probable
cause. I'm video taping, it's illegal.
It's not illegal to videotape. And he
just, he stonewalls the guy and he goes,
and I'm on my property,
you're actually on my property,
get off my property police. And every
time he says the shit, you're like,
oh my God, he comes to the beat
down. But it never fucking happens.
But who's kidding,
who?
The only reason why it goes down like
this is because there's witnesses.
There's too many people standing around
because of this guy tried this shit in
the middle of nowhere with a cop.
The,
the video camera would
be up his ass and uh,
he would also be facing some sort of
charges of assaulting the police officer
because the police sprained one of his
fingers when he shoved the camera up his
ass. Um, at least that's
been my experience. Um,
what are the youtube videos?
Let me make sure I read all of these.
Let me show you and show,
you know they used to,
before I move onto the next
topics here, uh, for Christ sake,
where the fuck fucker, the other
youtube videos. Oh, this is a good one.
I think we actually did this one a long
time ago. Uh, boyfriend, fuck you. Uh,
you have to do that shit.
We hit on a girlfriend.
She lets you get on a girlfriend.
He hit on some girl and she lets you do
it for 10 minutes and then brings up her
boyfriend, uh, this guy does the
reaction that you want to do, uh,
to call boyfriend. Fuck you. And
then we got some music ones here,
a crossroads festival. Uh, Steve Winward,
Eric Clapton and Steve Jordan, my
favorite drummer and Derek trucks. Um,
what else do we got here?
Mark?
Knopfler I haven't even looked at these.
I've been so goddamn busy.
We've got some, uh, music ones this week
and a, what the fuck was the other one?
Oh, I know what I wanted to talk
about. You guys. Do you guys,
do you have a guilty pleasure movie
that you watch that you would be
unbelievably embarrassed that other
people would know that anytime you see it
you definitely watch it. This is mine.
It's actually called the good bye girl,
which is arguably one of the
gayest fucking movies of all time.
All right.
But what I love about it,
the reason why I like it is cause it's
Richard Dreyfus, his first big role.
And I'm a big Richard Dreyfus Fan and
I just love it because you see a guy
seizing the opportunity that
he's got this role and he just,
he just goes all out. It's a total fucking
chick flick or whatever. But I dunno,
he's always funny to me and the amount
of shit that he has to do in the movie
that I would be embarrassed to do when
he pulls it off is why I always end up
watching the movie. But, and I never
watch it from beginning to end.
I always catch it at some point.
Plus I'm a sucker for any movie that's
shot in New York and I get to see what
New York used to look like.
So that's another reason why I
love watching that movie. And uh,
it's just a great movie and
a lot of different levels.
There's another level where
the only people of Color
in that movie play muggers.
Like you really see what the fuck's
spike Lee is complaining about.
When you fucking see,
it's like,
it's so like how white they
make New York is unbelievable.
This just wall the wall.
Fuck everybody's white.
And then at one point though,
gets her grocery stolen.
So wretched drivers runs after this car
load of people and out of the car jumps
like two Puerto Ricans and a black guy
and they get fucking Afros and knives.
All of a sudden it turns into death.
Wish this chick flick
for like half a second.
It's completely unnecessary in the plot
in the movie other than to just remind
why people to be racist.
Um,
but that's not what I wanted
to talk about in that movie.
What really interests me in that movie
is I mentioned a zillion times as I drive
a Toyota Prius and uh,
when I drive it properly and I'm not
slamming on the brakes and stop it on the
gas, I can get 41 miles per gallon. Okay.
Which is supposed to be good
because a lot of shit gets 23, 25.
Now I've maintained for a while.
Now that car's in the 70s,
used to get like 33 35 miles of fucking
gallon. And that's Goddamn almost,
you know, 35, 40 years ago in
this movie, this chick flick,
the goodbye girl, that
chick that, uh, Dreyfus is,
is falling for. She's actually, you
guys ever go to a car show, you know,
they show all the, uh, whatever this
year they, uh, coming up in October,
they'll start having the car show
and they have all the 2012, um,
models that are coming out and speaking
of models that have these broad standing
next to him,
at least they did back in the day,
unless they consider it too sexist,
they'd have good looking women standing
there talking about the car. So anyways,
her character does that in this
movie and it's like, it's like 76,
1977,
something like that.
And she's standing in front of this
Subaru talking about the car and says it
gets 39 miles per gallon.
All right.
See,
this is why I don't believe in Shit.
I don't believe in fucking anything.
This is why everybody thinks, oh,
you're paranoid. You're a fucking
conspiracy theory. That's it.
Fucking right there.
39 miles per gallon on this fucking all
wheel drive Subaru or are those things
back there weren't oh yeah, four wheel
drive. Subaru got 39 miles per gallon.
That was their claim.
Okay.
That's 19 fucking 76 or 77
you're telling me in 35 years,
the best we've been able to do is get
me an extra two miles per gallon on a
fucking hybrid.
It's complete bullshit.
I think there's plenty of fucking oil
and it's the whole thing's horseshit.
You know what time I was riding,
I was riding in a cab in New York City
and this Pakistanian Dude was driving it,
you know, surprise, surprise. And uh,
I was talking to them about,
I always like,
I love talking to people
who don't live here,
you know who or who initially
didn't live here and now live here.
Just getting their whole viewpoint on
shit. Whether I agree with it or not,
it's just interesting to me.
So I was talking to him,
this is the first time the gas prices
were going through the fucking roof.
And he says to me, he goes, do you
know a Toyota Camry in this country?
Gets like whatever the fuck it was at
the time, 2125 miles per gallon. He goes,
do you know in my country it gets
like 38 39 miles per gallon or like 40
something ridiculous. He goes, do you know
why that is? And I said, no. And he goes,
because we can't afford a car that gets
23 to 25 miles per gallon because I
guess where they live,
whatever the fucking gas prices are,
whatever their fucking economy is,
they can't afford a car that
gets that amount of miles.
So they just adjust the goddamn engine.
That's what I'm saying, people's,
that's all bullshit.
I don't know where I'm going with this
stuff and I don't know who to complain to.
What about all those
grease monkeys out there?
You sit there and you watch these
fucking shows on TV where they, they,
they do like a build. They'll have some
car, you know, like we're at Tate today.
Well, you're not going to believe where
we're going to do. We got a 1972 fucking
GMC Willie's garbage truck and we're going
to combine that with the 1975 Porsche
nine 11. It's all gonna look fucking
sweet. And they somehow do it.
The fucking car runs and it fucking got
like nine wheels and he goes flying down
the street. He's got a fish
tank in the back. Right.
Why don't they use that talent to fuck
with the engine and get it to get it to
make like,
you know,
like a hundred miles per gallon or any
of my podcasts listeners out there.
Do you know how to do that shit?
Is it that fucking hard?
Isn't it just a couple of twists
of the screwdriver on a carburetor?
Do they have carburetors
anymore? Ah, Christ.
I don't know what the fuck I'm talking
about. Let's, let's plow ahead.
Everybody he's getting into
conspiracy theory. Oh Gee, he, um,
all right, let's go with advice
here. Um, you know, like always,
somebody sent me one and I can't
remember, uh, with a fuck I put it,
but some lady came over here from England
and she lives just north of New York
City. And, uh, she loves living here.
She loves the excess of America is
what she said, but her husband is,
she said it's driving him nuts because
he's an environmentalist and he is taking
the environmentalist stance to the point
that he won't flush the toilet when he
just takes a piss.
So she goes walking into the loo as she
calls it and he's got his fucking piss
in there and she's like, well what do
I do about this is what you do, lady,
you got to tell,
just put a fucking brick or a stone in
the back of your toilet so you won't use
as much water and tell the dude
to flush the Goddamn toilet. Okay?
Okay.
Just tell him to flush the toilet.
I'm all for trying to conserve but
flush the fucking toilet. All right.
And furthermore,
I don't like your attitude though,
cause she did the classic where,
you know,
he's doing all this other stuff too for
the environment. Like it's gonna matter.
I hate people who've got
that defeat us attitude.
That's not going to fucking matter.
You know,
like when you vote for Ron Paul and they
tell you that you wasted your vote by
voting for somebody who's
actually being honest,
whether you agree with them or not.
Like that's a wasted vote.
I'll really waste it's a wasted vote to
vote for that guy to try encourage more
people like that who don't give
a fuck to run for office. No,
he's not gonna so that,
that's why you vote.
You vote cause you want to
vote for a winner. Ah, Jesus.
That's depressing.
The speaking of fucking depressing the
fucking Stanley Cup finals this year.
I can anybody figure it out?
I think this has been one of
the most torturous finals, um,
for fans on both sides.
God knows those connect cons wouldn't
admit to it because now there were up
three games to two,
but you can't tell me during game
three and four you weren't like,
what the fuck happened to my team?
Why are they playing like a bunch of
pussies and allowing themselves to be
pushed all over the ice? That's
what's happened. Every home game.
The visiting team just gets smashed in
the mouth and does nothing about it.
It's fucking driving me nuts. All
right, I'm getting sick of you.
Fucking cannot fans talk and shit
like your team is fucking superior.
You've won three one goal games.
The twins. What have they done? Shit.
They haven't done shit. What
is Ryan Kessler done? Shit.
He's done nothing.
What about that fucking that God damn
Lou Longo with his sad basset hound eyes
behind his goalie mask.
You bunch of punks.
I actually liked your fucking team until
we played you guys in the amount of
shit.
You guys have been talking.
I actually used to like your fucking team.
I would have rooted for the,
if the Bruins weren't in,
I would have wrote it for the
Canucks cause they never won one.
But their fans are such con oh at their
stupid hankies that they have during the
Goddamn game. You only people who should
do that. Our Pittsburgh Steeler fans,
they came up with it. It was the
terrible towel. Anyone else who does it?
It's fucking gay and I can't wait for
the Bruins win game six and game seven.
So you fucking pussies are crying in
your Goddamn hankies Jesus Christ.
This is the thing though.
I actually think they're a great team
and they've got a tremendous amount of
talent on there,
but those mother fuckers are the cheapest
sons of bitches I've ever seen in my
life. I don't mind the hits. I
don't mind that shit. You know,
it happens. All right. But the fucking,
the diving and the flopping.
Hey, I asked this the other day,
uh, I was on Tsn, which
is the ESPN up in Canada.
I called in and I asked this,
can some hockey fan please explain to me.
All right. And one of the Games, the
last game actually gained five all right.
There at the lining up for a face off
in a Burroughs is right next to Luke
Cheech.
So what he does is he puts his leg in
front of Lucita stick and then just does a
prat fall and acts like he trips.
Okay.
Now, I would think that either he get
two minutes for diving or they would call
Cheech for tripping because they
didn't realize that, you know,
that they got faked out.
But for some reason Lou Cheech got two
minutes for tripping and Burroughs get
two minutes for embellishment or something
stupid like that. I don't get that.
It's like he either fucking trip the guy
redundant. What does that penalty mean?
Like, okay, he tripped you but
he didn't trip you that bad.
I don't know.
I've had it in the fucking goddamn twins.
Jesus Christ did [inaudible]
flopping all over the fucking ice.
That's how you want to win a cup,
Vancouver.
That's how you want to do it
by pretending you got hurt.
Yeah.
Fucking shameless.
Just a shameless fucking hockey team.
I got no,
I'd have absolutely no fucking respect
for like I've lost all fucking respect
for that Goddamn team
and I can't believe it.
There's no fucking reason for
them to be doing that shit.
They got enough weapons.
They sort of have a good goaltender
and there were great physical team.
Why do you gotta play like fags?
You know?
Why is that what you guys
do out there in Vancouver?
Is that what you do when you're not
going out on a fucking whale watch and
listen to,
to your euro trash music with your awful
tight clothes that you wear up there at
been to Vancouver for about 20 minutes.
Beautiful scenery.
If you're not looking at the people,
um,
uh, I can't wait to play
Tampa or Vancouver just for
the fan that actually takes
this shit seriously. Um,
anyways, plowing ahead,
plowing ahead.
Speaking of a,
speaking of what the fuck was I talking
about? Oh, gay and all that type of stuff.
A certain comedian got into a bunch of
trouble for a bunch of stuff he said
during a, during a, uh,
during a standup performance and uh,
people got offended and a, this really
bugged me. I was watching a news program.
I was watching a program that involved
the news and this dude came on and the
comedian apologized and they asked
him what he thought he could go in.
The guy was just like, well, you
know, I think the apology was good,
but I don't think it's enough.
I think he should donate some money
to the fucking blah, blah, blah, blah,
blah. And it just, it just killed
the whole fucking thing for me.
It killed the outrage. I should really
just look at the guy at that. It's like,
really at the end of it,
all you want to do is just get some
fucking money out of the guy. You know? I,
I don't understand that.
I really don't.
You know, somebody does something and then
they apologize. That should be enough.
You got,
that's not enough.
You've got to take the money out
of his fucking wallet, you know?
So if that's the case, then you really
don't give a shit about the apology.
You just want it.
So you just using it as an,
as an excuse to get some fucking money.
Right?
Yeah. Does that make any
fucking sense? I Dunno.
I'm basically judging the entire topic
because of that one Douche I saw on TV.
All right, let's plow ahead here before
I have to fucking apologize to somebody.
Um, uh, people of Vancouver.
Do you think that is his,
his apology that he made fun of
your white belts and white shoes,
your herb Tarlek euro trash way of
fucking dressing at your dance clubs?
The fact that he apologized,
was that enough? Um, I don't
think it's quite enough.
I think he should make a
donation to the Vancouver,
a mountainous region. Ag. Go Fuck
Yourself. All right, dear bill,
I am from Kansas City and there is
currently radio commercials in which a law
officer, a law, a law office,
offers their services exclusively for
women going through a divorce. Of course,
they do this a ton of
money involved there. Uh,
they talk about how they were view all
of the husband's finances and ensure the
woman will receive the maximum
amount the law will allow.
And then he writes in capital letters.
What the fuck are there any law offices
that offer services exclusively for men?
I doubted if there were,
I would imagine there would be a huge
protest from feminists all across the U S
I know you've addressed
this hundreds of times over,
but why is it okay k to completely fuck
a man over this commercial insinuates
the man is already in the wrong.
This is absolute bullshit dude.
Yet preach on this guys is
speaking the Gospel here. Anyways,
wanted to share this with you as,
this is just another example
of man bashing commercials.
That just pissed me off.
Um, all right, let's, let's, let's review
this. Ah, yeah. Okay. First of all,
he can't get mad at the lawyers because a,
they're just going with the monies and um,
and as you,
as you,
as you say that,
if it was the opposite way that there
would be feminist groups protesting.
All right.
That there in lies the fucking problem
until men actually get together and start
protesting that type of shit,
which I would absolutely love to
be a part of on any fucking level.
I would love to see that happen.
But what guys,
we don't do that shit once we get you
get punched in the face. Yeah. Fuck you.
You get up and you walk away. Like
you can't do that. Like, yeah,
this should be guys protesting it. I
think that would be fucking hilarious. Um,
that's absolutely terrifying.
That's one of 9 million reasons
why I never got fucking married.
That is just unfucking believable.
Yeah.
You know, I'll tell you what kills me
is most women who would watch that,
they always say the same thing. When
you liked, you'll say to them like,
can you believe that shit when they
always say that saint? Yup. That's right.
That's right. Yeah. That's what you get.
That's what you get a big,
stupid face. What the fuck?
Have you ever done that?
That's my whole,
my whole thing with dad is just a,
I don't know,
you get married, you just better
pray to God. It fucking works out.
There's a guy that's all you have
and the amount of power, it's not,
it's not a balanced relationship because
of the way that the divorce laws are.
It's the second, you know,
it's like when your single,
you have an unbelievable
amount of power as a guy,
even if you're in a relationship,
because
that she, she can't get to you
legally. That's it. It's fucking over.
You have your shit and that's it.
And you're a guy and you can earn
a fucking living and that's it.
You don't have to worry about shit.
And then the second you get married,
you lose all power.
Cause at any point should she can just
divorce you and fucking take you for
everything. You're worth, everything
you work for. It's, it's just,
it's fucking over.
Look at tiger woods.
Tiger Woods gave his wife a
quarter of a billion dollars.
She was a nanny. Fucking
nanny were what? Nine figures
for what she, he had a prenup was
she was only going to get $5 million,
only $5 million.
Who here wouldn't kill for $5 million?
I quit my podcast for a fucking 200 grand.
You know,
you find out your husband,
some dog going around
cheating or whatever. That's,
that happens to women.
And the guy's a broke ass son of a
bitch and they're left with nothing.
So it's not like women always make out,
but here's the situation.
We find that your husband's a
dog. The marriage is over. Oh,
but I get $5 million,
but that's not enough for the cont
cause she knows he has a billion and she
wants to get as much as that as she can.
I swear to fucking God,
I can't do these topics because it
makes you see red because they're not
entitled to it. It's bullshit. All right?
If you marry the greatest golfer of a
fucking generation who's won 14 titles,
okay. And you haven't even won a game,
a tiddly winks on a professional level,
you're not entitled to that money. You're
not. You are illegally, but you're not.
You didn't fucking earn it. You
can't. Ah, right. There you go, Bill.
Get to the core of the hatred.
All right, number two. Um,
Bill,
really the fucking new Norwegians get
you for multiple gigs and London gets one
night. Uh, you know how you know
they hate, wait a minute too.
What are you talking about?
The Norwegians. Okay.
You're talking about the
whole Scandinavian area.
I'm in a different country every night.
I'm an,
I'm an England one night than Finland
than Norway, Norway than and then Sweden.
All right. That's totally equal.
What are you bitching about? Uh,
not to mention I already played London
and I, the place was three quarters full.
I don't think I need to do a week
of dates there in front of nine,
nine people per show. Um, alright bill.
Really the fucking Norwegians get you.
Get you for multiple gigs in London.
Gets one night.
Yeah.
And I can't even,
I don't know what he says here.
You know they hate America
Q over in Sweden too, right?
What does that m e R I C U h l have to
look that up. I don't know what that is.
Are you trying to fill some sort of
urge to pal around with people who are
whiter than yourself? Well then
look no further than London, sir.
They are so white. They eat their
pizza with forks and knives. Um,
you what you think because
you've been here before.
You can just do London
in a night and peace out.
I use some sort of Anglo expert now.
I'm just fucking around.
Glad you give in London at least one
night. Look forward to seeing you figures.
I discover your con,
uh,
comedy after I move out to Los Angeles
while I'm out here in Los Angeles. Sir,
if you'd like to see me,
I'm doing a,
a benefit for a Greg Geraldo's wife
and a family at the Wiltern theater.
Um, what the hell's the fucking
date? Ah, Jesus. They're built.
How do you not know where
the fuck you gonna be? Oh,
you know what? I know when
the fuck it is. It's uh,
June 29th at the Wiltern theater. All
right. Not only can you see me, sorry.
You can see a bunch of other comics
doing their fucking thing. All right,
Jeff Ross is going to be out there.
Slappy white.
We're going to have a bunch of big names.
I'm all right. What is, oh, I can see.
Email wasn't done here.
By the way,
that email you read from that guy who
claimed to be French at a bunch of
condescending misinformation in it.
Right?
That guy back and tell him he's a prick
just like all the rest of the French, uh,
per regions or otherwise. Francis full
of garlic, eating pseudo mustache,
having dickheads. Granted there women
are clean shaven though. Uh, too bad.
The majority of them look
like dudes regardless.
Okay.
Now why do you think he's saying all that
shit people? Do you know why that is?
It's because his country,
his next to France,
nobody likes the country.
They're next to write.
Although I do like Canada except for a
Canadian Martirio Canadian fence and uh,
even Vancouver connect fans
with your hankies. Okay. In
your prayer. False eight.
When they,
all those pratfalls that they do,
do they play like a Benny Hill music
at the beginning of the, of uh,
whenever Vancouver has a home game,
when they show the highlights and they
got Wayne Wayne man pick a Dane, Dane,
an amp,
amp and name and name an nap.
And then you show everybody
flopping around on the fucking ice
laughing cause they're cheating.
Okay,
you got a hell of a team and you
might the cup. But Jesus Christ.
How about next year?
You make some sort of vow that you're
going to have some sort of fucking code of
honors, something. Jesus.
His whole fucking series.
Which one of the sendings was it?
Was it that fucking flopped onto his
back and the ref didn't even call it?
And when he got up, someone on the Bruins
were going, was going, are you okay?
Y'All right. Everything okay? Oh
Jesus. What a bunch of pussies.
Um, alright. Overrated.
Underrated for this.
Wreak a underrated
jerking off on the clock.
Everyone should do this
once in their lifetime.
You might as well be getting blow
by what? By your boss's wife. Oh,
that's fucking hilarious.
Yeah, but where do you do it?
And then the odds are getting caught.
That's a, that's part of the excitement.
Fucking Weirdo jerking off at
work were where exactly. Oh,
jerking off on the clock. Oh, I
see. So what, uh, you know what?
I'm going home for lunch. Then you go
back and you jerk off. Oh, but on lunch,
you know on the clock,
sir, could you please are,
could you please elaborate and let me
know where exactly it is that you jerk off
at work. Any of my listeners and you
guys, you have a jerk off at work has,
is this what the podcast is this
what it really has come down to.
Anybody else ever rub one out at fucking
work and when you do, what do you go?
Obviously the bathroom.
Wow.
I mean you really risking
your fucking career there.
If you get caught rubbing one out.
I'm trying to think of a job that you
could have where you could get caught
rubbing one out at work and people would
laugh it off. Obviously a comedian,
you know,
if you will rub it,
went out in the green room as
long as you sold the rum out.
You know, that's the amazing
thing about show business.
I was thinking about this shit
the other day, that if you,
if say you killed somebody,
you committed murder,
but it was judged a crime of passion.
You know,
you lost your shit,
you fucking killed somebody.
So you go in a jail for at least 15 years.
Okay, so 15 years, 17 years you get out,
where are you going to get a Goddamn job?
Okay.
Other than just continuing
to be a criminal, you know,
selling drugs or some shit. You know,
there's only two places that you,
I think that you can get a job.
You can become like a car salesman
cause they don't give a fuck, you know,
or you can get into show business.
It's fucking amazing. You can cut, you
can do a little walk right out of prison.
If anybody is in prison
listening to this shit. You know,
if you have these privileges,
you can get out of prison,
you know,
after doing 17 years.
And then they hand you your fucking Xe
Kava cheese that you wore when you walked
into prison back and fucking 1993
with your goatee. And I can't believe Kurt
Cobain just killed himself. Tee Shirt,
right?
Within a week,
you could sign up for [inaudible],
right? First fucking day,
you go out to sign up for an open mic.
You could write five minutes
material and you could be on stage
telling jokes within a fucking week.
And not only could you be,
not only would you be accepted when other
comedians found out that you murdered
somebody, their reaction
wouldn't be like, holy fuck,
you're a piece of shit. They
would just be like, dude, dude,
you should talk about that on stage.
That, that could be your hook, man.
You go up in your orange jumpsuit,
right?
You let people know that you killed
somebody. And then first of all,
no one's going to fucking hackle.
Yeah.
And then he can intimidate the crowd
that if they don't laugh at your jokes,
you're going to go be a
fuck. Do it again. You know,
I was actually talking to somebody about
that the other day about, you know,
that's, that's a conversation
that guys have a lot about.
Do you think you could survive
if you went to prison? And, uh,
I was talking to Keith
Robinson, uh, about this shit.
And,
uh,
I was telling him that I would go into
prison and I would immediately joined the
area nation immediately.
I would,
I would have a bic pen out if I
smuggled it in. I wouldn't have,
would be drawing the
swastika between my eyes,
not because I believe in that shit.
I just don't want to get raped.
So
I would be drawing that in on
the bus ride into the prison.
And I told Keith, you know, no offense
that if I did see him in prison,
I would have to call them the n
word. I just would just, you know,
not out of some racist shit.
I just, I would not want,
I just don't want to get raped and
I have to bond with the fucking, uh,
the psycho a,
the psycho fucking, uh, what do you
call them? What do you call those guys?
The white supremacists.
And I'd have to sit there
listening to their awful music.
I remember that from American history.
X rent with that fatty was in the
van singing the white man marches.
Oh, would I be counting down
the fucking days? Jesus Christ.
But you'd have to do it.
You'd have to do it.
You'd have to become a full on fucking
area in maniac. But what are your,
what are your options? You know?
I mean, I'm all for, you know,
not being racist,
100% all about it.
I think it's ignorant and
all that type of shit,
but I draw the line at getting fucked
in the ass. All right, fuck that.
Fuck that noise,
son.
I'll say some shit that will make
fucking a Charles Manson blush.
Ah,
well maybe that's the guy I'd knock out,
can walking up to him with his vampire
fingernails and just fucking slap the
beard right off his face.
Maybe that would prevent it.
I don't know if anybody's ever
been to prison. What exactly?
Someone like me right before I commit to
going in there and just shaving my head
and acting like a,
I'm part of the area in nation because
that's the only way I see, you know,
getting out of it.
If anybody who's been listening
to this shit has been to prison,
how does a Ron Howard,
Ralph mouth looking jackass like myself
who hasn't had a fist fight since junior
high outside of his family?
Um,
how do, how do you
survive? How do you do it?
And that's the only option I can think. I
got to go in there and I, I got to hang,
oh Jesus. Then I'd have to get
a bunch of awful tattoos. Ah,
AH, Jesus Christ. I'd
probably just kill myself.
That's what I was joking about that.
But then I wouldn't have the nerve to do
it and then I'd get raped and then I'd
be thinking as I was getting raped going,
fuck,
I should've done it earlier
because now I got to kill myself.
It's fucking unreal. So anyways, whenever
you see these fucking people, when they,
they,
I remember long time ago there was some,
like some kid in New York City,
it was this classic case where he,
he killed his girlfriend and he said that
they were having rough sex and it got
out of control. Right. Which is complete
horseshit. He killed her. Right.
But that's what he said.
So anyways,
he ended up doing all of his time
because he kept getting busted for shit.
So when he was getting a in prison,
so like they were talking about, uh,
they were talking about him getting out.
I remember he was getting
out and they're like,
so and so's getting out of
prison, the, you know, the
famous case, blah, blah, blah,
blah,
blah.
And evidently he was quite a busy man
when he was in prison and they start
giving him shit going.
Like he got busted on numerous
occasions for selling drugs.
He got into a couple of altercations
with the guards and other inmates and
they're talking about him like, he should
have been there coloring. It's like, no,
he was doing what he had to do so he
didn't become somebody's girlfriend.
I hate when people do that when they
talk about people not behaving nicely in
prison as if that's a place where that
is an option. I saw a guy one time,
he was saying that I'm one
of those prisons shows.
He was talking about how whenever
this they're coming into Yoursel, uh,
they give you the option
where you, you, you put your,
you put your back to the door and then
they reach it and they handcuff you and
he's saying you can't do that.
He goes,
you're options are basically you back
up like a bitch to the door and then all
the other inmates look at you like
you're a bitch or you fight him.
So what, what are you
supposed to do? You got you.
So you basically have to take a beat
down from these fucking officers who
address like robocop so that they
don't rape you cause your bag just,
it's fucking horrific.
It's absolutely horrific.
And the fact that I've blown off jury
duty for the last fucking 16 months,
speaking of being racist,
that's one that people always
say like to get out of jury duty.
Like they always just go in there.
You just go in there and you
just say a bunch of racist shit.
I love when people like, they think that
that's how you do it. It's like, you know,
yeah, war or you could just ignore
it when it comes in the mail.
You just don't respond to it.
You could always do that as opposed to
going down to the courthouse and just
saying racist shit. You know,
you're, you're overthinking it.
All right. Where the hell am I? Um,
overrated. Uh, American football,
even the name is inaccurate. Uh,
Mexicans don't play it. Brazilians don't.
Argentine teens don't.
Hmm.
Come Canadians don't play it much. No,
they do play it. They have a whole league.
You can't, you just too dumbed the name
of another country. How about Venezuela?
Dumb. Fuck. Um, and here's the crucial
bit, nor does the rest of the world.
This is a game where the super bowl
is played only by American teams,
yet they call themselves world champs.
Dude,
this is one of the oldest
arguments I've ever heard.
Even the World Cup events of hockey,
rugby and rock,
paper, scissors. Yes. That's a real event.
Invite competitors for
more than two nations. Uh,
it's one of these few sports
who's all American heroes?
From Joe Montana to Walter Payton.
We're a bunch of guys who only played
against their compatriots. Well,
you know what?
If you pussies want to put together a
team and try and join the NFL, I mean,
they play a game in London every year
trying to get you guys interested in it.
You're not interested in the fucking game,
and I guarantee whatever
fucking team you put together,
we'll kick the shit out of you.
Just like we have in basketball
are fucking sport. You can't
the fuck do you get off? Talking about
football is a, you know what football is?
Football is the correction to soccer.
See,
Americans were smart enough to realize
how goddamn boring you're you're fucking
sport is. And you want to talk about
a bunch of people diving. I actually,
I'm going to take it back.
I'm going to actually apologize to the
Vancouver Canucks for suggesting that
they were diving on an insane level.
Okay?
Professional soccer players take
it to an entirely different level.
All right? Every time somebody
comes up and barely touches you,
you act like he just got thrown out of a
fucking car and you sit there with your
scarves singing songs cause you're so
goddamn board waiting for a fucking goal
to be scored.
What would happen if you actually pick
the Goddamn ball up and ran with it?
It'd be exciting.
Like rugby.
Rugby is exciting as opposed
to soccer or football,
whatever the fuck you call it, and I
know what you're saying like, yeah,
but in rugby they're not pussies.
They don't wear helmets. Yeah.
They don't hit each other as hard either.
I've watched it. I've watched both.
I think they're both awesome sports
to watch. Both of them make me cringe,
but the American game is way faster and
way more fucking violent. It just is.
All right.
Our football players are actually dying
in their 50s and donating their brains
to science and they're
finding that they have,
this guys have died in their forties
that the whatever the fuck they have on
their brain,
they don't see in the average.
They see it basically with people who
die of all simers in their eighties okay.
People get paralyzed playing our game.
All right. If you don't like our game,
you know what it is the rest of the world,
you know I, this is what I think it is.
I just want to thank you big
fucking problem with America is,
is that you just like a lot of our shit.
You like our music.
You like our clothes,
you like a lot of our culture and it
kills you that we don't pay attention to
your shit. You want our fucking
approval on some goddamn level.
Don't roll your fucking eyes at me.
You do the fuck.
Are you doing listening to this podcast?
This is an American podcast, sir.
Yeah.
What is your fucking,
other than our foreign policy,
which I totally fucking
understand. What is it? You know,
because all the shit I
just said about soccer,
I actually really enjoy
the premiere league.
I really enjoy that and I just think it's
cool that you had to go there and you
sing songs and you drink fucking
beer with your red fet faces.
I think that's a good thing.
You know,
I actually,
I respect the fucking game here.
You come over here
talking about fucking a,
how the fuck is American football?
Overrated.
You never even said why it was overrated.
It is American footballs.
Yup. Yeah, but United States
is in the Americas. You dumb.
Fuck. What are we supposed to call
it? Asian football. You know what?
You're a God damn. Dummy
aren't. Yeah, I on the Dole.
Is that what you guys
call welfare over there?
Uh,
what is it? Mexicans don't
play. Brazilians don't play
it. Our teachers don't. Yeah,
they don't. They don't. What? Because
they don't play it. We shouldn't play it.
And it shouldn't be called American
football. Even though we're in America.
Explain yourself, sir. Uh, I'm
tired of that whole fucking thing.
Oh. Then he goes, well, let
me digress. It's a great game.
If you love commercial breaks.
MMM.
Well what your fucking game.
Your
game needs a commercial break.
You know what?
Do you know what fucking soccer needs?
Needs a Goddamn,
it needs like a halftime show
that's being played the entire time.
If you get bored
one nil,
we're into the penalty time
and everybody's sitting
there whistling in the crowd.
You did something bad
here. You got to, yeah.
Yellow card. Ooh, he
took out the red card.
Oh Jesus. A bunch of guys running around
in shorts. Um, anyways, advice. Hey,
bill loved the podcast. Most guys
would probably write in, uh, and how,
and ask how to get their
girlfriend to do anal. Well,
I've got a question that's
a little more practical. Um,
or girl that I'm seeing
absolutely loves anal. Oh, Jesus.
Yeah. That, you know something.
That's disgusting. All right.
I'm just going to say that right off
the bat that it's just fucking gross.
That's something that for some reason
became a big thing in porn for a while.
And uh, you know, all
I'm going to say is this,
I try to keep it clean. Here. You
participate in that act long enough,
you're going to realize why at some
point someday one time you're going to
realize why you should never stick pp in
there. All right. Without getting gross.
Okay.
She insist on it every time we have sex.
Yeah.
The other day after we got back from a
road trip that involved way too much gas
station food up. Here we go. Here we go.
She was having an abnormal amount of gas.
All right,
I'm going to pause here and give you
guys a chance to just kind of walk away
from your little recording devices so
you don't have to listen to the rest of
this. Here we go. Well, she
eventually got up off the couch,
ran to the bathroom and yelled.
I just shit my pants.
She was really cool about
it. Oh Jesus. I mean, I mean,
how cool can you be about it
other than just being honest,
but she's concerned about the effects of
constantly having things shoved up her
ass. Yeah. Well she should be.
She just turned 30 and has only started
doing anal on a consistent spaces for
the last few years.
Uh,
I was wondering if you could,
oh, well why are you
bringing my girl into this?
Get her to invite some of her
friends over it and then rambly.
Randomly asked her friends,
which ones do anal on a consistent basis
and whether or not they have problems
shitting themselves.
Thanks for the help.
Uh, yeah, she didn't, I don't know.
She didn't shit herself because
of the sex you're having.
She Shit herself cause you ate
it a gas station, I think. Uh,
but I can't tell you that. I, I,
you know, yeah, yeah, yeah. I Dunno.
Okay.
You know, I dunno by, yes. I
don't know what to tell you.
I don't know where to go.
I'm not a doctor.
I'm not into doing that to a female and a,
you know,
let's see. Uh, let's see, uh, very soft
membrane in there. You're dealing with,
you're dealing with the budget issues
there, buddy barge a fucking issue.
There's no reason to do it. Um, what
I would tell her is like, yeah, uh,
that's why you shit yourself so you can
get out of having to do that to her.
Uh, you don't want to do that to
the person you love though. Yeah.
That's the mother. Your
kids someday, uh, cut.
Uh,
or you know what we're done with that.
I think it's about time in this fucking
podcast. Let's go with one more of these.
Hey, hello bill. I'm 18 years old.
I built with my girlfriend for three
years and honestly I'm tired of fucking
honor. Uh, the relationship is
fine. Me and her get along great,
but I feel like the excitement
and the lust is gone.
This is a becoming a problem is making
it really difficult not to cheat.
I'm guessing at some point
you've had the same problem.
I just want to know is this going to
happen with every longterm relationship?
I feel like I'm living the
life of a middle aged, married
man and are uh, already,
but I don't want it to end it
as me and her get along fine.
Also, I just also just to add,
we've recently tried basically every
sexually and we've everything sexually
and we've easily had sex more than 500
times, so there's no way to really
spice things up anymore. Thanks.
Uh,
yes, I really think you would
blow up over here in England.
Fewer got your specials on TV over here.
You seem to tap into the British humor.
The podcast is great, man.
Yeah, Dude. You know what,
if anybody knows anybody
over there and TV,
I would love to get my
specials on over there.
I think I have to do local TV over there.
I should probably try and do that.
Do a local TV show over there.
That's a great fucking idea. Um,
what the hell was your question? Um, sir,
there is no way to spice it up
after you've banged a 500 times.
You just better hope that you love
her in the end. Sexual happened, uh,
less frequent and uh,
it's just how it is.
It's just how it is. But then, you know,
if you really loved this girl
and your dumper, you're gonna,
you're gonna be sad and be thinking
about her as you're banging this new girl
who you're going to be excited about
fucking probably about 40 times and then
you're going to be right
back to it. So, uh,
that's why they say it's
not the be all end all. Um,
I don't know what to tell
you. You know, I don't know.
Why don't you go down the costume
store store and dress up like a fucking
Milkman? Why don't you start with
that? I don't know what to tell you.
I don't know what to tell you too.
Yeah,
it's fucking brutal and happens
and happens to everybody. Uh,
sorry to end on a fucking Downer
there. Ah. Anyways, let's, let's go up.
Let's go up here.
I'm going to be at the Chicago theater
with one of the anti social network tour
dates with Jim Breuer. David, tell
them the wonderfully talented Norton.
Um, June 15th, Wednesday, June 15th.
I'm going to be out there
at the Chicago theater.
There's still some tickets left. Very few.
Please. Get off your ass. Come on down.
Come on and see the show.
You getting four for the price of one.
And it's as far as I'm concerned for
the best God damn comics you're going to
see out today. All right, look at me
talking a little bit of Shit. And, uh,
later on this month,
I'm going to be at the Wiltern theater
for the Greg Geraldo benefit here in Los
Angeles. Please, please, please,
uh, buy some tickets. Uh,
all the proceeds go to his,
uh,
his widow and his is wonderful kids and
it would mean a lot for me if you guys
can make some time to
come down to the show. Um,
I don't have the line up in front of me.
Maybe I'll read that next week,
but it's just basically a who's who and
really just lets you know how well Greg
was loved and respected
by all other comics. Um,
so please come down to the Wiltern
theatre in Los Angeles on June 29th.
That's it.
That's the podcast for this week.
I hope you guys all have a great weekend.
I hope next week when I yard,
this is what I'm hoping
the Dallas Mavericks,
when the Nba Championship
and the Bruins are, uh,
the Bruins are fucking a, actually have
won the cup. That would be amazing.
And I still think that they can do it.
All right. That's it. That's the podcast.
Go Fuck Yourself.
Talk to you next week.
Another homie got smell,
but it's no surprise everybody is tripping
because the boy was too young or die
assessed site. The Z Maumee.
Take his last breath.
Everybody's tripping cause
they can except Mommy's dead.
Another chilling was reported
on the evening news. Somebody,
his brother got behind a pair of
shoes in the midst of all this shit.
I think about myself wondered
when somebodies gonna try
to take me off the shelf.
[inaudible] be another valley casualties.
So when I'm building, I pack my pistol,
grip aside, money cause on the city's
three Sedalia brother just can't win.
When the pope you think are your friends
really and your friends and wish we
can't sleep.
When everybody around me
keeps falling six feet
pain as deeper side of everybody grows
as they approach to see the body before
the cats get close,
the person standing next to me and
snapped the flit wants us in the Catholic,
closed on, knew that that was sick. The
whole entire family spoke on this defense.
The Gwalia son yourselves
and make us reminisce.
You'll run all the song
and I broke down myself.
We're in a look and seeing the family
that my partner left at the end of why
your book into its final song,
thank contort myself.
The worst is yet to come.
Every one was headed for the final flight
as we creeped along the gravel on the
burial site.
That got wrecked.
The said as well as in
that was not a Sam as day.
Lower my little problem Tosa side,
the ground,
everybody dropped the
flowers on the coffin.
Tom and then the work Gomo
would that concrete block? Yes.
Damn.
A lot of mothers can rot.
I watched tears fall down from the eyes.
Everybody wants to go to heaven,
but nobody wants to take the chains.
They chose the music so day.
By the day.
I couldn't tell him nothing was a player
at the avid got caught up in the game.
Now my boy is sending the casket.
Everybody's looking for somebody else to
blame or shame that let his mother know
that he was in a gang. We used to
kick it out in the air that night,
coming up,
trying to have the finer things in life,
but now my boys don't.
I wish she was at home.
I wish she wouldn't have
never fell victim to the call,
so we're not drank a bullet for you.
I'll pull some on the block sun.
You might be gone,
but you damn showing forgotten long.
Remember whenever a wet
ever dead or alive real pot.
Let's come together.
You know though.