Hey, what's going on? It's Bill Burr.
It's time for the Monday
morning podcast for Monday,
January 29th, 2018
what's going on out? Why?
Yeah. Um, all right.
Well this was a board,
this would have been a boring
Sunday because there was, you know,
there's no football, right? They got the,
uh, you got the week off in between the,
between the Superbowl and the championship
games. They had the pro bowl today,
which was kind of cool. Look like football
in the future where they would get,
you know, they'd start to tackle somebody
and they're like, all right. All right.
Right, right, right. You know,
I don't know if that's the
concussion thing or the me too.
I don't know what it is.
He does not want you touching him.
Do not throw into the ground.
I have a special guest to
liven up my Sunday day. Uh,
uh, Jesus who? One and only 200
rigs for Christ's sake. Todd,
you all one of my favorite fucking
people in this business and you will,
one of my favorite comedians.
So Isabelle, pleasure through,
I feel that the feeling's mutual manager.
You don't have to compliment me
on this idols, man. Dude, you are.
You are the silliest fucking dude.
You make me feel mature.
That's what I like about you,
Todd. Rex, okay. Yes. Todd Rex,
who checks off a lot of boxes in this
day of caring. That's right. You do.
I don't even know that, man. I don't
even know what it means either.
I'm just trying to be progressive.
You would think that somebody would
come his fucking way and finally tap the
magic wand in his head and make
something happen and say, Todd,
you've been destroying at least three
times as hard as 10 times of the fucking,
or whatever the math is.
All the fucking comics out there.
I love working with you,
but I hate following you.
You fucking murder. Finally,
this fucking asshole.
He got himself a special that he's taping
and he needs some people to come down
and then you can, you know,
go on and I can open for,
for making you sweat a little lit.
No, no, not a chance. All right.
He's going to be at the satellite
theater in silver lake. Uh,
the satellite la.com for tickets.
That's right. Uh, February 11th, uh,
you're going to be the one in the show.
It's a Sunday, but usually come out
David support the all right. Sunday,
which is a week after,
uh, the Superbowl, right?
So everybody knows the seven 30
and nine 32 shows, two shows,
two shows to show. So you're going
to go out there. You fucking,
you knocked the first one out. Ego. All
right, I got it. And then the next one,
you just go off Cruze. Is that what
you do? And you do yours, the button.
The first one is tightened up and then
I spend the whole night trying to forget
that I'm taping one real and stop
trying to think like, oh my God,
I missed that tag.
Fuck.
That needed to be documented
in the comedy universe.
I just try to look at it
like, all right, this is just,
I'm just documenting where my hour was
on this night and this is how it came up.
And I want you to do that because
every night when you go up there,
I don't know about you, but I mean
I'm constantly fucking up jokes, uh,
constantly leaving shit out and
then adds to something else.
And I never think of it.
Never think about it.
Like I never thought to get you a glass
of water before you sat here for a
fucking hour. What an idiot. I'm going
to have to hit pause here in a minute,
but no good. Um, that's just how, uh,
I had to do it that way just because
I wanted to think about your,
I wanted to ask you about your thought
process cause I was curious. Um,
like I know the night before I'm
going to be a wreck, you know,
just was thinking about it and make
it all the funny guys. Worry hacks,
don't worry. Packs are already fucking
working on their next happy hour. Yeah.
They'd not even fucking nervous to just,
and they'll go off stage with this
shitty material, be like, dude,
I fucking crushed, crushed in every
funny guys. Like, who's it? Good.
I'm terrible. I do that every, every time.
I just really in a about way compliment
to myself. I know him. Um, I, you know,
I got to waste to go people, I don't know
if she's to you, what did they be obese?
Um, yeah, so I I uh, someone told
me, I think Louis Ck told me,
and I think he heard this from fucking
bill Cosby. How funny is that? Um,
that your dad, uh, you work
this hard to get there? Um,
uh, don't forget to have fun, right? So
make sure, yeah. Cause if you haven't fun,
that's going to be, you're going to
feel better about it afterwards, right?
If you're someone who
nitpicks set himself,
there's no way you're going to be happy
at the end of it. So just be forgiving.
Just be the fucking silly
fucking hilarious guy. You
all, you'll be fine. Yeah.
I'm not really too worried about it,
but I just want to make sure that I
already can tell you, worry about it.
You seem you seem tighter than usual.
She's still, I'm doing your podcast.
It's kind of a big deal for me too.
I feel like I didn't the whole thing.
Now that you've peeked behind the curtain.
It's just me with a fucking
$99 mixer from gutsiness Ana.
We're sitting here on the
couch like Ernie and Bert,
the all I did to prepare for you as I
turned on the AC and I scored some for
breeze. That's it. I know everybody
has these fancy fucking studios.
I just did a, I did your mom's house, uh,
with a Thompson Sigora
and Chrisia presents key.
I just did theirs and they
have this whole fucking studio.
Rogan has like literally like a
stern level studio. She's and um,
I should step it up at some point. Yeah.
But your house is dope. I don't know.
No one can see it, but your
house is dope. Oh, thank you.
It wasn't when I bought it,
but now that I've dumped all this money
into it and I could never get my money
back. Yeah, this is pretty good. I I,
this house was like almost a
hundred years old when I got it.
Almost 90 years old. I should say. People
live in here before though, right? Uh,
yeah.
I don't want to talk about that though
because then people will fucking figure
out where I live.
I already have to fucking edit out one
of the comments you made earlier that
will fuck two people that fucking
lunatics and that's what they do.
I'll tell you later just it was just
enough of something to make some psycho
just turn around and face speaker
and start writing down information.
But I'm a paranoid
dude. Um, yeah. Anyways.
Um, what was I talking about? What
the fuck we just talking about my add,
I don't know either. I have no idea.
You've been watching any hockey.
Did you see my Sean's elbow? I was
a thing of beauty. It was a thing.
It was so, it was perfect.
Filthy. He, he's, he got trips.
I know a, he's the size of
Barney rubble, so nobody paid.
He's not going to get called out like
all foods. Probably one of the worst.
But dude, he was and I loved Marshawn
and I loved the fucking bruise,
but I love him commodities. But at that,
the thing is, I don't like that aspect,
like throwing that shit. Did you see
when, uh, I also and destroyed them.
Oh Dude, my God. Ugh,
that was a brutal hit. Oh,
I thought he had like internal
bleeding after that cause he kept,
he kept skating but he kept skating.
Yeah. And he was just going like, ah.
And it seemed like beyond
the way,
the thing about PK, well, I'm so
glad he placed her in Nashville,
not from Montreal anymore. It was,
he used as best as he used to.
He used to get us all the time and
everybody knew that was his move.
And I don't know why no one,
because he just knew exactly when
your head was down for a second,
it was two crossovers.
He was inside and then all of a sudden
he was just in front of you and he just
ended your fucking life for
like, I dunno, like two shifts,
but um, yeah, I'm, I'm, uh, I always
liked that guy. I never take it to the,
to the point if there's a guy on a
team that I don't like, you know,
like when Derek Jeter played
for the Yankees, I couldn't,
I couldn't get myself to, to get to
the point of like actual g hating them.
It's like the guy's great. Right? It
is good. Yeah. I'll you saying is,
I wish this guy was on my tape.
No,
you haven't watched his hockey watching
my son play hockey. He's a beast.
Of course. I know you
showed me all the, uh,
the video of them and he like picked it
up and to see who's like playing drums
or something. Right. They also
plays the Romans and he plays drums.
Any place hockey Jesus
kids can be crushing if
were to get more legs than I am.
You can be a fucking grandfather by
the time this special comes out. Jeez.
Where you've been working to a lens as a,
I just flew back today from Phoenix.
I was with Craig, Craig
Robinson. You know,
I've been totally on them for like a
couple of years now when he's not shooting
television shows, which is all the
fucking time that guy works. Um,
so yeah. Uh, where were you guys working?
We were working at stand up
live in Phoenix. Oh, okay.
I know that plays five sold out shows. It
was fantastic. Had a ball. I did the uh,
you know, it's fucking, that's fucking
nuts as far as like that downtown area,
how lively it is if there's
something going on. But the second,
the workday ends like during the week if
you're there, like at five o'clock town.
Yeah. It's fucking creepy. If the
sons don't have a game, it's over.
Yeah. I love it though. I mean, I
couldn't live there, I don't think,
but I had a really good time there.
Um,
I had a good time traveling with
you though. We went down south.
I was just like reading some
comments about, give me the keys.
Just give us the keys. Oh yeah, yeah. That
lady. I thought about that the other day.
We went to check in that hotel and
that lady was just fucking with the
instructions. I, Jim is on the fourth
floor. It's open from nine to nine.
We did as a continental breakfast,
blah, blah, blah, blah. And like,
I'm sitting there going like, oh my
God, how long is this going to take?
And she's in the middle of eating.
You just choose the key.
She got like offended.
She goes bad for real
dude. I fucking was laughing
like I was in high school, man.
It was one of those labs.
So I was just like, oh.
Cause what it was was the fact
that she didn't find it funny.
It was already hilarious, but the
fact that she didn't find it funny,
it hurt her feelings.
She didn't have to deal with it.
And then she got mad all in like,
fucking like a half a second.
Then I felt like I was in class
again where it's like, oh my God,
don't start fucking laughing.
Or you're gonna,
you're gonna get like the tension or
something that you also took me to that,
that fucking, uh, was at that
barbecue place or something.
Oh yeah. What does it call it? Was it?
They'll say the name of
it cause it was terrible.
Well the first one we went through,
then we went to, we went to them,
we went to that one where it was a
giant fucking place and they had like 40
fried murdered chickens that you could
see. You don't remember that place?
It was gigantic and got all my God,
this place is fucking unbelievable.
Is that the place where you ate?
And then we went to the,
to the Nascar track and then you were
like t rex that you had a salad. Oh
where was that? In a hotel in
Charlotte. That was Charlotte. Okay.
And we did the Nascar experience.
That was very cool though.
So let's talk about crushing it.
That dude was driving us around.
Is 20 years old named Dylan. Remember
that? I know any as much as the jockey.
Right. Cause he doesn't
want to slow the car down.
I couldn't believe what like what a piece
of shit or race car it looks like when
you walk up to it.
I've seen formula one cars up close.
They look like absolute like it
looks like if you stepped on it,
the whole thing would fall apart
cause all it is, it's just,
it's just an engine suspension and tires
and everything else is just that the
lightest. Did you see the uh,
the, the gas pedal was shit.
It'll look a stick like bent coat hanger.
It's like real would have like if you
had like that just the floor thing,
whatever that the pedal is to rest your
foot on the, if you have that in them,
that's the difference between you like
I guess winning the race or a coming in
like third row because that fucking
thing is sitting there with a piece of
rubber that's going to win
that race. That actually they're um,
Nascar's not doing well. It's not,
the numbers are down now.
And I went to the Daytona 500,
they painted the seats
like every other seat.
Like they had like three colors and they
would paint them to make it look like
those people in the season. Yeah.
Cameras flying by. And you know,
used to have it like that was the
Minnesota north stars really used to have
seats like that and I thought it was cool
and now I'm thinking well maybe cause
nobody showed up for the game devs and
maybe that's why they moved to Dallas.
So when I hear all those Minnesota north
stars fan still complaining that that
team left.
I mean if there was people that well
there was people there I wouldn't have
noticed. Right for right,
exactly. You would've been
able to see the season on the road. You're
skating on thousand lakes there. No.
You watched any of the football, was
that, do you watch any of the football?
I haven't been,
I haven't watched any football.
The only thing in my life
is the Washington Redskins
and they're terrible number
one on safety from Baltimore hosts.
How'd you become a Redskins fan?
On and off from silver spring,
Maryland,
right over the DC line that people are
thinking blah. Okay. But my, you know,
I had grass and shouldn't my yard and
two cars,
both parents are, I'm not saying that
that's not available in Baltimore.
What people think of the wire and the
corner where the thing about Baltimore,
but that's not where I lived.
That's why,
cause that's where I met you.
I met yet the Baltimore Improv
with that fucking debt long.
He had walked down like that
three quarters of a mile
hallway the last mile or
whatever. Yeah. That was still
worst location ever for a uh,
for a, for a fucking comedy club
with the club. I was all thrilled.
They let me come down there and they
asked me if I wanted to close out the
Sunday one time because somebody canceled
and I was all fucking excited and I
drove there from New
York City to do it right.
And I was like I'm going to get in with
the Improv's and I showed up and there
was like 10 people there and the
owner talk was talking to the broker,
never talked to me and then
walked out while I was on stage.
And I remember being on stage.
Like I said,
I think I knew when I was on stage
cause I was kind of glancing over like,
okay well is that at least
works at Sonic Burger man.
And we didn't have,
it's really fucking annoying.
I don't know why anybody who ran a club,
why the fuck he would ever do that?
Because you don't know who's
coming down and for all you know,
they're going to go on, you know, and
do something. The fact that she would,
I was driving down from me,
he didn't even say thanks.
Classic fucking club managers. He
fat, big 50 inch fucking waste.
You know what I mean? But those
slacks, that giant fucking belt.
Well, right. That's the Gabardine
whatever they're called.
What are those flags called?
Action slacks.
Yeah, the action slacks. The uh, yeah,
I ran into a number of those fucking
people. That's my big thing though.
The shade. Do you know
what? I'm turning 50.
Turning five zero in [inaudible]
49 in May. You do all right.
They're young stuff behind you there.
You want to know what the next year
you life's going to be like? I, uh,
hopefully it's going to be
something like yours now,
while I've decided that I'm going
to, uh, I'm going to fucking
get myself that, like, rather
than looking at 50 would dread,
which I'm really not
considering it. I, you know,
so many of my friends had fucking
died, didn't even make it so, you know,
don't recommend DC. Don't tell me
he died. I swear to God. No, no,
we didn't see did last
weekend. Last one. The,
he fucking died of what?
Um,
there was like some Carter cardiac event.
One of his friends was like coming from
Connecticut and going down to Florida.
Hadn't seen Joe in life 15 years.
Stopped by his house to then they're
going to go to the Improv to watch, uh,
Lavelle Crawford. And Joe said he
had a headache. I went upstairs.
It takes him like aspirin or whatever and
like sit on the bed and like laid back
and Kroger while his buddy was there
that he hadn't seen it. 15 years
wash. Yeah. Isn't that crazy?
Oh my to that guy had one of my favorite
fucking jokes were about the compo. No,
the joke he did
when he was having unprotected
sex with the woman. You know,
when it goes on to my thing and I'm
doing my things, she goes, chalk,
don't you come and me,
don't you come and meet Joel job.
Goddamn you don't come to me. And
he goes, I blocks all that out.
Yeah.
Joe was hilarious.
I haven't seen him in fucking,
I haven't seen him in like 15 years.
I was going to be my chairs that now.
Ah Jeez. Ah, fuck
yeah. What we're getting at that age
where people are just dying and say,
you know what's really fucked up? Is that
what it is? It's behind that. I don't,
it's not even like shocking to me anymore.
Yeah. We only want to hear it now.
I used to be like,
oh my God.
But I was at my son's hockey game when
someone called me and he was like, Yo,
Joel, record on those, are you serious?
And he was like, yeah, want to know how?
And he's like, I don't know.
I'll find out. And I was
like, all right, call me back.
And My, my son talk again.
Well I have years ago,
what it is,
is the first wave that goes is,
it's usually a be bad genetics,
bad luck or bad diet.
And then after that it's like if you
had half a bad diet, half bad genetics,
just literally like when the grim reapers
going to get you. So speaking to that,
becoming an a dad at this point, like I
was fucking old as I am. I got, you know,
I've cut back on the Busan and uh,
so I'm,
I'm trying to get myself
down to my fucking, uh,
to my fight and weight and actually maybe
get a personally you look fit. Yeah.
I I I,
I took four months off of booze and then
for the last month I've been drinking
like lightly,
but I don't know,
I think I'm just too old now because I
took those fucking four months off and
now going back to it,
just, I get to the next,
I drink too and I'm just like
banged up the next day. Yup. Um, so,
I dunno, I think I'm going to go,
I was joking that I'm going to go,
I'm going to be like staying in my fifties
just to like fucking pilates and yoga
and tantric six,
try to learn how to come for 40 minutes.
That's how a lot of his
music is his recorded.
A lot of people don't know
that it's actually him coming.
And the beginning of a
synchronicity is that Ed.
Whoa, Whoa, whoa.
That's him.
They've caught him and I record on
favorite quarterback and his wife. Right.
For the first 40 minutes.
Then the last five minutes he just sings
this song and right as he comes that
stuff.
Yeah.
Gordon, some enough going.
So Gordon in there, Jeez.
I saw him at a, I saw him at the Hollywood
bowl with, um, Emma said Gaylord Perry.
It's a pitcher. Who's the guy from genesis
that sank? Sledgehammer. Peter Gabriel.
[inaudible]. Oh yeah, yeah. They both
were fucking awesome. And they had like,
and I was like, all right,
who's gonna? Who's gonna open,
who's going to fucking clothes?
And they just,
one would sing a song and then the next
one come out and sing a song and then
they were just both out there and if
there was the other person saw and they
would just sync back up early.
Oh yeah,
that's still Peter Gabriel had like
synchronized dance moves and shit.
It was fucking finish and they were bad.
But that was part of the joke when you
just see was he didn't give a fuck late.
It was like two guys like daughter plays
with them too sometimes. Is that right?
I was like the violin and she comes
out and crosses on the violin.
I'm trying to remember
if he had a violinist.
I just know that he was just like the guy
just aged and said fuck it was staying
was you know, still in shape and
shit. So PT gator look terrible now.
Oh Dude. He came out looking like, you
know that headliner that didn't make it.
If just doesn't give a fuck anymore. It
comes out with like where I like, oh,
the same sweatsuit he was wearing.
When you pick them up at the airport,
just walks on stage,
maybe put a hat on.
He had a be in a big ones that you on.
Staying always has one of those fucking
those clothes that looks like he's going
to do a,
what does that movie did with the Tina
Turner where she shaved the side of her
head? Oh my. Um, Thunderdome. Thunderdome.
I feel like he got a bunch of clothes
from that movie that still fed them.
He still has a trailer, the
wardrobe trailer, all that Mesh.
Spiderman looking shit,
flashy underwear peeking out of the back.
Shane Shane Bell shirt.
Yeah, I saw those guys.
They fucking, they absolutely killed
it here. I got to make shit. What,
20 minutes then at some point I do
have to read a little to advertising,
but I'm do who's your
fucking Internet provider?
T and t minus just, it's just not
happening for me. Yeah, I think I might,
I don't even know who I have.
Nia handles that and it's,
it's just been on the Fritz. I gotta
drive the Fritz. It's been on the Fritz.
I've got to drive over to
Starbucks. Buy something. Starbucks.
I don't drink coffee. All
right. I mean I guess they,
the coffee has to be amazing
maternity line. Strong as it is.
You don't need to be Katherine. Oh, you
know, I don't know. Worst wired as well.
I'm the worst dude. I, I need
like the reverse of that.
But you go into all of that food just
sucks all of their food just fucking
sucks. All right, let me, let me read a
little advertising here. Um, how much,
how much has been done, how much time
are you going to do when you special?
I'm doing an hour hour
that's doing it now.
Maybe a little longer so we can cut
it down. All I do is a little long.
I would do like whatever
you you want it to be.
I would only do a little bit
more than that. Yeah, cause yeah,
it makes it to your life so much easier.
If you,
if you want to do an hour special,
do like an hour and 10 are,
then you usually just lift a bit.
Or to the same guys that are shooting
want special shot only Adams special that
he's uh, they said that, uh,
the only like an hour and 20 minutes and
that they wanted to cut it down to an
hour because showtime wasn't buying
an hour, 20 minutes specials.
They're just buying ours. Then you've
got a set of killing your babies.
That's the doors.
But he refused to cut it and so they
just took it out in an hour and 20.
So if you watch the special that's on
right now, that's on showtime right now.
It's an hour and 20 minutes.
Jesus only yams telling the business
which way it's going. Wow. Call this.
I would've been like, all right, I'll cut
it down. All right. Oh, look, all the sip.
Great. Talk about the challenge
of finding great talent.
Well, usually I have a hack on here, but
this week I've found Todd rex. Thank you.
I found you on zip recruiter.
I looked up hilarious guys
shooting a special and fucking
silver. Like, all right.
Ziprecruiter knew there was a smarter way.
So they built a platform that finds
the right job. Candidates for you.
Ziprecruiter learns
what you're looking for,
identifies people with the
right experience and advice
them to apply to your job.
Uh, if read by the wrong
person, this would seem really
racist, wouldn't it? Yeah.
Um, these invitations have
revolutionized how you find your hire.
In fact,
80% of employers who post on the on sip,
okay,
Yay. Get a quality candidate through
the site and just one day you got to do
something interesting or
they won't listen to it.
And ZipRecruiter doesn't stop there.
They even spotlight the strongest
applications you receive.
So you never miss a great match. The
right candidates that are out there, uh,
ZipRecruiter is how you find
them. A business. Businesses
of all sides, trust, sip,
uh, for using their higher
needs. See now you're doing now,
right now my listeners can try
ZipRecruiter for free. That's right. Free.
Just go to ziprecruiter.com/bar that's
ziprecruiter.com/berg
ziprecruiter.com/burr the
smartest way to hire. Oh Jesus.
Look who's here but up, up,
up me undies beyond these,
no more sweaty balls beyond me,
Andy.
You could buy them at the fucking mall.
I'm on my podcast with Todd rex. See
shooting especial. What the heck?
Go down and get yourself some fucking
tickets in your balls will feel great in
these underwears. All right. You
want to look good, fake Todd,
do you want to look good
with your significant other?
Do this Valentine's Day.
You want your fucking
junk to be sliding around?
Silky smooth shit in that
checkout me undies matching pairs.
Would you ever do this
with you? USP, a unique,
fun gift for you and your Valentine.
They're the perfect balance of comfort,
fit,
and exciting prints.
Don't spend another Valentine's
Day giving the same old gift.
Checkout me undies.com find the best match
for your match me undies are the most
comfortable and fun undies you and your
significant other will ever own that
made from the softest materials on earth.
We're talking three times softer than
cotton and I believe that at this point
the cotton lobby has never debated.
This fetus for students may not a fetus.
I heard that,
that they dip in organic dyes so it
doesn't give you a ball cancer this
Valentine's Day get your platinum a gift.
That's for the both of you.
Order by February 5th at 10:00
AM for free standard shipping.
So your gift arrives in time.
Matching pairs are fun, thoughtful,
comfortable gift that going back in.
They should have ended it right there.
It's a comfortable gift you share with
your significant other 100% satisfaction.
Guaranteed me undies guarantees you and
your significant other will love your
matching pairs or your money back.
You know what they should do next
year four they should have everybody,
whoever sends in the cutest picture of
picture of them and there and they're
matching pairs gets it free.
Tip trip to matching Paris.
Oh no god matching pair is
nothing to get your 20% off.
That was just an idea.
People that's not an actual offers.
So don't fucking send people in with you
guys with the spare tire hanging over
you is silk John's
there, a long Johns. Um,
to get you 20% off your
matching pair of free shipping,
a hundred percent satisfaction guarantee.
Go to [inaudible] dot com that's Mandy's
dot coms. Oh, sorry. Mandy saw comm slash.
Bar.
That's Mandy's dot com slash birth.
This will be the best Valentine's
Day gift that you will give.
Start matching your bottom
half to your top. Better half.
Go to [inaudible] dot
com slash bar right now.
Pair of all promotional here.
They gave me some there. Yeah.
Did you Rocco? I definitely
want, but they, they definitely,
they gave me the Greg Louganis cut
on one of them that lose the west,
the one now the uh, the, the
West Hollywood cut there.
So I,
I was not in a,
I was not in gay male shape when
I got him, so I did not look good.
I'm while I'm trying to get it in as good
as shape, as those fellas down there.
But uh, who he have the pit like
that I want to get in shape now.
I want to get engage shape
cause I had a buddy of mine,
all he does is he just loses like fucking
10 pounds and then he just sort of
push us down his shirt going,
dude, I looked good. You
know what you're like pat,
you stomach. I think. I think I'm looking.
All right. Um, do you and your wife,
do you guys, uh, do you guys,
uh, for kids? Of course we do.
And I'll do you guys,
do you guys celebrate Valentine's Day?
Is there now at this point, how long
have you guys been together? Since 95.
That's great man. Yeah, you 23 years,
but it took me till 2004 to tie the
knot. Oh yeah. What did they serve?
She was the one that somebody uses
that like 10 years, man. Wait, 2000.
One, 2004, 2004. So that's
nine years old by, uh,
it took me
when I was doing it took me nine years
to really the fuck. Yeah. Yeah. Stupid.
I knew in nine months, but I was
just like, I don't know. Right.
And then also my wife was a
little bit of a commitment.
Phobe we're both like commitment
phobes yet totally relationship people.
So it totally worked. You know what
I mean? Right. So we lived there,
our whole sid and Nancy fucking lifestyle
for awhile, you know, not married,
no kids.
Partying had a great time.
We did that for awhile to
hit all the water parks,
the magic t shirts. Oh
yeah. Matching me undies.
Uh, it took me forever to propose to her,
but I'll tell you why, why it happened.
I went out partying with friends of mine
one night and I ended up spending an ad
out in Virginia and I was on my way
back the next day, like 10:00 AM.
And my wife was furious.
She was my girlfriend at the time.
We were living together and she
was furious and she called me.
She already left me a message and I
checked the message and then she called me
again when we were driving home.
I don't know.
And so when I picked up
the phone and said, hey,
I was just was out here thinking with
my friends. The reason I was like,
I'm out here with my friends that spread
the night that it's like I was talking
to a man, I think, uh, I think I'm
ready to settle down and marry you.
Wow. That was in that way. She,
that you had to come up with that
she know that she better condition.
She will now when she listens
to this Nellie way. Oh Dude,
I want to get you in trouble. So what
does she do? What's that? She was like,
really? Oh my God, I can't wait for
you to come home. And I was like,
dude, I didn't want to have
a fight what I at home for,
for spending the night out. So yeah,
so that defused the whole fight.
Then it was coming up
and set you up for another thousand
more in the next year there.
Um, I, I just want to fuck did I do?
And I finally just realized, uh, yeah.
I just knew she was going to
leave Sundays off the pot. No,
it was some days when I was mad at her.
I would fantasize about breaking up,
but even in the fantasy of her
breaking up when she would walk out,
even in the fantasy of that, I
would still go, no, no, no, no, no.
That sounds like all right. I got
to make, oh yeah, that's, that's,
that was the,
Paul Versey helped me get through that.
Poverty has actually helped a
number of comedians get over that.
Like, uh, that's, that's thing, you
know, you think it's a mountainous,
you just stepping up on the
curb, which just like, dude,
where are you going? Right.
Or do you know she's going to be so happy.
You're going to be happy once you get
through the fucking vows and all of that
bullshit. Then you just said a party with
all your friends and is fucking great.
He was, he was 100% 100%
fucking right. So, um,
I was going to ask you, do you
guys go out on Valentine's Day? No,
we don't really sell celebrating.
Like what? I'm going to chocolate. There's
nothing like that or cards, you know,
we might know we have the kids,
so a lot of the times we're just a,
we'll wait till the kids go to sleep
and then we'll have a bottle of wine and
watch a movie or some downstairs, some
corny like that. And that's way better.
We're going to go an hour and go out to
dinner. Like, dude, we're so old now.
Sometimes it feels like a,
we want to go out and have a good time.
So we're gonna like,
we're gonna go out to dinner and then go
into Hollywood and get some drinks and
maybe go to a dance club or whatever that
by the time we're done eating dinner,
like you just go home. Uh, and it's,
how psyched are you on the other person
says that? Yeah, this is like, yes, yes,
I do. Just want to go. I don't want to
go to Hollywood right now. Yeah. Like I,
I for years would rather drink at home.
I got better stuff here.
Then they got out at the bar. They
always have some shit stuff in the rape.
You all the praise also.
Yeah.
And once you're with the person you're
going to be with that they got the worst
booze. I'm not interested
in meeting anybody. Right.
So all I'm going to do is go out there
and then I've got to deal with like how
am I getting fucking home? This is before
like Uber and all that Shit. I've been,
I've been drinking at home
the for for years.
[inaudible] have some like,
yeah, we have what? Bourbon.
Bourbon whiskeys. Scott. I think
Tequila. Yeah, there's really smokey,
I think whiskey. One time I was here
that was probably a scotch. Scotch.
It was like, yeah, it wasn't good. Yeah,
it was good. Oh, did we smoke cigars? Uh,
oh no, no. I don't think we
did because as I was thinking,
my daughter just had her first birthday
and I was looking at the house.
And to do that, we had like
16 kids over here. Really all,
I have friends who have kids now
cause you know, once you have a kid,
all your friends who don't have kids,
it's just like they keep live in their
rock star life and you're like, you just,
you get like six more calls.
Like Ah,
you got gotta watch the kid and he gets
the gist. You just fade out and started.
Yet they start disappearing.
Horizon, you just fade out. Uh,
like that bad member who's on
the first album and he goes like,
what am I fucking half that can
happen. Then they, then, you know,
they never see that guy until like the
VH one behind the music. He's just like,
why am I,
you know,
they're putting out a second album and
they just didn't have a call me and all
of a sudden I was just like,
we're like, get them out. Um,
yes. So I was looking around
the living room and we had like,
like 16 little kids in there. Oh
my goodness. Agency encounter.
Yeah.
And just like toys Galore and
just shit all over the place.
And I was just looking,
thinking like, you know,
18 months ago this would
have been five of my friends.
We would have been getting shit faced
watching a game and smoking cigars and
just how like how much it changes
in a good way. Like we went to the,
went to the park today for
the first time I went over,
I put her on the swing and shit. She loved
it. Oh yes. Squeeze means the greatest.
See all your pictures and video
of that man because of high,
Nelson goes by so fast and you'll look
back at those pictures with a tear in
your eye.
Oh I know I'm already doing it.
I'm already like this a
part of me that's like uh,
uh as psyched as I am to be a dad there,
there was a mild depression with
her turning one going like ah,
she's not a baby anymore man.
She's a Todd.
The next year she turns to her age
doubled in a year. Yeah she's helped.
But I see why people keep having babies
cause you just want to keep hitting
reset row cause it's so fucking awesome.
And I like talking in a positive way about
it because when my wife got pregnant,
just so many people said all this
negative shit and they all do yo know boys
Lincoln, it's over for you. Yeah,
no more getting a little coozie plus
no more go into Thailand and
see what's up over there.
Like all this degenerate shit.
And I was just like, yeah,
this is way better than that shit though.
Yes.
Now today we were over there and was just
uh, I was having the best time and I I,
you know, it was yeah, it was quite good.
Clean Fun is actually getting a little
bit of exercise right. Um, clean and, and,
and she kind of took her first
step in the park, which was cool.
And uh,
so yeah,
so now we figured out what the motivation
tactic was to get it going. Dude.
I see you have to tell you what's fucked
up though was Imani is the definition
of organic in the deaf in the dictionary
versus the definition of organic within
the food industry. Like they
literally changed it like with law,
what organic means. Cause I know when,
when we're giving her like poisonous shit,
she's fucking so excited to eat it.
Like the real organic,
no, no, no, no, no. The shit
that they call it organic,
but it's really got like fucking this,
like,
like they try to get you addicted to it,
like cigarettes,
the same fucking thing.
So we had these little puffs
that said organic on them and uh,
I just noticed that like,
we would have like really good food and
she would start pointing at the other
ones, like a lab rat. And
then one time I went to reach,
just reached for the can and she
started like hopping up like, yeah man,
give me a hit. So you should either fix.
Yeah. So, um, yeah, we phased those out.
I'm actually, that's not true. We
have, we have one more canned down,
so we're going to wean her off
and then it's all, you know,
she's a kid so she doesn't see it. She's
not going to be thinking of them. But, um,
I, that's the thing that's, uh,
that can also drive you nuts is, uh,
that type of shit. And then
if you have any sort of, um,
friend with a kid in your life that is
totally up on all these issues and then
they just, they just come
to you. It's like a fucking,
it's like this cloud of
fear that they just dump on.
You go to this website,
you have to fucking
being a dad and I,
we have friends like that or at least
a couple in their fucking annoying and
it's like,
and even though our kid likes their kid,
we have to like cut them back a little
bit and I'm like, my daughter's like,
well when did she come over? And I'm
like, if the kid comes over is fine,
but I can't have the parents
come over here to like,
did you get your kids vaccinated?
How do you handle that?
Because that's what I realize
now is that you can have like,
you can be friends with people,
like a couple of you and your wife are
friends with a couple and then all of a
sudden,
and they have kids but you don't have
kids so you're not dealing with them on
that level. But then when you have
a kid, the relationship changes.
Now you not only do you guys have to
like get along socially when you go out,
you know, you both vibe.
You got to kind of on some,
they gotta be within your wheelhouse
of how they raise their fucking kid.
And if the kid comes over and he's a
fucking lunatic like bite and a dog and
shit like Elon, what? What is this cave
man? You got to kind of be like, oh,
I don't want my kid acting like that.
Right? No, we have a,
I'm not saying any names says I don't
want to alienate any people that might be
listening to this,
but we have one family who has a kid
that's just fucking rude and I can't have
it and I just, I cannot stand. But my,
my kid wants this kid to
come over and was like,
Jesus Christ should we lends this fucking
kid come over and then like maybe they
changed over the last six months and
they come spend the night and it's a
fucking nightmare.
What are the rules?
If a kid comes home and he's rude,
like what can you say
now to a fucking kid?
Did I started just getting serious
with it all? I do go back to the bed,
go back to bed.
So I fucking waking up every 10 minutes
of calling for your mommy and then
when I say I'm going to call
your mommy, there's, you
know, no, don't call my mommy.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no. I'm like,
then do, what the fuck are you doing?
I don't say fuck no, no, cause I
don't know. I'm not going to be linen.
Shut the fuck up.
You being a fucking asshole.
All right, so I'd be a little asshole.
Notice that I told my wife. Am I doing,
he gets up one more time.
I'm not talking to them.
You got to talk to them cause
I'm going to start getting mad.
Do you remember back in the day,
like if your friend's Dad said anything,
you will fail.
You are afraid of us,
right? Yeah. Hell yeah. Go back to
the room and go to bed. Like, Oh shit,
this motherfucker serious
and it needs to come down. I hate that
they call me by my first name tied.
No they don't. Yes I did.
Todd. I'm scared. Can you
call my mommy? I'm old school.
I'm old speech. He had called
me Mr. Burke that said let him,
he fucked a bill.
You got wait, what's to eat here? Right,
right. No Dude. I would literally be like,
what the fuck did you say to me?
You Little Shit. I won't say that,
but that's what I'll be thinking.
So that of course, as I say,
please address me as Mr. Burn the subutex.
He will here is,
what the fuck did you say to me?
You Little Shit.
And then he'll say to his mother and yeah,
you mean
right. Let's walk. A little girl comes
over to her house and she was like,
she'll come downstairs,
I sleep in all morning and then come down
with the kids where my wife and I are.
My daughter's still asleep and she'll
come downstairs before everybody and she
be like, what's for breakfast? And
my wife was like, well, you know,
pancakes and sausage. She was like,
yeah, I don't like that stuff.
What else is there?
And my wife says looks at me and was like,
this is a bit serious right now.
Like oh the fuck back upstairs.
Yeah, what the fuck? Oh my,
I would love to hear a kid now
and he's saying to my mother,
my mother would just be, well
that's all there is. I guess.
You know I've talked to you at lunch.
My wife's a lawyer says,
I guess you'll just be hungry then cause
that's what we're having. If you're in,
if you don't need to
just going to be hungry.
It's amazing how like some of these kids
are rude to sit and you say something
to the parents were like, yeah, she's a
little crazy. She, she's, she's like, no,
now that's, that's like when people have
a dog that's fucking nuts. Like I did,
but I, I quarantine the thing when people
would come over except one time I got a
little confident and watch to me the
dog whisperers and then my friend end up
getting bit j law had got bit by a dog.
Yeah. Bit of on his calf given nip.
Um,
yeah,
that dog scared the living shit out of me.
One time we were downstairs and
there she was in a cage. Oh yeah.
That doesn't know that she was in there.
And I was like walking past
and like went out the case with the
battle of the cage and scare the fucking
Piss island all point. God Yvette
Cage, I'll be shredded right now. Yeah.
Yeah.
She was an adorable Hell Hound.
She loved the hell out of me and
about six people and everybody else.
She treated as a fucking intruder.
And, uh, I just, you know,
it was the smartest, most painful, uh,
decision I ever made, but I didn't
understand, uh, that I was still going,
I guess are, you know, the last two
days in a row she's in town, uh,
like you've kinda still take care of her
in a way, right? Oh yeah. Oh yeah. Yeah,
definitely. And I get pictures
of her all the time and when,
like once every two months she'll
come to town and I just take for,
for a hike every single day like this.
You remember, you're like, Yup. Anyway,
she did and she does. She
does. And uh, if, when I,
when I go out to where the guy lives,
if I show up,
she's kind of looked cause she's not
used to seeing me down. You know,
first they see the shape and it's
the smell like the whole way that dog
brainworks or whatever. Right.
And then, um, then, you know,
then she's all back to normal
and everything. But I got to,
I was nervous meeting her because of
the way she was because I knew at that
point she had bonded with the new person
and it might view me as like a threat.
I mean the dog was like through that
dog. It, my buddy said that there, uh,
as Cleo Ferzli yeah, verse he goes to,
this should be a 30 for 30 on that dog,
that dog's life. Like how it was
abandoned by the La River. I mean,
so many times this thing should've
just been like, you know,
like whenever the Olympics come around,
they always have like those crazy stories
that make you tear up all the shit
that they went through. Like,
you could do that other yeah.
And like as a pitbull be in that
big of a pain in the ass like that,
those things, if those things sneeze, they
get put down, it's fucking terrible. But,
um, the fact that she still like living
this awesome life, uh, makes me feel good.
And every time I see her, like,
um, you know, the dude had gotten,
it was my former trainer,
so, uh, and he, he just like,
she has her first dog friend now.
Every dog, she tried to murder,
now she's like friends with the dog,
but like they,
they needed like his level talent like is
he says jokingly said, yeah, I'm, I've,
I've been slow cooking or she's
not someone that you like, okay,
this is how it is.
And then boom to that,
it's just been this year long thing
that she's now finally ready to just,
and even when he started hanging,
she started hanging out with another dog.
There was this whole fucking process that
he had to go through and totally keep
an eye on my dog because my dog does
this shit where like when she's going to
attack, she's in the cage. Wow. She did
that shit, but she was out in the open.
Um, she just made the decision.
There was no growling,
there was no warnings going right.
She just did it. She just, she had,
she would just fucking do it.
Let me read 'em let me read some of
the questions here. All right. Um,
taught by the way, you're gonna. You're
gonna fucking, I can already tell, Dude,
you're already wound up about this thing.
You're going to fucking murder, dude.
Thank you there.
I'm excited about it. I really am.
I feel like this is like, you know,
I've been doing this shit for so long
and I'm at the age right now. Like,
if it doesn't fucking pop for me right
now, it's not going to fucking happen.
Nah, that's, that's the old dude.
That's the old way of thinking.
You're totally in control.
I do this business like it's a giant mall.
Okay.
And I have my little store in the
mall and you walk into my store, hey,
why don't I tell jokes? I
do a podcast. Got a cartoon,
see anything you like. That's what I'm
selling. If you don't fucking like it,
I get it. See you later. But when I
first got into this business, I would,
you know, it's like you're walking around
the mall. Oh my God. This selling shirts.
I gotta sell shirts. Oh Fuck Day. They
got sneakers. I've gotta be doing.
You try to like do everything with
the Joneses. Right. Fuck that too.
Just by the way, your cartoon is
fucking hilarious. I'll thank you.
Frank Murphy and a vicar. Motu Vera
guys. Oh yeah. You wait till the UHC,
you wait for the third season where
we're editing, editing like fades.
It's going to be out later on this year.
I'm not allowed to say exactly when.
I don't have an exact date either.
But like Netflix has like, you know,
they like the fucking geniuses
of this new thing is they, they,
I remember the last time
like, well last time, uh,
when I had a special coming out there,
they wanted me to come in to meet
with them to like talk about,
discuss promoting it. And
I'm thinking like, what the
fuck are we going to discus?
Throw up a couple of billboards. I'll talk
about my podcast. Dude. I went in there,
it was like bill Belicheck
shit until, I can't even,
I can't even explain it.
Like I went in there going like,
this is ridiculous that this is just an
idiot like me with a bunch of Dick Jokes.
And then I just,
I,
I watched them breaking down to how
they were going go up promoting it.
Like two people who are watching Netflix
and their fucking algorithm and all of
that shit judged by what you
watched and all that shit.
And not saying it's a perfect
system. It, it blew my mind.
Just fucking blew my mind.
They didn't listen. Dude.
There's a reason why they're
global right now. Um,
and it's not from hanging out with me
there. All right. A peach cobbler recipe.
Hey Billy Cross king. I like
to bake by the way. Yeah.
I mean my daughter told me that before
I made my daughter a birthday cake.
I'm doing that every
year of a life's easy.
Are you doing the non GMO with the no.
Gluten, the non tasty for us. Oh No.
There was a bunch of sugar and fucking
nice stuff on talking dead baby seals in
it.
That's a big politically incorrect cake.
Um, alright. Deliberately crest king.
I am invited to a super
bowl party by the way.
You know the Patriots are
in it again this year.
Do you realize if Tom Brady
gets another ring? Jesus, Chris,
him and bill Belicheck we'll have more
rings than every franchise in the NFL
except for the Pittsburgh
Steelers. There'll be tied. Wow.
Then their entire 50 years,
50 something years of every franchise
trying to win one at Brady doesn't lose
though. I'll just let you know
that right now. Yeah, he does.
He lost twice to the giants.
I think this is going to be,
it's just give him the
ring. No, no, no, no, no.
That talk makes me nervous
through the eagles.
The Eagles got a fucking
horrific horrifically
terrifying fucking running game.
And uh,
nick folds is not a backup quarterback
that as a starting quarterback who lost
his fucking job and he's coming
back like a fucking revenge movie.
That defense looks,
looks fucking great row.
And I don't think we would have done
to the vikings what they did. So yeah,
I dunno. I would say take the, trying to
be humbled and to keep the gods happy.
Take the eagles and the points. That's
what, that's what I would do with my mind.
I'm not doing Edelman's out.
Gronk got a concussion. Um,
Ammon Dola had the game of his
fucking life. Did you get that song?
The Hammond Dola Song? Ah, it's like
that song, Lola. Really? Oh Dude.
It's fucking go.
D O l a doe now that play a nick fold
and the super bowl as far as it may not
show old. Alright. Hey Billy. Chris King.
I'm invited to a Superbowl party.
Don't worry.
Just dude's and nobody interested in
commercials or half time shows. Thank God.
And I am the designated dessert maker.
Uh,
you are talking about peach cobbler
on a Monday morning podcast,
but I can't quite remember if it was
a recent one or an old one. Anyway,
would you mind sharing your recipe with
me? Because I want to have the real deal.
I'm from Germany and can't figure out
if the recipes I find here any good hope
to hear from you and go fuck yourself.
I just googled and looked at pictures and
then I found one that looked good law.
This is what I would say. I would say, uh,
I would say if the cinnamon,
nutmeg,
whatever they tell you to fucking put in,
add more,
cause they always be like an
eighth of a teaspoon of court.
They're going to make it taste good,
but they're not gonna make it taste great.
So definitely be tasting you're filling
and don't be afraid to get a little
light, a little heavy handed
with some of the spices,
especially the cinnamon sugar.
A little bit of some butter in there.
And then I give it a little Dustin before
I closed the Pi of the, the really?
Oh yeah, you got, it's gotta to be
a big fucking delicious going mess.
Um, that's how I do it too. It,
everything's gonna be on fucking baking.
I'm trying to get you all right.
Political relationship advice. Oh God.
Here we go. All right, let
me, I want to hear this one.
I literally unfollow people on Twitter
if all they do is talk politics.
Unless you're rationally kind of trash
in both sides, but like, you know,
it's going to be like, you know,
so our Trump just did this.
It's just like, all right. I will tell
you that. Well, I mean, yeah, I mean,
trauma one sided to Conan,
Conan O'Brien and the funniest fucking
joke about Trump. They go, how do you, uh,
Andall the whole trumps that she,
what's the hardest part about the
Trump situation right now? He goes,
he goes trying to write a joke that's more
absurd than what's actually happening.
I like how we have like
Trump on Twitter just is,
it's just considered normal now that
like a president has the time to,
I don't even like people
shit on me all the time.
I don't even get back to them watching
the quote leader of the free world or
this is all just, you know,
that wasn't a stain on my tie.
That was actually a presidential seal.
The all right.
Political relationship advice.
Hey Billy Willy Concoct,
I don't know what that
means. That's an, you know,
one with a little bit of alliteration,
uh,
to pair love the podcast and of
course the stand up. Thank you.
You're the only comic that actually
makes me bust out laughing. I'll wait.
You see Todd special cheese.
So I'm a 21 year old guy and I've been
seeing this girl now for about nine
months. She's great. Treats
me good, loyal and is pretty,
all of these relationship things that
we start off like a horror movie.
Well that was all sunshine.
Everything. I'm 21 prime of
my life. I get darker ship,
everything's going great.
All right.
The main problem I have though
is she is a big Democrat,
big democratic.
It's promise.
She's a big democratic and
he's a super conservative. Uh,
she's black and I'm almost
as white as you. Oh God,
this is like a fucking bad porno.
She gets upset when I post
political stuff on Facebook,
like pro a pro video of Trump,
but yet she posts all this stuff about
kneeling for flags and Obama is all that,
uh, yeah, dude does this relationship's
not going to fucking less. Uh,
she wouldn't even talk to me when I wore
a Trump shirt. Oh my God. Yeah. It's like,
dude,
like this is,
this is a guy who like sort of saw how
the Nazis were baited into running over
somebody with a car going, well, you
know, there's hatred on both sides.
Um, dude, I really wanted to side
with you, but you know, this is,
this is like astoundingly fucking,
like,
I respect the fact that you like Trump
and all of that shit you want to wear as
t shirts, but your confusion that she
gets upset is a little fucking weird.
Uh,
touches me off.
But I don't want to ruin the whole
relationship over something as dumb as
politics that's too late.
So since you are already in an interracial
relationship and for and for a lot
longer than me, period. What's
your advice? Question Mark?
The lovely mia. It's Nia with an end. Um,
can tell me her 2 cents as well, even
though she'll just side with the chick.
Just kidding. Thanks. And is
always go fuck yourself. Ps.
Tom Brady's the greatest
of all time. Ah Sir. Um,
I gotta be honest with you, like if you
don't understand why she is upset, um,
you'd have to try to put yourself in
her position and then read some of this
shit and some of his opinions I
guess would be the best way to do it.
But I'm like,
you're not just a conservative if
you're were like rocking the t shirt,
like you're all in. You
know what I mean? Like a,
his girlfriend hates when I wear my
swastika tee shirts. Not that deep.
Do you think that's, it's that bad?
I mean he has, he hasn't run like,
I'm going to know mean no,
but I'm just saying
is he like a Trump icy,
like a Hitler light?
Ie
booze would hit Luby was that he's
gotta be like Moonshine. So where's
Trump Yeager?
He's a Yag of body.
Like that's shitty.
Bourbon goes schlog.
Yeah, he's like a Lulu flakes instead
of gold flakes. Yeah. Johnny Walker red.
And there's, there's no, there's
no, yeah, there's no fun.
Okay. And uh, got whatever soft
drink to fucking mixed with it.
What's the worst when you approach this?
What's the worst period of ahead?
Constantly. Yeah. College age. Ah, Shit.
Uh, Milwaukee's best. No.
Warren that or natty bow and there was
no Bohemian was pretty damn bad. Oh yeah.
I always hated was fucking a Bush light.
Bush light was like, Bush itself was
just, yeah, that was just like, yeah,
it was like water. And then they wanted
that town we used to eat. I never,
you know,
something.
I never got into Pabst blue ribbon
because I resented the hipsters that we're
drinking them because it used to be this
blue collar beer that all these fucking
townies drank.
And then all these hipster people
were wearing their a flannel shirts.
Well you know those shirts for awhile,
were they wearing like the gas station
shirt that had somebody else's name on it
where they actually had to do the fucking
job and they funded some thrift shop.
Like my fantasy was that they ran
into the guy who owned the shirt.
They just walked up like,
Hey, I'm Jim. You know, it's,
oh I just needed a shirt and then
he gets the shit kicked out of them.
But most of my fantasies are
violent. Um, my advice is,
uh, to, I don't if get a bunch of empathy.
Uh, I don't know. I don't, I
don't see this thing working.
I just don't see it working. That's
going to be like, cause you guys,
so if you're that far
away from each other,
you're not going to get married and
have kids. Oh yeah. That's like,
yeah, there you'd be fighting over
them politically too. Like, so what?
They're going to be Democrats
or conservatives when they
grow up with a refill.
That's a whole nother can of worms.
Yeah.
So enjoy banging her and uh,
I would while she lets you while she
let you and then I would fucking, yeah,
I would just be like, yeah, but
he's also 21. He doesn't know.
He generally seems like he doesn't
understand unless that was just, you know,
sometimes people just lie and they
writing crazy shit. All right.
Girlfriend drinks too much. Uh, dear bill,
I was telling me you gotta help me
out with the problem I've been having.
I've been living with my
girlfriend for almost a year now.
We are in our mid to late
twenties just for some background.
Everything's going great except for one
thing we worked regular nine to five
type jobs, which means most of
the fun we have is on the weekend.
And like most people,
we tend to lube up on the liquor while
we're out and about or even just staying
in, well, I don't think anything
wrong with, with drinking.
My girlfriend doesn't know her limits
often. She will drink way too much,
too early and ended up passing out or
throwing up though commonly both will
occur. Wow. Yeah. She
doesn't know how to drink.
You've got to pace yourself
out there. A few examples. Uh,
she will insist on watching a
movie after we've had a few drinks.
We finally decide,
uh,
we'll put it on and then after
15 minutes she passes out.
Then I'll have to stop because of
course I can't watch it without her.
Yeah. What we'll teach her a lesson.
Watched the whole movie and be like,
you missed a great one and
in the end the Butler did it.
So lay off the booze cause I'm going
to start fucking doing that to you. Um,
number two,
we went to a hockey game a few weeks
ago and when we got to the arena she
ordered me a beer and herself
to double gin and tonics.
Oh my God. She has a promo. We had
already had a couple of before arriving.
She then proceeded to down both of them
in 10 minutes before the puck drop and
passed out soon after
the hockey game by God.
That's the fucking problem.
I had to drag her up to stand for the
anthem and again when they were honoring
the troops. This is fucking, this
is like a Kristen Wiig character.
Uh,
she then left for the washroom.
That's been one of my favorite scenes
though when she gets fucking wasted on the
plane in bridesmaids and she just,
when she goes [inaudible] the fuck is,
he was walking out, uh, I see.
Then left for the washroom,
but came back with two more doubled
Jen's a hotdog and a bag of popcorn,
which she spilled and blamed it on me.
Oh my gosh.
Sounds like a episode of intervention.
Even if I did do it,
the first thing you're going to
do is snitch on me. All right.
That just took a left turn. But,
uh, get the fuck out of here.
We're supposed to be a team,
but I digress. Sorry for
the rant. Uh, last weekend.
My God, these are all like
bullet pointed. By the way,
in the Uber ride home she preached,
she proceeded to whip out
her tit to try and seduce me.
I told her to put it away because she
was in no condition and I didn't want to
fuck up my Uber rating
passes out. Wait, what?
The passenger gets an Uber Rating.
Oh yeah.
The radio's too for the drivers.
That might actually boosted his rating.
The driver will look back and slows,
looks sloppy to me.
We'd fucking gin and tonic on it. Uh,
anyways, I'm gonna fuck up my Uber a pet.
She passes out 30 seconds later in pukes
in the elevator on the way up to the
apartment.
It didn't make it a lot.
It didn't make a lot of a mess as she was
able to hold it back before I got into
the toilet. Oh my God. This guy's
just truncate the piece de resistance.
Uh, she passed out during the bill
Burroughs show at the Sony Center. Uh,
how do you pass out for that create man
who just came in to entertain us? Uh,
just a pre face. I had an allergic
reaction that morning was toast.
Had a little bit of weed before the
show and I was able to be fully alert.
But yet you are the one that's
falling asleep. Jesus Christ.
This is like the fucking war and peace.
This is like Barfly,
uh, saying all this. However, I have
to admit that I'm no saint either.
I arguably drank much more
than she, Ireland would drink
much more than she does,
but I hold my boobs a
little better than she does.
I probably made her sound
worse than she actually is.
You gotta take it all away.
That going to go back a little.
Now you already begin to
look like a drunken mess.
Yeah, but in truth, she's a wonderful
girlfriend who cooks with math for me.
Cleans to me is very beautiful.
Well in fucking live happily ever after,
which is not three sheets.
She's not puking on the
sheets and as you can tell,
is willing to come to a
hockey game with me. And yes,
she did buy me bill bird
tickets for my birthday.
She is a truly amazing person and
I planned to marry her someday,
but this is just getting out of
hand and I want my weekends back.
Can you do me a favor and turn that
light on my fucking eyes or a shot here?
The Sun's going down here. I'm not trying
to have a romantic podcast with you. Um,
uh, let's see here. I've had conversations
with her before and when she,
she's sober,
she gets it,
but it doesn't stop her when she's drunk
and she will get angry at me when I
tell her she's had enough and I can't
stop her from sneaking off to get secret
drinks with my money.
She feels bad and I honestly feel guilty
writing this to you and she is truly
amazing.
I feel like he wrote the first half and
then she walked into the room and is
looking over his shoulder.
Um,
but it's tough not only for me,
but I know this is not easy on her,
but some to her body sometimes as well.
I just wanted her to be all right
and for us to be able to have a good,
healthy time.
I'm not quite sure what to do here.
Am I right to tell her that
she's got to take it easy,
particularly when we go out
because it seems to be working.
Do I have to set a better example and
drink less, if at all? Yeah. I mean,
if she's a fucking boots
town, maybe, uh, maybe both.
Maybe both. Try to, uh,
drink a little bit less.
She might be one of those people,
you know, where once she has a kid,
she'll just fucking knock
all that shit off. Or
Oh God,
I could just drive a rover the completely
where she just stays hammered all the
time.
Yeah. You'll have a drunken
baby, you know, coming out,
fucking stop emailing and Bill
Byrd started emailing drew Pinsky
it's
kid comes out dressed like foster Brooks,
um,
to do a fucking,
I love Boston Brooks run the
simulated drunk comedian. Oh yeah.
It was fucking hilarious.
And He, uh, and he never
really drank. Yeah. The way
I know
he had it down to like do,
that's back when like being an alcoholic
was like funny, right. This is how,
this is how much I have to be careful
though is talking about all that drinking
made me want to drink.
Like I love it. I fucking,
I hate how it makes me feel though
now. So I kinda, I just lay off
Craig.
Craig Robinson didn't drink for a year
and then we just had drinks and Arizona
this past weekend. We felt like trashed
both mornings that we drink. Yeah.
And so he was like, yeah, I thought
I was back after taking a year off.
I thought it was back, but I'm good on
drinking. I think I was like, yeah man,
I don't feel good either.
I had a headache every day.
It's an age thing. Like
it's really, that's a young
person thing. Like is it like
we had fun. We were down to like we'd
do those shows, those theater shows.
We would go to like the cigar
bars have a drink with cigars.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. No, I, I
still, I think what I, I'm, I
my drinking may be, we'll be,
is like a,
this year when I go on the road,
I think like if I go up for three
days, like that Middle Day, yeah.
Not the first night because I
traveled and not the, not, you know,
the night before I have to go to the
airport, but just that in the middle one,
finding a good place. Um, I dunno if that,
that might be the, uh, that
might be the way I'll do it.
You know what I went to last night?
Oh my God,
I went to this fucking
this eighties, like, uh,
all these bands, this crazy
fucking lineup was, um,
the real bedrooms attributed
them. No, it was like tutor was,
uh, what was it? Ah, like
drama Rama and with them.
Holy Shit. I think, I can't remember
the song is that flock of Seagulls,
the Romantics, they were all
really their tone. Loke oh my God.
Fucking the violent femmes Melly Mel
than the furious five for his phone.
Uh, and boy George closed. No Way. It
was fucking, it was, that was this,
this was at, uh, the Microsoft
theater, which used to be the Nokia,
me and Nia went down there and, um, I,
it was fucking awesome,
but I learned a lot about show business
watching those p you could tell like who
is sick of singing their hits. And it was
also like, fuck this, I'm bringing it.
And then I also learned, you
know, watching, you know,
he got to take care of yourself.
I have a story about that
because I swear to God, Dude,
if you see a band that let themselves go,
it's like depressing on like yours
because you love them and they look like
shit. And then all you're thinking
is like, oh my God, I'm all,
I'm fucking 20 years older than he
was when he put that song out a fuck.
We're all gonna die.
But when you just see a band come out
and they kept themselves in shape and
they're fucking killing it as much as
they are older, it's, it's like, uh,
like I'm not gonna name names, but I saw
one band that made me think like, dude,
I'm never drinking again.
And then I when saw the violent femmes
like two pages came out and with just a
fucking tight sick aspect, like
I watched them, I was like, man,
I want to go play drums. I want
to practice. I want to get better.
Like there was nothing like
negative about watching them.
They just came out and find they for,
they went on after uh,
Melly Mel in in a 35 who fucking killed
and you couldn't be more of a different
band, like literally up to
the stage would just turned.
Oh yeah, that's bad. As I did the
I heart radio music festival thing,
they have like the band,
the stage of rotate one 80,
and then they'd have the band and then
they'd do the set dressing behind and
then it would keep turning through ios.
I loved it. I loved that. They
get like a down in Anaheim,
they had it in like salt and pepper
was on in a couple of people.
It was fucking nuts.
It was,
he just knocked out like 10 of the
bands that I should have seen back then.
And uh, you know, they all sounded great.
There was just, well I'll tell you off.
It was just one person that I looked
at and it was just like my God,
but he was still singing great.
But it's just like fuck dude.
Right. See we saw cameo like
six months ago down. Uh,
I can't remember what it was like by
the water somewhere here in La and Roger
Troutman. I remember Roger Blackmun,
wasn't it? Yeah. What songs does he say?
Um, Shay's all BRAC. Oh yeah. House. Okay.
Of all those dude, he came, you know,
cause he used to come out in like
leather chaps and a cup, you know,
it's the 70s fucking coke spoon around
his neck and dude, he's still doing this.
Like he can't, he can't win
the belly. And I'm like, oh,
not bad. Hips and knees and
it's still wearing a company.
It was like his leather pants in the
back of look like the diaper and he would
come out and he does like,
dude was a little like trying to be
sexy and wrote swivel his hips up.
My wife has died laughing. She was
like, he needs to fucking stop. Stop,
stop doing that company.
Even even,
even when you keep yourself in shape
and he was not in shape, you as you,
but you it,
you can't do that sexy shit.
And I'm telling you that is a self
involved baby boomer thing that is being
passed down.
Like do Madonna is an unfucking
believable shame for her fucking age.
But when she starts
twerking, it's just like, ah,
mom,
what are you doing right?
Can't. Yeah. And then
it's like the older guy,
which you got to do is you got to like,
uh, I sucked to de Rosa about this.
You know, you gotta dress like Dana
White, right when you get older,
right? Like Dana White is roughly my age.
Dana White, you know, he wears as suit,
he ways to college. Sure doesn't have
the title, the title, rather than,
so he's a little bit relaxed, but he's
dressed like he doesn't look like a creep,
you know what I mean? But if he was
to show up, you know what I mean?
I'm not just putting it on him, just
saying that, that fucking look, just,
you take a guy the same age,
my fucking age,
and you're going to try to
fucking pull off like a tank top.
Like even like when you watch these,
these, those P90x things, right.
And the old guys that are working at a
58 year old guys with the ABS, it's like,
dude,
amazing putting your fucking shirt on
because there's nothing they could do for
the loss of Alaska density
in your fucking skin. Yeah.
You're decomposing in front of me.
Yeah.
She'd be sitting in a giant fruit bowl.
Little little fruit flies flying around
you. So I learned a lot. That guy watched,
uh,
those bands and it was the people that
we're comfortable with their age and kept
himself in shape and came out and we're
having a good fucking time. Oh yeah.
It was just like, aw man,
this is fucking granular.
Like you just were really excited.
But if they came out like you know,
they'd fucking this,
this still fucking partying.
Like you know Keith Richards back in
the day and then they're coming to and
you're going to still wear
like leather and shit bro. Um,
HD net have this concert series a
couple of years ago and there were,
so these commercials for them for the
concert series and they would show they
show at Steppenwolf.
Right? You don't know,
you can are gonna kill me.
Then again.
And then that middle section that goes
on for fucking ever memories used to work
in a warehouse.
That whole fucking the psychedelic
part. Yeah, it goes on for two.
Sorry I interrupted your story.
But they would show like them playing
concerts back in like the 70s and there'll
be jam packed arena
and people going crazy,
the crowd and then they show him now like
it was smashed cups from then to now.
Oh now they're playing on like
an outdoor stage tire audience.
Oh,
only about 300 people are sitting on this
lawn in like lawn chairs and I'm like,
I know because we're all too well.
Yeah.
All the people that love him
back then are old now too.
So it was like watching people perform at
like shady acres, retirement community.
I know, but those guys are like 70 I
know it's fucking, I'm sure that guide,
the band still sounds
great and everything,
but it's gotta be weird having
fun with it. Just like fuck,
we still have to make money. Only
one. A lot of those guys they got,
they got so stolen from and
just completely ripped off
and then you add that if
somebody got divorced and shit, yeah,
you're going to be singing that song. Ugh.
I just realized I cross my legs wearing
slippers in front of you. I'm sorry.
Those are great celebrities.
Great slippers.
Now I finally bought some new socks and
I just wanna I wanna to try to keep them
white for a lot of things for you.
I bought,
that's why I wear black socks all that.
Well,
I can't wear black socks if I have on like
dark sneakers though. Why not? I mean,
I can't wear white socks
with dark sneakers now if,
I'm sorry if I have white sneakers,
I need white socks. Really? Yeah,
I guess. Yeah, I have mostly
white sneakers. No offense.
Um, no, but I think a lot of those guys
that, that's what ends up happening.
So I think the way to do it is,
and I haven't figured out
how to get into the game yet,
is you get to a certain point when you're,
the height of your, your earning power.
I think you should already be planning
your graceful exit from this business
because it's so broad strategy.
So I think rather than going out and buy,
buying flashy shit,
fucking hovercraft and all the
dumb shit that that art is by,
by start buying rentals, man rental
units, I'm not buying a helicopter.
I'd love to, but I, I can't, uh,
I can't justify like maintaining it to
fucking play this. I got a kid now, man.
I came from smash cut
[inaudible] the,
you know what's cool is I'm doing
Irvine on Tuesday and Wednesday.
You know that's like, you know, it's
like two hours of traffic. Oh to, yeah,
I'm renting a little 22 I'll blah
blah blah blah. Up Bubba. Bob.
Go right over it in like 20 minutes.
That was fucking awesome. It is us. Yeah.
Oh my God dude.
Fuck five.
I did my time. I did my, I'm
not fucking do it. Am I me yet?
Another comedian talking
about how horrific the traffic
was during the first 10
minutes. How about I go up there and be
the comic who's in a good mood, right?
That's what people are coming. Outflows.
10 minute helicopter ride. Oh yeah,
that's fantastic. Oh right up in
fucking over it. And this is the thing,
I'd like to look at the parking structure
on the roof of the Improv. Now, um,
we're trying to find,
you got to call up.
It's like every time you
fly you learn something.
So I'm learning this time is like,
they'll have this,
all these helipads so you can
even go beyond the airports.
Cause I'm thinking like
John Wayne is close by,
but then there's another
one that's even closer,
but then there's like these helipads
on top of buildings and all were,
I'll just all around it.
But you have to,
you just have to call him and tell him you
go fly down a solo. No, no, no, no, no.
I don't have confidence to fly at night.
I fly solo during the day,
but at night it's just a
whole different ballgame.
And I'll never forget one night doing a
night flight. I was with an instructor.
And how you transition,
uh,
the airspace at lax is either you fly
under, you're not underneath it, but you,
you're, you're along the coastline
flying like a hundred feet off the water,
which is awesome and scary as shit.
Um,
and or you fly over [inaudible]
over like those glow stick things.
Like, you know, I think it's like a 2000,
I've only done it once like 2000
feet or above. So with night,
we flew over over the
[inaudible] and you know,
it's fucking freaky because there's all
these jets coming in that if you're at
the same altitude altitude t-bone, you
said we're flying. And I go, yeah man,
I go to the cow pig,
that end, that's crazy.
And how big these planes are landing
here? And he just goes, yeah,
there's one right there.
And it was like almost underneath us.
But because when you're looking down and
there's not a lot of streetlights and
just the lights from the city, I didn't
see like a fucking, you know, holy seven,
49, seven 40, say whatever
the fuck they fly. Now,
I don't know what the numbers are anymore
was like going right underneath this
and I was just like, wow, you didn't
see that? No, but he did this the right,
this is when I was getting my license,
so I didn't know how to,
to look for Shit and everything.
So night flying isn't entirely,
entirely different games. So,
uh, I'll be flying down, um,
with one of my instructors. So, but
if it was, if it was like the, uh,
if it was the fucking summertime though,
but every time, every time it's going to,
by the end of the show
it's going to be dark out.
But that is a goal of mine
who's I would love to fly solo.
Now let me ask you this, how much does
it cost? It will cost you to do that.
It will fly down to, you have to
like run through vehicle and peds.
It's like 300 bucks. I mean it's,
it's a decent amount of money,
but it's also like that bad though.
It's not just going to close.
[inaudible] grown, but no, no, no, no, no,
no, no, no, no, no, no, nothing like that.
It's like 300 bucks and then,
uh,
and it's fun and then I get another,
like I'll get like another,
I'm going to get another two hours
under my belt flying at night. And uh,
I got this killer fucking
instructor right now.
My auto rotations are the
best they've ever been,
where they basically will fly around now
when he just sorta like he'll just out
of know what go,
you know,
engine failure and then you just have
to pick a fucking spot. And you know,
you just,
I mean we don't take it all the way down
to the ground and I land on somebody's
fucking front yard. But
um, I have learned so much,
I always had great instructors,
but this guy that I have now is,
is really got my confidence
back up again where, um,
for me to go solo and everything would be,
you know,
I would have the confidence to do
it, but I like, but what's good is I,
I'm super fucking cautious. I'm
not one of those people, you know,
with the fucking nine oh two one
oh look on my face, you know,
show up with like a fucking sculptures
now. But there's a lot of people that get,
they get their a,
they get their license and once they get
the license they stopped the training
and because it got it well cause they
know how to fly. And then, you know,
and then you just, they just started
flying around. Oh my God. Yeah.
So did you fly your parents? Yeah. Then
when they came out here and visit it.
But I also did that with
like an instructor and that
was a will the impress your
parents blown away that a,
they definitely day had a good time and
they are very conservative people. So,
you know,
sometimes you don't necessarily know
what they're thinking or going crazy.
They won't go crazy. They were just like
lovely. That was nice. I was very, uh,
very in trouble.
I was exhilarated.
I heart is beating out of
my chest right now. Um, no,
my, my dad, uh, had a pilot's license.
It has a positive cause once you get it.
So like he knows other,
no, he had fixed wing,
so he knew a lot of the shit
that was going on. So, uh,
you know,
but my mother thought it was awesome.
She loves it and wasn't scared at all.
My Dad, I think because he had a license,
understood that probably more of the
danger of it and that type of shit.
So he probably thought it was a little
squirrely when we will 100 feet off the
fucking water flying under the, you
know, the jets or whatever. But, uh,
I'd say it's one of the great things
that I've done in my fucking adult life.
And, um, I don't know, but we're
not here to talk about make,
we're here to talk about you.
We've already done an hour and 15
minutes just like that. Uh, Hey, can I,
can I come down the 90th tape
dude or nothing more? Okay.
All right. Well, some people, you
know, like me, I'd be like, no,
I don't want anybody there.
Nobody. I fucking know.
So it's just one more thing for me to
think about. We're going to do like,
you know, I'm going to come on, I'm
going to be brought from all stays out.
Another comedian opening for me to gun
and Frankie quiñones who does the Cholo
fit videos and he usually
towards the Craig and I,
and so I'm going to have someone
bring me on stage from offstage.
You got that fucking voice. Oh yeah. I'll
definitely do it. I'll definitely do it.
Yeah, I'll just double check my schedule.
I'm 99% sure I'm in town. Right.
And Go February 11th, February
11th Sunday Day. Yeah.
What have I got?
I got reno,
I got Santa Barbara and then it gets
something at the Patrice O'Neal benefit
towards the young month.
Oh Man. Um, let's try that.
I met Patrice was mom and sister with
you. That was, that was fucking amazing.
Oh yeah, that was great. A lot of the
best. They're the best. Hey, so I'll uh,
I'll tell you this when you do
soundcheck. Yeah, just make sure,
speaking of Patrice, cause
I haven't, one time he,
he did some taping and the sound wasn't
right and when it came time for him to
do his taping, you know, they thought he
was a pain in the ass, but he was like,
this sound isn't right.
And he was like,
I want to be the loudest
thing in the room,
so make sure your monitors so you know,
you gotta just make sure that is right.
That's fucking right. Then it's like,
yeah, you light saber is totally on
and you know, you know that deal.
If you get up there and you can't fucking
hear yourself and God knows when you
go to tape, there's always somebody
who fucks something like that. Oh,
I thought it'd be good to just have
the sound way down, you know? Um,
just make sure all of that shits right
and then go to school up there and kill
it. Oh yeah. That's the plan.
I've never seen you so fucking nervous.
I'm not nervous. I'm just like you.
I'm anxious and I know you are going to
be great. If you were doing it tonight,
I could tell this whole
podcast. Yeah. We'll also,
I don't want to be loved because I
know your daughter's leave it. Okay.
I know dude.
And I'm tired and a little
bit hung over other than that.
But other than that and a little
bit, yeah, I always wanted like this.
Whenever I have one of those coming up,
I just feel like just can you just bring
me up now in my slippers so I just go
out there and just fuck it. Just do it.
The waiting is the worst part, right?
That's the worst. All right,
well that's the podcast, dude.
I'm so site and I can't wait to do this.
I can't wait to see it and I can't
wait to promote the hell out of it.
And I can't wait to see you finally
getting your name out there and everybody
knowing how fucking hilarious she need
this more than this in the world, right?
You've got four fucking
kids. They're going to be in
college at some point, right?
You're going to need this
story out of college.
So I know you've got a nice spread
their rights in a 24 to seven. Yeah.
2047 they go 24, seven.
They're all right, man. Todd,
rex, everybody once again, a
view different walking into yeah,
the satellite la.com for tickets.
Uh, definitely be tweeting this out.
Um, February 11th. It's a Sunday,
seven 30 and nine 30 in silver lake,
Los Angeles. It's the weekend
after the Superbowl. So you know,
you're gonna be all depressed at
football is over for another six months.
Come on out and see one of
the best comics. I know. All
right. That's the podcast.
Go fuck yourselves. I'll check in
on you on Thursday, you know? Geez.