like a boss.
Um,
speaking of which actually watched this
documentary my wife take was talking to
that,
the charisma of Adolf Hitler on PBS.
And it was this fascinating thing how
they talked about just what is charisma.
Charisma does not exist
on its own in anyone.
It exists only in an interaction between
an individual and an audience and
individual like Hitler. He was telling
the audience what they wanted to hear,
you know,
and they had this whole thing was
saying how like Hitler could not,
I had just no functioning
relationships with anybody one on one,
but he just crushed it in front of a
crowd and how he would make them wait and
all of that shit is fucking hilarious.
Like he's waiting to start his speech.
Everyone's cheering and he's just
standing there until they're dead silent.
You know,
Hitler Talk to the German Nation as
chancellor on the 10th of February,
1933 thousands were in the hall,
in front of him,
and millions were listening on radio,
but Hitler made them all wait.
You reminded me one time,
Nia took,
I took Nia to go see Erika Badu and she
comes out and everyone wants you to sing,
and she spends the first five minutes
just walking around lighting the incense.
So I'm watching Hitler, Gosh, she got this
from Hitler to the same fucking thing.
Everybody's, I go, Whoa, we
need to behave ourselves,
and then the performance will begin.
But they had all these creepy
fucking speeches that he was getting.
He was doing this thing where he was
going, there's a group of people among us
who
can basically live anywhere.
They do business anywhere.
It doesn't matter them to them. They
live in Paris. Next month, they'll live,
they'll live in fucking
Vienna. Then they'll live here
and blah, blah, blah, blah,
blah, with no ties to that hole, and
he just keeps spoon feeding them.
Do you know he won't come out and say it,
this group of people,
because they have no
attachment to Germany,
you know, but blah, blah, blah, blah.
Then finally sent me, the crowd goes,
Joe yelled out,
Jews and it learned,
never addressed it,
and then just kept going.
I believe
[inaudible]
[inaudible] and it was, I you have
to see this to it is the creepiest,
absolutely, absolutely creepy fucking
thing I've ever seen in my life. And then,
uh,
but I would,
I would be lying to you if I didn't tell
you that I learned some things as far
as performance in front of a crowd.
I mean, you got to give it up.
The guy was a beast. I don't, I don't
even remotely agree with the guys message.
But Jesus Christ,
the guys going out in front of a crowd,
you know,
a Kevin Hart size fucking crowd
and doesn't say a fucking word.
He doesn't get to do as the exact
opposite of the clippers game :
Makes some noise.
Jesus Christ.
Okay.
Hitler's got to come back and start
running the NBA there. I said it,
I said if he can just get past the fact
that 99% of the players are African
American, I think he could do
some great things for the league.
I think he quieted down.
Alright, sorry. Anyways,
so I will be going to eastern Europe.
That's what I was trying to say.
Or Europe in general. The
UK. There we go. All right.
The Kabbalah reading mother fucker.
Get the fuck out of my house.
Yeah.
See this?
That means not welcomed.