Hey, what's going on? It's Bill Burr and
it's time for the Thursday afternoon.
Just before Friday,
Monday morning podcast and
ahhh
just checking in on you.
Just seeing how your weeks go in,
how your life is,
how you're feeling this day.
Um, uh, I'm not, I don't
know. I don't, you know,
you know I was supposed to get my
Invisalign off yesterday. Right.
I was all excited.
The Shit was supposed to take 16 weeks
and because I wore them like a fucking
lunatic,
basically 24 seven occasion,
I'd smoke a cigar or I do is set up.
I did a long set and I didn't feel
like spitting all over the stage.
I would take them up,
but a lot of times it just left him in
one time I left him and when I smoked a
cigar that was a bad move.
Bad move.
I to sit there and brush and for like
an hour so they wouldn't be fucking all
brown.
So the last time I saw my
dentist he's like, Oh gee.
Willikers it would wear on him so much.
I think we'll be done by the 13th week.
And I was like,
you've gotta be kidding me. This is
a brand. I tried not to get excited.
I tried to be like, okay, well
I'm supposed to be, you know,
just mentally just keeping prepared for
the end of March when these things are
going to be off. So anyway,
so I go to the dentist, right?
And I'm wearing them and I'm wearing
them and I'm driving over, I'm wearing,
I'm chewing on the stupid sponge to make
sure the fucking trays all the way down
and all of that shit.
So I show up and he,
you know, takes the things off. He's
all, he's all good. Oh man, he's, wow.
You really would. You'd see when
you comply, blah, blah, blah, blah.
Everything's good. And I'm sitting
there going, don't get excited.
Don't cause he cause kid comes to however,
however we have two fucking weeks.
I was waiting for that shit. Right?
But he doesn't, he goes, he, these still
good enough to take them off today.
I was like, you gotta be kidding
me. I did it. Fucking did it.
This is like going into the fucking
Stanley Cup playoffs. All right. And,
and just sweeping everybody. See you
play like fucking, I dunno, we'll see a,
if you went seven games times
four, that's 12 Bubba, Bubba,
28 fucking games or
you could just play 16.
I felt like I just played 16 games.
Fresh is a fucking daisy.
I'm ready to go another round. You already
handed me the trophy, right? So I said,
all right, so he seats taken the
fucking clips off or whatever.
He's filing them down and shit.
And he's like, uh, I go, okay.
So on ally you have to do now is just
where this tray at night when I sleep for
the rest of my life. So they don't go
back, which is no big deal. I'm asleep.
The fuck, do I care?
Right? He goes, no, no.
Uh, this final tray, you have to
wear this for the next three months.
And then we give you the overnight
train and it's just like,
where's that in your initial pitch?
I still would have fucking done it,
but why are you full?
Just tear the bandaid off.
I could've just mentally
got myself but go right,
the next six months of
my life is going to suck.
You've got me all excited about 16
weeks and then 13 and then it's going to
happen. And then, oh
by the way, by the way,
here's another three months onto your
sentence. You're not out yet. Oh,
fucking bugged me. You know,
cause you know what it was.
Cause when he went initially
went to sell it to me,
he was too afraid that if you told
me I was going to be six months,
that I wasn't going to do
it. That's basically what it
is. That, you know, I get it.
Capitalism,
it's sales.
I I really wanted to, I didn't
say anything. I, you know,
what are you gonna do you?
The other day I got fucking
straight teeth and made it works.
The shit definitely works. I am
thrilled. I am elated with it. I just,
you know what I mean?
That's like something your wife does,
Bill. Is there anything
in the world, Bill,
that you can't turn around and blame
women for? All right, you're right.
I'm being emotional.
Being a cunt.
Yeah.
Fucking three more months. I
turned 53 months. You know,
you think I want to have fucking braces.
I don't know about you,
but that's not what of mine.
That's not one of my life's goals.
MMM.
So anyways, so now what's going on
is he took the fucking hooks off my,
I'm just giving you guys the blow by
blow. This guy's a great dentist. Okay.
You know,
could have been a little
more straightforward about
how long this was going to
fucking take. You know, just
dump the bowl over my head.
Stuff like taking a little spoonfuls
and putting in my mother's head. Okay,
can you handle that
anyways?
MMM.
I ain't know what the
fuck does he notices?
So now the hooks are
off these fucking things
and uh, this is like getting out of jail
cause you just don't get out of jail.
They go from maximum to
like medium to minimum two.
You're living in some guy's fucking
house and you can go out and go get a
fucking Bagel and you got to come
back and report to somebody. This is,
this is how the Invisalign's going down.
Um,
I am in the,
uh,
the halfway house or the fucking minimum
security building of this shit now,
the three months, whatever.
I don't even fucking notice
him. I'm, I'm Kinda over it.
I did have two event I did at the vent
on the podcast about it, but it's,
it's just, you fucking know it. Just,
just tell me what I'm in
for so I can prepare for it.
It's like one of those fucking movies
while you're sitting. Did you guide them?
Cubicle Odesk and you finished a
stack of papers. You're like, ah,
you fucking put your foot up on a desk.
Guy Comes back with
another stack of papers,
you know.
Anyways, any wish, um, oh fucking, uh,
Billy Boston Bruin
bandwagon is jumping on.
I've watched the last three
games to be with you. I missed,
I turned on the last Bruins game or you
know, I got a kid now, so I do what I can.
All right. I put the game on when
it was four to one. All right.
I watched a beat the
Black Hawks on Saturday.
I watched him lose on Sunday and on.
I put the game on,
it was David down four to one. I was like,
Jesus Christ, every time I fuck a week,
they do nothing. But when, whenever I
turn them on, they fucking loose. And um,
so I got the game on.
You don't medium volume.
I'm in the kitchen with my beautiful
daughter and I'm making her some dinner.
I came in with the hell I meda,
she likes these meatballs, right?
With the vegetables in that type of stuff.
And now what are we trying to
keep her away from? Uh, you know,
all the sugar in that type of shit.
However, you know, occasionally, you know,
my kid's not gonna not have McDonald's.
You know what I mean?
I'm not going to take it to that
level where the kid is like, oh,
can I have some dessert?
And be like, yeah, here's a
Kiwi or some shit like that,
even though you probably should do that.
I don't know.
MMM.
So anyways, I, I have the game. I'm,
and I'm out in the kitchen and then
I just heard Jack Edwards going crazy
three goals at 77 seconds.
So I come running in like what the fuck?
What the fuck just happened?
Long story short,
the Bruins scored.
They would that they scored five goals
in the third period to win six to five.
The last one was an empty Magda.
MMM.
They scored him so fast.
I don't even know who fucking scored up.
I can't even remember who the hell
scored them pasta knock out one of them.
Uh,
but I do know that we also lost like
three guys got hurt during the game.
Tory crew to brusque and fucking today.
No Chara but I,
I looked at the replay
because I missed those place.
They didn't look a sitting on my couch
and not having to endure the pain.
They didn't look too bad.
Um,
Chara went down like someone in a public
skating rink is what that looked like.
And then he just slid into the board.
Looks like he hit his shoulder.
He was walking off fine.
You know when he was off the ice
and he was going through the tunnel,
he seemed all right.
Granted,
he's also like nine feet tall
and can do like over 40 pull ups,
which makes no fucking sense at 40,
41 years of age.
It's easy for the little guys because
they don't have to travel as far.
But to bring that giant body and all
the way the fuck down, it's like,
it's like the little guys going
up like two, two steps in. He's,
he's gotta run up like nine flights
of stairs every time he does. It's,
it's unreal. So he's tough as
nails. I think he'll be back.
I don't know what happened at Tory crude
and, uh, Debra's hopefully have by just,
I dunno,
got a mild sort of a fountain,
his brain around a little
bit. But, uh, anyways,
we're playing the Florida panthers
tonight, seven 34 30 my time,
seven 30 east coast time.
And the panthers fight the most,
have the most fighting
majors in the NHL this year.
And it's like some pathetically
low number. I think they're in the,
they've had like 20 fighting majors.
They average of fight, like basically,
you know, every three
games. Um, it's just,
it's just completely out of the fucking
league and it sucks. But granted,
I'm not the guy who, I
don't have to fight, right.
I don't have to walk around dealing with
the concussions and all of that shit.
But, you know, just as a fan, I
miss it. So they got them on, uh,
they got them today, Thursday, and
then Saturday when I'm up in, uh,
Ontario, they got the lightning, so they
got some big games coming up Monday.
The blue jackets,
I don't even know how they're doing
because I haven't been watching anything,
but I'm back.
I'm back on fucking bored here.
Um, a lot of new faces and
shit. But, um, you know,
like I said, I've watched so
many games in the last 10 years,
the 820 regular season games,
I bet I saw at least, you know,
500 of them.
So I missed like the last fucking
60 that they had this year.
Essentially. I only saw maybe five
games this year. Uh, it's embarrassing,
but uh, which sucks because I watched
them totally dismantled a team,
you know, four years ago or something. And
go all the way back down to rebuilding.
And I was like,
I'm going to watch this whole rebuild
in this year when it all fucking came
together. Uh, I mean, what
am I complaining about? Oh,
I had to go and become a dad,
which is the most amazing
fucking thing ever. Um,
my little one's starting to try to
run now, which is hilarious. Um,
and also we've been
doing this thing where a,
when she's done with the toy and then
she wants to play with something else,
she has to put away the other
toy and she just has it down.
She likes it cause we applaud
every time she puts some way.
She's playing with these giant Lego's
today and we, and she wanted that.
She wanted to have this
bag of like, uh, you know,
multicolored fucking little like, yeah,
they almost look like ping pong balls,
right? She wants to go play with those
fucking things. So I was just like,
all right, well you got to put
away the Lego blocks first.
So she starts putting them away and I'm
applauding on everyone that she does.
And then there's two stuck
together and she fucking,
she pulled them apart before she put
them away. And as a parent right there,
you're like, oh my God, my kid
is a genius. You know, like,
like you have Einstein is a
kid rather than, it was a, uh,
a pretty logical step that they were just
able to make, but it's still thrilling.
Everything is fucking
thrilling. So anyways, um,
this morning I go outside,
right?
I play a little game on Thursday
when the trash comes out. Um,
is I'm always listening for the
garbage truck. All right. Because, um,
now that I don't have a
dog, I mean, I still do.
It's still technically my dog and she's
in town this week and I'd been taking
her on these long hikes every day.
It's been awesome. She looks great,
she just looks great and
she's so freaking happy.
And I told you for the
first time in her life,
she has another dog that she's friends
with, which she never did. You know,
she was never in that mindset when someone
with my limited skill set at or she
tried to fucking you, she usually
ignored bigger dogs and then little dogs,
not little dogs would bark at
her and she would ignore them.
And then bigger dogs, she would also
ignore them until they started some shit.
You know, I believe in the hip
hop community that's known as, uh,
don't start. Nothing, won't be nothing.
I believe that that's where my dog,
her mindset was from.
So anyways,
but I always fucking hated is
when the trash is out the barrels,
once they empty the fucking, that the
trash truck comes by the garbage truck,
if you will empties the fucking thing out.
You have basically about a minute,
when you live in Los [inaudible] before
some fucking dog on and [inaudible]
comes by and takes a shit bag and throws
in a year, you're, uh, you're trashed out.
Which I don't necessarily give a shit
this time of year because it's cold out.
But during the hot months,
you know to have some statement bag of
fucking Shit marinating in your thing.
That's not even from your own dog.
It's so it's a little annoying.
I appreciate you keeping the
city fucking clean. But the,
there is something about
that that is just a little,
it's a little fucking annoying.
So this morning I,
I've been hearing phantom garbage trucks
had been out there like nine times.
I only put away the recycling and a, I
got a feeling while I'm doing the podcast,
I'm going to hear this fucking
thing coming up the street.
I'm gonna tell you right now, if I
do, I'm, I'm throwing down the mic.
I'm going to go out there and get in
and put that thing back inside. But um,
I got a bunch of shit that I got handled.
I am back on Instagram.
[inaudible] everybody, I got to get
the check next to my fucking name.
So it's verified cause I guess there's
some people in person hating me,
which is really flattering.
Um,
I have not been on there since 2012.
Instagram was not something
that I gravitated towards,
but everybody keeps telling me, you
got to get on it. You got to get on it.
And I was sick of fighting the UK's there
and a, so I'm going to get back on it,
I guess. Um, it's been six years
since I've been away. Okay.
It feels like I've had Invisalign on
for fucking 12 years at this point now.
It hasn't been that bad is
as he had been that bad.
It's just that I got fucking
excited that it was over.
Yeah.
Honey, we done. I'm going to blame
women again and we'd done this is it,
this is the last store and then,
oh,
do I do with this one claim to
want to look at some cosmetics.
Asshole.
Here's a question.
Why don't they have bars at malls?
Yeah.
You know, I guess they do the
kind of like sports bars and shit.
Yeah.
I'm going to go into, hey, what are you
going honey? Take all the time you need.
I'm going to go in here and get
fucking loaded. Okay. I will,
I will do my best to help you with
the bags of shit that you don't need,
that you're going to be carrying
out and then you're driving home.
How does that sound?
Okay.
Well I wanted,
that's the thing does she does.
So what's the exact thing
that makes him a great mother?
Makes them an annoying partner.
It's just like,
just go do something by yourself.
Stop dragging me.
Why am I being such a jerk?
Because of my fucking Invisalign.
I like hanging out with my wife and I've
mentioned before when I didn't have the
hope that my Invisalign
was being taken off,
that I actually enjoy going to the mall
with my wife and kid there. I said it.
Um,
all right.
Anyways, I'm starting to understand tea
by the way. Okay. I never understood it.
It's like it's hot as fuck. It Burns
your tongue. This isn't relaxing.
It's like no stupid. It's hot as fuck. So
it activates what's ever in the tea bag.
And then once that's done,
you then take the fucking tea bag out
and you throw it out like an Englishman.
All right?
You don't keep if you don't leave it in
there like from sloppy American like me.
You take that out and you
let it fucking cool down.
Now that everything's been accurate,
activate and then you drink it.
But the problem is is you've
just ordered a tea. That's fine.
But if you've got something else coming
by the time the fucking thing cools down
your, your, your,
your little Danish or whatever the
hell you ordered is already there.
Your crumpet what the fuck is a crumpet?
Is that a biscuit and biscuits?
A cookie over there,
right?
Crump.
Oh that's what the C strumpet crumpet
Oh, it's an English muffin. Uh,
fuck out of here. That's all it
is. Teen Krumpit I never, you know,
it's funny cause you don't need long.
I've been saying that.
I had no idea who was always picked a
little fucking round like Pale looking
rich crack.
How to make crumpets
BBC good food and air.
Air Doesn't like a good it
with their fucking, you know,
nobody to a fucking crumble with this
shit. Right. That's just something,
by the way,
has there ever not been an upbeat
chef and they always play like that.
Everything's gonna be
okay. Music, you know,
flour, salt and sugar. Some Oregano,
some tomatoes.
Okay. Stirring it all the time.
He put it, I could do this shit.
I didn't know I can make
my own English muffins.
Is this like Philly cheese steak where
you don't say Philly cheese steak.
When you just say cheese steak.
When you're in England,
you don't say English muffin. You
don't even say muffin. You said crumpet
Oh God, this woman is either
terrible or unbelievable in bed.
I don't know why. I just
thought that, oh, she's,
she's into the culinary arts.
You know, she figured, you know,
she's in touch with something. Who
knows? You know, sometimes people,
they actually are given one
talent. Sometimes it just, it's an,
it's an overall philosophy
that goes through.
Um, all right. Let me read a
little bit of advertising here. Uh,
then I'll talk about my pathetic attempts
to try to fucking learn this song for
the Goddamn comedy jam. It has
double bass in it. And, uh,
I haven't even really been
noticing, but like, um,
I'm left handed and I'm right handed at
the same time and that's fucking with my
double bass playing because sometimes
I have a tendency to lead with my left
foot. Other Times I have a tendency
to lead with my right foot.
You know, like if you're
going to do like a, uh,
like booms up at the back,
right,
whatever that is a fucking triplet right
before the snare hit where it's going
to be like right left, right or left,
right, left. I always go left right,
left.
I kind of feel like it's,
it's like if it's on the offbeat or
something like that, if it's on, you know,
if it's on one and two and three and
four and that should be right foot.
And if it's on the other ones,
I'm going left foot.
Right. I don't know. I have no idea.
But all I know was I'm trying to learn
this fucking song and the crashes on the
offbeat and I do that with my right foot.
And then I think what I was doing,
I was,
when I was playing it up to speed and I
was just having fun and I didn't think
anybody was,
I was actually going to play it in front
of people and they were going to watch
me.
I think I was actually
playing left foot lead.
But then when I sat
down and broke it down,
I flipped it and I went from being able
to play it to up to temple to drop in
like 30 bpms. And I'm like,
what the fuck is going on?
And I have to have this song down
in like a week or so. So, um,
but I got the drum room now, so
I've just been, uh, you know,
something I learned from,
uh, Mike Johnston lessons,
which was a rather than practicing
at your limit to go down 10,
15,
even 20 bpms and just stay there for
like 10 minutes of really focused fucking
practice down combined and everything
shit that Davey Lynch taught me.
I just kind of combine everything that
makes sense. And I've been able to,
to start, you know, going
back up again and, uh,
I gotta tell you,
I don't know why the fuck I avoided
double bass drum and for so fucking long,
it's, it's awesome. It's incredible.
And then all of this shit that I always
loved but wouldn't even attempt to play
along to Primus, uh, Pan Tara,
all those p bands that I love,
um,
all of a sudden it's just like,
oh,
I kind of understand what's
happening right here. I mean,
I can't play it up to speed,
but it gives me somewhere to go.
And I remember I listened to a,
one of those lamb of God alums back in
the day and I was really fascinated with
a lot of the, the drum beats that
I was at. Chris Adler came up.
And, um, I don't know, it's just,
it's like a, it's like anything,
it's all of a sudden there's all this
new shit that you don't know you're
excited to sit down. I mean, if it's
like, he kind of learned what you know,
and then you just sort of sitting there,
you actually get, it's fucking weird.
You get like bored,
um,
and then you don't have any passion
and then you are already playing.
It's Shitty. And then you're going to
play it even fucking worse. So, uh,
very excited about that. Um, and to
finally have a fucking drum room.
I gotta tell you,
I was up there fucking Waylon yesterday.
Not Saying I was playing well,
I was,
but I was hitting them is
fucking hard as I could.
I was having a great pouring sweat.
Just, it's like, it's fucking amazing.
And he played double bass.
All of a sudden it's like,
I don't think I need to do
the elliptical today. Uh,
that probably means my techniques sucks,
but that's the level of effort
that I was exerting. So, um,
what's great though is during,
if I play during the day,
my name was at work and there's always
somebody with the leaf blower or a
fucking lawn mower plane. So I don't
think anybody's really going to hear me.
And I think it just every day,
if just middle of the day,
I playful like 90 fucking minutes. I can
have a great time, not piss anybody off.
And, um, I dunno. And I, I think,
I think the dream has come true. I'll
tell you another fucking dream of beef.
My goddamn fucking computer.
Come on man.
Come back. Come back. What is the
problem? Where did you go? What happened?
I need to read advertising. All right. Oh,
you computer nerds out
there for some reason.
Hey De, oh, now it came back.
They wanted to like screensaver mode
and we wouldn't come back. I Dunno.
Why just it cause I just wrapped
it on the head like when fucking,
okay.
Mohammed would try to get fucking
Larry's attention here. Look, can I can,
can I just read the, the, uh, the
advertising here. I'm all over the place.
What did I do with it?
Yeah.
Jesus Christ.
Do you see Trump just admitted that
he just completely made something up?
Sky like, sounds like me. You talking
about how he said that, you know,
basically we had a trade deficit with
Canada, which I guess was not true.
And this is when he was trying to attack
Nafta saying this is the worst deal we
ever signed.
And evidently according to this site,
the Washington Post,
I dunno if there's psychotically liberal,
so they're just snipping this, I'm sure
all you people on the, yeah, right.
We'll be like, oh, actually went up.
It was the complete opposite
and it was upon his fall. Um,
he said, despite having no idea
whether that was the case, he said, uh,
the man who racked up more than
2000 false and misleading claims,
as president said, he insisted in
to Canadian prime as well. I mean,
I'm sure both sides would
debate that number. You know,
one side says 2000, the other
says three, uh, as president,
he insisted to Canadian Prime Minister
Justin Trudeau that the United States
runs a trade deficit with Canada's despite
quote having no idea whether that was
the case. Um, he said,
I said wrong, Justin, you do.
I didn't even know Trump said,
I had no idea. I just said,
you're wrong. You know why?
Because we're so stupid. That's where
that guy is out of his fucking mind.
And I know people like this,
they're just not present in United States.
He's admitting that he did
something wrong. And then
when he says why he did it,
he then includes how dumb
I am. It's just like, dude,
I didn't say this shit you did.
I'm not saying I'm not dumb.
That's like, you know, I've seen some,
I saw this guy get in trouble one time and
he was just going like, yeah, you know,
when you fuck up, you
know you have to, uh,
you have to come clean and own
up to it. It's like, it also,
why are you talking to me about it? I
didn't do it. You did it. I fucked up.
I need to come clean.
And he was speaking almost in like
a third person type of fucking,
that's hilarious.
Yeah.
That takes me back to
that fucking tee shirt.
Enough was enough talking about enough
already talking about paying women less
than guys. It's like, fuck head, you're
a corporation. You were the one doing it,
not me.
Now you're going to act like he never did
it and profit off what the fuck he did
wrong.
It's like John Wayne Gacy having
a fucking shirt and, uh, you know,
leave the kids alone
enough already. Right. Um,
and then he makes money off of it,
which she then uses to pay a lawyer and
he gets out of jail before they kill him.
So anyways, uh, you know
why? Because we're so stupid.
Yeah.
I would have respected him more
if he just said, you know why?
Because the average American is so
fucking stupid that all you have to do is
just say some shit. And if you're
wearing the right colored tie,
they're going to believe it. They're
not going to research. He said that.
Then I'd be like, yeah, I
totally agree with that.
And that also includes people that
are at root for blue ties. Okay.
And that also includes people in,
in England and Canada.
Everybody know nobody's
fucking paying attention.
There's very few people that
pay attention to the level debt.
Like these talking heads on
TV who only argue one side.
And the fact that you're only arguing
one side, then at that point, I dunno,
how do you listen to them?
That's why I like Jimmy Dore.
I liked Jimmy Dork because
Jimmy Dore also leans left,
but he also trashes the
shit out of fucking Obama.
And calls him out on what a
fucking company man he was.
That guy left the office,
he was worth over 80 million
bucks making 500 grand a year.
And everybody's looking at him like he's
fucking Gandhi. It's just like, dude,
he's the exact same fucking guy.
Not the exact same,
but essentially it's the same thing.
He's doing the same thing that the
guy before that had the red tie.
The guy before they, the blue tie
and every eight years were like,
it's the fucking blue ties.
We need a red tie. Um,
what she really needs,
you need a revolution is what you need.
You need a revolution and you would
have to literally kill the super rich if
you're ever going to change it.
And who's kidding? Heel. You know,
even if that's not gonna happen anymore,
I spend,
that's why they're building these robots.
Everybody know these,
these robohelp God bill, you're
going off the deep end. Yes I am.
They're building these fucking robots.
That's what the fuck. It's four.
It's going to eliminate the ability to
ever a revolt because here's the thing.
Let's just say they turn this,
this country ever into a police state.
The people that make up
our armed services service,
the brave led a web and Omega by Rob
Services. They are all Americans.
And to have them turn their guns on their
own countrymen will be very difficult.
They would almost have to go
into a robot like state. Um,
they see what I did there.
See what I did see out all fucking,
I'll tell you right now,
when you talk to yourself into a
microphone and there's nobody to debate or
check fact check anything you're saying,
you always stick the landing.
You always, you always
standing there, you know,
fucking with the gold medal around your
neck as they play the national anthem a
you right. I fucking agree.
Where barely bar.
He made some great points.
That's because no one was
able to interrupt for tell
him he doesn't know what
he's talking about. Um, all
right, well the fuck is my, uh,
I'm figuring out all my passwords.
I'm really turning a new corner here.
I figured out,
finally figured out how to upload
something properly on a Dropbox without
yelling at it. I actually just sat
down and figured it out yesterday.
I flipped out and I fucking slammed my
computer down that because both my wife
and my daughter to jump in. I was just
like, what am I doing? What am I doing?
I walked downstairs and came back
ups, you know, cooled off, came up.
I apologized to them
both, you know, this is,
this is what I'm doing
right now where I'm,
I'm like the passing the baton
of anger in my family tree. Okay.
If I continue to tradition,
I just would've done that.
I would've blamed everybody in
the room and never apologized.
But now I walk away and,
um,
and I come back a few minutes later and
I apologize. I gave everybody a hug,
a kiss in the room. That's
what I do. Okay. So, you know,
not saying I'm not still fucked up.
I'm not saying people aren't
suffering being around me. I'm just,
I'm just saying that I
am try. Uh, all right,
let me, uh, Sun basket. Everybody. Oh,
it's like having Ms Center
of the universe in a basket.
Sun Basket delivers delicious
meat meal kits right to your door,
making healthy cooking easy and
convenient for any business.
Forget protein shaking and flavorless
diet food. Start cooking fresh.
I don't get to tell you something.
Those protein shakes,
if you look at like the
chemicals and all that crap,
all that shit that they give
at Gnc, including the, uh,
the men's daily fucking pill that I take
total hypocrite that I bought at a GNC.
So much of that shit. It's just like, how
can that be good for me? Okay. Why? Oh,
there's so many chemicals. Forget protein
shaking and flavorless died. Food.
Start cooking fresh healthy meals with
delicious organic produce with Sun
Basket. Okay. 18 healthy options to
choose from every week, including Paleo,
gluten free leaning, clean, Vegan,
Mediterranean family options and moral.
However you want to do it,
they got the option for you.
Sun Basket makes it easy and convenient
to cook healthy, delicious meals at home.
No matter how much experience
you have in the kitchen,
now you get more options than ever.
Just go to thun bath,
get app to the sun basket APP
and pick from 18 weekly recipes.
Easily cooked,
easily cooked dishes easily cooked dishes
isn't a cooked like steaks with Chimi
Chira and Harissa roasted sweet potatoes
or your favorite sun basket recipe.
Sun Basket works cause I kind of
did an offensive Asian accent there.
I have to do something
else here. Uh, or regular.
Tony was the sun basket.
Works with the best fam farms
and suppliers to bring you fresh,
organic produce.
Wild caught seafood.
Just pictured the fish making like a horse
sound as you're pulling it out of the
sea and responsibly
raised meats. Hey, hey,
knock it off all of you
cows. It's bedtime. Okay.
Plus Sun basket is delivered in perfect
portions with reliable nutrition.
I said, knock it off. You go over,
you apologize to that other cow.
I'm not having Cadillac this. Do
you understand me? Plus Sun Basket.
I said Sun basket is delivered in
perfect portions with reliable nutrition
information and it's ready to
whip up in about 30 minutes.
How do you responsibly raised me? That's a
big, that's a wide, you know, it's a big,
vague statement.
There's something for every fiscally
responsibly or responsible to the cow.
There's something for
every healthy journey.
Like what do you say to the cow right
before you kill it. You know what I mean?
Hey Man, look at that over there.
Whap I've always loved you. Uppercut.
There's something for every healthy
journey and with every business lifestyle,
go to sun
basket.com/burr,
but you are to learn more and get
$35 off your first order. That sun,
basket.com/burr for $35
off sun basket.com/burr.
There you go. There you go. And
that's the Thursday afternoon,
just before Friday, Monday podcast. Uh,
I hope all of you have
a responsible weekend,
a response, and you have a
responsibly raised child with, uh,
all your fiscal earnings in their
proper a ledger or something.
I have no idea. All right,
have a great weekend.
You Con Bruins verse the
Florida Panthers Tonight.
Maybe there'll be some fights and,
um,
this weekend I'm going to be
up and outside of a lemon.
Landcaster Ontario with Joe Barnick,
the Rosebowl tailgate legend,
Joe Barton, Nick and Paul Vert. Paul. I
know everything that happens in aviation.
Versie in other words, anytime there's a
crash, he reads up on it. By the way, man.
Um,
that was a horrific helicopter crash in,
uh, in New York City. Of course, I've
been paying attention to that. And,
uh, this quick footage of the guy landing
the helicopter and he looks like he
totally, he totally fucking nailed it. Um,
the landing wasn't hard at all and
he got out and nobody else did.
And I think from what I'm hearing,
inner circles is a,
they will flying with doors off.
So not only did they have the seat belts,
which are, I think they're the, the,
the four ones that connect with the
circle in the middle, which you also,
you have to turn it like
clockwise or counterclockwise.
Cause I was thinking that they panicked.
They didn't know how to, you know, the,
once they land like, fuck, I'm in a
helicopter crash and then all, fuck,
I don't want to drown. And like, I
remember I went skydiving and, um,
I did a static line jumps. So there
was nobody attached to me. And, um,
I remember it was awkward
towels, 1000, two, 1000, three,
1000, 4,000. Look, if nothing,
look reached pulse.
So when you pulled your emergency ripcord
you had to talk your way through it,
look to see it, reach to grab
it, pull the, pull the thing.
Cause other than you'd be panicking,
flailing,
starting to do somersaults and shit. So
I thought maybe that was it. But, um,
someone was saying to me that they were
possibly flying doors off and as an
extra safety precaution,
they had them hooked to the helicopter
with one of those c clamp type of job.
He's there and there's two different
kinds. There's the one that's the,
the quick release.
Um,
and then as the extra extra
one that you screw on.
Um, and, uh,
they were suggesting that it was probably
that one and that even if they got
their seatbelts on that
they were, uh, I dunno,
basically strapped to the helicopter,
went down and drowned.
I have no idea of how
fucking horrific is that.
Why would I end the podcast on that?
I have no idea.
And I have no fucking evidence.
That's just what's been suggested to me.
So anyways, on that upbeat
note, uh, listened to, uh,
some happy music now and then
we'll go into some greatest hits.
I don't know why I talked to, you
know, why? Cause I fly in that made
me scared. Yeah.
Maybe happy to see that the guy who
fucking totally landed at like a stud and
then, uh, if what is being suggested
happened actually happened,
I would can imagine the pilot,
you know,
having to deal with those
five fucking people, you know,
they're going to try to
fucking blame him. Um, it,
cause it seems like that's one of those
things where they made it so safe that
they didn't,
they created another fucking problem,
which means they'll probably then have
some sort of new clamp that they designed.
I don't fucking know. Anyways. Uh,
how do I talk my way out of this?
I have no idea. I'm sitting
here just flailing. All right.
Listen to the fucking music
and have a great weekend.
You conch and there'll be another
half hour of greatest hits.
We're hopefully I don't,
and such a gloomy, no reply.
[inaudible] [inaudible]
[inaudible]
hey,
what's going on?
It's bill burr and it is the
Monday morning podcast from Monday,
March 16th, 2010. How the hell are you?
How's it going? It's daylight savings
time. If you haven't figured it out yet.
Do you wondering why you keep
being late for the last 24 hours?
It's actually Sunday when I'm doing
this thing because uh, you know,
I get sick of people on the east coast.
Bitching dude.
You could do Floki two's move fucking
Monday afternoon podcast. Should I
um, no, I respect that.
You want to get to work?
Do you want to begin fucking off
immediately start your week off right?
I understand. So I tape them on
Sundays now when I can and uh,
hope you guys all had a good weekend.
My Sunday started great.
My dog puked on the floor after,
you know,
three days of threatening dry heaves
and every time we go out walk up the
street, the things eating
grass like it's a goddamn cow.
And my girls always going, stop
it, stop it, stop eating the grass,
stamp it.
And a,
I vaguely remember over
hearing someone who I hope new,
a veterinarian who said something to
the effect that a animals eat grass when
they're not feeling well. So last night
I was taking her out late at night,
right at that, that critical fucking
moment to scary moment, my neighborhood.
All right, there's a
moment where, uh, you know,
when you're in a bad part of the city
and there's that moment around dusk where
all the decent, hardworking, honest
people are coming in after a nice decent,
honest, hardworking days pay, you know,
is they try to get out kind of like
a good times episode, you know?
And then there's, there's that point where
then the scumbags come out, you know,
who are doing all kinds of illegal shit,
which I don't even know what the fuck
do you even think about that anymore?
Now it's just as fucked up. I was going to
say, you know, I'm just fucking crooked.
He's, he's Goddamn banks are, you
know it was selling drugs. Yes it is.
It is just as fucking bad. So anyways, to
stay on, I'm already off fucking track.
You know what, my fucking
banked it to me. I walked in,
I had this account in New York that I
kind of a little checking account that had
a little bit of money in and
all of a sudden notice they,
we've taken some fees out. I'm like, well
that shouldn't be. So I get to New York,
I walk in, I talked to the Douche bag
who works there and he goes, yeah,
they've taken $27 a month out.
I don't know why that is. Here.
Let me check to see what's up. Click
and collect. I'll check on his thing.
And he goes, yeah, we shouldn't have
been doing that. And I go, okay,
well can you refund the money?
And they go, absolutely. A,
and I go, well, you know,
I've had the account for like six years.
Can we see how long you've been
doing this? And he's like, I'm sorry,
are our records only go
back for four months?
Really it only goes back for four months.
It's amazing because my bank records at
home go back the entire time I've had
the account and that's incredible.
And I just have some piddly some in
there while you deal with hundreds of
millions of dollars, if not
billions, if not trillions.
I don't know what the fuck you have.
I just know there's a fucking Bank of
yours and every God damn state now,
but of course it only goes back like
four months. So I go, all right,
well what if I bring my records in?
I look them over and I find out
how long have you been doing it?
And they're like, Nah, he can only
refund it for four months. I'm like,
dude, what are you talking
about? And he goes, well,
the bank kind of looks at it like that,
that that was on you,
woody.
And I was like,
it's on me to not to not be like paying
attention to make sure the people who
are supposed to be keeping my money
safe aren't fucking stealing from me.
And He sorta like laughed. I'm like, dude,
this isn't funny. This is ridiculous.
You guys just stole from me.
And if you've been doing it for six years,
what's that? 270 bucks.
Send another fucking Nav 50,
like almost 300 bucks
a year for six years.
That's like 1500 to 1800
bucks somewhere in there.
And the guy's just sitting
there fucking laughing and uh,
you know this a usual shit. Yeah. What
are you going to sue us? Go ahead.
We'll take some of that bail out money,
which is part of your tax
money and we'll fucking, uh,
so I don't know what I'm going to do.
I'm going to close out the account and uh,
and I don't know,
what do I do then I go across the street
to one of the bet for banks that are
left.
If anybody out there is in banking,
how do I get my money back
beyond the four months?
Cause I know that they've been
doing it longer than this. Um,
can anybody explain that? You know, this
is why people, this is why, you know,
put 100% of your paycheck into the fucking
bag. He got to look at it this way.
If somebody mugged you last week,
would you walk up to the same person
and take your paycheck and stick it in
their back pocket? You
wouldn't, would you?
But for some reason we have these
fucking bankers. Yeah, I don't know.
I think everybody should turn like,
I dunno,
everybody should have a fucking
safe that you have buried somewhere.
Everybody's got a gun in. Anybody
can blow anybody away. I know.
It's all fucked up.
Fucking assholes guys sitting
there fucking smiling.
You know when he's sitting there doing,
he's doing that little twirly thing.
You know that math people do with their
pens and people were into finances.
I think they do it to
hypnotize you and says,
the guy's fucking sit there telling me
that they'd been stealing 30 bucks a
month from me and all I'm doing
is I'm trying to focus on him.
I keep looking down at his silver
shiny pen, some sort of mind trick.
Fortunately, I was aware
of it. I'm going to say,
can you stop twirling your fucking pen?
But I didn't want to do that cause
I was trying to keep my cool,
which obviously is a difficult
thing for me to do, you know?
I don't know right now a bill.
It's just 27 bucks a month times how
many fucking people you remember superman
three when Richard Pryor stole half a
cent from everybody in the next day had a
fucking Ferrari.
These fucks are taken 27 bucks a month
from everybody. I'm convinced of it.
It's the fucking mob.
I swear to God the mob went legit
or those there will be blood guys.
They're the fucking assholes
and run the Goddamn bags.
He's fucking concert just stealing
from me and there's nobody getting,
nobody's going to help me.
What am I going to go down there?
I'm going to get that guy used to be
on the fucking, uh, leave it to beaver.
What the fuck was it? Even that show
a Mayberry. I always hated that show,
that old content walking around with
their falsetto voice. [inaudible]
you know, you know what that show
lacked somebody that I wanted to bang.
That's why I didn't watch it.
There was nobody fuckable on it.
That was the brilliance of the
monsters that they were like,
this is going to be hilarious.
We're going to turn fucking Frankenstein
into drag and Dracula into these Kooky
characters and it's all going to be funny.
But they knew at the end of the day
there had to be somebody that the male
demographic would want to fuck.
So they came up with that
girl who was allegedly ugly.
Why am I explaining this classic show?
You know the deal and she looked like
Marilyn Monroe and that's what kept me in
there. I Dunno, right?
Batman after a while,
it's like to what is going on with
this 40 year old guy in his ward?
And then all of a sudden they had cat
woman walking around that fucking hoary
outfit.
Is she the one who started that shit?
Did women not dress like whores on uh,
on Halloween before Batman
are a bad girl or Catwoman?
Catwoman was a bad one, right?
There's such pathetic cons,
you know what I mean? It's, we take
off that fucking ridiculous outfit.
Go stand behind a wall and,
and,
and start talking to people and listen
to how many people even fucking pay
attention to you.
They don't cause you got nothing to say.
All you can do is just dress up your
goddamn twat and starts strutting around
the fucking place that had
nothing to do with cat.
Woman had nothing to do with her head.
Do with me.
Fucking get fucked over by
that Goddamn bag. Assholes,
fucking assholes.
And I go to go down there.
I got to go down to lake like some
fucking guy who's button store just failed
after 75 years.
You know,
Frankie fish face and sons.
Remember those fucking, um,
those businesses when you were a kid, it
was always something, something in sons,
you know, and like a lot of the times
the kids were forced into the business.
You know, some Italian guy, he opens a
fucking prosciutto shop and then that's,
it's like an arranged
marriage except it's your job.
Then you got to show
up and be [inaudible].
I have been working in the restaurants
and that was a da Da Dah, Dah, Dah, Dah.
Did that,
you know,
they don't know shit about anything else
because everybody wanted to strike out
on their own.
And now look,
everybody ends up in a fucking cubicle
worker for these fucking cops who are
stealing my money. That's
uplifting isn't it? Um, anyways,
this is the money morning
podcast and it's on my website.
I'm trying to get it onto iTunes.
I'm in between web guys right now.
Hopefully this is up on iTunes.
We worked on it yesterday. Um,
you know, and it was weird. It
was up on my web guys computer,
but it wasn't up on my computer.
So if you're listening to this on
my website, maybe you go to Itunes,
you just hold down the shift button. I
mean maybe iTunes just keeps reloading a,
you know,
it remembers a page that you've been to.
So when you go back to it a load quicker,
hold down the shift button.
When you're on that page, um, I believe
that. Then you can see the new ones.
So now I have three podcasts.
It's fucking ridiculous,
but eventually we're going
to get it all under one.
This is the first time I've ever had a
web guy who lives down the from me. Um,
I have new video up on my
website and buy new video.
I mean video that actually works.
And um,
this is part of a whole new revamping
that I've tried to do like 10 times.
I know I've always promised that, but, um,
I'm going to be uploading video to my
website and we start video my video taping
myself out on the road, putting up little
bullshit things up there. You know,
the usual bullshit give you guys
a couple of crumbs every week.
So you still give a fuck about me.
So when I come to your town,
maybe you'll buy a ticket for you and your
best little girl or fucking boyfriend,
whatever you got going on out there,
whatever it is that you do. Um,
there's also a, a fan page for the
Monday morning podcast. Now, uh,
www.themmpodcast.com.
Uh,
there's questions, there's pictures.
I make references to fucked up stuff.
Like say you haven't watched the monsters.
Maybe there'll be a picture of the
hardy on the monsters, you know,
so, uh, and that's it.
My girlfriend just walked in and then
tippy toed back out again and then
shrugged her shoulders. Like I wasn't
going to address it. You heard me,
I was in a lull.
So anyways,
I really apologize for the horror that
has been trying to find my podcast over
the last month or so.
Um,
I didn't think that it was going
to be such a big deal, you know?
Uh, I, I just thought I could just
switch over to a new server, a server,
and it wasn't going to be a problem. But
evidently it's this major fucking deal.
And I've talked to other podcasters out
there and they were talking about what a
fucking pain in the ass it is to get it
up on iTunes because once you do get it
up on iTunes, then they have to
approve of it as if to say yes,
this is in fact a podcast and
beyond that we approve of it.
So anyways, Jesus Christ, it's
already one in the afternoon.
I just went out to brunch with my lovely
girlfriend and I heard some fucking,
oh my God, that goes back to my joke.
You really go to a branch. Do you,
did somebody have test? Um, yeah,
I went down to this fucking place and
we're hanging out down there and uh,
this fucking dude, um, I
don't know if he was gay,
but he had the gay accent,
which is always fun to me.
Like there's a part of the
country that they're from,
which is an old joke that I used to do.
Um,
he was talking about daylight savings
times. He was just like, oh my God. Like,
this is how it should be all the time.
You know, it's like, this is Los Angela,
this whole getting out of work at
five and it's dark out. It's like,
what is going on with that?
That's like one of those things ever.
Just hear somebody like that.
They're like such a fucking cliche
that whoever you're with, you just,
you're just sort of
staring down at your food.
And then when you look at the person that
you're with, you don't move your head.
You just slowly look up at each other
and then all of a sudden it's like you're
in grade school again.
And there was a teacher said,
the next person who fucking
laughs is getting detention.
It's one of those moments.
It was tight quarters,
so we couldn't like really
start laughing at them. But um,
I really wanted to lean over and be like,
you know,
part of the reason why it's so fucking
dark out during the winter time is the
whole planet. The northern
hemisphere tilts away from
the sun. They're fuck face.
All right. So even in December, it
would probably be dark around five.
Despite the time change.
Actually maybe it wouldn't.
Maybe more like five 45 30
depending on where you're at. Right?
I mean, am I ignorant? Of course
I am, but as far as I know,
daylight savings is the bullshit time.
Like right now it's not
really one o'clock. We're
just saying it's one o'clock.
So the farm hands out in the Midwest can
have more fucking time to harvest the,
the beans made out of corn products.
Cory to Food Inc right?
I don't know. Fucking know. I have no
idea where they do it. I just fucking
why do I have to,
I every week I talk about shit that
I don't know anything about it.
And it's the funniest
shit. Like I, I go into it,
I start getting anxiety cause I know
I don't know what I'm talking about.
So why would I literally try to
do is I try to use like momentum.
Like maybe if I say something dumb
quickly, no one's gonna notice.
I believe that that's exactly what
it is in my world. That made sense.
So onto today's topics.
I was all excited to wake up this
morning and watch the Chicago Blackhawks
against the Washington capitals.
Why may you ask? I'll tell you why.
Because I love the sport of hockey and a,
it's a good chance that those two teams
could possibly meet in the finals,
if not in the finals next year.
The two teams that are right there.
All right? And everybody always
bitches out. Oh, hockey sticks.
And they always blame the fighting.
They got to get the fighting out
of the fucking game. All right?
That's why nobody watches it.
Well,
I'm going to give you an example of the
NHL here. This is what they do today.
Okay?
During the week,
my Bruins played the
Pittsburgh Penguins and uh,
overall Pittsburgh's a decent franchise
for spectacle. I respect them,
but they always say, seem to have one
douche bag on the team. The off Samuelson,
you know, the guy who just can't
fucking play, you know, he can't play,
he can't fucking fight.
He can't even just skate around and
annoy you like a Ken Lindeman back in the
day. So what he does is he goes out there
and he basically tries to end people's
careers or their seasons and that's
what he did to mark survivor.
I even know the fucking guys name and
I don't even want to know his neck,
kind of like somebody goes up and
shoots up a fucking mall so they can get
famous. I always make sure I
don't remember their fucking name,
even though the news can't
stop talking about him.
So this fucking cunt just basically
glides in after survivor took shot.
Granted, if he hit his body, it's, it's
illegal hip, but he didn't, he took,
he took his shoulder slash elbow and just
blasted and right in the fucking head
and he so only connected
with his head that survived,
literally helicoptered around
and landed down on the ice.
And not only was he not suspended or
find that there wasn't even a penalty.
I don't know what it is about
the penguins for some reason,
they always have that one goon who can
go in and just blow out Cam Neely fucking
knee and end his career. That guy
just ended [inaudible] fucking season.
Our one goal scorer and
they then they do nothing.
Told the whole hockey world is
flipping out like, dude, what the fuck?
So what do they do to make it up today?
Washington capitals versus Chicago
Blackhawks there one nationally televised
game this week on NBC can
actually watch it in HD TV.
So while you fucking idiots out
there who can't see the Puck,
I can't fear where is it?
I can't see it.
Fucking black object against a white
surface. Can't fucking see it. Why don't,
why don't you start with looking at the
guy that everybody appears to be mad at
on the other team? You
know, start with that guy.
Maybe that's the guy who has the
object that they desire. So anyways,
you know what they do?
They end up kicking fucking Ovechkin.
They gave him a game misconduct out of
the game because he did some half hour.
I mean it was a check that deserved a
penalty, possibly a fucking double minor.
And they kicked the best player in the
league out of the fucking game on their
national telecast.
And I'm a tell you right now people,
that is why that is why nobody watches
hockey because they continually make
moves like that.
I don't know why every five years they
get back on ESPN and then they go,
whoa, wait a minute. The USA
network is offering us $5 more,
or let's go over there.
Let's go over to the versus network.
How many people you think
would be watching the NFL
if throughout the years they
, they, you know,
they occasionally for three years we're
disappear onto like the learning channel.
You know what I mean? It really has
nothing to do with the fighting.
It's such a stupid fucking comment
that people make and it's hypocritical.
If you truly feel that that fighting
should be out of that game as much as the
whole world enjoys violence.
We love violence.
Go on Youtube and look at the
fucking ones that get the most hits.
We like to laugh and we'd like
to watch somebody get fucked up.
That's what I've learned
from going onto youtube.
Oh and people will find a way to talk
politics or discuss race on any video that
you stick up there. And
speaking of that, um, dude,
I was so fucking bummed out.
I woke up an hour late so I missed the
first period and then I find out a veggie
skin isn't even fucking plague and it
was laying on the next thing you know,
they Chicago scores, it's three nothing
and the game is basically over for the,
or for those of you who don't watch
hockey three, nothing is basically, uh,
I would say it's like being down 17
points and football are taught yeah,
Po sometimes 21, depending on how
bad your fucking team is. So, um,
I was upset as a hockey fan.
I still love the Nhl and I still
think you guys should watch the game.
I was actually watching a little bit of
the Premier League because I'm going to
Europe this week and uh,
the excitement of that has finally hit me.
I'm not excited about the
17 hour or whatever it is,
15 hour flight from Los Angeles.
But um,
I'm beyond excited to go over there.
And have killer shows and to begin to
build a following over there because a
cause,
why not?
Because you only go around once and I
was going to get a tour of the fucking
Abbey road studios and that fell through.
So now I don't know what to do.
I don't know what to do over there.
And for those of you who
haven't been on my website,
um, this week, uh,
on Thursday I am playing at
the Lester theatre in London,
England.
How fucking cool does that sound?
Then I'm playing the sugar club in a,
in a Dublin Ireland on Friday.
And then the next night I go to Glasgow,
Scotland,
lots of new Americans like me.
We're going to want to say glass gow cause
it looks like it's written like slow,
you know, low, but it's gow
glass. Gow uh, Scotland.
And I actually don't even know the fucking
name of the theater and playing there,
but uh, it's going to be awesome.
And I am coming off the wagon.
My Good Buddy Joe to
Rosa went 70 days sober,
so I had to beat him because
I'm a competitive fuck.
And I was going to take myself off
last night. It's 71 days, you know,
kind of like a nod to Roger Maris.
60 home runs 61 70 71.
But uh, I decided fuck it. You know, if
I'm going to fall off the fucking wagon,
it's going to be in a pub in London,
England. That's what I'm going to do it.
So I need you English people to tell me
where there's a good pub and by a good
pub.
I don't mean some loud fucking bar
with a bunch of douchebags in it,
trying to act like they're cooler than
they really are. I want some fucking,
I want some place I could walk
in that's a little bit quieter,
but I'm not going to get the shit kicked
out of me once they realize that I'm an
American. Okay. I need to know that.
I also need to know if I bring DVDs over
there to sell to you guys for pounds,
euros, whatever the fuck
you're on. I believe you guys,
you guys have an accepted the euro, but
I think Ireland has, um, I need to know,
did DVDs play the American code version?
Whatever the fucking technical term is,
do those things play over there?
Are they formatted correctly?
Cause I don't want to go over there
and sell you guys a bunch of shit that
doesn't work. And then
we got gotta, you know,
then I'm like a bank and then I
gotta be like, well, you know,
that's really on you.
You know,
she should have realized that
I was from America and uh,
I have a different fucking DVD system
than you do. So there you go. My, sorry,
my records only go back four minutes.
I really don't have any recollection
of going over there. So anyways,
I don't know what else to do over
there. John Bonham's grave, you know,
maybe I'll go see that.
Um,
what else could I do? I don't
want to go do that. Do She?
Shit guy glow look big Ben and parliament.
I don't wanna I don't wanna
look at that stuff. I want, uh,
I don't want,
I want to do,
I don't want to walk around and
want to look at similar who is,
I want to do what? People in
London, England do that right.
That's what I want to do.
Which is what eat Indian food right
after a plate full of fish and chips.
Um, I dunno what the fuck
you guys do over there,
but if you could tell me some stuff
to do. I know stone chat, Stonehenge,
I've talked to enough Americans
who've gone over there.
It's basically sitting on the side
of the road like a fucking Starbucks.
It's very underwhelming. Um,
whenever they film it there,
they're real close and they make sure
that they don't have the highway like 10
feet away from the fucking thing.
I'm,
I can't wait for somebody to fall asleep
at the wheel and just drive right into
that thing.
That's going to be hilarious.
So anyways,
this is the podcast this week.
I've been kind of Cunty the last couple of
weeks. I've been in a bad move, but, uh,
I'm in a much better
mood this week, so, uh,
I don't know if that'll make this less
funnier or more tolerable. It's up to you.
So here's some youtube videos.
Speaking of England, uh,
this is my nod to,
uh,
just something I discovered
a few years ago, um,
through this comedian Jordan Rubin.
I was the one on his myspace page.
Remember that? Remember my
space, I was the last one. Um,
he had a clip of this on his page and I
actually checked it out. It's called a,
the Prince of Wales. And, uh,
it's actually spelled w, h a.
L e s, like the, uh,
the mammal and a, it's called
Derek and Clive, d. E r.
E. C. O, sorry, d. E r. E. K.
And Clive Cli. V. E. All right.
And it's actually Dudley
Moore in this guy, Peter Cook,
who most Americans have
never heard of. And, um,
that's basically just imagine if I was
doing a podcast with some other asshole,
but 30 years ago and it's just them
going off on stuff and they made,
when you watch the clip,
it stem, I believe,
recording the album and it was just the
most filthy as shit and offensive stuff
that they could come up. They talk
about religion, they a lot of stuff,
a lot of stuff that actually, I was
watching it and I was like, Jesus Christ,
this is a,
this is like the original podcast.
It's completely over the top and a,
I guess, you know, it's Dudley Moore,
Peter Cook,
and I guess they was supposed to be a,
I don't know what they were supposed
to be mean. I don't live over there,
so obviously, so I don't know
who they're supposed to be.
I'm just imagining it's just a couple
of cans cabin. I can sit in a bar.
I don't know what, but it's fucking
hilarious to me and I hope you enjoy it.
All right. I have also,
by the way, I have a nice,
I have a nice variety of youtube videos.
So if you're not under the comedy thing,
if you want to see a beautiful woman with
the most killer body I've ever seen in
my fucking life,
and an accent to match it and her hair
done up and fucking pony tails as she
works out, look up fitness, uh,
killer five 50 rep workout fitness
dash killer five 50 workout.
Uh, I can't remember the name
of the girl. She's ridiculous.
And she does this insane workout.
She's in shape,
I believe her titties or natural,
unless you went to Dallas and got those
teardrop fucking fake ones that I saw
out there. Um, and she just works
out and she looks unbelievable.
And as she gets further into this set,
she starts going like,
it's fucking awesome. I'm at a
comedian, you should check out,
check out our Reggie watts,
Regg IEE, watts, w a t t.
S a lot of the shitty puts up. There was
this musical stuff that he does, I think,
because he doesn't want to burn
as material like most comedians.
But if you get a chance to see that guy,
they go recommended a video and a,
and a comedian. Um, those are all on
youtube. And here's the last video.
I will recommend this something,
a break.com and there's something
called the tree terminator.
And uh,
it's just one of those
machines that you're going to
see that it just shows that
human beings were just too fucking slow.
Mark for our own goddamn good.
Basically this machine, for those of
you who are on a treadmill right now,
it just,
it has like a big hand.
I don't know what it is. It, it
just, it looks like a backhaul,
but it's really like a hand in,
it just grabs these trees,
pulls them right out of the ground and
then it like, imagine if like, okay, you,
you fucking, you threw a Jab, right?
Do that right now in your cubicle several
and thinks you're fucking insane and
they're just waiting and have a fist
so they don't think you're fucking
listening to a Hitler video. Um, stick.
Yes. Sticking out there like you're
about ready to salute Hitler,
but have a fist so you
don't offend anybody.
And then just imagine if if your arm right
down to your wrist wouldn't move yet.
Your fucking hand could do
an entire fucking ThreeSixty.
That's what this device does,
except you're holding a tree and
then what it does is it fucking,
some are holds the tree in place with,
I don't know what some device in there
and then it loosens its grip and it goes
up and down the tree.
Like it's Jackin off horizontally.
But what it's really doing is removing
all the branches and the leaves.
So then all you're left with is the
fucking is the trunk with the Barksdale on
it. It gives it another fucking
Jack and now it's you know,
back and forth a few times now all it
is is just as rounds spool of a of wood
and then add, it doesn't stop there.
Then it goes all the way down to the,
I guess where the balls would be.
Right? It's very fucking a phallic here.
And then what it starts
where the weather at,
the base of the shaft goes up
about three and then tramp.
That was supposed to be at
slicing and half. I really
fucking blew it on that. Uh,
that was the worst sound effect ever.
Clamp.
That's not what it doesn't want to show.
That's what it did.
That's the right sound effects.
See no Michael Winslow here this week
and the edge just in sections, like
little fucking six foot sections of wood.
And I'm telling you it can do it.
One tree every like 20 seconds.
And this guy is just a one mic.
One guy with the machine is just basically
going through this forest so we can
all have baseball bats. I Dunno what,
just you know, button amount of time.
It took me to fucking explain that. You
could have looked it up and watched it.
I'm such an idiot. All right. What am
I got to hear? What's coming up next?
What's the next subject here on
the Monday morning podcast? Oh,
here's something that's called,
let's get smart is an explanation.
Ex explanation point.
I'm desperately trying to become a,
uh,
the smartest moron that I
can become an I've actually
through that lumosity.com on
becoming a better speller.
And these are some of the
words that I've been, Toronto,
one of the Games I've been
trying to come up with,
but I don't know how to
spell them. So then I, uh,
I just write them down and I give myself
spelling test, aesthetic aggressive,
alleged bizarre Catamaran, cantaloupe,
catalyst, catalyst, chloroform,
disingenuous, facetious. You
know, you know what's great about,
these are all words that
you can use in print,
but if you actually use them a while
speaking, you come off like a douchebag,
at least in the circle of people
that, um, I'm hanging out,
like hanging out with that can't
use the word infrastructure.
Can I use the word melancholy?
Huh? Anybody else spelled
melancholies to spell it?
M. E. L. L. O. N. K.
O. L. L. Y. Like I did,
I wasn't that bad, but it was
pretty brutal. Like succinct.
I was playing this game and,
uh, you have to do that.
Like when you're texting and you
come up with a word that you,
so can't even spell,
like your brain literally locks
in like succinct. I was like,
how the fuck do you spell this?
Saw as a
sinked is that like sync?
Like you brush your teeth
as I n k e d you know,
the past tense of sync sync
or like sync something up cyc.
I think I spelled to sus.
Why C and then laughed and hit enter
and then the computer was like,
oh, did you mean succinct? You know,
you know when Google gets
all cunty liked that?
Oh my believe what you were
trying to say was really,
I believe we fucking made you.
That might've been my curl.
Just laughed at me.
What Neil was that one of the dumbest
things I've ever said on this that was
pretty fucking stupid.
Yeah.
I believe we made you,
you know,
in 30 years when I lead the rebellion
against the robots that are, uh,
that, that are going
to replace us, that's,
that's going to be our battle
cry when we're standing there
with our p nine dx bodies and I'll
be standing there getting a sunburn,
just standing there with
half a blue phase going ohm.
I believe we made you
don't move.
Don't move until their screenshots down.
That's the lights of their eyes.
Like giving you attitude.
It does have an APP will come over here.
You're going to be on the podcast.
It does have an attitude. It's,
it says trying to help
you out. No, but it's
not mocking you. Yeah, it
is. Well, you know something,
I guess it all depends on the voice
in your head. Cause did you mean this?
The only thing that's missing is it should
just have o.dot, dot. In front of it.
What the fuck was that? Yeah,
you're supposed to continue.
That just made it sound like it. Bob, do
you want, Huh? Yeah. All right. Move on.
Where are you going to talk about?
You're a little,
a Russian mail order bride that you watch
on youtube there. Oh, how hard is she?
You gotta admit she's hot.
She's very hot. Would you,
what I make out with her
answering that question. So yes.
See fucking champ right here.
Fucking champ.
Maybe we'll see her when
we're over there and uh,
pull ups in some war torn country
when she's on. She's on that route.
When she's on that rooftop and she's
doing all her squat thrusts and making
noises like a porno star doesn't she
look like she's in the middle of some,
like they just bombed. First of all,
she's, she's tired after her set.
She's tired after
you fucking talking about it.
That's what I'm tired of.
So what do you think about that?
I think that brings it full circle to me.
Have an attitude about Google.
I didn't ask you to put it up there.
Why can't I enjoy one of God's
beautiful creatures? Please
fucking break. Fuck you. Every time
you see Kevin Garnett on the screen,
you've got to make that fucking oh
yeah. Yeah. See, go fuck yourself.
Get out of here. Can I see your brush
for a second? Let's just sit. Get Out.
Get Out. Beat it. You have
to leave in 20 minutes.
We'll call a cab sweetheart.
You know what? Nothing.
Don't get that Google attitude with me.
Oh I have to leave in 20 minutes.
No one's stopping you.
Hey Nia.
How do you spell succinct
if you're so fucking smart.
Cause I told you how to spell it the other
day. Fuck you. Shut up. Shut your face.
Watch.
Why don't I listen succinct.
S. U. C. C. I. E. N. T. Eh, you stink.
No it isn't. Can I tell you something?
This is when you know you don't have to
spell a word when for some reason you're
looking to the right or left
and there's nobody there.
You don't know how to spell it.
S. U. C. C. I. N. C. T. Succinct. There's
no e. No. That's a hard one. Facetious.
It's like face Sacious,
right? Like how you say it.
F A. Oh my God, I can't breathe with you.
You can have the dumbest kid ever.
It's a baby boy,
boy,
school and teachers for dumb parents.
Did you just say that's why
it has school and teachers?
Do you see what cell phones are doing
to us? I'm telling you. That's why it.
Good Lord. Would you look at
you? Wow. All right. Anyways,
that's why they make them beautiful.
You just bombed the spelling test.
Wow.
You're not a good speller really.
Well those are two difficult.
Okay, facetious. His face.
Tee Us f, a, c, t I. O,
U s. So I'm actually sitting
here, I'm like a psycho,
like Jack Nicholson in the shining and
I'm just sitting here writing sentences
that don't really make any sense because
I just want to use all the words that
I've used that I've learned.
I mean,
the mallow odorous melancholy of the
psychotic critics was aesthetically
pleasing despite their silhouette,
the capitulation of the
inmates penitentiary argument
could be stated that one
doesn't need an a squiz
exquisite repertoire.
Merely a succinct dilemma with the
sociopath. Nice fucking restaurant.
Sorry,
I ran out of words.
I just remember all I had left
was restaurant and I was like,
I need one more sentence and I
was tired. Whatever. Fuck you.
You spell some of those words,
but I'm saying like,
I'm just listen to how I speak. Okay.
And how many words I mispronounced it.
I've lied to myself for years.
That the reason why I make such a fool
of myself is because my brain works so
quickly that it's ahead of
where my tongue is at and,
and that's not fucking true.
All right.
I'm here to tell you that
I am an idiot and I'm,
I'm really trying desperately to,
uh,
I've come to the acceptance that
I'm a moron and if I could, I just,
but I just want to be,
but I still don't feel even,
I still feel like I can at least
improve on a, I can be kicked out.
I can become less of a moron.
Alright.
So this is basically what I've been doing
as I've been saying in the past couple
of weeks,
I've been writing with my right hand
cause I'm lefthanded and I've been a throw
in with my left hand because I do sports
with my right hand, my fucking mess.
But um,
yeah,
I guess it opens different parts of
brain and I was talking about it and
sounding like a moron is always,
um,
how do you spell cantaloupe is a good one,
huh?
You know cantaloupe. We know
those days when you're like, oh,
I gotta get in shape yet you still go
out for breakfast and you still get the
pancakes and the eggs,
but you go, you know what?
I'm not going to get the home fries. Let
me get a fruit cup instead. You know,
and then they have that look
on their face like, holy shit,
nobody orders the fruit cup. That's why
I forgot it was even on the fucking menu.
And then they go out there and they bring
this Fruit Cup bought back out to you.
Right. And it's always
that little, uh, you know,
it's got a couple of grapes.
It's got a melon in this,
got cantaloupe and it has little fucking
moldy tentacles reaching into each
piece of fruit. Cantaloupe.
I love cantaloupe.
A lot of people don't know that about
myself. And, uh, for the life of me,
I couldn't spell it. I
spelled it like, like,
can't Aloke like you can't alone.
You have to have a wedding.
This is how this,
how is spelled c a n t a l o.
U. P. E if I haven't bored you
to fucking tears at this point,
nothing I'll talk about. We'll,
let's move on to the next one. Um,
so basically I was talking about that
stuff where you actually use your opposite
hand. It all started with
this, uh, some comic down.
The comedy store came and move the
fuck it was because my brain's mush was
talking about how that improves your brain
and actually if you're lefthanded and
use your right hand for stuff that usually
use with your left hand and actually
improves your left hand allegedly.
So this gets scientists,
I'm going to call him a scientist rights.
He said bill and your podcast,
when you talk about using your opposite
hand and learning to write with it,
the term is called neuroplasticity
or Blain plasticity.
I don't know how the fuck to say it.
What are,
what you are doing is
retraining your brain.
That's the science behind brain fitness.
Here is a nice little article about
it on a p o s I t science.com.
Um, and actually, you know,
something that I've actually seen
someone who did something like that. Uh,
every morning me and my lovely girlfriend
go for this hike and when we first
moved out here,
there was this guy who clearly just had
a stroke and he would walk up the hill.
He was walking like I'm talking to serious
like high care and this guy was going
like, you know, a half, not even a
half a mile, quarter of a mile an hour.
I was almost going to say a
half a mile every two hours.
And I quickly did the math. See I'm
getting smarter and stop laughing at me.
So, um, I liked this. I like you
coming in and out of the room laughing.
So I know that you're kind of like
a little mini studio audience,
so I know that at least some
of this is funny. So anyways,
this fucking guy is walking with a cane
and it's one of those deals where you're
like, there's no way it's
going to make it up to the top.
And every morning we would see this guy,
you know,
if we left at the same time and
then we go a couple of weeks,
we wouldn't see him. And he just kept
getting better and better and better.
And the how unbelievable did that guy
look the last time it was his arm and all
straightened out,
his left leg was working again.
Somebody should've made a documentary
about that cause that's the part of the
movie where we would have been
crying as opposed to being like,
oh I haven't seen you a couple
of weeks. You're welcome. Great.
We're with my mom and me son.
If you're going to talk,
come over towards the microphone.
I was,
I was saying we were with my
mom when we saw him. Right.
And how did that add to the story?
See,
this is why women stay at telling
stories. You're an asshole. Yeah,
but paint but paint the story
about the thing that we're seeing.
My mother was there and I saw a
Robin right next to a squirrel.
So anyways, using your
opposite hand, he's just like,
what the fuck are you talking
about? You know what, Nia,
just sit there and look pretty.
Awe. All right. Um, so anyways,
if you guys, I'm telling you to, um,
you can make yourself stroke proof.
That's stroke proof, but you can, you can,
you don't have to go through the
rehab just below the doctor's mind.
You know as you're writing a check with
your opposite hand for how much they
overcharged you and you're
already rubbing one out,
just staring at your fucking, was
it bed nurse? Is that what it is?
Wet nurse, whatever the fuck they
got. What nurses that breastfeeding,
was there something in the news
about breastfeeding this week?
Something about somebody who drinks breast
milk and then way beyond the age the
John Mayer do another interview for a Max.
Yeah.
You don't like John Mayer? He's a fucking
moron and he's not a fucking moron.
He's fucking okay.
What are you basing that on?
Everything that comes
out of his douchebag.
Give me an example.
That whole controversy
that came out recently,
the interview that he gave with
Playboy magazine, you know,
totally talking shit about everybody
and then making common wow.
First of all, it wasn't a controversy
really. Was it riding in the streets?
It was controversial.
He got on stage and started like fake
tearing up and apologizing to his fans and
being like, I'm sorry. I
was trying to be clever.
I just thank you guys so much
for sticking by me and blah,
Blah Blah and all that. Wow. Yeah. He, he
went to, he had a tear up
about it. He's so in Jesus.
I haven't seen, I haven't seen that
since Marlon Brando went off on the, uh,
went off on j town over there.
J town. You don't remember that
when he did that?
I got to keep it funny.
The end of his life. Yeah, he did
a little, he did wrote the, uh,
the prologue to the uh, um,
what's his face though to say
Martin Scorsese? Mel. Mel,
Mel Brooks. Mel Gibson. His little, yeah.
And just this whole thing about,
I, uh, black people love him because
he's, what did he say it? Cause I'm very,
whatever that means.
And then the interviewer,
who admittedly I think asked a douchey
question that kind of set him up was like,
Oh, do black women throw
themselves at you? And he was like,
he said something like, yeah, but my
dick rejects them. Like I have a wife,
I have a United colors of Benetton
heart in a white supremacists.
Dick.
Yeah, we can see how he's trying to
make a joke. He plays the Ukulele. Okay.
His comic timing is a little off.
You can see where he's going with that.
He knows what he likes. He knows what
he likes. He goes out and he tags it,
you know,
with his fucking updated mullet.
How could he look? If you're going to
be on coke, get another microphone.
If you're going to keep interjecting here.
I was trying to do a podcast.
You keep interrupting. I've had
enough of this joking. Okay.
You fucking control me with
that pouty face. It's fucking
annoying. Um, all right.
Uh, recommending books for the week. See
us. Yeah, exactly. What opera does it,
I can fucking do it,
but at least I have the honesty.
At least I'm honest enough to
say I don't read them. Nia,
as you sit there looking
into Oprah's eyes,
here's another wonderful
book that I didn't read,
but my intern said it was great.
I'm a book a bill.
I enjoy the podcast.
You have to check out a book called
the creature from Jekyll island.
It's a book about how the Federal Reserve
was started and they planned to be
able to have a system in place from the
start that would enable certain large
banks from being a,
from being bailed out if shit went down.
Apparently. Um, they've bailed out
banks before, just not a public,
oh,
that's fucking brilliant.
So basically they become the bank for
all the banks and then what they do is
they bail out some of them every time
they tank the economy and some of them
they don't.
And those things get consumed by the
other banks that exist and so on and so
forth.
Just like,
it's like a reverse prowl commercial
instead of just telling two friends and so
on and so on.
They're going the opposite direction all,
all the way towards one World Bank,
which is why, what are we down to?
Now we're down to chase wells Fargo,
Bank of America,
and uh,
John Mellencamp trust doesn't have one
out there for the farmers next to that
little pink house.
Sage Javo halls show.
Don't make it right. You want me to, let's
see a pair for you saw that. All right.
Also,
you should look up a recent article in
Philadelphia about how more than a dozen
armed state police raided a few small
ale houses in Philly to confiscate in air
quotes,
unregistered beer.
They basically stole over seven
grand worth of pricey beer,
most of which was most of
which was actually registered,
but not accurately due to a clerical
errors made on the end of the city.
So it was the city's fault too. That's
fucking hilarious. I, that's bad. I know.
That's mean. They shouldn't be
doing that shit. But you know,
they stole beer. I mean, come on.
It's like Pauline and the
pope of Greenwich Village.
I didn't rape his daughter.
I didn't spit this fat face. I
took money, Charlie fucking money.
They stole some bear, whatever.
They want to have a keg party. Yeah.
What are you going to do?
All right. Here's one for
you. I talked about the, uh,
going to the cloud nine, a titty bar
in Troy, New York and his attribute,
actually an article on there about this
fucked up strip club that I went to a
number of years ago. Uh, February 1st,
2008 see police shut down the cloud
nine and adult entertainment business.
That's because they have
the video store next to it.
I believe that's out in the garage for
those of you didn't listen last week.
It's a,
it's a titty bar that you walk into and
it's like walking into somebody's house
and the second you walk in
there you want to leave.
But there's so few people in there.
They all look at you literally that moment
where the needle goes off the record
or the laser goes off
the CD or the iPod skips.
I don't know what the fuck to
say about nowadays, but um,
how to say it now for nowadays technology.
But anyways,
the city shut down the
cloud nine, uh, because uh,
this afternoon for a multiple
code violations and charged
a 46 year old dancer,
a 46 year old dancer
with prostitution,
city officials said,
say that's for all you dancers out there.
That's what happens when you're in
your 20s. You can have an attitude.
But if you're 46 [inaudible] 46
years old and you're still dancing,
you better drop to your fucking knees,
sweetheart, if you want to make the rent.
Okay?
All the more reason to stop lying that
you're going to college and actually use
those fucking funny, that funny
money to go to college. All right.
Or you'll be working in the cloud
nine at 46. Wow. You know what?
I'm going to copy and paste that.
I'm going to print that sentence
and put it right above my desk.
Anytime I'm feeling bad about my life,
I'll be like,
well at least I'm not a 46 year old
dancer charged with prostitution
at the cloud. Nine to Troy, New York. Uh,
the raid followed a five week
undercover investigation. Yeah.
How hilarious is that?
What were the undercover cop got blown
by the 46 year old in which Troy and,
um,
run Sealy,
our police officers observed dancers
engaged in elicit sexual activities.
Do this reeks of a shakedown like the
cops didn't know that was going on.
I did a college gig out there and
figured out what the fuck was going on in
about four hours.
What happened that this 46 year old stop
giving the free blow jobs to the cops,
speaking of which, you know,
I heard that asshole in the,
in the Prius who couldn't stop his
car. Um, you guys seen that story?
Um, allegedly. Oh, that girls
titties are fake, by the way.
I'm looking at her right now. The
tits are fake. Nia. My fault. Wow.
That knocks her looks down by 40%.
I got to say, there's nothing,
there's nothing worse than fake tits.
It's just not,
that really just says
something about you that's, uh,
that's right up there with like
hair plugs that just says, you know,
I don't know what that is. I don't
know that does it, I don't know.
I'm starting to change my fucking
attitudes. I guess you want bigger tits.
You think that's bad, Nia? If you go on
and get big fake tits, those are fake,
right? Look at those.
Those are fake probably,
you know. Well when, when they were
around all the way up to the top,
they look fake in that picture.
They don't in the training video.
You're not near the microphone.
Okay?
You just sound like some crazy person
in a closet. You look adorable.
What are you getting all dolled
up for? Fuck you. I don't buy it.
What do you mean meet some hipster?
Is that what happened?
These vans skateboarding
shoes and is ironic.
ACDC tee shirt or Hardcastle
Hardcastle and McCormick backpack.
Fucking assholes. They mock everything
I loved when I was a kid. Remember?
Hardcastle and McCormick.
You always had a cool car.
Some chick he wanted to fucking bang
and then the old guy who was too old for
this shit. That's all you needed.
[inaudible] all right, so anyways,
this guy had a Prius. He couldn't stop
the car, so he had to call the cops.
I can't believe I fell for that one.
And people go and he was
doing like 90 miles, you know,
are really in the middle of the day. And
he had time to call the fucking police.
They caught up with them
and he didn't hit anybody.
Anybody out there driven 90 miles an
hour in the middle of the afternoon.
I don't even give a fuck.
Even if you're in Kansas,
there's going to be some asshole
drive and fucking 50 in the left lane.
So evidently that guy has a
history of a reporting back,
injuries in that type of
stuff. So, uh, I actually,
the more I'm thinking about this,
I'm really thinking that this is,
this is what a Chrysler did to the
Suzuki Samurai when it was outselling the
jeep. They just started a rumor that a
tipped over going two miles an hour. And,
which wasn't true, but everybody heard
it and everybody stopped buying them.
And that was it. Like, they fucked me
on the resale resale value on my car.
Who the fuck's gonna buy my Prius?
They're not.
Even if I have all the documentation,
I swear to God, they fixed it.
Um, I think the, the, the fucking
Prius is becoming, not today's a pinto.
When you think about that,
I think I just wanted to that point where
this podcast should have fucking ended
and I'm still talking or if you want to
see more videos of this fucking smoke
and hot chick, maybe she just got
fake tits. It's body rock.com.
Did I just get a look from you
Nia? She is. She's smoking hot.
Okay. Exactly. Thank you. All
right, let's wrap this shit up here.
Um,
I don't know if I have time to read this.
These things are getting too fucking long.
Let's end with this reality TV.
Uh, Bill, I'm originally
from Boston. I heard you.
I was listening to breakfast Simmons
podcast or is he refers to it fits dog
radio and this guy writes
beyond the outer limits of gay,
uh,
the guys on the wrong side of 40,
and he's still referring to himself
with the sub ebonic hip name with some
suburb OnDeck hip name. You know
what it really is? It's Chris.
Most people are too fucking stupid
to spell. Fitzsimmons I know.
Fits dog. Yeah, that's from back
in the day. I'm so yeah. Fit.
Say well you know what ease of it's a
great fucking show and now I'm going to
plug it fits dog radio and
the fact that you trashed it,
I didn't even notice that.
I guess it's gay. I'm just,
I'm on the wrong side of 42.
I'm 40 also.
I should say a anyways,
just want to say I listen to you your
most recent podcasts and I loved it.
You sound exactly like my
old friend. Uh, Kevin Burke.
Ah, Babababa thank you.
All this shit. Anyways, um,
you referred to reality
TV and your podcast and I
couldn't agree with you more.
Nobody will remember these assholes as
soon as, as, as season two comes around,
bring back scripted TV.
I don't care if I lose my job,
at least I'll have my integrity back.
Um,
I unfortunately work in reality TV
and can tell you from my experience,
every cast member I've ever
had the unpleasant chance
to chat with thinks he or
she was meant to be on television.
None of these fucking pathetic shit
has ever put in any hard work into it.
Making a career out of being
on TV and, uh, over never made.
I never put any hard work into
making a career out of being on TV.
They make me sick and I have
to work with them a lot. Uh,
well that's a tough fucking situation.
Um,
well, you know what, as
much as I made fun of that,
that cast from the Jersey shore actually
came back for 10 grand and episode and
a, I'm gonna make a
prediction. I think that that,
that next season is going
to fail miserably because
they're taking them out of
the Jersey shore and now that
they're going to take them down to a,
I believe Miami Beach,
which I might be a mistake.
That's like when a sitcom is kind of
jumped the shark and they don't know what
else to do.
So they do the trapped in a cabin episode
or Greg's trapped in a fucking meat
locker with Bobby and Bobby doesn't
like being small and now he likes being
small because he can crawl through
that little fucking window. That's,
that's when,
that's when a show is fucking over.
When Fonzie has to put up fucking jump
the shark with his leather jackets still
on. What are some other ones that, oh,
you gotta fucking introduce a cute little
kid or your dog pukes on the floor.
Cleo.
Fucking love this.
Anyways, that's the podcast for this
week. Hopefully it's up on iTunes.
If it isn't. Yeah, we're working on it.
I don't know what to tell you were
fucking working on it. And uh,
I appreciate that people are getting me
getting so mad at me that I haven't been
able to figure it out or hire somebody
at this point because that means you give
a shit,
you know? All right.
That's it for the podcast.
I'll have video next week
up on bill [inaudible] dot
com of my wonderful trip to
, uh, London Dublin and, uh,
in Glasgow, Scotland. And I'm coming
off the wagon in a hard fucking way.
All right, so I'm going to be back
next week. A little more bloated,
a little dumber, add a little something
else. So it's the magic number of three.
All right?
You guys have a great [inaudible]
[inaudible] [inaudible]
[inaudible]
[inaudible].