Hey. What's going on it's Bill Burr.
It's time for the Thursday afternoon,
just before Friday,
Monday morning podcast and just checking
in on you so I couldn't give you a big
one.
I fucked up my voice going all
the way back to San Jose Cruz,
uh, Beck, the San Jose Gigs. I
Dunno what I did. I know what I did.
I was imitating somebody yelling.
I was having too much fun.
I didn't come from my diaphragm and I
fucking choked up and I just fucking blew
the voice out.
That's what I did.
I always spent the main rotor and my
fucking throat is what had happened.
So now I, uh, I gotta go easy. You know,
I got drink a little throat coat tea,
you know. Um, anyways, what's
going on? How are you guys doing?
You're feeling good. I get energized
and excited about the fucking weekend.
Um, I've actually been
working out finally. I'm still
eating like a fucking moron,
so I haven't been dropped that
much weight, but I feel better.
You know what it is. I'm at this
fucking age. I swear to God.
I have one sip of this,
a one bite of that and it just fucks me.
It's unbelievable. I swear to God, if
I didn't work out, I would be like,
I would look like every other fucking
war on walking around the mall.
That's all it is.
I'm really starting to believe that a
lot of people now was kid knew we shove a
bunch of cake down our throats. I just, I
don't, I don't know what the fuck it is. I
know.
It was just weird how he said that.
I eat like a fucking
Olympian until about three,
four in the afternoon.
I work out like a soccer mom,
but I eat like a fucking
Olympian because my shoulders,
my shoulders coming
around, by the way. Um,
so I'm doing like the elliptical and
that type of shit put up for the fight up
until about three. I
fucking kill it, you know?
And then the weakness starts coming
in like a fucking cold front,
like a rainstorm.
The cloud start forming around
three or three 30 in the afternoon.
And I feel myself getting wheat going,
come on, Bill. Come on. Veggies, veggies,
fuzzy, shoved down your
pie hall. Let's meet baton.
That's me putting fucking
plywood over the windows.
You know, before I do something stupid.
And then just, you know, I dunno,
I keep trying to do this thing where
I'm going to be done eating around six
o'clock at night and then just
drink waters the rest of the time.
And if I get hungry, I'm just going
to have a little bit of celery.
And I know salaries on the dirty dozen
list of fucking pesticides is basically
anything where they just spray it
directly on like cantaloupes. Good.
Cause they spray the shit on, you know
the fucking Ebola, you know what I mean?
The AIDS virus, whatever the fuck
they do to keep the mosquitoes away,
they spray and spray it right
on the fucking cantaloupe.
But it doesn't get to the part that you
eat and you don't lick the outside of it.
You know the way fat show licked is the
bottom of his sneakers in the MTV cribs.
I will never get over
that. It's like, dude,
those were made in a sweatshop cause you
to walk around New York and we have no
fucking idea. Don't get
a tetanus shot, John. Um,
anyways, uh, fuck was I talking
about? And so salary, you know,
cause I'll spray it right on it cause
it doesn't have a husk or whatever the
fuck it is.
Um,
so this person tells you who just
go get organic salary, salary,
salary,
just get our Kerrick celery.
And I wanted it to be like [inaudible]
how to fuck you don't know where the fuck
any of this shit is. I think it all
comes from the same God damn farm.
And they go, oh that one looks greener
than those ones. Call them on organic.
That's about ready to go
and say that's organic.
And they'll think that the reason why
it's rotting is because, uh, you know,
because it's so fucking fresh.
I Dunno.
So at night I tried to do like the salary
have just a little bit half a spoonful
of sugar, no half full, half a spoonful
of peanut butter to try to get me through.
And, uh, you know, and then
you just go to bed like upset.
That's what happened. If you're
eating right, you go to upset,
you're not in a good mood. All right.
Now a lot of fucking nutritionists,
Dietitians, fucking personal trainers,
fucking crossfitters and all that.
It'll say like, no, if you really,
you shouldn't feel hungry at all because
you body will be full of all the new
cheesing needs and it will be
craving a shut the fuck up.
We get tight clothes dressing like
a goddamn x men to do fucking curls,
workout clothes at the dumbest.
It's a stupid as shit.
Yeah.
I was watching an old,
uh, odd couple Boto Ooh,
Ooh, Ooh, Ooh.
Two.
No. My favorite part of that song is
when the horn section kicks in ballet,
but that the to to do bow
[inaudible] back then when it
was actually a fucking orchestra,
it wasn't some guy with a laptop fucking
pumping his fists like he's going to
reboot the Arsenio show for the third
fucking time. It wasn't like that.
It was actual,
it was somebody that practice the
fucking trombone since he was knee high.
Fight in the dust bowl
during the depression right
before fucking Pearl Harbor
and he had to beat out
50,000 other Tuba players.
Everybody trying to put their own
stamp on [inaudible] but up buddy,
how you know,
you sitting out there all fucking nervous
known as dad's going to give him the
belt if he doesn't fucking book it right?
Yeah.
He's on the other side of the door just
listening to other people audition,
you know, proper proper
fuck. That guy nailed it.
Um, I was watching, I'm getting off track
here. I was watching that show and uh,
Oscar,
yeah,
Oscar w had come from the gym and he
just had on a gray sweatshirt and gray
sweatpants. He didn't have to go
in there all fucking aerodynamic.
Like he was doing a time
trial in the Tour de France.
All of this fucking shit that Nike makes.
Who's kidding?
Who that children make in
the Nike Factory? You know,
before they tried to jump out the
fucking window. Or is that apple?
I have no idea. It's all a
legend. I don't they, it,
it's fake news is children are happy.
They put the nets outside the window
because he enjoyed jumping into them.
It's a religious holiday. Um, Oh
God, I gotta work on my Trump.
I got to work my Trump. It's, well,
I'll tell you. It's rough, you know. Um,
that's all the fuck you need
now. Everybody's got all,
they got all the fucking,
but he's walking around dressed
like captain America. Oh my God.
I saw a shit show at the mall
yesterday and absolute fucking,
she,
she was such a shit show.
I actually was looking around for
someone to be trying to film me for my
reaction. Um, I had gone to the
mall again, that's twice in a week.
I never go to the mall
twice in a fucking week.
And this time I went to the growth. Now
if you don't, if you don't live in La,
okay.
The Grove is basically,
it's like going to times square on
New Year's Eve, except it's a mall.
It's a fucking nightmare.
All right.
But I was going down there
because I'm a man and I,
um, Deanna Adler, Steven
Adler, his mom who wrote, uh,
the wonderful book,
we'll actually jump tragic book and
then it comes out this sons, you know,
it starts off with sunshine,
it gets really fucking cloudy for come
on pages and then it comes out again.
It's a great book.
Um,
called a sweet child of mine and she
was doing a book signing and as I said,
I was going to be down there and um,
you know,
so I went down there and the book
signing was great. And uh, her sons,
Steven and Jamie came down that dude,
Steven Adler is fucking hot. Hilarious.
It was a huge crowd.
Thank you to everybody who showed up to
listen to my podcast and went down there.
Um, I think, you know,
had a couple of am and podcast listeners
down there that I ran into. Um, do,
he was fucking killing, killing,
say whatever he wanted to.
Some woman in the crowd. She's, Hi Steve.
I do you remember me back in the day?
I used to stand out from the
rainbow. He's like, I add,
I did I fuck you said
then Barnes and noble bar,
the noble is it? I don't know. I
don't read Barnes and noble or nobles,
NBA Final Stanley Cup final
and the Stanley Cup finals.
I can't remember in this
fucking bookstore, in a
microphone. He said that, um,
just complete mind me like a comedian
that just didn't give a shit. Um,
whether they ever work the club
again, it was fucking amazing. And uh,
he absolutely destroyed and uh,
and they sold a bunch of books.
So a order one today. It's an
incredible read, man. I'm telling you.
It's fucking brutal. It's fucking
like if you already read his, his, uh,
Stevens was brutal enough,
but now to hear the mother's side going
through the pain to try and help them
out. I tell you, I'm going to be honest
with you. I haven't gotten through it yet.
That's so fucking brutal.
It is.
I just got into the part where Stephen
starts going off the rails and I'm just,
I got mad. I got to go like one
chapter at a time. Um, in other words,
she pulls no punches. So, uh, definitely
check that out if you can. So anyways,
back to this shit show. So
I'm going to the mall, right?
And uh,
I Polen I valet right?
I valet like a fucking big
shot cause this is our,
this is to two things or I don't give
a fuck. I'm usually a frugal comment.
All right. My Malcolm
young tee shirt, right.
And I don't spend any fucking money cause
I know how this business works. Right?
When you go out, you buy something
flashy. It's a look at him. Look at him,
look at that freckled gun.
He thinks he made it.
Then they come over and they walk in
here and get right out from underneath.
That's not ongoing out. Uh
Huh. Not, not me. Nope. I'm
going to buy some strip malls.
I'm going to start having some money
coming in from outside of this VA me,
Hollywood,
um,
who's was who it's going to
be a sad ending just like
everybody else's. You know,
I'll come walking out one day on
some fucking telethon, you know,
my jaw fucking quivering uncontrollably.
And you guys all going to be like, oh,
what happened? Whenever I
used to be so young. Right.
And all you guys will have to shut
it off because I'll look so bad.
It's going to remind you of your
own mortality. Right? There you go.
There's something to look forward
to this weekend. Sorry. Anyways,
plowing ahead here. Um, so I'm
walking to the, to the mall, okay.
And a half shirts or back or
as they call them, crop tops.
All the ladies,
all the ladies who fucking
eat right or aware, a,
you know what I mean?
And I'm sure the fatties at some point
are going to hate them and say that those
crop tops are sexist and you're creating
an impossible body image and they're
going to blame those women that
actually took the time to fucking push
themselves away at five o'clock and
just sit there eat and salary and shit.
Pass that drinking waters
hating themselves. You know,
here's all the people that are going to
resent the crop tops where they, huh? Oh,
they're sitting there having a great
fucking time to getting gelato. Well,
the side a case,
that's something fat people
do. You know? Oh, I'm low.
I'm fucking blowing up this
spot. I live with a fatty, I do.
I'm telling you I have fat,
French, okay. All of that shit.
All of those ice creams that you see,
those unholy matrimonials of
fucking candy bars in ice cream.
Like who then now fuck thought
of that out. The fat people,
fat people, fat people, you don't Pat,
right?
They all came up with that shit.
They all came up with that shit late at
fucking night. They're like junkies. Okay.
And what happens is,
is after awhile doing heroin isn't enough.
You gotta put a little coke in there
and then you got to speed bullet.
So the fat fucking person speedball is
when you take and you, if you get fat,
you listen to it, you know it's fucking
true. You know you shouldn't be doing it.
You know, you're excited. You
know you're excited, right?
When you know you've got the
ice cream at home, right?
And you stopped at the red light,
you look over to the left and it's
at seven 11 right in that demon in.
You just goes, Hey, are you
driving? Then go get a Zag.
Not by,
he had vanilla ice cream at home.
I was kind of playing and he'd
need to take it up a notch bond,
you know you want to do it, you
know, you start crying. Well see him,
he likes it. So I'm just going
to have the ice cream man.
I said make a left turn,
drive in there and get her shot.
I'm not bar and you fucking turn in there
and you buy the fucking thing, right?
Like you're going in there or rent a porn
back in the 90s and element of shame.
You don't want to make eye contact, but
you don't want to look away. You know,
cause it got a couple of git films in
there. You know, you gotta have that.
Maybe I'm going to rent sleepless
in Seattle. Look on your face,
right as you walk into the pawn shop,
except it's the seven 11 and you walk
past all the other fatties in the fucking
people.
You know the junkies buying those fucking
hot dogs that have been there since
fucking Ronald Reagan got shot,
right.
You fucking go in there.
Probably grab a couple of healthy things,
like maybe one of their fucking bananas.
It's still green.
You know the hand of
the kid that picked it,
you know his fingerprints is
still fucking on it, right?
Then you just walk right up to the
cash register at the last second.
You try to make it seem like you know it
would not be old and you gotta be like,
uh, yeah, I'll stop right there.
You go the fuck exact nut bar.
And then you take that fucking thing home,
right?
Driving home now excited while
hating yourself. Excited.
Passing over the Double Line
into your fucking house, right?
You put on fucking Netflix and then
you sit down and what do you do?
You've got to take the ice cream out.
Now this part's the hardest.
It's killing you. You gotta let the
ice cream melt a little bit, right?
So you can fucking GM at Goddamn
candy bar right in there, right?
That's what fatty still, I don't
want, I'm talking about here.
So I'm at the fucking mall. Okay, I'm
going to fill up a half hour. Okay.
I gotta have some tangents here.
You know,
you want to do a half hour don't material.
Yeah.
You want to try to fill
it up a lot. Right. Um,
so anyway, so I'm walking through
so this fucking, you know,
this is another person that I can't stand.
You know,
cause I'm so goddamned perfect,
right?
The fucking person just refuses to
admit that they're old. You know,
I don't mean like just your old,
just go sit there on the fucking couch.
I don't mean that, you know,
definitely get out there.
You don't get yourself sitting here,
but you know, put on some sunscreen.
You old fuck.
Okay.
The people that you passed a certain
age and they're still trying to keep up
with young people with the styles
and shit. I saw this woman, right?
Tragic trauma from fucking 80 yards.
You could tell there was no father
ever in her life. Okay. Which is sad,
but you know, at some
point you've got, you know,
you've got to put your tips of ways and
you gotta look in the mirror and just be
like, look, all right, so he wasn't there.
Fuck that guy. He's a piece of shit.
I'm worth something. This
lady did not have that. Okay.
She's fucking walking. Okay.
She is like,
I don't know what age she was.
She should have been 33 do something about
or said 33 but she looked like 47 and
she was in good shape
for her fucking aids,
but she's wearing the crop top.
Okay.
And she's doesn't have a flat stomach.
She has just that little bit of of uh,
it caught belly or whatever you call it.
Right. So it's hanging over in the front,
it's hanging on the back and she's wearing
a fucking crop top and the crop top
said bitch on it.
She's wearing these little short shorts
and these fucking high heels and you
know,
you know the lady's feet after fucking
three decades of sticking yourself in
horseshoes, you feed a beat up.
You know, you see like the heels,
there's like those white circles
from like no blood supply and shit.
And it's just like, oh my God, get
yourself a player of flat shoes.
You know, I'll put on a sport coat
and you, you, you put on like some,
something flowing. You did your
time like young people be young.
So she fucking walks by and uh,
I dunno,
the only excuse I can make was maybe
she was a hooker. She was a hooker.
I don't have a problem with it. God bless
her. You know what I mean? If she had it,
she had a, uh, a fucking, I
don't know what you'd call it.
A goddamn I'm charity I would give to it.
But if she was just a regular
fucking person man, shit
show. Right. And once again,
half the reason why she was driving me
nuts is it just reminded me of how old I
was. I was like, uh,
I am old enough that I was alive
when that woman was still high.
Okay.
And I'm not going to apologize, Freddy and
this shit, if you're going to walk out,
okay, you got to know your age. All
of these fucking, you know, you know,
people tell you that, you know, you
know, being fifty's the new 40, you know,
fucking says that 50 year olds, no,
50, 50 put some fucking clothes on.
Um, Geez, I'm on a fucking tangent
here. Not a rant. It's not a rant.
Don't even say it's a fucking rant.
All you guys have ruined that word rant.
Rant is your complete. You're barely
holding your shit to get a rant.
Goes with raving like hall and Oates.
Rant and raving.
All right. This whole thing that, hey,
he talked about the same subject and
he reasonably calm tone for the last
fucking seven minutes.
He's on a rant. You don't,
you don't see no defines it that fucking
millennials. And you know why that is?
Cause they wear helmets when they ride
bicycles and they had play dates and they
had helicopter parents. So then in
Denver even know what yelling is.
God help us.
God help us when Isis that doesn't have
a plane or a boat somehow figures out
how to fucking get over here from the
other side of the world, you know,
in their pajamas or whatever the fuck
it is they're doing over there. Okay.
God help us when they show up in
the millennials have to fight him,
you know Jesus Christ.
Anyways,
so here's the good stuff.
The good side of it,
aside from the fact that DNA ads are
sold a bunch of fucking books. Um,
there's a store over there out of Detroit,
Michigan, and it's called Shinola.
So I'm going to shine.
I immediately,
I got to go in there because of that old
school expression. My Dad always said,
I'll cry set guy crazy.
He doesn't know shit from Shinola.
Wow.
That was a great one. That one of
my, another one of my favorite,
my dad got try sec.
I could fuck up a free lunch.
Oh that one made me laugh
every time you fucking said it.
Cause he always said it to
them about the right person.
And then just just doing the math.
Like what would you have to do to fuck
up a free lunch where you can literally
have the person, you know what fuck
you go somewhere else to get your food.
You know, like what would you have to
do? The guy's giving you a free lunch.
What would you say to the guy
other than thank you. Um, anyways,
so there was an expression, it was kind
of a Midwest thing, right? I think a,
you don't know shit from Shinola.
Shinola was a shoe Polish,
uh, that was in Michigan, I
believe outside of Detroit.
So the expression going,
you don't know shit from Shinola
basically means you would know if you are
shining your shoes with
shoe Polish or shit.
It's basically saying you're a fucking
moron. So I'm like, all right, Shinola.
I got to go in there.
So I come walking in there and the first
thing I say to the guy was like, dude,
I had to come in here.
Are you familiar with the expression?
You don't know shit from
Shinola? He goes, absolutely.
That's how we came up with the name of
the store. So evidently this company,
they make all these cool shit in America,
in Detroit,
a city that needs fucking industry,
great goddamn city,
just waiting for someone to invest in it.
Um,
they make all of this stuff.
So I fucking go in there, dude,
you got to look these things up, man. Um,
aside from all the watches and all the
shit they had and they had these fucking
bikes, um, you know, I'm actually
gonna post a video and, um,
and I say, hey dean, check this
shit out because I sending it to
Dean del Rey Cause Dean del Rey is,
is a, a a a connoisseur of fine shit.
The man does not own a lot of shit,
but the shit that he owns is fine.
She top of the line shit.
So they had bicycles in there and um,
they look like paperboard
bikes from the 1950s, you know,
when I fucking did my time from third
grade to ninth grade to like fucking,
I did it all the way up to
high school, you know. Um,
so I always liked those bikes even though
they look corny too, a lot of people,
but it was all modern technology.
So when you quickly looked at it,
it looked like a peewee
Herman style fucking bike, um,
with the bell and everything on it.
But then it was all this state of the
ash shit. It's kind of like a resto mod,
but like a bicycle version.
And they had this one,
it was like an 11 speed bike in all,
like the, all the gear changing was like,
I can't explain where the fuck or was,
it was like a,
I guess where you would say the
differential would be on a car,
but I'm just the part that it's
usually just part of the wheel.
All the gears were in there.
I'm not enough of a gearhead
to explain this properly.
They had the wires going into the bike.
It was all like streamlined.
It had fucking disc brakes on the front
and the back that things were crazy.
Crazy. So, um, wait a minute, I got
the fucking pamphlet right here.
I swear to God,
if I,
if I wasn't trying to downsize my life
and they weren't so God damn expensive,
I would have fucking bought
one. Um, yeah, I do these,
but these bikes, they're
really fucking, you know,
a lot of you guys are gonna think
these are nerdy looking bugs,
but I think they're fucking sick.
They got one called the Detroit aero ones,
the Bixby and one's the
Runwell. Um, and I'll tell you,
I'll tell you the chief, you know, but uh,
the fucking sick man. That's why I wish,
you know,
I don't know how it happened.
Part of it was because there was sweatshop
labor and then you had the unions and
the unions became what the fucking cops
were. And then everybody just said,
you know what? Fuck a union. And
they just left the country would,
wouldn't it be great if we just
made shit in this country again?
I'm telling me we got to start with,
we'd all right.
They got to legalize it on a fucking
federal level and we should make the best
fucking weed in the world.
We export that shit.
You get the whole world, you know,
fucking buy in are we? They got the best,
like the, like the way Cubans
got the cigar thing locked down.
We should do that with weed.
Okay.
The government should
fucking stay out of it.
Just make it legal and walk away
and then tax the shit out of it.
Okay.
And have your eyes wide shut parties and
fuck some other woman while you look at
your wife getting banged by senator,
whatever it is,
you upper 1% people fucking do. All
right, but just walk away from that Shit.
Let us grow the [inaudible]. Couldn't
we? In the fucking world. We export it.
We make all that fucking money. You get
your fucking your skin with the tax,
right? Send it to those costs
over at the Federal Reserve,
whatever the fuck it is they do.
And then you know,
you pay off the war and then we just,
right.
Just given the Tesla, we just fucking
will drive those fucking cars.
Have the fucking blue blood
constant run the oil industry.
Just slide them over
to the electrical shit.
They'll still make the
same amount of money.
Then we don't have to be
over in the Middle East.
Stick in our fucking nose and all that
shit. We all fucking come home. Right?
You put on a game,
you've got some solar energy,
you know you've got some
fucking weed. I know, I know.
I'm over simplifying all of
this. Yeah, I'm over simplifying.
All of us. Um, anyways,
I don't know what the fuck I'm
talking about here. Let me, uh,
let me do some advertising reads.
It's do some advertising reads,
man. Um, I got to type
in my fucking password.
It's of course vulgar.
I don't know why,
because of this fucking
anger that you have in you.
I don't know what your problem is anyway.
To own, to be the same thing. All right,
let's see. So everybody safe though. Um,
every hear of something being
a barrel of laughs. Well,
a barrel might not be enough laughs
in the days of horses and buggy. Well,
a barrel might've been enough laughs
in the days of horse and Buggies,
but you live now or do you gotta
put your laughs on the cloud
by the way? You don't have technology.
I fucking love those fucking headphones.
That guy gave me right from Bose wireless.
I was against that shit gone.
I don't need any more radio waves going
into my brain, man. I fucking love them.
I don't give a shit what it's doing to me.
I don't care if I turn into a fucking
Zombie. That's how convenient they are.
That's why CSO CSOS library of standup
television and original content provides
streaming laughs up to 1.7 mega
barrels and that's proven by science.
We see. So you get unlimited access
to seeso original series next day,
late night, hilarious standup
specials, binge worthy classics.
Sign up now to catch brand new standup
specials like the breakout special from
Faheem pronounced Fahim
Anwar like Anwar Sadat.
There's no business like show
business, uh, access CSO,
lot of acids content from
anywhere at anytime using ios.
No, an upside is that Iowa
Ios, android, Roku, apple TV,
Amazon fire TV windows
or x box one Amazon fire.
That sounds like a cologne. Ready for the
punchline. CSOS just three 99 per month.
No joke. Three dot three 99 per
month for all the comedy you want.
Anytime anywhere ad free.
Just go to seeso.com right now to sign
up for one month for free with Promo Code
[inaudible] at checkout.
That's [inaudible] dot com
spelled s e s o.com Promo Coper,
Jesus Christ. That's seeso.com Promo
Code Berg. I'm a check out some of those,
you know, cause everybody's on Netflix.
You know I want to be different man.
I'm over here on CSO about
Amazon, man. All right,
me on this beyond [inaudible] me on
the checking out new stream and do,
do, do beyond days beyond Asia
balls. Be fucking gleaming.
Watch a bunch of fucking standup specials.
Rub your Tate.
I guess the material,
it's twice as soft as fucking cotton.
Yeah, but da Ba Booboo, Uber do.
But elevate your underwear game
to the next level with me on this.
You've perfected your wardrobe. But what
about this stuff? Nobody gets to see.
What about the stuff that
actually touches your junk?
If you've been settling for store
bought underwear, five packs.
I have something that will change
your life for the better me undies.
What's the first thing you put
on the last thing you take off?
It's your underwear less.
You Matthew Mcconaughey make your
most important piece of clothing.
The best part it can be with me on this.
You know what?
I was just a picture and like a cop
at the end of the day, you know,
it takes off everything from the waist
down and now he's completely naked, right?
And then he takes off his gun.
They, excuse me, detective,
you've got the fucking thing right?
Is that two village people, few guys,
me and these are designed in La and made
from sustainably sourced micro modal,
modal of fabric, three times
softer than cotton. And guess what?
You can save time and money each
month with a monthly subscription.
How much do you shit your pants that you
got to have a monthly subscription? Um,
I have underwear from
like two presidents ago.
If you're not ready for their
subscription, that's okay. Hey,
you can still say that's because me
undies is offering you 20% off your first
pair.
Just use our special URL me
undies.com/burr and get 20% off.
Your first pair said, go ahead,
revamp your underwear drawer.
You deserve it once and you deserve it.
Get yourself some new underwear. You
fucking animal. Once again, that's me.
undies.com/ [inaudible]
[inaudible] dot com slash Berg.
Um, all right. How much
time we got left off?
28 minutes here and I got a
phone call in seven minutes. Uh,
thank you to everybody that watched the,
a tour of Phoenix from my yet to be
critically acclaimed and acknowledged
towards of cities. Uh,
I did one in San Jose.
That one's going to be coming up soon.
It's all on my youtube page,
which I of course do not have in
front of me. Just look up the, um, uh,
Bill Byrd tour of Phoenix and
you'll be able to find it. Uh,
we'll send another link out to it.
Like I told you my fucking youtube page.
That's got to be blown up soon.
I hired a fucking animator.
I got some people doing some shit right?
I'm gonna be doing towards them
every fucking city. Excuse me,
that I go to get the hiccups. Um,
and all of that shit. All right,
so here we go. What can we talk about
here in the final couple of minutes? Uh,
all the Bruins, the Bruins had
their backs up against the wall.
We were after having a nice
comfortable fucking leave,
we would up to like a fifth seat.
We tumbled all the way down to an eighth
seed one ahead. The Tampa Bay lightning.
All right.
And I wasn't paying attention to Tampa.
I was just watching the Bruins lose.
And then I looked at the fucking standards
because one night I was watching the
lightning play in the Black Hawks
and the Blackhawks dog dog, dog.
We're up fucking four to one and you know,
the lightning started coming back
and I'm fucking in it. Oh Shit.
Forward it to Oh shit. What
the fuck? What a great game.
I didn't realize that
that was hurting my team.
And they ended up winning in overtime.
They get two points and they will,
they will one point behind us. So we beat
the fucking, uh, we beat long island.
All right.
Long Island be the islanders that playing
Brooklyn. Figured that one out. And um,
and then Tuesday night we
beat the fucking press.
So tonight,
who do we got?
The fucking staff is such a Boston week,
predators,
stairs. Um, that's who
we're playing tonight.
And in the lightening have the Detroit
Redwings who are not having a good year,
but they, you know, they
always get some fucking
Sergei Federoff next phenom coming
up. You know, they kind of like, uh,
the Pittsburgh penguins where they just,
they got the fucking,
they got that down man. Somehow they,
you know, I mean the penguins are crazy.
Do they had fucking Mario Lemieux and
Jaromir Jaga then he had like a fucking 10
year drought,
15 year drought or whatever,
and then they come back with
fucking Gino and sit, you know,
and you know something,
the Bruins could be like that if we
didn't fucking ship 'em out all the time.
You know, we had Tyler say again, Hey,
what'd you have a fucking cores light
a get out of town buddy. That's, so,
that's not what we do here in this racist
town. This is an upstanding community.
So we shipped him out
and now look what we got.
We got fucking Pasta Knoxx
become, uh, you know,
he's become a super sa Brad Marshawn,
you know,
it's just like what a
Tyler was still there.
You could centrally be rolling in three
fucking, I don't know shit about hockey,
but I mean, I don't know. We're always
doing shit like that. Look at you.
Look at all the goals Joel.
Joe Thought and scored in San
Jose for why they never won shit.
We didn't get shit for him in the fucking
trade. We just didn't want to pay him.
But anyways, anyways, that's an
important, we have the stars tonight.
Okay.
The stars at night are big
and by Beekman out of Texas.
Um, but Dallas is not deepen our to
Texas. It's right out there in the open.
So we're going to win tonight, I hope.
But you never know. They got Jamie van,
they gave fucking Patrick's yet.
Patrick shap on the Dallas Diaz.
I'm the next f one race by the
way, is in, I'm not this Sunday.
It's going to be next Sunday. And that's
in China in dokie. And by the wait,
speaking of China, um, I
got satellite radio now.
So I finally get to listen to
the Howard stern show again.
And his wife has some sort of cause.
And you know,
I'm always worry of a cause dude,
I only listened to half of it and
I had to turn the fucking channel.
How would is describing they got some
day over there or I don't know what the
fuck they're doing with dogs
where they torture them.
They scare the shit out of them.
They think that they have like adrenaline,
you know, high anxiety. It
makes the meat taste better.
They fucking torture them in front of
the other dogs to make them more for the
dogs here, the, the, it's, it's
going to give you the rest of it.
It made me sick to my fucking stomach.
So there's a petition that you can sign
to try to get the fucking animals that
are doing that shit to stop on Howard
stern.com you just scroll down and uh,
you know,
I had to sign that shit cause uh,
even if you got to do something
about how to you do that to a dog,
you know what I mean? I know what
all you vegetarians, you'd say,
well the shit they do to cows and all
that, you know what you fucking right.
Isn't that a way to just,
you know,
fucking give a cow to behind the year
when it's not even like paying attention.
The thing is once you kill one,
the other sense it and everyday it's,
it's fucking brutal. But you
know, then at the end of the day,
a fucking hamburgers delicious. I
don't know. But do you know you,
why don't you fucking have some cows?
Maybe it's because they have
a billion people over there.
So there's not enough cows for
people. I don't, I don't fucking know.
But I love dogs.
So if you love dogs,
Howard stern.com sign that fucking
petition anyways. And then as far as, um,
the motorcycle racing goes,
I'm going to try and get into
this shit cause he's racist.
A nice increase races got a
little Christopher Walken.
There is rice is there.
I'm not going to do Christopher Walken.
All right. Listen to fucking Craig.
Guests are fucking Jay
Moore. Uh, the, the next, uh,
I think the first one of that season,
if you want to get into racing now,
motorcycle racing is fucking insane
cause they still bump each other and shit
and they're on motorcycles doing that.
Don't no fucking 190 miles an hour.
That one is on April 9th.
Sunday,
April 9th in Argentina at
3:00 PM east coast time.
I'll actually be in San Antonio.
Um,
and uh, let's see. So that game
will come on from me at two o'clock.
For me.
It's going to come on at two o'clock and
I just have to figure out how the fuck
I'm going to, uh, where the hell I'm
going to watch it. I think it's on Fox,
but uh, I'm totally into this shit up
totally into it. All right. All right.
That's it. Everybody. Go fuck
yourselves. Have a great weekend.
You [inaudible] and I'll, uh,
I'll talk to you on Monday
with, um, also listen to this music here,
a little bit of musical or music bed here
and then we're gonna play you some, uh,
some classic Monday morning podcast that
Thursday afternoon just before Friday,
Monday morning podcast from a Thursday
or a Monday from the year gone by.
Um, a lady roommate. Hey
Bill, huge fan of the show.
Wanted to see if you had any
advice for this situation.
I found myself in a
little over a month ago.
I moved to Phoenix and moved
in with the friend of Iad.
You go up camelback mountain yet. That's
a fucking great hike. You got to go up.
That one.
Somebody dies up there every fucking year,
which always me up to be
like alone in the wilderness.
While you can actually see
buildings in the distance.
It's got to be so frustrating.
Um,
little ugly ass fucking roadrunners.
All right.
A little over a month ago I moved to
Phoenix and moved in with a friend from
college.
No real problems there.
But he did have a female college
age roommate that he got along with.
So we ended up setting settling
on a three bedroom. All right,
so it's two dudes in a chick.
This is already like a sitcom.
This is like fucking
reverse three's company,
Colin. [inaudible]. Well it gives us,
I'll fucking, America was just like
that, you know, ice and simple.
I guess it was probably fucked up then.
I was just too young to notice
sitting there eating a popsicle.
We'll look is his own
bloody do Beatty booty.
Boop. Larry's upstairs.
50 years old. Fucking everything
that moves. Um, all right.
I only know a few people in town
and my work schedule is grueling.
It makes it really hard to meet to too
many people over the course of the week.
All right,
so you're setting up to your excuse to
why you're already fucking your friends
friend. All right. You know, I work,
Lord, I can't get to meet people. Uh,
why go out for pussy when it's right next
door? I get it buddy. I get it. You know,
it's discovery channel.
Does the line go after the toughest
zebra or the fucking wounded one of the
little baby one or the one walking
around wearing the fucking juicy shorts.
Um, I'm sure by now you've pinpointed the
key word in the above paragraph. Female.
Yes, I am Sir. Yes I have. So
you can see where this is going.
My second weekend here,
we all go out get sloppy jalopy drunk
and she informs me that she broke up with
their boyfriend of five
years. Ah, wonderful.
So of course I do the gentlemanly
thing and fuck your brains out.
Oh, he goes, oh, of course. Yeah.
I do the gentleman thing and fuck her
brains out or flop around like a dead fish
on top of her. Um, it's one of
those too. Once I'm done, I leave,
I go to my room and we don't mention in,
we don't mention it,
don't mention it in the morning.
And it's not awkward at all. Ah,
if I add the Allah your song,
Oh, that's fucking great.
Would you guys look down at me if I
told you that I was just jealous of this
person right now?
That's fucking perfect.
And the hardest thing is going to be for
you to not fuck this up for you not to
develop feelings. Okay. You know,
that's going to be a hard one.
But if you can somehow do it,
if you can somehow keep
yourself separated, you know,
you could just,
it would be like a,
it'd be like stamps.com having the
post office and you fucking apartment.
Now you've the post ups should apartment
and now you have this blow job machine
also there.
I mean it's tremendous,
you know,
and then all you gotta do is just decide
what kind of food you're always going
out for and you really like
and you buy that appliance,
be it a Panini maker or a
fucking cappuccino maker.
You got that stamps.com and the blow job
machine down the hall. And I tell you,
lets it get the NFL package,
call it a life.
Um, so anyways, he goes,
we've gone about doing
this for a few weeks now,
but since I'm never home during the
week and she works during the day on
weekends, we don't exactly see
each other. And when we do, we,
we literally never say anything about
it or hint edited, all et Cetera.
Dude,
please don't fuck this up.
Please don't fuck this up. Okay? He says,
my question being as this is the first
time something like this has happened,
is this a time bomb waiting to happen
where all the crazy is going to come
flying out like the Ark of the
covenant or is she just rebounding?
And I'm the free and clear until I
settle in and find something else.
Keep in mind, keep in mind that Jesus
Christ, sorry I didn't go to church today,
has died for rose and
is risen from the grave.
He did it all for you.
There's no way for you to thank him
once you give us a bunch of money.
Um,
keep in mind I've never been accused of
being good looking and she's pretty cute
with the grade a ass on her.
Any advice is appreciated and
I guess go fuck yourself. Um,
okay. All right. You did
the right thing. You know,
you've got a great situation and you
don't want to fuck it up. You know,
this is like the first time
I went deep sea fishing.
I got a bite and I looked at the dude next
to me, my doing it right. What do I do?
And I let it run a little bit. Let it
run a little bit. Hey, bringing it right.
You're doing the same thing. All
right, so what is your questioning?
Is this a time this, this is okay, this,
there's the wildcard that
she's a psycho, but she, she,
she would have shown her colors by now.
I would think if she was a psycho,
you know, there would have been some sort
of, you know, God, you worked so much.
I don't get to see you when your 20
[inaudible] going to do on that,
you know,
fucking twisting your arm here or
doing something fucking annoying.
Some sort of annoying sort of touching.
Right? So she hasn't done that.
She's totally putting out the vibe
that
she's basically in the mindset.
It's this thing seems like it's
exactly what it is. You know,
she was in a relationship for
five years, five years. Man.
She's got to decompress from that.
All right.
She likes to go out and get hammered
and get fucked and go to bed and not see
your dumb ass for the whole week.
All right? Just keep it at that.
This is the deal.
You don't ever bring it up either.
You don't have to bring it up or you
just keep it the way it is. All right?
If she's barely talking to you,
you barely talk to her and he'd just have
fun with it and this is another thing
you do. All right. Have
Fun with this shit.
What is some things that you always wanted
to do with the woman and you haven't
done yet? This is the girl
you do it with. All right,
and she's going to probably do it with
you too because she doesn't give a fuck
about you, which is a great thing.
What you have sir, as a fuck buddy,
congratulations. This is your first
one. This is what men dream of.
This is what men really want for, this
is what we want for Christmas. You know?
If we could just have a fuck buddy,
somebody who was clean with no diseases,
you know,
and somehow then had this pill they
could give you that you drank, you know,
you washed it down and it got
rid of any sort of fucking guilt.
It will be perfect. But you're
single do to, there's no guilt.
So my thing is just don't, don't open
your mouth and fuck this thing up.
All right. You got a great thing going.
Okay. Just keep doing what you're doing.
And uh, the only thing I would correct
is this whole thing where you say,
you know, I'm not that good looking at
guy, you know, work on your self esteem.
She's pretty cute. Hey, you know,
good for her. She got a nice ass.
Why don't you go to fucking do something
to it, but not during the week.
No fucking during the week
you focused on your job,
you have a great fucking
time. And I know it, you know,
I guess eventually if you do meet somebody
and you start bringing them around,
there's part, there is a potential, but,
uh, you just got to nip that shit in the,
but I guess you've actually met
somebody that you liked, uh,
that Jesus. Yeah, I
didn't think about that.
All right. First, first things first
before we even get over to her.
Uh, I mean dis, okay. Whole
new can of worms here, dude.
You have to be cool first and foremost.
All right. Because eventually,
you know,
if she meets some other dude,
you've got to make sure that
you're not going to flip out.
So do not develop any
feelings for this girl.
And the only way you're not going to
develop any feelings with the squirrels.
If you see her once a fucking
week and your Banger, okay?
You don't want to know how many
brothers and sisters she has, right?
It's like reservoir dogs. You guys
shouldn't even know each other's names.
Tell you name them to be a fucking, I
don't have any name. Yeah. You know,
you don't. You want that. All right. All
right. You fucking Mr Pink or whatever.
She's mister blonde or
Mrs Blonde. Uh, sorry.
Um, that's the only thing
you got to worry about.
All right.
So,
and I've learned to just be totally
fucking up front and honest.
So if I got some new girlfriend,
I would just tell her what's up?
What's your deal? Yeah. I'm single.
I'm kind of banging my fucking roommate
once a week, you know, we don't, you know,
just sort of a fuck buddy thing. Oh,
does that make you uncomfortable? Well,
all right, well then this relationship
isn't going to work because you're already
uncomfortable with me.
Now if I got feelings for you,
I wouldn't keep banging her,
but you know,
I'm not taking it off the table
after one fucking trip to Applebee's,
Jesus Christ free pussy. That's
like free shoes for you, right?
You know, I dunno. That's all I all, I
can tell you dude, you can't control her.
Who gives a fuck?
Dude?
Someday you're going to be 50 and you've
got to be married and she's going to be
bitching at you about something. And
even if you love or you're at some point,
you just can be reminiscent going,
you know,
where my life was the greatest was when
I had that little fucking goddamn three
bedroom apartment.
All I had to do was make this amount of
money a week and I had some check once a
week with just fucked my brains out and
not talk to me for the other six days.
Goddamn dream. You got
the dream, sir. All right.
And I don't know where you're going to
wake up, but enjoy it while it lasts.
Okay. I hope I answered
your question. I really do.
You're in a hell of a situation.
Enjoy it. All right. Kudos to you.
I am jealous.
Hey, what's going on?
This is bill bar and this
is, uh, this is the Monday morning
podcast. This is the official one.
That other one that I just left was
a, was an unofficial and was not, uh,
was not sanctioned by the board of
directors of the Monday morning podcast.
I've had a crazy day. I've been talking
all day long. Uh, trying to be cute,
trying to be funny.
You're trying to sell tickets from my
theater dates this weekend and I am pretty
much all fucking talked out. So this is
going to be a straight ahead, no bullshit.
Let's get right to the meat of the
fucking issue podcasts because,
uh, I'm going to the ranger
game tonight and, uh,
I'm going to a bar first, which
is stupid. I'm going to get sick,
but I don't know how to say no, you
know, I don't know how to say no.
What the fuck else am I gonna do?
You know,
so just regard the unofficial podcast,
which said that I would be doing this
podcast after the hockey game cause I'm
not,
I just decided fuck it.
I'll do a quick 20 minute one
within 19 minute intro. Um,
if you're new to my podcast,
I do one of these every Monday and I do
them right here on Bill bird.com and uh,
I also do them on my myspace
page. No, I am not on Facebook.
If you want to know why I'm not
on Facebook for a, to the podcast,
the one before this.
And even though it's unofficial,
it is my official feeling
of fucking Facebook.
Do you like this is footnotes with this
podcast. All right. And this is the deal,
man. Every week I do one of these
and I answer people's questions.
I read shit that they find underrated.
Overrated. I give people advice,
I read stories about revenge and whatever
else this thing spins into when I also
heightened my gigs. Like for example,
this weekend I'm going to be on April 3rd,
I'm going to be at the lake shore
theater in Chicago, Illinois. Um,
all the information is on billboard.com
myspace.com/bill burr.
It's all up there.
And on a Saturday I am going to be at the,
uh,
Trump marina.
Isn't that what it is?
I can't remember. I think
that's what it is. Yeah.
Will be in Atlantic city
at the Trump marina.
Why doesn't that sound right when it
comes out on my fucking mouth or whatever,
that's where I'm gonna say I'm
going to be a Trump marina.
We just added a second show, which is
why I've been doing all this media today,
which is why I'm fucking half asleep.
So I'm going to sign a little bit drunk,
but I'm not. Um, that Gig
is this Saturday, April 4th,
and I will be working
with young Joe de Rosa,
one of the new stars of the
OB and Anthony Show. Um,
and he will also be on the opening.
Anthony show with me as well.
I this whole week,
I'm going to be on it on Tuesday,
Wednesday and Thursday of this week.
That would be March 31st April 1st and
April 2nd and Joe to Rose's coming on on
April 2nd. So there you go. Look at that.
I got all my high-pitch out
of the way and like I said,
this is going to be really quick. All
right. And uh, let's talk about my gig.
This past weekend I was working at the
house of comedy in Saint Louis and I had
a great time,
unbelievable crowds all weekend.
Uh, my, uh,
my eight person fan club showed
up to members strong and a,
I want to thank them for showing up.
Uh,
that's the group of people
that followed me to Nashville.
And you guys remember that story
when they went to Kansas City?
You want a quick recap because we've
patched things up, um, between,
it's actually had a blowout with
my fan club. There's only, I can't,
who the fuck gets into a fight with
the fucking fan club? All right.
I just like saying I have a fan club.
I feel like a teen idol.
Like it should be singing some song
about teenage teenage anx, you know,
no bill. We don't, yeah,
you deal with my fucking hair slicked
back if I still adhere to slick back,
you know,
I'm looking over my shoulder
like a fucking gay actor
trying to be straight and
then I fucking cat crashed my car and
Mulholland drive is basically what
happened.
My Fan Club last time they saw me,
they went to at least
these St Louis Chapter. Um,
um, basically they went to Kansas
City when I was working the Improv.
I'll tell you this story
really quick. And, uh,
they came in and they were excited
and evidently they were being loud.
So I'm sitting in the green room and
the bouncer, it comes back and says,
hey bill, this is a table. People out
there that really loud, they seem drunk.
Do you want me to tell
him to, uh, you know,
sort of chill out a little bit before he
go up? And I go, sure, that'd be great.
And evidently the bouncer goes out there
and he says to the fan club, he says,
Hey, Bill Burke told you guys to shut
the fuck up or something like that.
So naturally they were besides
themselves and for some reason decided to
continue to drink so they could have a
nice rational conversation about it after
the fucking show. So the show
went, next thing you know,
I get 20 people come to me with, hey,
bill written on their shirt and uh,
they're all telling me what
a fucking asshole I am.
And I had nothing to do with it. And I
explained myself on a podcast about it.
I don't know when the fuck is was. This
was years ago. And uh, but anyways,
it's the first time I've met any of
them since then. And they were nice.
They didn't try to kick the shit out of
me. So evidently everything is all good.
So I want to say thanks to them for
coming out and also thanks to that crew of
guys from the University of Kansas.
That's right. Mother fuckers.
They're sitting right now around a laptop,
high fiving each other,
probably doing drugs,
legal or not legal.
I want to thank all those guys, those
motherfuckers on college, kid money,
you know, drove all the
way from uh, basically uh,
the other side of Kansas
City to come out to my show,
which was really flattering
on college kid money.
Unless they got one rich French,
which they probably do.
There's always one rich front and you
act like you're friends with them.
I'm going to blow up this spot right now.
Act like you fucking friends
with them and you're really not.
He just had gas money in the fucking car,
you know,
then all of a sudden you wreck it.
And then what do you do?
You have the guy who
should be in a biker gang,
but for some reason he's still in college,
welds a new front end to it and you
turned it into a float and then you do a
bunch of shit that would be considered a
terrorist act in the air with the whole
nine 11 Patriot Act. You'd never get
away with it, right? Sound familiar?
All right. Animal House reference for
all you youngsters out there. All right,
so this is the Monday morning podcast and
this is going to be a lean mean one in
these lean mean times of a fucked
up economy. Anybody else who do uh,
did the right thing with their money
and they're sick of people telling them
that they have to pull themselves up by
their bootstraps. It's like, no I don't.
No, I don't. I have to fucking,
I have to. What do I have to do?
I don't know what have to,
I had to pick myself up off the floor
because he had done fucking ass.
Knocked me down to it. I
didn't do anything. You know,
this whole all this time and make the
front of that MTV cribs lifestyle,
I should have been living
in everyone else's,
doesn't make a fucking
difference in the end. You know,
I'm trying to figure a way out, man.
I'm trying to get off the wheel.
I was trying to stop running on the
wheel and I can't use fucking bankers.
Got The whole thing sewed up. If it
go, this is another dick in my face.
There's no way to
fucking escape this shit.
I'm really just going to have to work
until I'm 106 and then I'm going to die
and then that's going to be the end of it.
You know,
you think I don't have dreams.
I don't want to retire open some fucking
stupid ass bar down on the Florida keys.
Sit there in a Hawaiian shirt.
You know what I mean?
It's like fucking sell drinks to convicted
felons and a gay mass murderers who
are on the run because they
killed the fucking, sorry,
I can't remember how that
one went in front of you.
What Andrew Cunanan referenced there?
What did he kill Versace?
Uh, I saw a really good looking
woman sort of down. You don't,
you don't like my girl gets like so good
looking is so super model looking that
they kind of look like an alien.
I was actually doing this interview with
this Guy John McCarthy who has his own
fucking website which escapes me.
The name of it escapes me cause I'm half
asleep and I did 10 of those interviews
today but we were looking at this one.
We were like,
she's beautiful isn't she said,
yeah, she's unique. He's like,
is kind of looks reptilian.
There's something about like once you're
taller than five 11 as a woman and you
still are somehow under 120 pounds,
you know your eyes get really big.
You just, you walk like literally alien.
He look, you know what they look like.
They're little,
they look like big praying mantises
praying mantises that you want to fuck.
Okay.
Um, anyways, let's get to the
podcast questions. Like I said,
this is going to be a real quick one.
Other this,
we're only 10 minutes in and Mario
on the questions. All right bill,
I love this question by the way, cause
this question needed to be asked. Bill,
what the fuck is the deal
with Ed hardy shirts?
Can everybody just relax,
take a big inhale and then exhale and
just be happy that somebody questioned
those fucking things? I'm gonna read it
again so much. I love this question. Bill.
What the fuck is the deal
with Ed hardy shirts?
Seems like it has become the
uniform of the power tool.
Am I an ask for not realizing these
aren't the, these are the coolest things.
Wait a minute.
Am I asked for not realizing these
are the coolest things ever or am I
accidentally smart for realizing that I
don't need to wear a dress shirt with a
drawing of a dragon fucking Buddha,
thanks in advance for help, Todd,
you couldn't be more right. I don't,
I don't get those. You know what,
those things are going to be, you know,
every period I'm going to
talk about fashion right now,
every period has a moment
where somebody where you know,
a style comes out where
you know that you know,
10 20 years down the line when they do
the dazed and confused movie of that
period, that's like, you know,
they'll try to act like
everybody was wearing that shit.
Jesus Christ built say what you're
trying to say. But at this way,
I was alive during the 70s but
I never worked bell bottoms.
You know what I mean?
I never had a big pink comb in my
back pocket with feathered back hair.
Brandon, my hair used to be like a
fucking Brillo pad so I couldn't do it.
But you know what I'm
saying? Well, you know,
whenever they do a movie about
the 70s everybody looks like that.
You know what I mean?
Everybody dresses like that.
That's what those Ed hardy shirts are.
Those are the fashion mistake of a,
of this time period did fucking horrific.
And not only that,
that whole a bunch of
drawing on your shirt.
I wasn't that in like three years ago.
I remember when I was still trying to
be young three years ago at a, a at a,
at a very, uh, very tipsy 37
years old. I, I, you know,
I started wearing shirts like that.
It was those shirts where initially for
the people who weren't man enough to get
a tattoo over their entire torso.
And I remember like,
literally like I think like a year and a
half ago, I was just like, you know what,
these, these fucking bedazzled shirts
with the eagles and the fucking,
uh, I dunno, ant eaters on them,
whatever the hell they are with all
these like prison tattoo designs,
this shit's over. And evidently it
isn't. They're continuing with them.
And Ed hardy doesn't dare like these.
Uh,
it's like those awful
designs and bright colors,
you don't seem like they would wear them.
And the growing up Gadi sort of
kids seems like they would wear,
you know, big Wareham and they'd
still get pussy, you know,
cause they got the guns, they've got the
attitude, you got the end, they go red.
Now you get the attitude that
movie fast times at Ridgemont High,
every movie reference I'm gonna make is
gonna be fucking 30 years old at this
point. All right, you're absolutely right.
I don't know what the deal
with Ed hardy shirts are.
They fucking horrific and not even
Armenian guys wear them. They,
at least as far as I know,
they seem to wear those other bizarre but
there bizarrely designed and they step
out of Maseratis or at least to Armenian
guys did at a car wash I saw in La.
So now that becomes every
Armenian guy in my mindset,
but that's even fucking make
sense. I don't care. Okay.
I'm working on five hours sleep and I've
been running my mouth. I'll fucking day.
Uh, and yes, I will be giving excuses
every five seconds for this podcast.
All right. Question number two, Bill,
I'm recently new to your podcast,
but thanks to iTunes or the,
the, uh, my podcast question is,
do you follow the World Cup
soccer in general? If so,
do you root for any team specifically?
And if not,
you should consider the Seattle sounders
then come up to Seattle for his show
and a game they,
Seattle sounders.
All right.
Just when I thought Ed Hardy was going
to be the worst thing I could picture in
my mind,
I'm just picturing the crew of people
who sat around a fucking conference table
and came up with a name
for your soccer team. Dude,
I'm not shitting on soccer before
I trashed the name of your team.
Let's get back to the first question. Do
I follow World Cup soccer now? I don't.
I would love to. You know, I,
I've tried to follow that uh,
w premier league. I tried to get into
it cause I think it is cool as hell.
And I actually, I actually liked
soccer. You know, I actually like it.
I know a lot of Americans don't like
to shit, but I actually like it.
But I don't like American soccer just
because Americans don't seem to be into it
that much. So it just kinda seems
like you're watching the WWE NBA.
There's no excitement in the crowd.
And you know,
I can't get excited if no one else
is excited cause I'm codependent. So,
uh,
the only time I followed the World Cup
is when they actually have the World Cup.
And when I watch it, I just root
for the countries that I am. Um,
you know,
that my ancestors were,
I guess some German Irish
with a little bit of English.
So I pretty much just, I root for uh,
Germany because I think it's funny.
It's just funny to root for Jeremy to
be in a crowd of people rooting for
Germany. It's just so fucking Cliche,
like Naziesque, you know what I mean?
There's no way to fucking sit there and
a crowd full of people be sharing on
Germany and somehow not feel like you're
advocating the policies of Adolf Hitler.
That's what I, that's what I like
about Rudy for Germany is the,
he just start laughing halfway through
it. Like, Hey, wait, am I not be,
oh wait a minute. No, no. I'm just
waiting for the soccer team. That's right.
That's right.
And uh,
I also root for the teams in South
America because evidentaly if they miss a
penalty shot, they go home and they
get executed. So, um, but you know,
there can only be one winner.
So getting back to, uh,
the Seattle sounders, I get
it. What? Because uh, what is,
what is outside of us at Puget sound?
I know that some sort of sound,
I just hate that fucking word.
I gotta look it up again.
What the fuck is this sound?
You don't
something?
I don't know that I could define any sort
of body of water other than an ocean.
I know what an ocean is, right?
I know what the fucking ocean is.
We're trying to psych myself
up so I can answer this.
And Ocean is a, it's a lot of
water. Water between continents.
Yeah.
What else does it have? Well, I
had sharks that has salt water.
I'm a fucking moron.
What does this sound?
We're just going to type sound in.
Let's see what happens here.
Sound is a vibration transmitted.
That's not what I'm talking about.
Hang on a second. Sound.
Let's just write sound water.
Water, sound effects. Geography.
The glacier produces a
sound speed of sound.
How sound in air differs? Sound
water productions. What the fuck?
All right, how about this? Let me, let me
write it and then you gotta be a moron.
This is how you find shit on the Internet.
What is a sound?
Enter web definition.
Sound, sound, investments.
You fucking con.
I'm spelling it wrong.
How do you spell sound for water?
Here it is.
Sound geography.
Let's go to Wikipedia.
God knows they're credible and geography
sound or a seaway is a large sea or
ocean inlet? Larger than a bay. All right.
What the fuck is in inland and inlet
is a narrow body body of water between
islands or leading inland
from a larger banal.
I'm not going to read the rest of it
cause it's just going to get confusing.
I like that. An inlet is a narrow
body of water between islands.
Okay. So if sound is a big inlet, uh, Bay,
I don't give a fuck. And then,
Oh, Jesus Christ. I like,
did she get a definition than every other
word is highlighted because they know
you're fucking stupid.
So geography is sound or seaways a large
sea or ocean inlet larger than a Ba.
So I guess it is salt water.
Huh?
Okay. I sort of get what that
is. So they're the sounders.
All right, let's look up Seattle sounders.
Let's look this up. This is exciting,
isn't it?
Seattle sounder.
Jeez.
Jesus Christ.
You know,
it's a small club when they're not even
the number one fucking thing there.
The third,
that third lead on that Seattle sounders
and see,
do they have history?
Yeah.
Jesus Christ.
You guys are really into that
awful green and blue up there.
Why don't you guys always have that? What
does everything you have to look like?
Algae when it comes to your sports teams.
You know,
given the algae isn't a good team
color. Um, all right, let's get,
let's get the stop fucking car. I actually
liked soccer and I'm trashing that.
I mentioned the shadow to the
people from Kansas University.
Let me get back to fucking anyway. What
the fuck are we here? Hmm. All right.
Anyways, well here's the kid hyping
up the Seattle sounders game.
Are there new mls expansion team up
here and the atmosphere was electric.
I suppose I'm a little bias in the soccer
is easily the greatest sport in the
world, but having been over in
Germany for the 2006 World Cup,
the sounders game felt oddly similar.
Okay.
Now do you work for the Seattle sounders?
Are you really going to say going to
Germany for the 2006 World Cup that going
to a home game for the Seattle sounders
was equivalent to that? I don't know.
Evidently he is saying that it's a shit
and he should have and you only go up
there and you have a good time
because you'll be surrounded by a sea,
not a sound,
not an inlet of a of green.
That was stupid. Why we just said
that. I see. Not a sound, not a bay.
That's what I should've said inlet.
That didn't make sense.
Did it cause an inlet is why she
and let does make sense, doesn't it?
What does an inlet, I
can't even remember. See,
this is why something in school and
inland and let is a small, straight,
sorta fucking body of water between,
okay.
He didn't want,
if this sailor listened to this shoot,
I hope you're enjoying this because
I know you're fucking laughing,
but just know that you dressed like
you're in the village people. Alright,
let's get onto the revenge
stories, shall we. Uh, well,
how about we do overrated underwear
because I didn't close with the revenge
stories cause he thinks
he's so fucking long.
And not to mention there's a guy talking
a little bit of shit about some of your
other revenge story. All right,
let's get with overrated, underrated.
All I have this week is one overrated
because this is going to be the stripped
down. Send me a text message out,
right? The stripped down version. Okay.
Over, I gotta end this thing in five
minutes, so I got to hurry here. Uh, Ross,
I'm going to miss my drinking time.
Overrated. Uh, thanks for the end.
I'm a little tall kid, then I got an
overrated for you fucking relationships.
Why in the hell can't guys get it out?
Get on the damn boat already.
The single guys have it down.
Wind them.
Dynam fucking and fucking leave.
I guess it's like you said,
uh, I'm sorry. People like I can't, I,
you know, I usually suck at reading them.
Just really even worse.
Signup Dynamynd you fucking leave.
That's all the single guys do it.
I guess it's like you said,
I think it was two Paul
podcasts ago or so.
You feel the gravitational pull
to get married and have kids.
I guess that's guys had the same poll
about being dumb enough to try and make a
relationship work. Uh, yeah. I think
there's a lot of truth to that.
I think what you should do is you should
just remain signals for your entire
twenties, you know, and right time,
right about the time you're like 30.
Then you know, once you get all
your fucking out of your system,
then you can just kind of be like, all
right, I need to, I need to, you know,
you're going to want to hang with
somebody at some point. You know,
you don't want to be the
old guy in the bar like me.
Like I'm about to be in 45 minutes,
you know, hey, there's sugar, you know,
calling women by old
old rat pack names.
Um, all right, well let's get on
to the, uh, the revenge story.
I'm going to read this guy's first cause
he's talking a little bit of trash and
I like this guy's coming up calm and
he's coming out really confident.
All alright. Revenge story number
one, Bill. It seems if all the,
it seems like all their events or
stories that you've been reading on the
podcast lately have been sent sent by
a bunch of pansies that take the pussy
passive form of revenge and
fuck with somebody's car.
Shit like that is lame and a pathetic
attempt to get back at someone.
What they really need to do is
take a more aggressive approach.
Here is my revenge story and
I want you guys to know this.
I haven't even reviving read this one yet.
All right.
I just saw that intro and I'm like,
well, with an intro like that,
this has to be the best revenge
story we've heard so far.
So with that,
let's all judge this guys revenge story
as I read it for the first time and I
want you to know that things
like fucking nine pages long,
Goddamn people take revenge is a quick,
what the fuck did I just do?
Revenge is not a quick thing here.
Hang on.
I just accidentally hit the wrong
button. All right, I'm back. I'm back.
All right, here we go. The
revenge story. Hi Phil.
This happened a few years ago when I
was 17 and working at a fast food joint.
One night I was closing the place and I
was rolling a blunt at one of the tables
to smoke after I got off
of work and other words.
He was a typical fucking fast
food kit. So anyways, a new,
a new kid that just started working there
a couple of weeks before thinking he
was doing the right thing.
Oh,
did you read? You read, you know,
half the shit isn't my problem.
You guys don't write in
complete sentences. End.
It was a new kid just got
thrown on a fucking joint,
a goddamn table in the new kid.
Thought he was doing the right thing and
he turned me into the manager on duty
that night.
The manager laughed at him because he
couldn't care less about what I was doing.
All the fact that his employees
smoked weed. That isn't that Nice.
A great manager.
Next day when I go into work,
that same manager tells me what happened
the night before. I'm not pissed,
but I'm more like,
you know what the fuck does this guy
would run to the manager and think that
he's some sort of whistleblower.
I decide.
So I decided that the guy needs
to learn his lesson. Jesus Christ.
Nice set up so far and I'll see you
guys. I'm enjoying this. So anyways,
I call up a friend of mine to get what I
need and when the kid goes on his break
in order to his lunch, when he's not
looking, I dropped the two hits of acid.
I brought two with me in his drink.
Okay, what did I read that wrong?
I got two hits of acid. Okay,
you're not you guys,
can you proofread these fucking things
so I don't sound like the dumbest person.
You know what he did?
He took two hits ass and he dropped him
in his fucking fruit punch. So anyways,
he sits down and he starts eating and
I go back to work and I wait for it to
kick in and the entertainment to start.
All right,
I'm starting to get the guest
to the vibe of this story.
Evidently when he says your king the car,
he doesn't mean that you're
a pussy because you didn't
do something face to face.
Evidently this maniac doesn't
think you took it far enough.
All right, back to the story and an
hour later when he clocks back in,
I can tell it's beginning to kick in.
Hard I watch is to do good or current
starts to trip balls and freaks everyone
out.
Such a trip balls and freaks everyone out.
Nobody else knows what what
is going on with the guy,
so they lock them in the back manager's
office to this is really dangerous
because he didn't know he was
probably never done drugs.
He probably thought he was going crazy.
Okay.
That's
really dangerous and fucking hilarious.
All right. When he's in there,
he really starts to lose his
shit and tear the place apart.
My manager calls the cops and when
they get there they go back and cuff.
They go back and cut them and
put them in the back of a squad.
There's a lot of confusion in the place
and everyone tries to figure out what
the hell just happened.
The cop starts to question everyone to
try and figure out just what went on,
but I play it up dumb just
like everyone else saying.
He just started to act crazy too.
What do you have a life of crime?
You're playing that shit off,
not worry that you're going to get
caught or you want to work release from
prison. Anyways, after
taking everyone's statements,
the cops leave and caught the guy off.
He never did come back to work or even
show his place face in that place again.
Don't know if it was out of embarrassment,
confusion to what happened.
Hang on. Diffusion to what happened
or outright fear of the place,
so I don't know.
Whatever happened to him,
it's still is the best 15
bucks that I ever spent.
Jesus Christ. Dude, that's
fucking hardcore, man.
I like you. I you confuses. I Dunno
why. I Dunno if he was embarrassed.
If he was confused through do you don't
think he figured out what the fuck
happened and he wasn't able to put fucking
one and one together and make to how
big? That's what I had to say.
Really instead said, rather than say,
put two and two together and get four,
this is so easy. This is one in one.
Let's see.
I read it out.
I mean people do think he read it out
for doing drugs in the last 24 hours.
Then all of a sudden he
starts fucking tripping. Wow.
I'm such a sadistic fuck.
Maybe there would be a part of
me that would really enjoy that.
Especially if he was like, uh,
like always doing the right thing.
You know what I mean?
You know,
people who always fuck up in life just
really hate people who are doing the
right thing. You know? I told them,
I talked to you about these people they
called [inaudible] and as much as I hate
cons, I really am one when it
comes to certain kinds of people,
I have no tolerance for people
who are pussies. I don't,
and it's not because I'm a tough guy,
probably reminds me of a certain part
of my personality that I don't like.
But in general,
you know who goes on and tell somebody,
you know what?
Fuck that guy.
What was he trying to take you a position
at the fryer later so it could be
fucking Douche bag of the month
that really must've psychologically
damaged and made me think about that.
You know, his whole life, that Mama's
boy, he probably always like, you know,
Eddie just said it sandwich.
Now we swim and he didn't wait 15 minutes.
Oh,
that's very good Mike.
He always got rewarded for it and
then he fucking ratchet you up. Hey,
you know that fucking,
you know guy over there smoking weed and
then the manager. So it's like, yeah,
that's what you do.
We work in a fast food joint.
Do you think this was our dream
in life for the love of God?
Somebody give me a hit because I can't
take the fucking paint a reality anymore.
Once you go mop something up your little
pussy, that's probably what happened.
And the next day's a cheat. If
I went home, talked to his mom,
I couldn't believe it. I
mean, I mean he was doing,
he had a marijuana cigarette.
Well don't you worry you
did the right thing. Okay.
And you just stay away from him and you
go to work tomorrow and you make sure
you doing coach and then he goes to work
and he fucked a fucking puts the date
rape drug in there at the date rape drug.
You know what I'm saying?
He puts acid in that Jesus Christ
that you've never even had mentioned.
You've never even had a sip of beer in.
The first thing happens to
you is to hit the athlete.
I never took assets that God, thank
God, thank God I never read it out.
Somebody doing drugs. Um,
anyways. All right, here's,
here's another revenge story.
I'm going to read this one, then I
got to wrap it up. Uh, hey bill. Uh,
I'm with you on the no revenge
rule. People suffer. Oh,
this wasn't even a revenge thing.
This is just a question.
This guy needs some
advice. This, this, uh,
falls into the asset bill
portion of the podcast.
The advice people like to ask me for
advice, even though I'm a fucking moron.
Let me just read this whole
thing. Cause, uh, anyways,
I was writing to you to talk about,
okay here,
here's the part where he s
he needs some advice. Anyway,
so I was writing to you
and talk about my cousins,
have a girlfriend and
hopefully to get some advice.
I love how con is just become the
catchphrase of the podcast here. Anyways,
me and my girlfriend have been together
for about two and a half years.
We knew each other as teenagers.
Um,
along with some other people she dated.
she dated one of our friends and he
eventually moved on and got married.
Me and her remained friends and eventually
we became close. We started dating.
She isn't the best girlfriend.
I figure that.
Consider your calling her a con.
Yeah because she had a couple
of things that annoyed you.
She has the best girlfriend
but I have become pretty,
pretty comfortable having her
around and her two kids not from me.
You love or two kids?
Not For me.
They love me and we have
become quite the family.
Here is where Shit went wrong
recently we visited our friends in New
York and we are all partying and shit and
I get a horrible headache and sit
down on the couch to rest it up.
I was out of it, so like 30 minutes
and I wake up to a nightmare here.
My friend in the kitchen hitting
on my girlfriend. Wow. If,
if, if that's not bad enough, she's
into this shit and encourage him,
encouraging him and flirting back.
After I had all I could take,
I walked into the kitchen and they made
the oh shit face when they looked at me,
but I didn't say anything.
Then I didn't say anything.
Then in there the next night for possibly
or possibly the same nights since that
was hammered.
Every day I was there,
me and my girlfriend go to bed in the
guest room while we are laying there,
she gets up to go to the bathroom
and after she didn't return,
after about 15 minutes,
I opened the door and what do I see
him and her standing there alone in the
hallway,
having a quiet conversation.
Jesus Christ to this is getting creepy.
Here's her story.
She was just entertaining herself
and it wasn't going to go anywhere.
She feels she didn't sleep with him
or anyone else. So I'm overreacting.
I'm overreacting by considering
breaking up, considering all we really,
she have to lose. Oh, considering
all that you guys have to lose. Yeah.
It's really her with the two
fucking kids. All right. So anyways,
she's been walking around crying and
upset about the shit she has told me she's
sorry and will never happen again.
She has been pretty much worshiping
me the last few days and the shit is
starting to eat away at me.
I also know that I purchased most of the
shit in this house and if slash when we
separate I'll be taking most of it with
me and that is going to make it a lot
more difficult and painful for her
and her kids at this point I'm like,
fuck all of this and I am ready to leave.
I'm ready to leave and shit.
But honestly I'm starting to feel like
a real douche for not being able to get
past this shit.
The kids will be devastated and they
pretty much doomed once I leave because I
am pretty much the glue that holds
this family together. At the same time,
I feel like if she would do this
shit after years, we're kind of hope.
Does that give us for the future?
What kind of relationship can we
have app to some shit like this?
I would love some feedback on this bill.
Even though you never read my letters
during the podcast insert guiltier just
telling me what you think I should
do in this situation. All right dude.
A year in that classic
halfway point between emotion,
you know for your feelings.
For the kids.
You're in the halfway point between that
and knowing exactly what the fuck you
need to do and you're
doing what you need to do.
You need to reach out to people who are
going to re affirm what you know in your
heart of hearts. What you have to do is
you have to get the fuck out of there.
You gotta get out of there.
All right.
Do you think that's the first
guy she hit on? You know,
and if she's hitting on guys, that
means she's probably fucking other guys.
And if she's not,
she's going to,
and right now she's just in a panic
mode and she's in a panic mode,
not because she's worried about losing
you because of all that other bullshit
that you mentioned because you sound
like you're the most responsible of the
people there.
And the only fucking hope her kids have
is that you'll stick around because she
is a, I don't know, she doesn't
have her shit together. Um,
you got to get out to, you got
to get out and you know, you,
you might be good for the kids right now,
but eventually you're not going to be
because of the misery that you're going to
have.
Being in a relationship with somebody
that you can't trust as far as you can
fucking throw him is eventually going to
rub off on how you feel about the whole
situation.
And it's going to be really hard for
you not to be a fucking douche around,
but those kids,
you probably gonna start drinking and
eventually you're going to start a fucking
relationship. And the longer you're
there, the more shit you're going to buy.
This is what you gotta do. You gotta give
yourself fucking six weeks, all right?
Just break it up in two week increments.
The first two weeks is going to be brutal.
Just cry on the floor with
a pint of fucking Haagen
daas like a little bitch and
get through it.
And every time you want to call that
fucking cunt that you can't trust anymore,
you call a friend of yours.
Instead,
you call a buddy of yours to kind of
buddy who's gonna fucking take you out
drinking and gets you back in the
fucking game. That's what you do.
All right?
And you do that and turn that time.
The last bucket thing you do is get
into another relationship. All right?
Don't fucking do that. Don't do the J. Lo,
we get out of that and you jump into
something else. Fuck that. All right?
You stay fucking single,
you know,
and just just get through six fucking
weeks in gradually and that after two
weeks goes by, you know what I
mean? You start having a life.
You'll start going down the park, playing
Frisbee with your next door neighbor.
I don't know what the fuck
you'll start filling up the time.
That's all it is in the breakup. Haven't
been, you know, after like a few days,
unless you really love somebody,
you're already getting past them.
What you're really trying
to do is wondering,
well what the fuck did I
do during all this time?
How did I use to fill up my free time?
And that's what you got your boys for.
They'll take you out, go
drinking, go to games, you know,
by the big fucking industrial
sized box of condoms.
Just fucking, you know, Bang away, do
all the shit you gotta do. But Dude,
you got to get out of that relationship.
You know,
you got to get out of the relationship
and it sucks. But you know what, dude?
It's a fucking, it's a 20
minute conversation. 20 minutes.
What you have to say?
It takes fucking 30 seconds,
but you got to deal with
fucking the next 20 minutes,
all her bullshit trying to use all these
different techniques to try and get you
to stay. She's going to go with the
guilt. She's going to go with the Stereo.
She's going to go with anger.
She's gonna fucking unload her female
fucking gun of emotion at you and you just
have to stick to your fucking, you
gotta stick to your guns. I'm out.
I'm out. Cause you fucked up. You fucked
up. I can't trust you. I can't trust you.
The relationship is over.
Relationship is over. It's over.
Not only were you hitting on another guy,
hitting all my best friend,
you fucking cunt,
you untrustworthy fucking con.
And you've got the balls to sit here and
act like I'm going to fucking stay with
you. How are you out of your fucking
mind? Wait a minute. Strike that.
Don't say that mean Shit.
Don't say that means shit.
Cause then then you had done two.
Don't do like that. Just say, look,
I can't trust you. You
know what? Yeah. Fuck that.
I don't know what the fuck ups man,
you know what you gotta do. All right,
but don't, don't, don't, don't get sucked
into a, you know, fuck you. Fuck you.
Fight with her. Right. And she's going to
do the usual shit that women always do.
Once she gets to the anger
thing, then uh, she'll,
she'll go with to go with
the usual chill somehow.
She'll question your sexuality,
you, your, your ability and bed.
She'd probably do that. Well maybe
if you fucking blah, blah, blah.
I wouldn't be hitting on your friend.
She's just going to do that.
And a last ditch hope that you're going
to turn around blast during in the
fucking face so she can get a little
more money out of you and you can go to
jail and she can keep your
fucking playstation. So
don't get sucked into that.
When she says that remark, just be
like, yeah, you know what? Yeah,
I guess I guess I do suck in bed. So
you know, have fun fucking my friend.
You know, you seem like you really
want to, you know, or whatever.
Now that was lame, but you know,
most of that was good. Okay.
Don't get sucked into that.
Don't get sucked into any sort of
domestic violence thing. All right.
I'm not trying to judge you,
but that's a really white trash,
that sort of situation. You're
involved in there where you got this,
you know we do. Dude, you said in the
beginning that you fucking thing. Yeah,
I'm Kinda, I'm only kind of end to this
girl and she's got two fucking kids.
You know what I mean? Cause why
you got to stay single, dude,
you got to figure out what the fuck is
with you that you got yourself into this
mess to begin with. All right? But
do it, it could have been worse.
You could have fucking,
you could have had kids with her.
He could even married eight years.
They could have been who?
She could have been fucking poison in
you every morning. You know those girls,
they don't know how to break up to
these. So they start putting fucking, uh,
that cyanide and you and you
got damn a rice krispies.
Alright dude, I'm telling you.
I'm telling you, get the fuck out.
You know what to do. Alright. Get the
fuck out. He called one of your friends.
They listened to it. I got to get
out of this situation. It sucks.
So I'm going to need you
over the next six weeks.
Anytime I call you and I'm like, I need
to go out boozing. You've gotta be there.
You and your fucking liver have
got to be there for me. You know,
that's what you gotta do.
All right, there you go.
I know I just said the same thing
for fucking 20 minutes, but you know,
I've been in that situation never with
the two kids. But you got, you got,
you got to go. Do you
got to go? All right.
I at grasshopper, they'll make me proud
and send me an email on the weekend.
Tell me that you got the fuck out of
there. All right. All right. That's it.
That's the Monday morning
podcast. God bless all of you. Uh,
hope to see out of one of my shows.