Oh
Hey, what's going on? It's Bill Burr and
It's time for the Thursday afternoon.
Just before Friday. Monday
morning podcast. And
ahhh
just checking in on you.
Sorry Cleo.
My dog just popped up like what the
fuck dude? What's going on everybody?
How are Ya? How's it going? Do you
guys watch any sports lately? Go.
I've what with the baseball there.
Um,
Jesus Christ.
What a difference a couple of fucking
days makes my god the fucking Cleveland
Indians up three games to one
looking to end their street to,
did I call it or did I fucking call it?
What did I say?
Did I say it to you guys? I thought
I said that. This is just fitting.
They see that on Monday cause I think
it was three games to two by then.
I said that whatever team was going to
fucking win was going to look like they
were going to lose.
So they taught you the shit out of their
fans or whatever team was going to lose.
Who's going to look like they were going
to win because they take their emotions
right through the fucking stratosphere
and then slam them right down on the
pavement.
And game seven was literally
the microcosm that that the way,
the way that whole fucking
game played out was basically,
if you ever wanted to know what it was
like to be at Chicago cub or a Cleveland
Indian fan,
and the only reason why they both
didn't face plant each other is because
mathematically it was not an option.
Somebody had to win the fucking thing,
but neither team was just getting,
neither team was just going to win this
fucking series. That was basically it.
That was the point I was
trying to make the other day.
They were going to torture the fuck out
of their fans to the point that even if
they did win the thing,
you'd still have some sort of nervous
fucking twitch or a tick for like three
days afterwards. Jesus Christ. What a
game. If you didn't watch game seven,
I feel bad for you as a
fucking human being. You know,
as it's fucking 71 degrees in Cleveland,
Ohio in November,
there no reason to be concerned.
Let's play it off.
Oh,
Jesus.
Enjoy it. Enjoy. While last people,
before we get to the tipping point where
this global warming thing isn't a fun
thing in November anymore.
Anyways,
back to bread and circus. Let's talk a
little baseball here. Dark Ebay's fault.
Um,
congratulate
relations to the [inaudible]
2016 world series champions.
The fucking Chicago.
I never thought I'd, I'd,
yeah, I didn't. I mean,
I guess I thought I'd say to some point
when it finally saw the red sox winning,
congratulations to the cubs fans.
I've been there, you know, and I only,
I only lasted, you know, out of the 86
years, I only saw 36 years of it, right?
Of course, you know,
whatever the first 10,
you're just a kid running around fucking
sticking shit. It fucking, you know,
you're poking dead skunks and stuff. You
don't give a fuck about a curse, right.
Some from my teen years
on, I, I've suffered for 20
fucking years. If I'm honest.
Uh,
I vaguely remember 78 and
[inaudible] 86 was my,
was my christening as a red
sox fan. Like, hey bill,
this is what it's going to
be like, buckle up. Right?
So I've been there and Cleveland Indian
fans, my condolences. I've been there too.
I've fucking been there too. But what
a fucking game. That was Jesus Christ.
And you knew what? The cubs had
to go out early. They had a score,
a bunch of fucking runs
because as the game went on,
it was going to tip in favor of
the Indians because they had,
they had fresh or arms and everybody was
fucking shitting on all fucking the guy
from the devil rays.
I don't know anybody's names by the way.
I don't know anybody's names,
so just fucking deal with it and they
will all shitting on him for putting
Chapman in there.
I'm on the depth chart now so I can look
at the face and know who the fuck I'm
talking about.
Right for keep putting Chapman,
Julie,
she's overusing or what is he doing?
It's like, dude, they've played
three elimination games in a row.
You got to use the guy.
Don't you think he brought
a middle too early?
I love when people say that they haven't
even coached a little league fucking
team to a victory yet. And they're
questioning what a major league.
I mean I guess she can question it but,
and it's always like,
well the guy who I would
have put in who didn't go in,
so you have no idea what would have
would have happened if you put him in.
I'm going to hypothetically say that we
then would have won the fucking game or
it would have gone smoother.
So I look smarter.
They had to put that guy in there and um,
what was,
what was the big problem you put the
fucking guy in instead of throwing 105 he
was throwing 98 I mean, well what are
you going to do? You had to do it.
Cubs go up.
I can't remember what the fuck happened.
There was so many goddamn
twists and turns. What was
it? It was like five to one
then like a wild pitch or whatever
and fucking lie had cheese.
Do you want to see the funniest fucking,
if you want to see the funniest, like,
like run a tweets. Go look at Jason
Law heads, Twitter, that fucking guy,
he quit in the fifth inning.
You know I was just going to wait to
the pitchers and catchers report, right?
And then fucking two seconds later,
wild pitch. It's five to fucking tree.
It's still a game. Oh, I
never saw a guy. He just what?
He was packing it in, packing
it in back in it in. Um,
and you said he wasn't gonna tweet
anymore until the catchers and pitchers
reported and then all of a sudden
they fucking tie it up. That home run.
Who the fuck can I got
to get his name right?
The way it's Cleveland step
stepchild Davis, right. Was that,
oh it was the left fielder.
Holy Shit.
And I gotta tell you something right now.
I flip flopped so many times.
Who the fuck I wanted to see when I
initially I was with Cleveland cause
everybody wanted the cubs fans.
I saw that 30 for 30 with Bartman and
I was just like, you know these guys,
they're not the fucking a salt of the
earth people that they try to make him out
to be the happy go lucky, take your
shirt off. Maybe we will. Maybe we lose.
As long as we enjoy the America's pastime.
These aren't who these are.
They're just like me. Every red sox,
every Yankees, that'd be Philly Fan.
I actually argued with the a Yankee fan
today. He was going like, fuck the Kobes,
let Steve Bartman Shit.
They ruined that kid's life.
That wouldn't have happened in New
York. I was like, get the fuck out of,
you know when that happened in New York,
what happened in New York,
it would have happened in Boston. But you
know what, in fairness to cubs fan base,
what that really was was the morning,
you know, the shock jock guys.
And what they did was they stirred
up the lower 10% 15% of people,
you know,
as pissed as I would be or whatever.
There's no fucking way would you really
get on a phone and start making depth,
death threats?
I mean really think about the level of
mouth breathing more on that you would
have to be to take it to that level.
Um, so I, I don't so whatever.
So initially that's kind of, I was, I'm
a contrary and everyone's for the cubs.
So I was rooting for the fucking Indians.
And then what happens?
They went up three games to one and
I'm texting with a couple of my Indian
buddies and one of them had cheat.
She's just so fucking like,
we know when they will in a game four.
And it was like, you know, I don't know,
nine to something. And he was
going through it. I, I hope,
I hope it goes all the way up to
like fucking, I always go 19 runs.
I hope they run out of pitchers.
And immediately I was thinking like,
Jesus Christ, how quickly the suffering
forget. Why would you wish that on them?
You just want to win. Right. And then
he was going like, now we've got Lebron.
This is just the beginning.
We're going to go on a run,
like they were going to stick and
somebody tweeted or texted Cleveland title
town after two fucking titles.
You don't even have a fucking hockey team.
And you end up in the brown and studying.
You lost your fucking team.
You know the city treated him so shitty.
They thought Baltimore was a
better fucking option. All right,
you're far from fucking.
So then they started bugging me.
I'm just a contrarion cunt.
I didn't have a dog in the fight
and I was happy that one fee.
Be honest with you. I was happy for
Cleveland or Chicago, that one teams, uh,
misery was going to end. Right. So at that
point then I was like, well fuck this.
I'm going to root for the cubs. Right. I
got a couple of relatives that cubs fans.
I got to say I fucking, you know,
I'll, I'll go with this shit.
Then I was kind of like gap. I like
the Indians van. Like I like Cleveland,
you know, Cleveland needs a fucking
hand. Do that downtown area.
It's gradually coming back. Every
time I come there, it looks better.
I love the Midwest. Well Chicago's
Midwest too, but I don't know,
that's kind of like the New
York City or the Midwest. Um,
tremendously underrated cities still.
But anyways,
so it's still kind of hanging
in there for him. And uh,
you know what the final tipping point
was when Mike Friends Saska trashed the
fucking cubs for showing
Bill Murray Goldman.
What do you know the whole deal
Marijo he talk thing, you know,
it didn't work for me.
Mike Francisco,
who gives a fuck what works
for you and what doesn't?
Your team's not in the playoff.
All right, you're a non factor.
Your team's a nonfactor it the funniest
fucking thing, man. At the Yankee fans,
they cannot handle the fact that other
people are winning championships and a
good fucking time.
And that sort of the unwritten rule
because whenever the Yankees won a world
series, which God knows is quite a bit
like ESPN there, their stock line is,
they'll go in all is right in the
baseball world again. It's like,
aren't you guys supposed to pretend
that you're kind of rooting for any,
you're not really rooting
for anybody. Um, so anyways,
fuck Mike Francessa my Francesco,
he's one of those fucking guys who doesn't
realize that he's just as stupid as I
am. He's one of those guys
where he's just been doing,
it's so fucking long that he really,
he forgets that he's just commenting
on shit that doesn't matter dude.
You talking about a baseball game?
Okay.
All the shit that has happened even
in New York, fucking New York City,
all this shit that's
fucking happened there.
The cataclysmic world events that
have happened there and the level of
seriousness that that guy takes himself.
Oh,
with his stethoscope fucking headphones.
That guy,
he drives me up the fuck I
have never been more happy.
The full fucking mad dog when
he got the fuck out of there.
Jesus Christ to be looking
across from that pompous ass.
Is there anything worse than the box
seats fucking sports fan that is just so
fucking impressed with themselves and
their dumb sweaters and shit? I Dunno.
You give them a little more fancy a seat,
and I'm telling you it's,
it's like the space shuttle for their
ego and they just go right up over here.
The daffy duck thing didn't
work for me. Oh God. Well maybe,
maybe the cubs out of fucking,
you know,
rethink their relationship
with Bill Murray. Hey Mike,
are you the fucking Bill Murray of,
of,
of sports broadcasters fucking off.
He's just another guy who watches
sports that never gets on the treadmill.
I don't understand. How can you look at
all those guys in that level of shape?
And when you're at the end of the game,
when you go into brush your teeth,
you don't look at yourself
like Jesus Christ.
Can I at least need a fucking salad every
once in awhile? Oh, this feels great.
This feels great to totally overreact
to what he said. It's a fun thing.
So anyways, um, congratulations
to the Chicago cubs.
You got the fucking goat off your back.
Whatever the fuck you want to call
it was the dumbest curse ever. Okay?
You can't bring livestock to a
baseball game. All right? You know,
what you really did is you did not have
a curse the same way the red sox didn't
have a curse.
What it really was was you were fans of
an unbelievably inept franchise for a
long fucking time. And
uh, thank God, you know,
we finally got Theo Epstein,
we finally got Terry Francona,
we finally got the ownership that the
red sox have and it all came together and
we finally did what teams
like the fucking Yankees,
the cardinals, the Patriots, teams like
that, that know how to fucking win.
I actually can't say the Patriots.
That's even modern modern era.
The Celtics back in the day, um, you know,
as much as I hate the fucking Yankees,
like their, their, their front office,
their ownership, their franchise,
their farm system, it's a
shit is the shit. I mean,
you can't get mad at them for starting
around network for being smart enough to
do that. I don't, I don't want
to hit on any of that shit.
But that whole fucking thing where
all is right, if, if they went is,
that's a little, it goes a little beyond.
But other than that, I don't put grudge.
They fucking 27 championships. I
really dumb. Um, having said that, uh,
we finally got the right people in place.
So you finally got the right people
in place and having said that, um,
whoever was going to win last night,
the cubs or the Indians was an automatic
one way fucking a ticket for either
Theo Epstein or Terry Francona
into, uh, into the hall of fame.
So congratulations to Theo
Epstein. Um, without a doubt.
I mean that guy ended the curse of the
baby and the curse of the goat. I mean,
he needs a nickname at this
point, something right. I
can't think of it right now,
but I'm just saying that guy at 86,
[inaudible] 86 and 108,
that's 186 and the 194 years of suffering,
that fucking guy just ended.
You know, it's like a champ too. You
see the guy who's in his forties,
he still looks like he used
to be an astronaut. I mean,
the guy's just crushing it
and somebody fucking levels.
You can really see how people would try
to root against them and um, whatever,
man, the Indians will definitely be
back. I gotta be honest with you,
I'm still more of an Indians
fan than I am a cubs fan,
but it was so fucking great,
like seeing the look of joy on,
on a bill Murray's face.
And by the way, uh,
what Francisco like did you not
enjoy seeing that? Watching him?
She's fucking lead. However old he
is, was all just fucking coming out.
It was tremendous. So, um, it was
great. It was what a fucking gay man,
Jesus Christ,
where to go.
And then I forgot the fucking rain
delay and then they tie it up,
they fucking tie it up. And I was
like, oh my God, this is on. It's,
it's gonna reverse again.
Like the way everyone's, like,
everyone just kind of thought
the cubs are gonna win it.
And then the Indians go up three
games to one. They're like, oh my God,
the Indians are going to win it.
Then reverse then looks like
the cubs are gonna win it.
And then the Indians tied fucking
back up again. You're like, fuck,
I know I'm getting hyped
up here, but dude, when,
when does baseball get this
fucking exciting? Right?
And then it starts fucking raining
and they bring out the fucking tarp.
That's the funniest shit. And that's
one of the great, that's like this.
The sport within the sport of baseball
is the fucking rain delay. And uh,
they got to put a book.
If there's never been a book put out
yet about people just talking about what
goes through your head as you're going
through a fucking rain delay and you have
to sit there and fill up three hours
of fucking broadcast time telling your
stories. I mean, that's when you
got to hope that you got like a, uh,
a Pete rose there.
You know what I mean?
You got to have some guy with a zillion
fucking stories that knows how to tell a
story, um, to how great was
he? He was fucking phenomenal.
A rod was great. The big
herd, all of those guys,
when you got like hall of
famers sitting there, you know,
just the way they break down,
but nobody breaks it down like Pete Rose,
Jesus Christ, you know all the
games that, that guys played,
all the experiences he's had.
And then you combine gambling on it.
So he took it to a whole other level
of the way he looks at numbers.
I mean guy is like second
to none with his analysis.
By the way, Jason Heyward, huge fan,
that fucking catchy made,
I forget what game where he leapt up and
then had to reach back and then when he
fired the,
the through that strike like Dave
Parker in the all star game grant,
Dave through it from the warning track
to the home plate when he threw it in a
second to get that guy out kill
the fucking momentum is great.
As that was the worst at bat of the
fucking of this series was his one of his
last at bats to, did you see the two
pitches he fucking swung at? I mean,
Jesus Christ, 50 cent could've
struck him out at that bad.
I mean it was, it was like,
you know, they just stayed,
take some fucking guy like 50 cent
out of the crowd and they, oh my God,
it's 50 cent and he just goes out and
throws the ball. You're like, oh my God,
he really is an artist. Um, you
got to look that up by the way.
I think I tweeted when he did that, I
said, 50 cent didn't throw that ball.
Curtis Jackson did you have to see
it man. It's just like, it was a,
I dunno, it was like watching Jon
Lester trying to throw to first base,
which I had no idea that he, he
won't even do it. I'm nuts. Is that,
that's like a,
it was like chop Nog Chuck Knoblauch,
Steve Sax Times fucking to at
least one of the videos that I saw.
Thank God that he didn't.
But, um, anyways, um,
my condolences to the city of
Cleveland, man, I, I really,
I love that city and a municipal stadium.
I'll let shit back in the day that
I grew up watching. Like I said,
one of my relatives lived out there when
I was a kid and he kind of would always
be rooting for them and you know,
he was cool.
So I would fucking route for them to
a buddy, of course, red sox first.
So I always kind of had
that thing with them.
And the Tigers that kind of
like the surrogates if the, uh,
the red sox aren't in it.
Um,
and I also liked the
royals and I like the A's.
I Dunno. I like the pirates.
I like the cardinals.
I like the giants and I liked the
Dodgers back in the day. So I, I,
there's a lot of teams that
I fucking thing, you know,
they all take a deep second to fucking,
the red sox aren't in it,
you know what I mean?
So anyways,
I even rooted for the Yankees in 2001
after nine 11 I was like, all right,
fuck it. I gotta set this shit aside and
then the fucking Diamondbacks beat him.
I was like, fuck, I should've been
rude for these guys the whole time.
I wouldn't jinxed him. So anyways,
congratulations. Um, and Cleveland. Amen.
Your next,
or I guess I should be rooting for the
Arizona cardinals cause they have the
longest drought,
I guess with the championship since 1947
when they were the Chicago cardinals.
Um, and then they went
to, uh, I don't know.
I can't remember what the
fucking lineage of that team is,
but like I don't give a fuck about them
because they've lived in so many fucking
cities. Like the city doesn't carry
the pain. Does that make sense?
Middle of Arizona cardinals right now.
Uh,
I'm surprised it didn't
just pop up on my thing.
You know your computer like
listens to you. I actually
get dead Arizona cardinals, you
have to do that. You just say, yeah,
fucking a pumpernickel bread. Oh,
what's in pumpernickel bread? You right.
You right like p you and then
it says pumpernickel bread.
Like your phone will do that.
Like who,
what the foot of fucking odds
that came up. You listen to me
said fucking robot lady on the phone.
She listens.
She listens to Oh yeah, she's listening
to you. Let's see here. Official site now.
It's pretty sad case.
You got to go to Wikipedia to find
out that fucking history the quickest.
Actually, maybe it isn't. All right,
here we go. The cardinals, let's see.
They were the Chicago cardinals,
1920 to 1943 they took a
year off during the war.
1945 to 1959,
uh oh they were the cardinals card pit
in 1944 I thought they had the eagles in
Pittsburgh and made the struggles.
Anyway. St Louis Cardinals,
1960 to 1987.
Phoenix cardinals 88 to 93 94 to present
Arizona. So they've been all right.
They've been cheated. They've been in
Phoenix for fucking almost 30 years. Wow.
They've been there longer
than they weren't St Louis.
How [inaudible] how about that?
And they were in Chicago
basically for 29 years.
Isn't that something? So they weren't
fee Arizona the longest, then Chicago,
then Saint Louis. So anyways, I don't
really count that fucking shit. Let's see,
the longest stretch I can see the next
person I give a fuck about past Cleveland.
Right? Let's see. Longest
sports droughts, bing,
Bang, boom, drought sports. Uh,
longest active droughts in sports.
When was this made? This was
done three hours ago. Okay.
So they should be fairly accurate.
Correct. So it goes the Arizona cardinals,
then the Cleveland Indians. Just
give me the fucking list. All right.
The Arizona cardinals shut up.
All right.
69 years. Cleveland Indians,
68 years. Sacramento,
kings 1951. They will like
to Rochester royals, I think,
or some shit like that. Uh, they
haven't won in 65 years to Troy lions.
Seven one since 1957.
The Atlanta Hawks when they were
the Saint Louis Hawks, 1958,
uh, then the Philadelphia
Eagles, 1960, um,
Texas rangers. Never. 1955.
Never won a championship.
Tennessee titans,
they used to be the Houston Oilers.
They want an AFL title in 1961. So
a couple more here. Houston Astros,
never 54 fucking years.
Um,
San Diego chargers,
1963 53 years since their AFL title,
and then the Toronto Maple leafs. So if
we're going to go sport by sport, uh,
the longest drought and football
is the Arizona cardinals baseball,
the Cleveland Indians.
Basketball is the Sacramento Kings
in hockey is the Toronto Maple leafs.
There you go. 69 years, 68, 65 at 49.
So there you Toronto
Shit. These other guys, they got,
they got fucking 20 years on you. Um,
and actually nowadays when there's that
many fucking teams going to get 32 teams
to go 50 years, considering one of them's
going to, you know, when a couple, two,
three, if not four or five over 30 years.
Right. It's very easy now to go 40 years.
All right. Tell I think we've had
enough of the sports talk. All right,
well maybe I have to, let's talk
about flat top grills, shall we,
by the way, I have not called La head
yet. I'm going to wait three days.
I'm going to rub, run into them. I'm
going to give him a hug. You know,
tell him, you know, you
still got the NBA title.
You got a little hyped up there.
Oh my God.
The agony j law.
He remember that the agony of defeat.
Do you remember when the ski jump
Guy went off the fucking ski jump?
If you look at j law heads, Twitter
feed, dude, it's fucking hard. Delirious
because if he's not joking,
he's literally,
he goes off to ski jump like
five times every game. You know,
when any just lay in face down.
He like, is he dead? Is he dead?
And then he somehow pops his head up,
shakes his hair out,
he puts the fucking goggles back on and
he fucking gradually walks back up the
stairs again.
Okay.
Yeah. I'm telling you, man,
it's, it's really entertaining.
Anytime there's a big Cleveland game,
I recommend following j
law had Jason Lie ahead on,
um, on Twitter. You know, just sit
back and just watch the floods.
It's tremendous. It's, it's
an amazing thing. It's,
it's a great sportsbook every fuck. And
just, just in tweets. It's incredible.
All right. So anyways, let's talk
about a flat top grill. Everybody. Oh,
I want to get a flat top grill. Um,
I told you a few weeks ago when, um,
John Fabrice, you know, was shooting
some stuff that possibly, I don't know,
he might do some footage
with, uh, you know,
cooking Edison place.
I went over to the taping mean the lovely
Nia and we got to hang out with, uh,
chef Roy Choi who started the
whole gourmet food truck thing. A,
they cooked on a grill,
which is something I never did.
Even when I worked in a restaurant. I, I
cooked on a mesquite grill. I did Burgers,
shrimp, brochette, chicken sandwich,
whatever the fuck you want. Right? Uh,
but I never worked with uh, on a, on
a griddle before and now, uh, I am,
I am so fucking into those things.
It's ridiculous.
And I found this one on the Internet.
I'm not going to tell you the name of it,
just look up flat top fucking grill.
There's too,
it's not the Blackstone one.
This is like a smaller one.
It's more compact for
my little La Backyard.
And I'm trying to convince my wife
to let me get it, man. You know,
cause we're re we're redoing the kitchen
and so we went to go do the stove,
like the one that had the little griddle
on it was just going to take up too
much counter space.
We have a small kitchen area
and the number one thing
was I hated the those like
no prep area in the kitchen and I hate,
I hated the island.
Have ever told you guys that how much
I hate a fucking island in the kitchen.
I F I don't think, I didn't care if it
could fit in my kitchen. He couldn't fit.
They just put an island in there because
it was like the fucking thing to do and
you just want, it's like having a
fucking hippo that passed out on booze.
And did you just kind of walk around
like the worst fucking thing is whatever
you're at the stove and whatever you need
is diagonally across the other side of
the fucking house. You got
to walk all around it. Okay.
Now for all my friends around
the world in war torn countries,
this is what she complained about
it in the United States of America,
that Goddamn island in your
fucking brand new kitchen. Right.
Sorry.
But anyways,
so we didn't get the griddle and now I'm
already kicking myself and because we
end up going with this stove
as six burners, I'm like,
oh there's two of us were like,
what the fuck do I want?
Even when we have Thanksgiving dinner,
I've never had more than three going
at a time. You know what I mean?
You have some in the oven,
you've got something else.
And so you've got two sides,
maybe three sites, right?
That's it. You don't need six.
I should have got the fucking griddle.
But then I saw this,
this attachment that you can get
that you put the griddle on top,
but it's not the same cause now you kind
of control in the heat with like the
burners. So what I would do is I
put one on simmer, right or low,
and then the other one I'd put,
put it up on the cook and eat.
So I can do that whole fucking thing
of a moving the food around, you know,
if it's going too fast, if it needs
to chill, if the bread's brown and up,
but the cheese hasn't melted yet.
All that shit that I learned.
If Fabro ever puts that shit
out, dude, I'm telling you man,
I learned more goddamn shit
about cooking just with that,
controlling the heat and moving it around
and actually looking at the stuff I
can't even,
I'm beside myself.
I immediately became 15 to
20% better cook than I was,
which isn't hard because
I suck. But um, anyway,
so I started watching this guy. You
guys got to check this guy out on, on,
on Youtube.
Um,
he actually promotes the grill
that I wasn't going to get.
It's just a little too big for me,
but it's the Blackstone grill
and there's this guy, uh,
what the fuck does he call himself?
He goes by Todd Tovan, T.
O. D. D. T. O. V. E. N.
And m.
What does he call himself,
although rocky mountain meet hunter.
All right.
He's on Twitter at rocky mountain,
meet hunter.com.
But you don't need to go to Twitter
unless you want to just tell him you like
his videos, but you just watch this
guy fucking Cook, you know? Uh,
I know he's hyping all these barbecue
sauces and rubs and all that ship a good
fan.
A man's got to make a living,
but the shit that he makes is
fucking unbelievable and a too,
when you see this griddled there's no
fucking way, just to let you guys know,
they make a smaller one, um, that I'm
thinking about getting, but a dude,
it's fucking ridiculous.
He's making fucking cheese steaks.
He's making case at d is he made
pizza in this other fucking thing.
He's toasting up the bonds. He's
got his onions, peppers going.
He's got elk on the grill.
Whatever the fuck you want.
I actually watched this guy was so
inspired by him and in a frying pan,
I took some of that elk that Rogan gave
me and I made late at night. I made a, um,
sort of my version of an elk cheese steak.
I had some peppers and onions going in
with a little bit of mushroom. Right.
And then, uh, the meat that he
gave me is more like hamburgers.
So it was more of a consistency of
hamburger. So I couldn't really lay it in.
I had to kind of pour it into the bun, but
I put the, uh, you know, the fucking, uh,
uh, the provolone on top.
I don't like the wisdom.
I don't like to waste provolone on top.
I could have seasoned the meat a
little bit more of just my salt shaker.
I don't know what it is. I can't
see it coming out. It comes out.
So finally I was tasting it and I didn't
want to oversell it, but I needed to,
I probably should put like,
I don't know,
garlic salt or something
like that in there,
but a little cheese on top with
the mushrooms and then the peppers.
And then I had the best fucking role ever.
And I made this thing like
one in the morning, you know,
I was coming home from doing my
spots and I made it. And you know,
Nia sitting there going,
what are you two and it's too late.
And then I made the thing, I came walking
in and she was like, what is that? Right.
And I gave her a bite and then of course,
you know she does that fucking shit.
I want one. Oh look at what is, oh
she just called and I missed the call.
Um, anyways, so I am
crazy in the doing that.
So I'm, I'm thinking about getting that
for the backyard. We'll see. We'll see.
He has already given me, you know,
she, she knows what she's doing.
She just sort of, you know, like when you
really excited about getting something,
your wife just sort of just,
you know, it was quiet and nods.
That means they don't want you to get
it and they're just waiting for hoping
that your excitement will go
away after a couple of days.
But I do the same thing to her.
What's up buddy?
You totally know how to work the angles,
don't you cleo?
Sometimes when she wants something rather
than, than coming over and being crazy.
She just comes over and she just put
her head on my leg and then just sort of
look at me, you know, how do you resist
that Cleo kitchen? Not Thank you. Come on,
go lay down. Go lay down. Go
lay down. Go on. All right. Um,
maybe read a little bit of
advertising here for the week. Um,
oh, audit. Speaking to Joe Rogan,
Joe Rogan's company on it. I'm on.
It has a new product.
It's called emulsified MCT oil.
Mct Oil is one of the fastest sources of
clean fuel for the body and the brain.
It's one of the best ways to power
up your performance. A kickstart,
a weight management program. There
are lots of MCT oil brands out there,
but there's none like emulsified MCT oil
from Onnit available in three delicious
flavors, coconut, Vanilla
and strawberry. As I said,
that's all my three flavors.
I got a coconut head,
vanilla skin and strawberry
peach emulsified MCT oil
mixes like a cream easily
in your morning. Coffee without the
need for a blender. No mess. No,
you can even mix it right into
your favorite foods right now.
If you go to [inaudible] dot
com slash bill you can get on,
it's emulsified MCT oil for 12% off.
That's o n n I t.com/bill to get
emulsified MCT oil for 12% off.
And for any reason, if you don't like
it, they'll give you your money back.
No questions asked, no biggie.
You've got nothing to lose.
Go to [inaudible] dot com slash
bill and get on it. All right.
D s l t d genes, Jesus Christ, uh,
Delta, Sierra Lima, Tango, Delta genes.
The problem with jeans
is that they're really,
that the really good payers cause
two to $300. Isn't that the truth?
Easily in the bargain brands just fall
apart. It look terrible. That's also true.
So you either you have no
money, right? Or uh, you know,
your ass is hanging out and people
beat the shit out of you. I mean that,
those are your two options. You
know, unless you're, you know,
you're one of those fucking son's
of a Saudi Arabian prince, right?
And you just rolling barrels oil down
the fucking stairs every morning.
Tea stld pronounced distilled. I didn't
know that actually I did, but I forgot.
Has revolutionized the fashion industry
by creating timeless luxury grade denim,
so you get genes that would cost you
hundreds of dollars starting at just $65
this was my question. How do they
do it? Let's see how they do it.
By refusing to work with department
stores in retail middlemen,
there's no markup, no bullshit, just
great chains at an unbelievable price.
Just go to distill.com spelled d, e,
s, t, l, D Delta, Sierra, tango, Lima,
delta.com find the perfect
pair with the perfect fit.
They'll ship them to you for
free and guarantee the fit.
Or we'll send you a new pair till they
are perfect or it doesn't say they'll
take it back. They'll just keep shipping.
You Ain't getting your money back.
You're going to get more jeans.
See for yourself.
Why a list celebrities have been spotted
in magazines like vogue and Gq wearing
distilled jeans while
you're fucking paid him too.
If you just spot them out back, you know,
making a fucking hotdog without the bun.
Of course they got to keep the abs there.
Even c list celebrities like me,
I don't like how they made me trash
myself. I will do the trashing of me.
I'm a c plus celebrity. I've got a
cartoon on Netflix that makes me see,
plus I got a pair of raw denim and it,
the fit is amazing.
You know what's funny about this?
I have not gotten that yet.
You know my fucking producer on the
show he's wearing and he said they're
fucking unbelievable and he wears them
all the time. All right, so I never,
you know, I got too much shit in my
house. So whenever these advertisers say,
we'll send you some stuff,
like I never take it,
but he's wearing them now and he's
been raving about them so much.
Now I want to fucking pair. That's how
it works. That's how America works.
That's how you defeat isis distilled as
the only place in the u s where you can
get this weight of denim for this price
point. And with the natural indigo. Look,
remember the indigo girls.
I went to the doctor,
I went down on my friend.
They're going to fit beautifully
and for last four years,
but you don't need to be already or
have a stylist or you pay $100 to look
amazing. Just go to distilled a
starts at 65 bucks. Half off. I,
you're lucky we get it. Where the fuck
did we go? That's distilled.com DST
ld.com/bird for $10 off right
now. Five levers, five letters,
d s t l d.com/burr. Oh, that
was fucking, that. That was,
I liked it. I went to the time. I'm sorry.
All right, Luke crate everybody. Give me,
uh, be the envy of your friends.
Oh my God. Look at him. God,
I wish I was him.
What is,
what does the person doing that this
would be the envy of other people and get
100% exclusive
crates@lukecraig.com slash burr and
enter my code burr to save $3 off any
subscription. Why do you want
to be the envy of your friends?
Why won't you let your friends know
what's going on and y'all get a crate.
Jesus Christ, Luke Crane,
you boxing yourself out.
Get Out,
get a fucking loot crate and tell all
your friends about it so there's no envy
and they can all stand around. Hey, I like
you wonder woman outfit. Well thank you.
I like your Flash Gordon fucking wig.
I'm on a quest for epic gear,
housewares and collectibles.
Is that what you want to
do while loot crate has it?
Loot crate offers an epic range of pop
culture items for less than $20 a month.
Uh, if you're a more of a fan
fanatical, I just want to,
if they have wonder woman's fucking
drawers, one of those nerds,
they can put it on their fucking,
they can sleep next to it and you know,
sniffing her and invisible pussy. Well,
she's done a visible issue. Her plane is,
it never made any sense.
Um, if you're more of a fan,
but you can still every comedian do that,
but you can still see her.
She should be invisible in it.
But then just for animation purposes,
then you'd have to be like,
you know where, where is it?
Would you showing clouds going by?
You know what's funny like this is
probably like a 40 minute argument in the
writer's room at Hannah Barbera, one of
those fucking places a long time ago.
Back to the advertising.
Yeah. If you're more a fan,
fanatical Fashionista than try loot where
monthly wearables and accessories with
cult classics and your
favorite franchises.
I want to Hook Joe to Rosa up with this.
If you want to get fantasy,
get a bigger box and even
bigger loop with loot crate DX.
Get ready for Novembers
and chanting theme.
Magical loot crate is a cast as cast,
a powerful ancient spelled deliver you
November's crate featuring be witching
items from Dr. Strange, not
doctor strange love, Dr. Strange,
fantastic beasts and where to find them.
Sorry. They just ended and then
it went to the next sentence,
but there was a gap there.
A big trouble in little China.
I love that movie and so much more.
Do not wait.
You have until the 19th at 9:00 PM
Pacific to subscribe for Novembers crate.
When it's over, it's over. No more
crates. Go to Luke crew duck loot,
crate.com Luke crate.com/burn and enter
my code bar to save $3 off any new
subscription today. Luke. Cute.
Um, oh Jesus Christ. How many more?
Okay.
All right. Two more. Two more.
Hang in there guys. Hang. Well,
how much time is left me?
Go fuck around a little more and then
I'll read the last of these. All right,
we'll fuck around a little more.
MMM.
All right. What did I want to talk about?
Oh, fucking who's playing this week?
Who's was playing this week
in college football? Anything?
Do I actually have anything else that I
want to talk about other than the fact
that I like making Hash browns snuff.
Oh,
do I tell you guys how much I
enjoy making fucking Hash Brown.
Take your breakfast to the next
level with a griddle. Make it some.
Fuck that. You know
something. If you just have,
I just want to shut people the fuck up.
Just make some Hash browns.
Start them off the cheesy ones,
and then you bake them in the oven
and you shot everybody the fuck up.
If you want to shut me the fuck up,
that's basically what you can do. Hey,
shout out to Steve Bartman. Everybody.
Hey Dude, stay in hiding, man. Don't,
don't let those carts draw you back out.
All right.
They had the chance to be friends with
a great person like you. All right?
You know they're going to try to ask
you to go to the parade, you know? Oh,
all is forgiven. All
is forgiven. You know,
it was just fucking 13 years of health.
Um,
do you guys think he goes, do you think
he goes back? I don't think he does.
He said no to 30 for 30 kind of. Seems
like he would just eat, you know,
he's a very commendable person.
He was somebody that has
no desire for fame in this
century, which is a, you know,
more than I can say for myself or in
90% of the other people out there.
So God bless them. All right.
Actually, I have one question.
I usually don't read questions. On a
Thursday afternoon podcasts. I'm like,
Tom Steele, Yo Billy ginger tits.
Yes, I did enjoy the two hour podcast,
but you're wrong about one thing.
It's not illegal for women to show their
titties or even go topless in most of
the United States. I
didn't know that. In fact,
33 states have laws specifically
allowing it. However, certain towns,
cities,
and municipal areas within each of these
states prohibits to practice a sighting
disturbing the peace as a misdemeanor,
as interpreted by law enforcement
sometimes incorrectly.
Uh, if you're digging it, okay, I,
this is the deal dude. Like I guess,
you know, in Africa and some
of these other countries,
they walk around with their titties out.
I guess people don't give a shit about it.
It's like not a big deal.
They get used to it like seeing
a woman's legs or whatever.
If women want to do this shit, I
have come full circle. Fuck it.
You want to walk around with
the Goddamn titties out?
I don't know why you'd want to,
I gotta be honest with you.
Most men should not be walking around
with his shirt off like they should be a
rule. Okay. You want to have your
shirt off. Either you're at the beach,
you're in your own backyard or you're
working on a chain gang fucking digging a
trench in the side of the road.
Okay.
If you're actually working for a fucking
live and you want to take your goddamn
shirt off and risk skin cancer, by
all means do it. Okay. Believe me,
there's a lot of guys with
their shirts out there.
They got bigger tits that most of the
women out there. So um, I just think
it's a funny thing that like,
I just don't understand why women would
just like, why can't we do it? They just,
they,
they just have that fee maybe cause it's
a position they are in society the way
men kept them down for so fucking long
that every last fucking thing that we do,
they want to do regardless
of how fucking stupid it is.
You know what I mean?
Who the fuck wants to walk
around with his shirt off?
Yeah.
Matthew mcconaughey, people like
that. People in like p 90 x shape,
like walking around with that this year
and which makes sense. You did the work.
God bless you. I've never had a desire
to walk around with my fucking shirt off.
Yeah,
yeah. Why would you be half?
Especially past a certain age,
you got to start covering
up 48 fucking years old.
You don't want to see a half naked
anything. There's a few out there.
Madonna kept herself in great shape.
You know what I mean?
There's a few people out there. They,
they've kept themselves, you know,
and in phenomenal shape,
they can take their fucking shirts up.
But for the most part, most people by 23,
24, by all means, man, a man, a woman,
keep the fucking shirt on. I Dunno.
That's just one of those things.
I don't know what they mean.
It's like listening to somebody complain
about the island in their kitchen.
It's just like, don't you have
anything better to focus on? All right.
The hypocrite continues.
Um, so I guess, uh,
see claiming equal topless rights for men
and women go topless is something here.
Uh, go topless claims that women
have the same constitutional right,
that men have to go bare
chested and public. Uh,
I really disagree with
that to try to say like,
our titties are the same as your titties.
My titties can't get me around a drinks,
you know what I mean?
If I show half a fucking man peck
hair that doesn't get me anything.
Or maybe I'm just in the wrong bars, maybe
I need to go into a gay bar there too.
That's a great youtube video.
Go into a gay bar and dress like a man or,
and see how long you can drink for free.
That would be fucking hilarious. Near the
end of the night, the guys like, hey man,
do you want to get out of
here and be like, yeah,
but I'm not going on with you and be like,
dude,
what the fuck bought Shell is drinks?
We like, yeah, well I'm straight. Well,
what the fuck are you doing here? I
just want, I wanted to drink for free.
Yeah.
Then he goes to swing at
you just go, no. Right?
You get out of their drinking a
bunch of Budweiser's simply safe.
It's crazy what engineers are
coming up with these days.
The engineer invented the simply safe
home security system was attending Harvard
University. When his friends got
robbed, he wanted to help them out.
So they started shopping
around for home security.
But all the security companies
at the time were just awful.
They'd sell these clunky,
expensive systems that required all
sorts of drilling to install. And again,
I'm yet to sign a huge longterm
contract. That's what I did. So this guy,
simply safe to try and fix all the
problems with the security industry.
Simply safe has wireless.
There's no drilling.
I did all of this to my house.
You don't have to put a bunch of holes
in your walls to keep your family safe.
God dammit.
Okay.
This is why. Why buy anything?
Because then they always come up, oh,
just hovers in the fucking air.
Anyway. Simply safe is wireless.
All right? Um, there is no
longterm contract. You don't
have to pay for something.
You're not using 24 seven monitoring.
It's just 1499 a month.
That's three times less than other
security companies. Fucking cock suckers.
Visit simply safe bird.com today with
this 60 day money back guarantee and a
three year warranty.
You've got nothing to worry about.
Plus go today and get a free
shipping and a free key chain remote.
He can arm and disarm your system with
the push of a button that's simply safe.
bird.com simply say
[inaudible] dot com fuck
yeah.
Yeah. Jesus. Well, what do I feel like?
Everything in my house is
the technological equipment
of a fucking laserdisc
player. I'm going to look into those
guys and see what the fucking deal is.
All right. [inaudible] everybody.
This is the last thing.
Buying tickets online for
sports and concerts has been
a confusing process for a
long,
long time.
It's always been hard to find the best
deal for that game or show you want to go
to and none of those older tickets sites
want to charge that. Change that. Sorry,
but SeatGeek is different.
They've come along and created an amazing
APP and website that makes it easier
than ever for forever for
fans to buy and sell tickets.
Siki does all the price comparisons for
you by searching multiple tickets sites
and ensuring that you get
the best possible deal and
seek wants to help you get
the most bang for your buck.
That's why every ticket on SeatGeek
is given a grade based on value.
You'll immediately see any underpriced
seats to be able to find the best deals
that fit your project. Best of
all, my listeners get $20 off,
re a $20 rebate off
their SeatGeek purchase.
To get your $20 rebate on tickets,
download the SeatGeek APP, go to settings,
go to the settings tab and click add
a promo code. Enter the Promo Code.
Burr SeatGeek will send you $20 off after
you made your first ticket purchase.
Download. Seek Keke the seed APP and enter
the Promo Code bird today. All right.
That's it for the advertising.
That is it for me.
Congratulations once again to
all the Chicago Faithful, uh,
to the other 80% that showed up.
Congratulations to you too.
And the bandwagons, um, Micah
Dolan's is to Cleveland fans.
You didn't get the calves this year.
Uh, you do have Terry Francona.
You've got great players in,
uh, yeah, I mean, I dunno,
we won one with Manny Ramirez
and everybody else to so
many, like the Phillies,
Yankee fans,
red sox fans.
All should've been rooting for Cleveland
because we all used your fucking CCS.
Your Manny Ramirez, you, Jim told me he's,
we all use those guys to get
our championships. And uh,
also that pitcher who fucking pitch for
everybody to forget his fucking name
wasn't curt Floyd.
Was it clear? Was it, can I get
a whole lot of you before we go?
That's kind of the sign off now.
Hey Cleo,
you want to quote say
down,
down?
No jumping cleo.
Cleo not fight.
Cleo.
Do you?
Oh,
she always stayed cause she's kind
of itch. Come on. Come on you guys.
You know you can meet as long enough
he can hang in Memphis, cliff. Sit.
Sit Cleo
to, she's not going to do it today. Cleo,
Cleo.
[inaudible]
I think especially when we get out
of it. Alright, go fuck yourselves.
Congratulations to the
cubs. My consultants as the
Cleveland Indians at all.
I'll see you on Monday. Have a
great weekend. You can listen to.
These are greatest sets
after this music of juices.
When we say
[inaudible], Hey, what's going
on? It's still, but it is
Monday morning podcasts for Monday,
October 27 2008 and the Year
of our Lord Jesus Christ.
What is this? The year four,
are you Catholic? What do we do?
I know that the Chinese people,
he always got, you know,
the year of the Yak and why is it?
That's always my default animal
yak is just funny. I'm sorry,
I didn't know what the fuck it is.
What is a Yak?
That's your homework for this week.
If you're a regular listener,
let me know what a Yak is and what,
where are they indigenous to?
Okay, I'm going to go out on a
limb and I'm going to say, uh,
I'm going to say Scotland.
I don't think there's any JAKKS over
here at the Rye JAKKS over here.
They were brought here against their will.
Much like those people from Africa.
And, you know, I think it's high time that
they made an Amistad for fucking JAKKS.
You know, what about all the
livestock? What about the
fucking Dodo Bird? You know,
what about the fucking llamas give it
just couldn't be in the middle of nowhere
and somebody has a fucking Lama,
you know, how did it get there?
That thing doesn't have a story. That
thing doesn't it need to go, you know,
check out his family tree and figured
out where the fuck it came from.
What the hell was I? I was
in, no, no, I was in Richmond,
Virginia and I'm driving down the street
with the guy who works over there,
buzz with one Z who was one of
my favorite people in comedy.
The guys literally 60 years old and he's
still hits on like 22 year olds and he
creeps him out every time he does
it and he doesn't give a shit.
And uh, you know, I got to
respect him for that, but anyways,
would drive it in the radio station and
there's a fucking Lama in the middle of
Richmond, Virginia. And, uh, you know,
I really wanted to know why.
You know,
what exactly,
what do people do with llamas?
Devin tell you guys that I love
goats if ever told you that shit.
Like the goat is the perfect pet for me
because I haven't, I like to fucking,
I have a tendency to fuck with animals.
You know what I mean?
I fuck with people and it doesn't stop
there. You know, I don't know what it is.
I stopped playing with the puppy and
then eventually I rolled him over on his
back. I semi sorta hold him down,
which gets them all fucking, uh,
you know,
all aggressive and next thing you know,
they take a bite out of my hand,
you know, take a chunk out of me.
So that's why I don't have a fucking
Doug because I turned them into a,
those dogs you see on the news
that need to get put down.
So I found goats actually enjoy that shit.
Then when you look in,
you know,
when you're,
when you're looking the other way and
go to take a run at yes. You know,
they're like a dirty player and uh,
it was,
it was a classic dirty player from
way back in the fucking day. I,
even Chris nine and island, you
know, he would do some shit.
He did Rick Middleton in the mouth
with this the button end of his stick.
That's kind of a dirty, but I know
he was never really into boarding.
I'll Samuelson.
That's what a goal is to go is the
all Samuelson a fucking farm animals.
Anytime you've got your head down and
you're facing the bar and the thing,
I'll take a run at you.
And the problem is it never gets
suspended from the league. All right.
This is the Monday morning podcast.
My name is bill burr.
I mentioned that earlier. And uh,
currently I am in the midst of the, uh,
the uninformed a radio tour,
which a is uninformed,
the radio show I do with Joe de Rosa and
the two of us around on tour right now
to hype the show and things
are going great. And our
next stop is going to be in,
uh, Washington DC, the
weekend of, uh, you know what,
I don't know what fucking weekend it is.
I think it's the first
weekend in November.
Let me go here and go onto my new fancy
website. If you guys checked it out yet,
if you're not on my website right now
and you have on myspace page, you know,
they'll do it now cause you'll lose the
fucking podcast. But at the end of it,
go to [inaudible] dot com and a brand
new sleep website with a bunch of sexy
photos of me, um, that make me look like
I'm a lot cooler than I am. All right,
November 6th through the eighth,
I'll be at the Improv in Washington
DC on the uninformed tour,
me and Joe de Rosa and on,
uh,
the 11th November,
sorry,
November 13th through the 15th,
we'll be at Zany comedy club in
Nashville, Tennessee. And uh,
the next big data after that is going
to be at Carolines in New York City,
uh, December 4th through the seventh.
And if anybody cares on December 8th,
I will be at the La Forum. Am I
going to be doing stand up? No,
I'm not going to be watching ACDC.
ACDC had the La Forum, but I
tell you guys, my pumpkin died.
My pumpkin. I mean technically, I don't
know. Well, when did the Pumpkin Pie,
this is going to get like the pro life
pro choice pumpkin people up in uh,
up in an uproar here when,
when exactly does a Pumpkin,
like what is going on? You know, that's
just so much shit I don't know in life.
Is this stem was that was
that it's fucking in biblical
cord and you set it free.
Now it goes off to live a life and
hopefully not marry the wrong person,
you know,
and get divorced and end up on a Fuckin
futon or the second you snip that the
does is the function. The function is
the fucking pumpkin dead. The function.
It's a good name for a band.
Come up on stage playing fucking P
funk with Pumpkin's on your heads.
And you know what?
If he had a catch phrase,
you could be a huge comedian and you
could play the La Forum. Now, seriously,
this is what I learned with Pumpkin's.
All right.
Don't call him three weeks before because
they die in your refrigerator and it
makes you sad and you've got to throw
them out and nobody even got to see him.
So, uh, so I gotta make another one. I
have to make another one. You know what?
This is just classic me
on my fucking podcast.
I started talking about some shit and
I forgot where the fuck I was going.
And now here I am. Here I am
pulled over the side of the road,
looking at the map, trying to figure out,
all right, let's go to the questions. Uh,
you're new to my podcast. Um, I do,
uh, answer questions every week.
People email me,
they email
me@billatbillbird.com or they go to my
mind space page and I try to answer as
many as I can. And, um, you know,
people try to enlighten me like
a, you know, what is a Yak?
You know,
what is a Yak?
Is that like a fucking druggie
cow with this hippie hair?
You don't want to fucking
Google a fucking Yak right now.
And I'm looking at an image.
How do you spell yak?
It's not why a c k that means you puked.
Speaking of which to,
you know when I was looking at all
the different Pumpkin, uh, pictures,
you know,
ideas pumpkin's that one where you,
where your carve of pumpkin phase with
its mouth open and then you take the
inside of the Pumpkin and place it around
the mouth and it looks like it puked
is very hacky.
They must've been 80 pumpkin's like that.
Jesus Christ. But the
debt, that's a fucking Yak.
Wow. Okay. I've got some a
don't fuck with me horns.
It looks like, it looks like a
Texas longhorn that needs a haircut.
Is a guy milking one? Oh, is
that a woman? Hang on a second.
Yak uses. You guys want to
learn about JAKKS. Here we go.
Statue of Golden Jakks in downtown Tibet.
Exactly
the fuck are you x doing over here?
The YAC is truly the treasure
of the plateau. Well,
why don't you let me be the judge of it.
I hate when people make up my mind for me.
All right.
Evidently this Douche bag says it's
the treasure of the plateau. Well,
what does its competition?
I'm the gopher. All right.
As the inscription reads below,
the Golden Statue of Jakks is in a
busy intersection in downtown La,
Hoffa in the mountain,
Tundra and ice desert of the
Tibetan plateau with altitude,
altitude soaring over 19,000 feet.
Jakks flourish where other
domestic DCE die because of this.
People inhabiting this region
use the Yag for everything.
Okay. That's an open ended sentence. Okay.
So they obviously use it as a food source.
There's a girl milking one,
some Tibetan lady, and uh,
they use it for everything.
Okay.
Are you lifting the tail up and doing
something disgusting that's on Youtube or
is it more tube eight?
The YAC is inescapable in La Hasa.
The accurate,
slightly sour smell of yak
butter permeates the streets.
Okay.
I guess I'll never be going to lots of,
who the fuck wants to smell
sour butter at 19,000 feet?
I, you know, something
I would not be able to,
to keep the look of disgust off my face.
And then they all start speaking into
bed and thinking that I was some American
who thought they were above
people rather than do.
There's a fucking pungent smell,
you know,
a tangent into the mainstream
was will Ferrell in a anchorman,
pungent stings the
nostrils. Um, all right,
so it permeates the streets and temples
where pilgrims burn the whitish yellow
fat at a numerable altars and carry
smoking candles through the streets.
Let me just make a living like that.
This lady milk at a Yak, no laptop,
no iPhone dress like an Apache
everyday.
Just reach underneath some fucking
JAKKS utter. And there you go.
You don't have to go down to,
uh, go down and get a smoothie.
Yak Milk is golden in color and
very rich and fat at seven to 8%.
And why the fuck is she so
skinny and as a Swedish taste?
Then why did you just describe it? You
know, you know what? Fuck this website.
He said sour smell. And now you're saying
it's a sour smell with a Swedish taste?
Maybe that's why their eyes are so
squinty. It's not because their eyes,
I like this because they're confused.
They say it doesn't make sense, you know,
smell sour taste.
So sweet.
No protection from Jakks is
seasonal hybrid JAKKS oh good. Okay.
Everybody's on the global warming and I
want to want to far it has like 90% less
, uh, uh, got damaged
on the tip of my tongue.
What the fuck kind of gas is in cow's gas
begins with an m methane.
Maybe JAKKS have less methane gas.
Is that the green people? They're going
to do that. Eat a Yak Burger instead.
All right. I think I'm sick
of yaks at this point. You
guys sick a good, you know,
and I felt that you're like, all right,
bill enough with the fucking JAKKS. Um,
so anyways,
they're into bed and next time I do
a road gig in like fucking Austin or
something, I swear to God I'm a drive
by and be like, what the fuck is that?
And some guy names,
you know,
fuck with oneF is going to be like a,
that's a Yak.
What is it doing here? I don't
know buddy. I don't know.
My job is just take you the radio station.
Why don't you just focus on that being
funny is spelled sell some more fucking
tickets.
You know what I mean?
How many fucking specialty you need to
have before we can fill up a fucking
comedy club?
Why don't you get a catch phrase?
Why don't you just go on stage and just
talk about JAKKS for fucking hour and
then you can be the fucking yet guy.
And I wouldn't have to drive you to the
fucking radio station because you would
have sold out second.
They put you fucking name up.
You ever think about that will
then shut the fuck up then. Okay.
Um, all right, so let's get
on with the podcast questions.
Hey Bill,
have you ever auditioned for SNL
when you lived in New York City?
That group seems to be clickish,
but I wondered if Lauren Michaels ever
gave you a chance to be on the show.
You know what? I can't remember
if I audition for SNL or mad TV,
but it was about nine years ago and I
know I bombed because I went in there with
jokes rather than characters I had.
I would have like a quick care,
I'd have a character and then just do a
quick joke about them and then move on
to something else.
Like I remember one of my characters,
I played a guy who was in the
Klan who had a speech impediment.
He gets blocked on Edwards and I just
remember part of the audition of me
staying,
they go in the noon to noon and then just
sort of ended and everyone was looking
at me like I had fucking
12 heads. So, uh, yeah, I,
I don't think the reason why I'm
not on SNL is because it's clickish.
It's probably because,
uh,
Lauren had watched that tape at some
point and projectile vomited. All right,
go. Me and a friend at work
run a celebrity death pool.
If you don't know what this is, here
it is in a nutshell. You put an egg,
you put an x amount of a month and
then you get a list of randomly picked
potential people who may die very soon.
You know what I noticed
celebrity death pool is,
and you didn't really describe it.
Well basically you a,
you pick not random people you paint,
you pick random celebrities,
famous people who you
think are going to die.
I thought it was in a calendar year.
I guess they do it every month because
these guys have a gambling problem set.
Basically. You'd be like, you know what?
I think a fucking Lisa Lu c or
whatever the fuck her name is,
Lucy Lu,
I think she's going to uh,
eat some bad sushi and a, yeah. I said,
should we film in over
in Japan and what's,
what's that Sushi that they
eat over there? Some sort of,
if eat the wrong part of it,
you could fucking die.
And if some macho thing to eat it,
she's going to go do that, you know,
to prove she's one of the guys and she
hangs out with the crew and she's going
to die like that. That's
what you would do. All right.
The payout happens only when
cnn.com announces it. Oh,
this is the are rules. Okay,
I'm back to the question now. The obvious
favorites or people like Fidel Castro,
Barbara Bush, Amy Winehouse,
that midget from Austin Powers.
That's a good one.
Patrick Swayze, etc. Well,
every month everyone in the
pool gets to pick a wild card.
Who wasn't on the original roster?
Well,
I took a lot of shit this past
week. Ah, I don't want to read this.
I don't want to read this because I don't
want to put ideas in people's heads.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry. I just, you know
what? I got you guys all excited. No, no,
I'm not fucking reading that
one. Um, all right, Bill.
I recently grew a beard. There's a
lot of social commentary in this. Uh,
these questions this week.
Bill,
I recently grew a beard and had an
argument with a gay guy that I work with.
He told me that all men
with beards are gay.
That must have really killed your fucking
idea of growing a beard. So he says,
and my whole argument was where to gay
people get off just claiming something as
their own just because they like it.
Am I the only one who thinks that they
can get away with this logic that they
can get away with this logic is
fucking crazy. You know, waxes,
eyebrows and going 10 to tanning salons.
I'll give him that one. But a beard.
When I think of people with beards,
I don't think gay.
I think lumberjack swinging axes.
It's kind of gay.
Um, Ben tobers treats thumb. Did you
ever see that Monty python sketch?
I'm a lumberjack and I don't care.
Have a good day. Buh, Buh, Buh Buh.
And eventually he gets gay or,
and dare and pull it out a fucking
dresses and dress just like me.
Mom. He's a warmer jacket. He
don't care. He fucking sucks.
Cock any licks the bulls. Anyways,
when he thinks of a beard, uh,
he thinks of lumberjack swinging
access like that job still exist.
Don't they have fucking chain sounds
at this point? Playoff hockey. Yup.
I'll give you that. And I think that
some gay people, some in quotes,
gay people have gotten way
too comfortable in society.
Those bastards. Where did they
get off? Be uncomfortable.
Cause if he lived in the
south and not New York City,
he'd be dragged behind a truck for saying
that all men with beards are gay and
not that I condone that behavior but
maybe some gays have it coming to them.
Jesus Christ.
Then he writes,
that's all really is that all uh,
you know you pop off at the mouth.
There are consequences if you
would your thoughts please.
I'll tell you what happened.
I think you're a little uncomfortable
with gay people and you wanted to grow a
beard and you are all set on grown in
and then some gay guy came up maybe
realizing that you are homophobic,
decided to fuck with your head.
And he said all men with beards are
gay and it pissed you off because you
thought this was going to be some rugged
shit that was going to get you some
pussy. And as you grow in it, you can't
get that guy out of your head going, oh,
men with beards. Aughey so
here's my number, sweetie.
Um, I don't know. I don't think
all men were put there to gay. Um,
and I think a lot of times when you
see a guy with a beard who is gay,
you can tell because it's too
manicured to George Michael ask,
you know what I mean?
But you gotta you gotta you do have to
manicure it to a certain point manicure
at such as that's fucking nails,
whatever. You know what I'm saying?
You got to trim it. It's two
landscapes, but you know,
you've got to keep it off your neck or if
it's just itchy is fucking hell. Uh, no,
I don't think beers are gay.
Um,
I think I thought more like
hipster guys do it, you know,
and all the hipsters are trying
to address like they're, uh,
during the Beastie boys sabotage video,
you know,
they're trying to dress that
way, but there's this air of, Oh,
I didn't even notice,
you know,
it just accidentally dressed
like I was in the 70s.
Um, one of my thoughts, my
thoughts are basically, dude,
I think that if you want to grow a beard,
you should grow a beard.
And I think if a gay guy in down south
and all guys who have beards are gay,
I would like to think that people would
just laugh and still grow a beard if
they wanted to rather than
get all uncomfortable to
the point that they'd want
to drag a gay guy behind the truck
and beat the shit out of him. Uh,
I don't think anybody has that
come into them in that instance.
You know what I mean?
Um, but if I was gay,
I would probably be careful
of who I said that to.
Considering there are people out there
who feel that people who do that should
be dragged behind a truck and get,
you know what you know,
in a way the person is right.
You, when you do run your mouth,
there are consequences cause you
don't realize who the psychos are.
And this guy seems a little psychotic,
a little psychotic.
He doesn't condone the behavior,
but he's just saying,
Jesus, can we have a lighthearted question
here where I don't have to, you know?
Okay. Question. Uh, Bill,
I was having a cigarette
outside a restaurant last
week and a guy who is missing
both arms comes over telling me to put
it out because I was disturbing him with
my secondhand smoke. All right,
you guys just making this shit up.
This really seems made up, but you
know, just for the comedy of it,
I'll go with it.
He was wearing a muscle shirt.
Okay. Um, guess I'm still
going to believe this.
He was wearing a muscle shirt
completely exposing his nubs.
I jokingly told this guy, I'll put it
out if he beats me at a game of rock,
paper, scissors and its
questions. Bullshit.
You didn't say this eight is it bullshit?
This is even if he had
a muscle tee shirt on,
even if he had no arms in,
even if he fucking came over and told
you to put out the cigarette is no way.
You said if you beat me, if I'd be, if
he beats you at a game of rock, paper,
scissors, you know this. That's like
the shit you wish you said when he left.
But I will go with it.
Okay.
You know far be it for me to say that
people are lying to me. All right.
Or exaggerating.
So evidently after he did this,
I'm the guy went off,
the guy went off on me and I felt bad.
So I put it out. Oh, after
you destroyed the guy,
then I put it down. I pissed them off
and I was like, all right, there you go.
They asked the question,
should amputees or people with horrific
physical deformities warn you about it
before starting startling you with?
They're terrifying.
Handicap. All right, that's
hilarious. What was he supposed to do?
Like beyond the other side of whatever
building dairy queen you were sitting in
and be like, why God just like, you know,
I don't have any arms said I'm wearing a
tank top and I'm color. I have the car.
So if you want to finish yourself,
serve and not get startled,
you know, you've got three seconds
to close your eyes. Um, you know,
something that is a, uh,
that is, yeah, it's, it's,
it's one of those things where you're
not trying to be mean. I don't know.
I can't speak for you, but
for me personally, you know,
you're not trying to be, uh,
you know, insensitive. But you know,
if you haven't been to war or you don't
work in an emergency room, they, yeah,
there are shit that you're not expecting,
but you know, you kind of roll with it.
Um, I don't think that they
should have to warn you about it,
but I don't know what you have to do
as a person to become more used to it.
I don't know. You know what? Sometimes,
sometimes I don't have the answers.
I'll tell you it's fucked up.
If you guys seen that new show on
MTV called scarred, it's insane.
It's basically footage of people
trying to do tricks on bikes,
on skateboards and on rollerblades
and it's not the funny,
Oh, and he lands on his nuts. It's
bones popping out of the skin.
And I'm gonna tell you something,
dude. It is fucking unwatchable.
And uh,
it was so twisted and sick.
I actually sent a text message to ob
from the OPN Anthony show to tell him to
get footage of it because it just seemed
like such an opn Anthony show clip,
you know, they already did two girls,
one cup. Now they could do a thing where,
you know, can you sit here and watch
bones come out of somebody's fucking hand?
Oh, brutal. All right.
Um, okay. Real quick.
Overrated. Underrated. Overrated.
Neal. Pert of rush. Awesome drummer.
But he gets way too much credit.
You know what? I would, uh,
I would definitely say he's an awesome
drummer, but yeah, he's too robotic.
I don't hear the, uh, I don't
hear a groove. I like John
Bonam like I'm way better.
All right.
Underrated Comic,
Louis C k some about three times
and he kills each and every time.
Oh Louise,
one of my favorite comics of all times.
I think he's fucking unbelievable
and he blows me away. So,
um, if somebody is saying he isn't,
then yeah, he is definitely underrated.
All right. But not amongst
Comedians, I can tell you
that. All right, last question.
Bill, here's a podcast question for
you. Uh, your business is comedy, right?
So let me ask you,
do you run the business or
does the business run you
hope? You know what I mean?
Chairs. I gotta be honest with
you. I don't know what you made.
Do I run the business as you mean my
personal business or show business?
I definitely do not run.
Show business. Are you,
do you mean do I take the time to fly
a kite each day and reflect on the fact
that I'm alive or do I just sit here and
do podcasts and fucking try to attempt
to finish blogs and shit? Um, I
don't know. It depends on the day.
Depends on the day.
I got my first massage in about
eight months and legal by the way.
And uh,
I felt great after it and I've decided
that I was going to start doing that.
You know, you know me, you know I
have fucking OCD. So I was like,
I want to do it every week.
You know,
I'll spend 50 grand a
year on fucking massages,
which would cause stress. You know, I
really gotta do something about my, my,
I, I'm just like, I just realized
that I'm going to be in Nashville,
Tennessee and before I do Nashville,
the Wednesday before I do Nashville,
I'm going to do the Bob and Tom Show in
Indianapolis. And I was thinking, well,
you know, I'm trying to go to every
sports fucking team for some dumb reason.
And I'm literally contemplating driving
down to go to a Memphis grizzly game
after I do Bob and Tom.
It's like a 400 mile drive.
And then after the game I would then
have to drive over to Nashville and get
there in time to check in, fall asleep,
and then do the radio in the morning.
And uh, I'd like to tell you
that I'm not going to do it,
but I think I'm going to do it and
possibly hang around and drive up to the
Cincinnati Bengals game on a Sunday.
It's pathetic, right? But, uh, I dunno,
I think I'm going to do it.
Am I running from something or am
I just a fucking maniac? I Dunno.
I Dunno what, but I can tell you this. Um,
you guys don't need to worry
about my fucking problems.
Let's wrap up this podcast. I think it
was a very good podcast. We learned, uh,
at some social commentary and uh,
we learned about Jakks,
learned about my OCD.
We learned about Pumpkin.
You guys will learn about pumpkin carving.
Something I learned when I was watching
Martha Stewart who I can't stand
watching.
It just so happened that I wanted to
carve a pumpkin and I was flipping through
and I saw pumpkin and I stopped and she
sat there with her cold demeanor where
you're poor core a point wouldn't
the things you want to do.
Cause she just seems like she'd be the
worst mother ever. Like couldn't hug you,
couldn't, she couldn't show
love and would just, you know,
could never admit when she was rung. And
Geez, I'm fucking projecting right now.
Um, so basically what you
want to do with the Pumpkin,
what I learned is you want to lead
area the side where you're going to be
carving into. You want to make
that as thin as humanly possible.
That way when you light the candle inside
of it, it glows this bright orange.
So if you carve something
scary or something like that,
it's the shit.
I really got to figure out how to upload
pictures from my cell phone onto my
computer cause you gotta see this ACDC
Pumpkin and I mean, you know what?
Now I'm going to hype it up so
much. You can be like, dude,
it really didn't live up to the
hype and then I'll be hurt. And uh,
which would be the reverse
of what I wanted to do.
The reverse of the exercise of carving
a Pumpkin was for me to be a happier
human being, more at peace. Um, all right,
let's, let's fucking wrap this up. I say
this every week and then I keep going.
Let's, let's re hype the
gigs, all rights I have. Um,
I'll be at the Improv, Washington
DC, November 6th through the eighth.
After that I'll be at Zany comedy club
November 13th through the fucking 15th.
And I'm, Hey, you know what? I'm going
to go to that Goddamn Bengals game.
What do you think about that?
Any listeners in Cincinnati,
you got an extra fucking let me know.
I'll come up to your tailgate.
We'll fucking eat some ribs that you cook
now out to you, don't it? I'll be like,
uh, I'll be like a has been celebrity.
I'll do show up like, this is what my,
uh, my career has come to you.
Gotta you gotta pay me in,
in fucking smoked ribs and I'll
show up to your tailgate. Um,
and uh, oh, I know one last thing. Uh,
we're going to be taping another episode
of uninformed. We always, uh, pre, uh,
pre taped these things.
I'm going to try and get some clips
of it up on a uninformed radio,
my face.com/uninformed
radio and a big news,
our guest is going to be Joe Perry
from Aerosmith. It's a long story.
How I ended up, I'm meeting
somebody who was related to him and,
uh,
somehow it all came together
and I'm hoping I don't make
an ass of myself when I
interview him because I'm a
huge fan and, uh, so whatever.
So I will let you know when that episode
is going to air and we will definitely
start trying to get a audio clips from
the show because people seem to like the
very special, uh, what was it Thursday,
Monday morning podcast that I taped
before this one if you want to go into the
archives. All right. That's it. I'm
babbling. It's not funny anymore.
It's just torture. All right. Hope
all you guys have a good week.
Please keep the questions coming and
I'm really enjoying them. The gun,
the underrated overrated.
And uh,
if there's anything that I said that you
felt was wrong and you'd like to, uh,
educate me, or if I asked any
questions. I know I asked about JAKKS.
Why don't you, why don't you tell me
about llamas? How about that? Where,
where they're indigenous to for some
reason, I'm thinking the Arab community.
Um, all right. That's it.
That's it. I'm rubbing my face,
which means I'm exhausted.
Or is that stress? Maybe it's stress.
Maybe I got too much shit to do.
So thanks for listening to the
Monday morning podcast. As always,
keep all the stuff coming in and,
uh,
please come out to my shows
and God bless all of you.
I hope you all have a good
week. All right. Take it easy.
[inaudible] [inaudible]
hey,
what's going on
the Monday morning podcasts,
every podcast by saying,
what's going on?
I got to come up with something else.
Maybe I should, maybe I should brand that.
Like that guy, uh, Michael buffer or, uh,
the, uh, the big bouncer looking
guy from the UFC. You know,
when he goes, are you ready? Are
you ready? Who's going? Yeah.
If for some reason he's
the only one I think,
I don't even fucking the typical, I didn't
research this, but as far as I know,
I think legally he's the
only one who can say,
let's get it on before UFC match,
which is fucking ridiculous because he
didn't come up with, let's get it on.
You know,
what's his face stiff fucking guy with
the beard who got shot by his dad,
used to wear the red hat, Marvin
Gaye. Marvin Gaye wrote a song,
let's get it on bending the 70s.
Evidently he was singing to some
fucking 14 year old girl. 16.
So I'll make them a freak 16 in the
studio trying to convince her to fuck him,
you know, so I'm able to set
up a whole nother can of worms.
The whole r Kelly thing that uh,
I don't know it was acceptable back then
or was it, was there a double standard?
Wait a second. I was going to say Rupert
Murdoch wasn't Rupert Murdoch. Who the,
what the fuck was that guy's name?
Who's that fucking guy?
He was from France. Any, uh,
he drugged up the 14 year old and a Jack
Nicholson's hot tub. Roman Polanski.
It's funny how he got in
trouble for that shit.
He had to literally leave the country.
Marvin Gaye is lily singing a song about
how he wants to fuck a 16 year old and
nothing ever happened to him until
his dad shot him. But I'm, I think,
I don't think that that
was related. Um, so anyway,
I want to fuck a 16 year old.
Let's get it on sugar.
I thought he was giving her,
that's how young she was.
You couldn't even bribe with money.
She didn't know what it was.
He was giving them those little
kid little Halloween candies. Oh,
did I carve a pumpkin this year? I tried.
I took a fucking picture of it. I caught,
I caught this awesome pumpkin. One
of them suck, but the other one,
the ACDC one,
and for the life of me,
I cannot upload it on
my fucking myspace page.
A good friend of mine heard
my problem on my last podcast.
She showed me how to do it on my phone.
I was able to email the picture to myself.
I was able to save that
picture and my fucking
eye photo thing, whatever
the fuck that is.
And then I went to upload it on my space
and then they're like, oh, we have a,
we have an error. There's an error.
I hate it. My space, how they go,
sorry. There was an unexpected
error. It's like, you know what Tom,
there's nothing unexpected about it at
this point. Okay. If it went through,
that would have been unexpected.
All right.
I've got a little look at a little fucking
up piss and vinegar in me this week.
Um, anyways, uh, I do this
podcast once a week here. Um,
I do it on a billboard.com and
simultaneous simultaneously
here on my myspace
page.
And you can download these on a,
was it iTunes and a yeah,
I do one of these every single week.
People ask me questions. I answered the
questions to the best of my ability.
And other than that, I rant about
shit and like I'm doing right now.
And, uh, before we get
started on the podcast, um,
I want to congratulate the Philadelphia
Phillies, but when in the world series,
look at that, they got this
second one. What a relief that is.
I know the feeling right now.
No one can talk shit to you and no one
can say shit to you for a long time.
You know,
you realize how long you have to suck
now in baseball for anybody to give you
shit, you know, and Ed, you fucking
done that a couple of years ago.
I would've been in trouble in Camden
because there's nothing I would have.
I could have sent him about
you. Actually, I could have,
I still could have come up with something,
but I don't want to get into that.
I'm trying to mend fences. Um,
yeah, the Phillies fucking wanted,
you know, Pete the Goddamn
double race. And look at myself.
I talked myself into a corner because
I have nothing mean to say about that
other than congratulations. And the
second year Nice. All comedy stops.
Um, anyways. You know what,
let me, let me see what, let's,
let's hype what I have co what's hype,
what I have coming up this week. Um,
I have,
uh,
I have to open a fucking window to know
where the hell I have coming up. Oh,
I know where I'm going to be. I'm going
to be at the, uh, the Improv in DC.
And let me tell you something.
Boys and girls tickets are going fast.
Um, I get unbelievable
support in DC and, uh,
the fuck is wrong with my website.
Don't start this,
don't start this. Oh, there it
is. I clicked on the wrong page.
Now I've got an unbelievable support
in DC. Um, last time I went there,
all shows sold out
before he even got there.
I didn't have to get up and do fucking
radio, but I still did it. I said, oh,
look who's calling in. It's
showed her rosa. Jodi is, uh,
uh, I'm in the middle of doing my
podcast. Let me call you right back.
I'll be done in about 20 minutes.
All right sweetie.
Um, Joe Rosa, my cohost on uninformed,
we're gonna be doing it this Friday and
our in studio guest is going to be a,
actually, he's calling is going
to be Joe Perry from Aerosmith.
So we're really excited and I'll let
you guys know when it's going to air
because we, uh, we prerecorded. But
getting back on topic this week,
I'm going to be at the
Improv in Washington DC.
Last I heard there was about
150 tickets left and a,
so if you want to go, uh, go to, uh,
what does it improv.com I know I got
gotta write down my myspace page.
You can click on it or if
you're on my, uh, my webpage,
if you just click on upcoming appearances,
there'll be a link right there.
I'm going to be there in November
6th, November 7th, November 8th.
And um,
it's part of the uninformed comedy tour
hyping my radio show with Joe to Rosa
who just called in. Isn't that
ironic? Isn't it ironic? I don't know.
I don't even know what irony means
anymore. I don't even know what fucking,
you know, was that serendipity, you know,
who ruined irony with the
fucking hipsters? You know,
everything became ironic.
I'm wearing an ACD, she shirt, but I'm
wearing it ironically. How do you do that?
How do you wear something?
Ironically, you are wearing it.
You fuck something ironic about it is
covering your awful on worked out torso.
I thought irony was, I think I've
discussed this before in podcasts.
You know what we did and people send me
definitions and I still don't understand
it.
I thought irony was when the,
with the fucking fire chief's house
burns to the ground. Isn't that ironic?
Don't you think? Right. And then you
walk around with Atlanta, it's more set.
You don't want her career went off the
rails is when she did that fucking video
naked and she had her lung,
uh,
fucking like, she just
crawled out of that. Well,
like that chick from the ring when she
had that hair hanging down over a titties
and I don't know what it was.
It was like,
she had a very pancake
shaped chief.
She looked like a gingerbread
man with long hair and titties.
That's what I was what you want with
a woman, you want the curves, right.
That little hourglass thing going on,
you know,
not to give women a
bad fucking body image.
Women do so much shit to just fuck
with their own heads. If you ever,
do you ever talk to a girl and
there'll be like, you're like, hey,
why don't you get that? That'll
look cool. I can't wear that.
Why can't you wear that cause
cause I'm a spoon. You're a what?
I'm a spoon. The fuck is a spoon. No,
that's my body shape. I'm a spoon.
Well why did you just say that?
Like that was a common term sweetheart.
And you find out that
they actually go to these,
these fucking people and they tell
them like what their body shape is.
And I guess his spoon means you
don't have much in a way of of chest,
but you have a booty. So that
means you're a spoon. You know,
if you look to hold the spoon sideways,
evidently that looks like a chick with
an ass. Which I don't think it does.
Cause personally I am an ass man.
I've never had the desire to fuck a
spoon even though he eats cereal every
morning for breakfast.
Okay.
And if you just titty,
what is that on the capital t?
I can't wear a hoop skirt.
I'm a capital. I mean I want, I
don't know what the fuck it is.
They just come up and you know,
I don't know what I am.
Actually one time I actually
looked at myself standing sideways,
completely naked in a mirror,
right?
I was in a hotel and I realized that
I am shaped like the pink panther,
you know,
Pink Panther as a big head and he's,
and he's got big feet and they use
his body that just goes straight,
straight down. That's, that's how
I'm shaped. I like to think my,
I have better shoulders than the pink
panther, but I don't know, you know,
that's not for me to judge. That's for
the poor woman who's hooked up with me.
You know what? Fuck this. Let's
get to the podcast questions.
Why am I telling them you
guys won't looking at myself,
make it in the fucking man y'all
do with everybody. Does it.
Um, hey, the elections
tomorrow. By the way, if you're
listening to this on Monday,
uh, as of tomorrow, um, you know, maybe
we're going to have a new president.
Bush doesn't declare martial law in the
last second being that's going to come
down to Florida again and they're
going be trying to count fucking votes.
I Dunno. I'm really nervous
that they're going to leave,
that Obama's gonna win and
they're going to leave him
to try and clean up this unclean
up a bull mess. I don't know.
It's just too fucking depressing to
think about. I do. Whoever wins. Okay.
You know what?
The great thing about this election
is if McCain wins or Obama wins,
at the very least,
we're going to have a president again
that can actually make a speech without
you having to look away.
And I think that's good.
I think that's good.
Even though they both worked for the
Rothschilds and we're on our way to one
world government, one World Bank. Fuck.
I was trying not to say that you guys
seen that commercial out where they're
going to make it easier for
us to travel between Mexico,
the the Caribbean and Canada.
If we all have enhanced
driver's license, wink, wink,
enhance microchip in it so they can track
your whereabouts cause they're trying
to get to cherish,
trying to get terrorist.
But I'm trying to see what you're doing.
You're trying to get terrorist. Hey man,
you ain't doing nothing wrong. He
shouldn't have a fucking problem with it.
People who say that should be processed,
you know,
I don't think they should
be killed. I, you know,
I don't know what to do with them.
Should I go with the Hacky,
stick them on an island and give him
some big fucking cotton candy machine.
Those, those fucking people in government
can listen to your phone calls. Well,
if you ain't doing nothing
wrong, Nah, she talking bout
the government can fuck you in the ass.
Well, Hey, if you got [inaudible] got fat
fucking morons. Yeah, just
keep giving away more rights.
People just keep doing that,
you know,
and I'm going to keep bitching about it
as I don't join any groups to prevent it
or organize or show up at any rallies.
I'm that guy.
I'm that guy who sits there and goes,
hey,
you know what the problem is and
then I don't do anything about it.
I'm an asshole. All right, question number
one of the week. Uh, number one, Bill. Uh,
we need nicknames and who better to ask
than one of the commentators from the
race draft the fuck.
Does that mean love the podcast?
Just thought it would be
something to talk about.
Well what's the funniest nicknames for
a fighter and what would you name the
four guys on our main picture?
What,
how do you think he would fare as a
fighter or was a corner man also who's the
best fighter ever?
I'll answer those last three cause
I don't understand the first.
I mean I'm probably fucking it up.
I mean sometimes people write
sentences that make sense.
But I read so poorly that
when I read them out loud,
I pause and weird areas and then they
don't make sense to me or the listener.
And it's one of the reasons why I was
never successful when I ran for student
government. I didn't run
for student government. Um,
I was too busy flunking every class that
I had. I was too busy doing that. Um,
all right, bill, what are the, let's see.
How do you think you would fare as a
fighter? I'm into it depends. Toasts.
The other person know how to fight.
Is that one of those brother to
brother headlock NNGUGI fights?
I always did well in those. Um, how
would I fair as a fighter? I think,
I think I'm all right.
I ain't tomorrow,
as long as the other person isn't trained.
If anybody has any sort of
training or any sort of background,
I'm fucked because I don't have any
trading and I have a huge head and it's a
big target. In fact, I was voted most
likely to be assassinated in, uh,
I think I've used that joke before.
I just love that one.
Anytime you see anything
with a big head in the crowd,
that's what I always think.
Like you could,
you wouldn't even need to put
that guy in a convertible.
You could hit them with a slingshot
from the other side of a fucking cotton
field. Like I actually know the size
of a cotton field like anybody does,
you know, other even cotton fields
anymore. Did that go out with NAFTA? See,
what we're gonna do is we're going to,
we're going to sand a copy and we
have other to pick our continent.
Then we're going to buy the shirts
back from them. Um, anyways,
how do I think I would fare as a fighter?
I think if somebody is a no background,
basically angry psycho like me,
I think I can hold my own,
although I'm getting a little
advanced in age, 40 years old,
wake up with aches and pains.
Um,
I think I would fare okay
as a professional fighter.
I would not make it out of,
uh, the cub scouts, whatever
that version is of being a boxer.
I have a complete inability
to, I don't know, it's wait,
I have good hand eye coordination.
I can catch things very easily,
but I'm not fast, which basically means
you can be like, Bill, I'm going to,
you could tell me what fist you gonna
hit me and what pumps you are going to
throw an 80% of the time. You'd still
fucking hit me in the head because I,
I don't know. By the time
I, I know what you're doing.
The only thing I have left to do is
close my eyes and lift my shoulders is if
that does anything, you know, you know
that move when you're going to get hit,
you have to see that guy. You look away,
close your eyes and lift your shoulders.
That's always a good day. Why? Why
would you in, why? Why wouldn't,
why wouldn't you rather lift
your hand up and try to fucking,
you know how boxes do in block it?
What I do is I close my eyes,
I looked the other way
and I lift my shoulders.
I'm basically trying to protect my,
from my juggler up to my ear lobe,
but my jaw in my temple and all that
other stuff. That's all for you.
You can have that all day long, baby.
I'm fucking eat it up. All right.
Um, how would I fair as a corner man? Uh,
you know, if you don't know how to fight,
how can you tell somebody how to
fight and who's the best fighter ever?
All right. That's some really
speaking in general terms.
How about my favorite fighter ever?
My favorite fighter ever. We're all,
all the middleweights from the 80s, except
for Sugar Ray Leonard. I don't know.
He was just too cute. I like Tommy
Hearns and Marvin Hagler was my favorite.
I love Roberto Duran. I like,
I love boxing back then.
Alexis,
are Gwalia Aaron Pryor giving the battle?
No, the one that I mixed.
Um, that's a fight.
Fans.
Um,
who else did I like back
then? Larry Holmes. I liked
Mike Tyson. I love, but he scared the
shit out of me. I like Michael Spinks.
I like Leon spanx. That
was it. There you go.
Those are the guys I liked.
None of that was funny.
I'm really boring the shit out of myself.
Okay, let's ratchet up the funny here.
Number two, Bill, you ever come into,
you ever going to come to Dallas?
How about this? Are you ever going to
come to the show? When I go to Dallas,
I go to Dallas every year.
That's one of my pet fucking peeves is
when people send me fucking emails. Right?
Like I just got back from Austin and I
got a letter this email this week. Dude,
you ever coming to Texas?
You know,
just look at my website, I got all the
dates. Okay. And speaking of which,
I got a slew of dates,
which means a lot.
I have a plethora of dates.
I have a fuck load of dates coming up then
I'm gonna be putting up on my website,
Bill burg.com and um,
yeah,
I'm going to have a whole bunch of dates
for a January. Um, January, 2009, right?
Two December,
2009 or is other people like
to say 2009 and um, Houston,
Texas is going to be there for all you
fuckers who keep asking me to come to
Houston even though every time I go there,
11 people show up.
You guys with your empty
promises, dude, you killed that.
I'm good to bring 20 and I up and there's
18 fucking people and I'm standing up
there, you know, feeling
like I'm giving away rubles.
I'm seriously,
I've got a whole bunch of dates coming
up and I'm going to be posting them and
I'm, I have a trip to Europe and Australia
in the works in the work. So England,
Sweden, Norway. All right.
Put on your fucking comedy hats
cause I'm coming your way. And uh,
also coming to Australia, I believe
next year. Anyways, a, we go,
continuing on the next question,
what do we got here? Uh,
but, but, but the, the, okay,
bill,
I subscribed to your podcast on iTunes
since the beginning and you are now over
a day of talking straight.
You know what I noticed that I've done
over 24 hours of podcast minutes anyways.
How is the podcast affected
you since you started it? Um,
see I just did that.
The sentence was how has the podcast
affect affected you since you started it?
And I read it this way,
how has the podcast affected
you since you started it?
That's exactly how I hit this weird
pause and then I said, oh my God,
there's another word. Because I
was already thinking of the answer.
How is it affected me? Um, I don't know.
I think my ability to talk to myself
on a phone for 40 minutes has really
improved.
Um,
it's helped me with my radio show to the
point that I really feel like I could
do an hour of radio by myself,
just as long as I wasn't in
a panic state of, oh my God,
there's nobody else in here.
Oh they get it done.
Cause that as long as I didn't go to
that place and I just had a couple of
subjects I can sort of subject
surf through my huge head and uh,
you know, I think it's
affected me that way. I'm, no,
maybe I can improv a little bit better
or maybe the standup has helped me,
I don't know. But, uh,
I've had a lot of people come up to
me and shows and tell me that they,
now that it's on Itunes, that, you know,
they listened to it at work or they
have like a designated time when they
listened to it and they've gone back.
And I had one person tell me one night
they sat there and they listened to like
all the way back to the summertime,
stayed up for like six hours
listening to my podcast,
which was really flattering because I
think I'm boring as shit a lot of the
times.
Look at me searching for a compliment now.
It'd be or you're not
boring, blah, blah blah. Um,
no, I think it's been a great
thing and it's something that, uh,
last week when I did the very
special one and I had Joe to Rosa,
I think I'm going to be doing more
of those. I enjoy, uh, I don't know.
I like working with other people in
problem with them fucking around.
And if I could figure out
a way to block my, uh,
my podcasts,
maybe I could do one where I could
actually call someone a regular listener
or have somebody call in.
I don't know how the fuck I could do it,
but then it would just be awkward.
I always feel like that those
things never live up to the,
someone's like all excited.
And then it just turns into that
myth that Chris Farley character,
they used to do,
you know,
the really bad interviewer or he would
just be like interviewing Paul Mccartney.
You'd be like, remember, remember,
remember the time when it's time you guys,
you guys did the the sergeant pepper
pepper album and then Paul Mccartney,
he's like, yeah, yeah, I
do remember that night.
And he just feel like that was awesome.
Like I worry that it will just become
that like a fucking staring contest. I,
you know, I actually worry,
I worry that would actually,
the podcast would be as bad as
the awful recreation of that.
Chris Farley bit. Did you like my really
bad English accent than I did in there?
It was so bad that I literally had
to throw in mate at the end of it.
So you would know that Oh,
he is doing an English accent.
I thought he just raised his
voice an octave. Okay, let's,
let's plow ahead. Okay. Bill. Um,
you should start writing a
book on your stadium travels.
You can give yourself the excuse that
you're doing it to make money. Oh yeah.
Rather than being a loser and
get on that new sports soup show,
you would be excellent on it. Um, yeah.
For those of you who weren't listening in
the past couple of weeks, I'm actually,
um, I'm not going home for
the holidays. Thanksgiving,
I'm not going home on Christmas
and I'm not working new year's.
I'm tapping out fuck the masses.
I'm taking a break and instead
I'm actually going to Calgary,
Edmonton and Vancouver with a buddy of
mine and we're gonna [inaudible] you
know,
I'm going to go,
go fucking go to some hockey games and
get absolutely shit faced with their
extra alcohol beer.
And um,
I said I'm going to do and
people have called me a fag,
you know, doing, how are
you doing that? You know,
that kind of stuff. But I
don't care. I like doing it,
but I know I'm also a psycho when it
comes to, I have like OCD, like big time.
Like I've so gotten into hockey that I
just ordered the NHL package and I am
literally watching like three
hockey games a night. Like,
I watch what the one hockey game that
interests me and then I take two others
and then I watch him like literally
like a fucking assistant coach. And uh,
I dunno, I've been thinking about doing
like a book on it, but you know something,
the whole reason why I became a comedian
is cause I don't want to have a job.
I don't want to do work.
I just want to do this.
Like I don't prepare for these podcasts.
I just laid out on the bed and
I run my fucking mouth for 45.
That's how I like doing shit.
I don't like rehearsing.
I don't like organizing shit.
I don't like coming up with
business models and you know,
I don't want to write a book about
my stadium Shit. I just want to,
I just want to go to him and
get drunk and talk to some,
the oldest guy I can find with the oldest
looking Jersey of the team and to ask
them, what was it like years ago when you
went to the fucking stadium? You know,
like I love going to Pittsburgh
and talking to fucking, you know,
the guy driving me from the airport.
I look at it, I'm like, okay,
that guy's like in his 50s. So that means
30 years ago he was in his twenties.
If I was in my twenties in Pittsburgh,
I would've gone to three rivers stadium
and I would've watched Franco, Terri,
Lynn Swann and all those guys. And I
asked him, do you ever go over there?
And he'd be, ah, yeah,
it was fucking awesome.
And then you hear these great stories.
I was at that game, Fred Bulletin,
the cough and the Raiders and yeah,
you can just, I know whatever.
I'm a fucking nerd. Okay, next
question. I noticed the trend.
You have a loving to rag on
either crazy or stupid people.
Um, oh Geez. Aren't you perceptive? Well,
I notice you're kind of angry. I'm
going to go out on a limb here. Um,
because of this.
I was wondering how you feel about Sarah
Palin given the fact that she is both
of these things crazy and stupid.
I don't think she's stupid.
I just think she's not ready.
You know,
I think she's really green.
You know what I mean?
She's more comes off as
somebody David Letterman would,
would talk to in a bit,
you know,
because they make their own jam and
they put it in a jar. I'll tell you why.
You know what,
I really don't like.
I don't like how a Bama and John Mccain
and all these fucking guys are like on
ESPN and they're going
on Saturday night live.
And I think it really trivializes what
they're doing. You know what I mean?
I think,
uh,
that they should be on shows like meet
the press and they should be doing
debates. And I think
that, you know, you know,
you're not supposed to
combine church and state.
I don't think you should combine political
figures and sketch comedy shows that
make fun of them. And then
they go on there and they're
all in on the joke, like,
yeah, yeah, I'm a fucking idiot.
That doesn't really make me confidence.
And either Mccain,
Obama and uh, you know, I don't know.
I gotta I gotta tell you something though.
I really want to get a John Mccain shirt
and just wear it around La just because
I love annoying people, you know? And uh,
you know,
I,
I just think that would be funny just to
have people that Christ is fucking guy.
This John Mccain. Shit, man, if I have
shut up, why don't you just shut up?
Why don't you stop and I just
want to see me people's noses.
I can get to wrinkle, um, about say
right now, I'm gonna tell you I'm,
I'm voting for Ron Paul. I'm voting
for Ron Paul and I don't give a fuck.
I vote for guys from here on out
who questioned the Federal Reserve.
And other than that, if you
don't do that, then you're,
you're just another company guy and I
have no use for you. Alright. Underrated.
Overrated. Um, somebody said, oh,
look at this underrated Doug Davidoff.
And uh,
I believe that he's in my top 80 friends
there in the page. Hilarious comedian.
This person says he's underrated.
He's a great and really under,
under the radar comedian.
So check out Doug Davidoff everybody.
Um, and this is, I love this
one. Underrated the cable guy.
It was a good movie. You
know what? I love that movie.
I think there's just one
too many music montage this,
you know what I mean? But I have to
admit that I downloaded that song,
uh, that hey man, nice shot when
a Jim Carrey goes up, you know,
dressed old school with the short shorts
and the, does he have a headband on?
Anyways, he puts in the mouth
guard and he's playing basketball,
but there's just one too many of those.
But I love that movie.
I thought it was really
dark and really creepy,
which is probably why
it didn't do as well.
It didn't perform as well at the box
office as they want it to because people
like to go to the movie theater
and forget their problems. Um,
overrated. Splenda, it's disgusting.
What the fuck is Splenda again?
Is that that stuff that makes Doritos
not make you fat but your athletes?
Is that what that is? Um, overrated.
Pink Floyd prison tee shirts.
Uh, it's a great one. I
Love Pink Floyd, but there,
there are way too many dumb teenagers
wearing that shirt that don't know what
the hell it is. Now I have to ask you
a question person who wrote that in.
When you say they don't know what that is,
do you mean they don't really know what
pink Floyd is or they don't know what
the Prizm is?
Cause I got to tell you,
I've owned dark side of the moon forever
and I don't know what the prison means
either.
I didn't even know what a prison is
other than a triangle that makes you go,
wow man. Look at the colors
and freaking out. Um,
I do have to tell you this. I uh, let me,
let me check the time of the podcast
here. 28 minutes. That's decent.
We're going to wrap this up at
about 30. That's a good one. Um,
one of the best musical experiences
I ever had was I bought pink Floyd.
God Damn it, the phone's ringing.
And who's this? Greg Fitzsimmons.
Hang on a second.
Greg Fitzsimmons.
Hello Gregory.
Oh wait a minute.
He pocket dialed me.
Let me listen to see if
he's talking about me.
No, he's not. No such luck. That's
like an, you know what? And now he's,
he's gonna call me back like 19 times,
cause I'm the last guy he calls and
every time he reaches over to scratch his
right ball,
his left ball is going to hit send on
his cell phone and he's gonna call me.
Anyways, getting back
to the, uh, pink Floyd,
a musical experience, I bought that, uh,
I believe on cassette tape
and I had headphones just like in dazed
and confused and I listened to that in
the dark for the first time.
This is for all you youngsters out there
who are not jaded and as long as you
haven't watched his
face as a death around,
that type of shit is
still relatively innocent.
Like I was back then pre internet days,
even though the Internet existed,
but it only existed for fucking nerds.
I listened to that album in the dark and
that album scared the living shit out
of me.
It's incredible music.
But that shit with people running down
the halls in heartbeats and all that type
of crap, that really, really
scared the hell out of me.
And it's a fucking masterpiece. So if
you get a chance, get some headphones,
if he can buy it on vinyl, off of Ebay,
you know, you don't even need drugs.
That's how good pink Floyd
is. And a, and there you go.
All right. The original pink
pink Floyd and I got a question.
Would you guys won't
let anybody out there?
Would you like to hook
up with that girl pink?
There's something really hot about her,
but then she's also kind of building
a fullback like, you know, like she,
I don't know
not to use the classic.
I think she rip your Dick
off man. Uh, anyways,
that's the podcast for this
week. Half Hour. There you go.
I'm fun to trim it back a little bit.
He's podcasts will becoming a little too
long, kind of like jam band shit. Um,
so anyways, I'm going to be at the
Improv in Washington DC this week.
Uh, the eighth ninth, I
can't even fucking read it.
No, the sixth, seventh,
and 8th of November. And
uh, the following week I'm going to
be uninformed, told with Joe de Rosa.
Once again,
we'll be at Nashville's Nashville,
comedies A's in Nashville.
I can't read November 13th,
14th and 15th. Um, just click on the link.
If you're on the mind space page,
[inaudible] dot com just click on upcoming
appearances and then click the link.
Please keep the questions coming. Please
keep underrated, overrated coming.
And please answer my question.
What a prison is and what the fuck it is.
Whatever that triangle is,
I don't fucking know.
All right,
now I've got a headache and I've
lost total momentum on this podcast.
It's not funny anymore and it
needs to fucking stop. All right,
everybody go out and vote tomorrow.
Go with your gut and actually
try to read the questions.
That's what I'm going to do today.
You know those stupid little signs.
People have full know an eight man
and then you keep a running tally.
Wow. Everybody keeps saying
vote nos and then you vote no,
and you read that little paragraph.
Can anybody explain to me why those,
when they have those questions,
it's never clear.
It's always no means yes and yes means
no. You know what I mean? It's like, why?
Why can't they just fucking just
say what the questions mean?
Why can't we just live in
a perfect world? Hey, bill,
why don't you just shut the fuck
up and in the podcast? All right.
That's what I'm going to do. I'll talk
to you guys next Monday. Um, that is it.
God bless all of you. And a day, the time
next week we'll have a new president.
Isn't that exciting? Someone who
could make a speech. All right.
Who are you voting for? The white
guy or the off white guy. Thank you.
I'll be at the fucking DC Improv this
week. Please come out to the show.
All right.
Motherfuckers
sit and have a good week.
So
yeah.
[inaudible] [inaudible]
cat.