Hey,
what's going on it's Bill Burr.
It's time for the Monday
morning podcasts for Man da. Um,
April 4th, 2016. How's it going? How, why?
Yeah. I am an Ottawa,
Canada right now. Oh,
can uh,
uh,
it's fucking freezing here.
Every time I come,
I know Australia's Dick
Together. Um, yeah,
we came, we did fucking, um, almost said
Wichita. I don't know what the fuck.
Damn Police Windsor.
If we did Windsor,
me Versie and fucking Joey be Joe Barton.
We did a Windsor the first day.
Not even know what day that is yet.
Friday we did it on Friday and um,
I brought this little fucking bitchy
coat. Yup. Nia calls it the Kleenex coat.
It's just a saline. All those
little ones. Babylon in the 70s,
when they had the big puffy coats,
well,
they're still making the puffy coats
to not just like Dylan Little ones,
you know what I mean? They look
like little, uh, you know, like you,
you're a rib shack in the open a little
think and then giving a little morsel.
Talent looks like there's a bunch of
those sewn into the code. You know that.
Thank you know what the fuck coat I'm
talking about when I was a little north
north face numbers.
So it got down in a hoodie because they
looked at the fucking forecast and it
said that um,
you know,
it's going to be like 50 degrees
and that coach good down to 40 site.
Donna was fine.
I was fine.
I was snuggling a little bug in the
rug with first. Was it two days?
Yeah.
Well now was I the second day?
Oh the second day I was at Casino Rama.
That's right.
And that's when it started the snow and
that's when I started questioning my,
my jacket game is the young kids
say my jacket game was not on point.
However,
by the way,
I didn't bring any of my fucking podcast
equipment because you know this trip is
a mother fucker. All right.
This is one of these,
it's known in my businesses is thrash.
All right.
Sometimes you go on the road, it's
a fucking cake walk. All right.
Whatever the fuck that means.
What is a cake walk? I know.
I've never even looked that up.
Is there a certain kind of way you
walk when you fucking carrying a cake?
Maybe that's what it is. Sorry if I'm
fucking, the levels are too high year.
Just trying to talk to him. I
recorded like a microphone. Um,
that's going to be my guess.
Yeah.
Is that when you have a fucking kick,
you know?
Yeah.
If you have a cake, you're going
to be walking a little gingerly.
No offense to me,
right?
Yeah.
So you walk a little lately with it.
Maybe you know what you're walking like
you walking like Paul Versey when he
puts on his fucking Jordan
fours for the first time,
you should have seen him
walking down the casino.
He was walking like on his heels
because he didn't want to create some,
I gotta tell you something.
I don't fucking understand.
People who fucking stand in line and then
stab each other over a fucking pair of
sneakers. I just really, dude, did
you see the gut to new Jordans?
Three's arou dude,
that fucking crazy.
The new Jordan trees are fucking crazy.
I swear to God,
they all look like nurse shoes to me.
Big Stupid, bulky look and fuck it takes,
I think I have a pair of Jordan ones.
I like the colors.
I never liked those fucking things either.
When they came out and
they were red and black,
I thought those were the ugliest fucking
things ever. I told you before, I'm,
I'm part of the back in the day.
I like those Bruce Jenner.
Um, the cattle on shoes, you know,
just simple pair with fucking
three stripes on the side.
I was cool with sneakers right through
towards the end of the eighties when they
started having like
the fucking Bo Jackson,
the neon Deon fucking whatever
that neon green and neon pink,
those fucking sunglasses to
second and went into that shit.
Those pastel colors and the
stupid fucking Reebok pump. Oh,
maybe if I put some more air in my
sneakers, I won't have white guy legs.
The Reebok pumps were,
we're as stupid is Batman
versus Superman there. Alright.
Okay Shirley,
here we go with this cake walk.
Surely you've heard the term cakewalk.
Did somebody write a whole
fucking article on this?
Yeah.
Good Lord. Cut to the
fucking chase. All right.
I'll read this as fast as I can.
Surely you've heard the term cakewalk
used to describe some sort of challenge or
task that is reckoned to be
pitifully easy. Surely you have,
will you stop saying that? Stop calling
me. Surely. Surely you have. Please.
Please don't lie. Good Lord.
Who fucking wrote this?
MMM.
The figurative definition has been
around since the early 19th century.
As long as the literal one,
in fact it appeared in print,
but did you know that the term is
actually pretty racist, racist, racist,
racist.
I'll bet you didn't.
What the fuck is wrong with this idiot
who this is such a classic, you know,
if you actually had to get a real job
writing, you wouldn't have one. You know,
everybody on the Internet fancies
themselves like there's some sort of
journalist, you know when
they're writing, this is just no,
you just fucking write it on a w.
Okay.
It's like acting in a web series
and you're upset. You didn't get nominated
for a fucking Oscar. Um, nor did I. Okay.
Did you, it was pretty
racist. Um, I bet you didn't.
What? Because you don't know some shit
and that means everybody else doesn't you
fucking cunt. I mean, I didn't
know it, but I'm a moron.
I really don't like this person.
Uh, he said, nor did I. Okay.
That's the first humble thing. This
person said, maybe you can come around.
Maybe I was wrong.
I still don't think I could drive
cross country with this person. Um,
nor did I until I looked into the origin
of the term and found out it had roots
in the,
yeah.
I don't know how to say
this word. Antebellum south
of the early 19th century.
Can you just tell me
what the fuck it means?
How it started during this era of
firmly entrenched slavery in the states,
the cake walk was a dance event where
slaves were invited to dress up in the
fine clothes and took on the
heirs of the white aristocracy.
Oh, so this is like when the
Wayans brothers did white chicks.
What are they doing?
Is this like the first def jam comedy?
They started doing the white guy voice.
I said,
get out in the field to do the
work that I should be doing.
And everybody starts flipping
out, dying, laughing.
The next wave coming to
the stage. Um, all right.
They were held in the plantation home
and the same rooms where the risks,
splendid balls were held among
whites of society. Oh my God.
How much did those people
fucking stink back then?
Putting on all those extra
layers of clothes? No such
thing as deodorant. Right.
Just joined you.
That's one of those things where you're
wash yourself in the same fucking trough.
The goddamn horses drank out
of the cakewalk was similar.
It was a ball held for the slaves.
Oh, so this is a Christmas party.
I didn't know they did that. I
didn't see that in roots. You know,
it wasn't all bad.
Every once in awhile they had like a
company party after 364 and a half days of
absolute horror than they would. They
let them in the house. Yeah. Hey,
sorry about all that other shit.
Uh,
would you like some pumpernickel
wife just made it, oh,
let's get them out of the house. Uh,
they seem to be a little restless.
That's fucking nuts. Oh, what an
ugly period. Um, the cake, like,
you know, like it's not, I'm prepared now,
but you know, it's less ugly. All right,
let's continue. Okay. The
cake walk was similar.
It was a bald ball held for the slaves.
Couples promoted, promulgated, sorry,
through the ballroom,
bowing deeply and frequently.
Chins and noses held highly a loft.
If you're going to tell me,
they finally gave him a fucking party
and they still were assholes about it.
The couple who performed
the best interpretation of
how the white folks did it
want a cake baked one imagines by a slave.
I, I didn't imagine that
stuff. Words in my mouth.
I would figure the white people after
all that fucking time. But yeah, I mean,
you know what, uh, consider
we ruined their fucking lives.
I think we can make
them a cake once a year,
but we're only given it to one of them.
Jesus crave time.
You think you've found the depths
of how evil that shit was. He,
you find another layer. True. Oh my
God. Another layer. Just like a cake.
Jesus. I'm an artist this morning. All
right. The cake walk looks similar,
but it was also very different.
It's intent was to emulate white
society in order to market or the Jesus,
there's a dangerous fucking gave me,
I told you this is like the first def
jam comedy and much the same way as
yeah.
Oh Jesus Christ.
Saturnalia the ancient Rome
winters solstice festival.
Oh yeah, exactly. Watching
the same fucking way, uh,
where the rules of some of social order
were turned upside down in the slaves
and laborers became the rulers
and Matt and masters attended
attend their servants.
Oh they did this in Rome.
Okay,
this is just all fucking weird.
Can you imagine the tension during that?
So then the master's fucking
tended to the slaves and you know, the
slaves wanted to be just as fucking mean.
But then they were like,
well we got to kind of aggregate around
this shit cause it goes back to the
regular way tomorrow. And then I would
think the master be like, alright,
you want me to wade into that
sea of hatred towards me?
Um, uh, just keep an eye on me.
Please stay tight. Okay. Bye.
A itch the left side of my nose, that
means a, I'm fearing for my life. Uh,
the slaves involved did indeed mark
the ridiculously refined customs of the
aristocracy. Yes. And they surely
meant it. But during the cakewalk,
yeah,
they were allowed to mock them.
And by ruling over even the very event
that should undermine his authority,
the plantation owners, it to assert
is at 30. You know something?
I was in such a fucking good mood.
I hate this shit.
Yeah,
it's a fucking cake walk while you
know what I already clicked off.
So how does that mean?
It's easy.
What does that mean?
It's, it's a cheap laugh
and all I got to go back.
I gotta I just closed the fucking window.
I've got to go back and,
okay,
so how the fuck did that become?
That does not sound easy to me.
Being a slave all year and then doing one.
Do you get to do one fucking day where
you get to make fun of this? The master?
It's not a cakewalk and
struck a difficult. Right.
Okay.
All right.
As if its roots in slavery don't make
the cakewalk racially charged enough.
It transitioned in the minstrel show.
Yeah.
How did it transition into meaning
something easy of the Jim Crow era or even
are even worse? Um,
God was even the power.
A lot of to the slaves too
by the mark and just have the
original cakewalk in stage.
Reproductions of balls of the balls.
White performers in black face performed
as blacks who made sincere clumsy
attempts at emulating whites
out of a desire to be like them,
not to undermine them. Ah,
okay. And then it became that.
I still don't understand why it's easy.
The original cakewalk
walks being local affairs.
How that, you know what? Fuck
the fucking Internet. Yeah.
All right.
Can I fast forward to this?
Yeah.
Oh God.
He used the word apparently.
Yeah.
There's no other word. Alternative comics
like to use more than that apparently.
All right.
Clumsy attempt.
So I thought the original cake walks
for being local affairs held in the
confines of the set southern plantation,
the minstrel shows traveling as a matter
of course, it was later interpretation.
They became just find the concepts of
the rest of the country in the world.
And what you could describe perhaps a
deep desire to stop being so incredibly
racist,
American societies of all the banner,
the racial basis of the
cakewalk in favor of,
it's simply describing something so
easy that just walking could yield the
reward of a cake. There. It is.
The definition is still vaguely racist.
Okay.
It isn't racist if you think the
definition means it's going to be easy.
You're not even being remotely vaguely
racist. You just don't know the history,
right?
Yeah. Jesus Christ. All right, well
there's that was fucking depressing. Um,
well, fortunately I'm up here
in Canada where, you know,
they have all the angelic white people
according to Michael Morrison, you know,
up here, they're all a bunch of angels
that nobody has to lock the doors. Uh,
what's your costs? We don't, that's
true. Just generally speaking,
people don't get along with
one another. Um, all right,
so that was an excruciating 15 minutes.
I don't know how you guys enjoyed it.
So anyways, kind of fuck,
did I get onto that shit?
Oh, because yeah, I taught the whole, um,
I thought the,
uh,
I taught this whole trip was going
to be a muffin dance about that.
Can I say something like that and say,
ah,
that was going to be a little
muffin dance. Did you know that?
The origins of Moffat dance.
Okay.
Um, you actually are pro domestic
violence. I bet you didn't.
Surely you've heard the term muffin
dance before. Please, please,
please don't tell me you have not.
Yeah.
The origin of Muffin dance
comes from the early 19 hundreds
when women,
when they asked can we vote to,
were forced to show their clams and
dance out of the voting booths as people
through desserts at the,
uh,
this became known as the muffin dance
because clam indicated that their pussy
stunk and turn men off.
Later in 1929,
the great,
great grandson of Abraham Lincoln said,
I cannot tell a lie.
Some of these bitches clamps to stink,
but there's still reason to
make them do a muffin. Dads,
they should be allowed to vote to, and
all the guys said, yeah, you know what?
You're right.
And everybody had muffins.
So next time you use
the term muffin dance,
just know that you're being
vaguely sexist. Um, okay.
All right. I'm sorry. Why am I doing
this? Why am I talking like this?
Why of why am I sitting here in this
fucking freezing cold hotel room?
I can't find where the fucking heat is.
I'm saying in one of these um,
red rum.
Um,
yeah.
Well just one of those, you know, I like
old shit to a point, you know, I like,
I thought I liked having an old house
until I fucking had to deal with it.
Oh, all the bullshit of how on in an
old house, old hotels, I kind of like,
I loved the lobbies, but the second
you fucking go up to your room,
you start walking down the hall.
You know,
you feel like you should be riding a big
wheel and you're going to come around
the corner and those too creepy fucking
chicks are going to be standing there.
Yeah.
God Damn it. That fucking movie freaked
me out. That would be still got,
it's still disturbing. That's just a
disturbance fucking movie, you know.
And it's not the fact that he
goes completely fucking insane.
It's just as a comedian watching the man's
suffering through writer's block like
that, and having that woman
coming up who's face is
shaped like a fucking parking
meter, asking you how it's
going every fucking 20 minutes.
I love how they blame the
fucking hotel rather than that,
you know? What would
you say she means? Well,
yeah, they just were a bad couple.
I think that that's what it was.
And when they were down in society,
they could go to events and
they could sort of watered down.
They're awful relationship
by interacting with others.
And then once they just got,
you know,
yeah,
let's say would just stand there
at the fucking hotel, you know,
for the whole goddamn winter.
I don't understand why they had to be
there to watch it. You know what I mean?
Like what do you, what are you going to
be doing up there? I mean it's, it's some,
it's the level with which said,
it's gonna fucking snow. No asshole.
He's going to go up there and vandalize
the place if they come there because
they need shelter.
It was really no reason
for it,
you know?
And that was also a vaguely
racist movie, wasn't it? Yeah.
Yeah.
Saying that reverse racist, that
white people will be like, oh yeah.
Oh the fucking snow's 50 feet
in the fucking air. Oh yeah,
I got to write a book. Yeah. Why
don't I fuck it. Go up there.
Y'All hang out there and I'll, I'll do
my own room service every fucking day.
I'll stay in room fucking
706 in everyday.
I'll take a fucking elevator all
the way downstairs to the kitchen.
How, who the fuck would sign up for that
free? You didn't have any separately for
yeah,
I'm just fucking with you.
I think it's a great movie.
I'm just in a grumpy goddamn moved
cause today I get to drive from fucking
Ottawa all the way up to Sudbury.
And then right after this show
I got my travels all fucked up.
I drive over to fuck Detroit,
which is like a fucking eight hour drive.
You know,
it takes me back to the days when I was
doing college kicks and I remember one
time I had this gig in the upper
peninsula of Michigan, right.
Some fucking town up there.
The began with an h. All right,
so like an asshole. I'm like, all right,
I'm in Michigan and I didn't
look on the map to see where,
uh,
okay
to see where, you know, basically the
fucking college was at and I just,
I just flew right into fucking Detroit
and then I realized that the upper
peninsula as actually it's sort of,
you know,
it's the Dick of Wisconsin.
I should have flown into
fucking Milwaukee and driven up,
but I didn't,
I flew into Detroit and I had to go drive
all the way all up the whole fucking
state. It was pretty cool cause I got to
drive over to whatever bridge that is,
the MACKINAC bridge or
whatever the fuck it is.
I'm trying to look it up right now, but
I can't remember the name of the fucking,
I think it was Marquette. Oh, you
said it began with an age maybe.
I was thinking Lake Huron.
I think it was in Marquette.
I did a fucking gig up there.
Yeah. And I had like a,
I forget what time my flight was,
but I had to basically,
it was an early morning flight in Detroit.
It was like a fucking eight hour
drive or some shit, seven hour drive.
And the show didn't start till nine I
was done at 10 o'clock and I'd like a six
or 7:00 AM flight. I can't remember.
And I just, I was just like, you know,
all right.
Goodnight everybody.
And I jumped in my fucking car and
just drove like a fucking lunatic after
already having done the drive,
drove all the way back,
just like nodding off.
Almost falling asleep is
one of the dumbest things I
ever did just to save like
the fucking $50 change for
you or some shit like that.
So you would think that
I would learn from that.
Not all freckles,
but this time we actually have a,
again like Barnett and you to help me
with the fucking drive. Oh my God, Dude.
Sudbury is,
yeah.
Yeah.
It's as high up as fucking,
okay.
The upper peninsula.
Michigan.
What a fucking ass off for some
reason they're going. Yeah,
there's no really no airports around here.
I don't know why we didn't just take
a couple of puddle jumper so I have no
fucking, oh, I know why. I know why.
Initially I was picking up a rental car
in Detroit and I was going to drive this
whole thing and then at the
last second they like, you know,
it's a pretty long fucking drive.
So I said I will fly most of it and
then we'll do the thing, you know,
then we'll get the rental car, I'll
get the rental car and fucking Ottawa,
blah blah blah. We'll do it one way. But
then I was still leaving out of Detroit.
This is so fucking stupid.
Oh this is going to suck.
But anyways, what will be,
because tonight I'm playing a,
a small like a hockey arena and a,
I was going to be great.
Ask Him fucking good time.
I played one of those last night
here in Ottawa, Yellow Silk Center,
whatever the fuck it was called.
Uh,
anyways, this isn't what the
fuck I wanted to talk about.
I have something else I want,
I want to talk about.
I gotta read the fucking advertising here.
I know this podcast is all over the place.
Okay.
I can't say it's a
fucking cake walk anymore.
Can't say a cake walk anymore because now
I know it's fucking racist. All right,
well actually I go, I can't say it to you
guys, but I could say it somewhere else.
You know who's kidding?
Who I'm going to say I'm going to say
it cause I've been saying it my whole
fucking life. You know,
it's just going to cut that.
That's how you've looked at
how you become an old person.
Where someone's going like grandpa.
Do you know the origin of that? Oh,
shut up your first year. Freshman.
All right. Fucking concept.
Been around 80 years.
Stop breaking my balls.
If I'm going to say 23 Skidoo Goddamn.
And I've got to say you do you want
me to cue you almost kill your fucking
grandfather. Tried to get them to stop
saying something. All right, let me,
let me get to the uh,
advertising here.
Oh yeah, we go, oh, the old trunk
club. Trunk Club. Everybody.
Do you hate going to the
mall? Sure. We all do.
You surely you've been to a mall.
Surely you're not going to sit
there and say you haven't. Um,
trunk club shopping takes forever
and no one has time for it. Well,
people who enjoy it too, they
live for it. Let's go shopping.
Eagle is fucking dopes.
It just go down and they would sit
there and look at outfits, you know,
never once putting their ear up to the
shirt and hearing the crying child that's
sewed it together.
You know,
throwing out their old fucking clothes
just end up in the ocean or in some
hipsters back who pretends he
had the job you had. Right. Um,
shopping. You know, I used to always drop
off clothes at goodwill. Who's kidding?
Who I still do. And I thought it went to
fucking homeless people and it doesn't,
it just goes right on their racks and
they've turned around and they sell them,
which makes me feel good knowing that
they don't end up in a goddamn ocean.
Right.
I anyways,
and now it's spring.
So you need pastel polos and boat shoes.
Right.
And it'd be nice to have your
own personal stylist too.
I think that it has to be a joke.
Nobody needs pastel polos and boat shoes.
I think that those should only be
for the upper 1% of this country.
You know what I mean?
It's for the Robert Baron's in their
date rape his children, you know,
and they can walk around and what'd be
great is you make an exclusive for them.
So they'll feel like, oh, look
at us. We are a cut above.
It'll be like a status symbol.
But really what it is is it's a warning
for anyone that dates their children.
You know what I mean? It was set out,
have aware wearing the scarlet a,
that euro whore. You just have those
pastel colors. Just be like, you know,
it gives,
it gives the ladies a little heads up.
You know that there's going to be a
sense of entitlement coming at him with a
heart on, right? You've got to give
him the fucking heads up. Jesus Christ,
which is trying to do my part here,
right?
Let me pour out a little wine
cooler for Edith Wharton here. Um,
and it'd be nice to have your own
personal style is too with trunk club.
You don't ever have to set a foot in a
store and you get your very own stylist
for free. Make it easy to look your
best and clothes that fit you perfectly.
Can't check by your own personal stylist
for free with Trunk Club. Go to trunk
club.com/bird type in your measurements,
share your likes and dislikes and you
get your very own personal stylist.
A, they'll pick your clothes
from milk now. Oh my God,
this is a muffin dance right here.
They'll pick your clothes from over 80
top brands and ship them right to you.
Do A,
you keep what you like.
Can you send back what you don't
and the trunk a trunk club.
You know they're going to fucking
send these close to some maniac. Okay.
Some serial killer. Cause you know,
they don't like to go to malls either.
Unlisted trolling for victims.
Right?
And what's gonna happen is they're going
to get confused and they're going to go,
you know, you know, which
is the fucking, the, uh,
I don't like this shirt
trunk in which is the one,
this stuff in the body and they're going
to fucking throw a bunch of shirts in
the bottom of a lake and they're going
to send a body back to trunk club.
I'm calling that right now,
calling that right now.
Then they're going to do a first 48
about it. But when this truck showed up,
they couldn't understand why they shirts
smelled so bad. I'm sorry. That's bad.
Trunk Club is not just another way to
shop online. It isn't. Your style is,
takes the time to your unique,
your unique look. Okay.
If you live in,
it's just so funny about that.
I was just picturing somebody standing
in a mirror looking at themselves,
trying to figure out, they look, you know,
you know that little thing where you
have your hands on your hip and then you
stick one foot in front of the other.
Like you're a horse answering a
question because you want some oats. Um,
and if you live in Dallas, Do York,
Los Angeles, Chicago and DC. Uh,
you can stop by one of the trunk club
club houses to work with your stylist in
person for free.
Now wait a minute.
I thought the whole point was
not to go to a fucking store. Um,
trunk club is not as subscription service.
There's no monthly fee.
This is what I like here.
Your stylist is free.
Shipping is always free and you have
10 days to try to try on the clothes.
Risk free. What are you putting
it off? Like a term paper.
Oh God, I gotta try that.
Sure enough. Make a statement at the
next big events on your calendar.
What the look that's hand picked
just for you and your style. Mike,
what are you trying to say?
I'm trying to stay on Metairie.
Rapists were quite pastel colors.
Get started at Trunk Club today.
Premium close expert advice.
No work.
Thanks to your very own
personal stylist at trunk club.
Get started today@trunkclub.com slash
[inaudible] that's trunk club.com/bar
excuse me. Trunk club.com/bar. Sorry,
my voice is a lot of out of it.
I've been screaming at my jokes
for three nights in a row. Oh God.
Am I really going to
start a singing right now?
Okay.
Oh fuck.
Boto do doot me undies me on days.
No more sweaty balls.
Boudou do do me undies.
Me On the skating down the fucking
canals here in fucking Ottawa.
You're on the canal.
You wearing your Randy's with your power.
Both your balls are really fucking dry.
In fact it getting really chafe
cause it's cold. You me on these.
We'll keep him warm. Alright
me undies. By the way,
if you have escaped the canal out here,
I've always been afraid to do it.
You know I, I've done it, but
I was nervous when I did it.
I just kept thinking about the omen
like I was going to fall through and
everyone's going to be hacking at
the ice trying to get me out again.
The canals only a foot deep, you
know, it's really no big deal.
So worst thing that could happen
is you could get severe frostbite.
They have to remove both your
feet like in that movie misery.
Um, well in the movie she just
fucking breaks his ankles in the book.
She cuts off his fucking feet.
Yeah.
I love when they do shit like
that and it's just like, okay,
so you've severed a major artery and this
guy somehow doesn't bleed out in a bed.
Cause let me guess. You tied your
fucking belt around his calf.
Yeah.
Does that even work by the way?
If somebody fucking did you see the
fucking redneck that blew his God damn leg
off?
Oh my God,
there's this new fucking thing
that rednecks are doing, you know,
cause they just love shooting
stuff and blowing stuff up.
And as much as people you know,
who don't have their own spread
living in the middle of nowhere,
judge them somewhere in the back
of your head. You know, it's fun.
Yeah.
You know,
riding around on a fucking four wheelers,
shooting a gun on your own
fucking property. You know,
it's got to feel great. That's a level
of freedom that I, I've never heard,
I've never felt, you know, I live in
the city where there's noise ordinances,
you know, which basically noise on
my property should not carry over.
Like you can basically call the cops
if somebody splash around that pool too
loud.
He's marketing the fact I don't have one.
Um, the cops go over there and he
just started beating people, right?
Or air quote, getting the
situation under control. Um,
Christ, what the fuck was I just talking
about? Oh yeah. Riding around, you know,
so I watched this,
this new thing that they do,
they take this some sort of explosives
and they put it in these old cars and
then hopefully they stand far enough
away and the fucking thing blows up.
Well this fucking guy,
right?
Redneck blows.
Look at this shit right here it goes.
Redneck blows himself up,
blows up house,
blows himself up in a bonfire,
blows up pigs almost blows his head off.
This is such redneck stuff.
Stupid redneck blows himself up.
A fire blows up,
blows himself up.
Boat Motor blows up.
Fucking rednecks at crazy blows leg off
and see where is it?
Come on. All right. Yup.
And an American gun enthusiasts,
a yet to throw American in there.
American Georgia man loses leg effort,
explosive filled lawn mower.
Um, I will link you this. You
don't see his leg blow off,
but you blow blow off his body.
But yet this guy basically it's called,
uh,
I hope I say it right Tanner,
right?
It's some sort of explosive in the new
thing that these rednecks do is they
fucking
okay.
He fucking, uh, you know,
you put it in whatever
vehicle in order to,
it's really what's going on here with
these rednecks are starting to be a little
more classy, you know, after
all these fucking years of, uh,
you know, having a car die, they
just leave it on their front lawn.
Now they're getting rid of it.
They're blowing them up.
So they put this Tanner right over the
fuck you said it's just explosive and
there's some sort of formula
like basically forever, forever.
You such and such amount,
you need to be like a hundred feet back.
All right, so let's say whatever,
what it will just say this guys,
if he's got a handful of
this fucking Tanner out, God,
we're doing math now, Bill.
All right. And he needed, he basically
needed to be about like, I don't know,
500 feet back and he was 40
feet away from this lawn mower.
Any fucking shoots the shit.
Right? He fucking shoots it
and uh,
yeah,
he blows the fucking thing up.
Alright,
listen to this shit.
Yeah, there are some had to do their
fucking written Dj remix of it.
Anyways, he shoot it and
he's shooting the lawnmower.
She all of a sudden fucking blows up and
then he's on the ground and you see it.
You just, you can't see
anything. You just, it, the
camera's pointing at the ground.
He just hear him go,
I blew my leg off.
Fucking unbelievable. I'm amazed
that he could actually say that.
I would just be staring at the
stop going. Ah, okay. I mean,
what am I, he's got gotta tell
that story for the rest of,
at what point does that, can he laugh
along with everybody else? You know,
I bet he's considered like
a tragic, tragic figure now
in the redneck community.
You know, like he'll probably, you know,
at the next cross burning the,
they let him late it,
he hobbles up and everybody
gives him a round of applies.
Like they're all fucking sad.
Like what happened to him with some
sort of a terrorist act rather than self
imposed fucking stupidity.
Jesus Christ. You know,
I feel bad for the guy,
but
yeah,
the fuck are you doing shooting a
goddamn gun at dynamite basically.
Whatever the fuck it is
in a God damn lawn mower.
Okay.
That's the fucking blade alone.
The shrapnel from that.
Okay.
I gotta look this shit up.
Top 10
John,
ways to blow you out today.
All right, let's see.
We'll go with that today.
All right,
well you can me hear your
march madness brackets.
Yeah.
Top 10 dumb ways to die.
Uh,
there's always the opening the elevator
doors before the elevator gets there and
not looking and then stepping in,
falling to your death,
playing with guns.
Yeah,
I don't fucking know I or t top
10 dumbest wasted day. Here we go.
All right.
Starving in a supermarket.
I don't even want to read that one.
Diving off a cliff,
but survive but die of shock from the
high price of your hospital bill. Oh,
Jesus Christ. Uh, Jesus.
Okay.
I don't need the hacky jokes.
I have plenty of those come on.
10 absolute dumbest wasted day.
All right.
Oh for this is all going
to be clickbait horse shit.
Okay. You know what? Go Fuck Yourself.
You guys should be dying right now
waiting for me to read this shit.
Trying to kiss a reflection
of the moon in a lake.
Yeah.
All right. Somebody died doing that
and then I got to click another page.
You know what I mean?
Once he can have advertising on every
fucking page and somehow you can fucking
afford Twinkies this month.
Go Fuck Yourself. All right,
so let's talk about the,
um,
yeah,
the tour year. So the first, the
first day we were in Windsor,
right across from Detroit and um,
it was awesome. Our upstairs is great
hotel and you could look right across the,
uh, what are the fucker was, I
guess it is in Lake Eerie, isn't it?
Yeah.
Is it just a river?
Yeah,
I dunno what the fuck you
call it. Is it a sound? Oh,
the Detroit river.
And you see beautiful downtown Detroit
and Detroit never looks more beautiful
when you're not in Detroit.
When you crossed the fucking
river looking at it from Windsor.
And I just kept asking a bunch of
people like, cause I'm going to invest,
I'm going to buy something in Detroit.
I'm going to do it. God dammit. You know,
invest back in America.
I think I totally believe in that city.
I know it's going to come back.
And I was asking people where to fucking
invest and they would just all laugh.
And you're like about 40 miles north.
Like nobody believes in it,
which is what's making me want to
fucking buy. They're even more, you know,
it's fucking dirt.
Goddamn cheap.
It's going to come back at some
point and it has to come back.
Sit right there on the river.
I know the fucking Cleveland Cavaliers
guy bought up a bunch of fucking
skyscrapers there has gotta you know,
he put like the people from Google
and one of them, I have no idea,
but the shit is so cheap there. I don't,
I don't get how you fucking loose.
And I like the idea.
You go in there, right?
You fixed the fucking place up that you
buy and then you don't kick the people
out that live in there.
And then they got a nice place to live.
Right,
okay.
Maybe that gets them in a better mood.
Slowly but surely you just start turning
it around. I think any American, right,
what we should do with
these fucking cities,
cause God knows the government's
not going to do anything.
I don't think they can because it bitches
to the fucking Federal Reserve bankers.
Right. I don't have any fucking money.
They're robbing Peter to pay Paul.
So I think with whatever money they let
us keep, we ought to just don't fucking,
you know, fine up some shit
and Detroit, turn it around,
don't kick the people out,
get it.
Go on and get,
maybe then they can start making
American cars right again.
Okay.
Start fucking with the Audis.
And it's a fucking travesty that we
don't really have anything they can fuck
with those cars.
The fact that they're going to allegate
around the base level Cadillac,
the base level, Lincoln
continental, all right,
are going to pale in comparison to what
those maniacs in Germany are doing.
I mean, I don't understand why, you
know, you know, we can fucking do it.
I guess Buicks are selling like
fucking hotcakes. Is that a racist?
It's a racist thing. Anything we'd cakes
in that I think is racist. Hotcakes. Uh,
back in the day when they
were actually every 10 years,
let us slave of a birthday,
one of the things the slave owners would
do was actually heat up the cake so we
would burn and burn their mouths
because they were that evil.
Here's another chapter of white
evil that you didn't know existed.
Um,
selling like hotcakes.
I guess high kicks were pancakes back
in the day and you know, God damn well,
you know, having pancakes
must've been a fucking tree.
Cause I remember back when you
read The Times, Sawyer book, right?
Uncle Barry Fen is fucking kids
paint a fence just to get an apple.
Like that was considered like a treat
because all day long you would
just sitting around eating fucking,
I don't know if she went on shrubs,
I don't know what the fuck you doin.
So anyways, I'm, I want to buy there,
man. I want to buy something there and uh,
not become the fucking evil person that
boots the people out that are in their
need is fixed the fucking place
up. It gives a shit, you know,
that's of course the people in
there than fuck the whole place.
Something I would be upset,
you know how much that plastic because
it was trying to do something nice.
Um, whatever. Eventually I'm
going to look into that. Um,
so we did wait Wednesday and uh,
we had a great time and Rosie was there.
So of course I smoked a
cigar. So, you know, you know,
I only do two cigars a month now.
So last month I only smoked one.
February I had two and a half because
we started to smoke one and it wasn't
smoking well and we have got halfway
through and like this fucking cigar sucks.
So actually smoked two and a half.
So I smoked two in January.
I flicked it fucking rain man right now.
So then four and a half, five and a half.
So I'm actually half a cigar
under my goal for this year.
So April 1st and he's
already smoked a cigar.
So now I can only have one more are
technically one and a half more.
But I'm actually going to try
and get down to one a month.
And to be honest with you,
I'd Kinda like to go all the way to my
birthday in June and not smoke another
one. Alright. Uh, God damn.
And I enjoy him. I joined,
enjoy the fucking lifestyle.
I enjoy the whole fucking thing about it.
I love going in. I love picking
them out. I love the excitement.
I love the smell. I love the old
fucking chairs. You sit there.
I love that there's no fucking
young people there, you
know? And by young people,
I mean anybody 39 in younger, I
used don't run into, you know,
everybody's just chilling the fuck out.
Smoking a cigar.
I don't care what kind
of a maniac you work.
All these fucking kids that they put
on Ritalin and all this type of shit.
You just give these kids a cigar. Sam,
sit down, puff, you know the casino.
You just,
you thinking about.
Yeah.
Just think about how great life is.
December smoked a cigar.
That's how you start taking out.
Upgraded is graded as he
can enjoy the fucking day.
You start planning your retirement.
How the fuck are you going to get out
of this bullshit so you can just sit
around in whatever zen you've
somehow come into. I mean,
I swear to God,
if cigarettes make you feel like that,
I understand why people do that
shit. It's funny, but you know,
nonsmokers like myself,
you know,
I actually am a smoker now with
the fucking cigars, but um,
yeah,
yeah know he's always looked down on those
fucking people that smoke cigarettes.
They were huddled outside knowledge shit.
You know,
I don't know. Maybe, maybe they,
maybe they know something. I don't,
I'm not advocating smoking. I don't
know what I'm saying. By the way,
Canada, Windsor Airport, Jesus Christ.
What a fucking gem that is.
I love small airports.
There's nothing better than
that little ass fucking airport.
Then when I went to Toronto,
we flew into, we flew over, um,
the propeller plane. Jesus Christ. If
you sub Rosie walk into that, he's,
he's one of those guys. I don't, I
don't want give you sees propellers.
He feels like he's riding in like
a model t Ford, you know? Um,
I always just say to myself, oh, well,
it's, uh, it's gonna fly better. Well,
we have much less of a chance because
there's less working parts here for
something to go bad, you know?
I don't know. That's what
I tell myself. So anyways,
um, we went to Toronto. We didn't fly
into their nightmare of fucking airport.
We flew to the TR Toronto islands,
which I'd never heard of,
is a fucking little ass airport there.
We get picked up and we took a little
fairy, you know, it's fucking hilarious.
I crossed at Western channel.
It literally,
like we started to go and
I started videotaping it.
And by the time I pay and from out
my side window to the front window,
we had already gotten to cross it. You
get across it in like 30 seconds. Um,
or they have a tunnel, you can walk
underneath the western channel.
We did that on the way back. It's
a nice little ass airport. Um,
after all these years of traveling, I
love a little mom and pop airport, get in,
get the fuck out. It's
hilarious. She show up.
They still have the old
school metal detectors.
So you don't have to go through that
fucking radiation shower that for some
reason, I just don't understand
that. So to stop terrorism,
you're going to give all of
your countryman cancer. Well,
if we fucking kill everybody
who they gonna blow up.
Um, so anyways, how far into this
fucking town? 45 minutes. Um,
anyways, but these shows cannot, it cannot
have, uh, been going any better. And,
um, I've been working my
ass off in Los Angeles, um,
for a reason that I'm not allowed to
say yet for whatever fucking reason.
So I've been worried that I, I
can't, um, you know, I can't fucking,
uh, do standup as much as I'd liked, but
us, I've been doing a bunch of spots,
like little 10 minute spots trying to
see shap they just do a little bit of my
act. Even the jokes they here
to make judge fucking see it.
So you remember how it goes.
And um,
I could not be having more
fun up here, Matt. Just having
a fucking great time. Um,
just figuring out my act even figured
out this new way to trash women that like
in his fucking mean as they used to do it.
But I still get to make the same points,
so I just still come off, you know,
it was a complete fucking lunatic all
the time and I don't want to be that guy,
you know what I mean? As much, you know,
something I realized I never finished
reading the [inaudible] think that,
you know, okay. Whether you're
wearing a suit or sweats,
you spend almost 24 hours
a day in your underwear,
but instead of making a statement like
Superman's tights under his everyday
clothes, your underwear is probably
boring. We, and he's about to change that.
Oh yeah, they're, they're about ready
to take your balls to the next level.
They're going to go hang a little disco
ball. You know, it's called the third eye,
the third ball right now, if
you're fucking nuts, you know,
can you imagine her excited face when
she sees a disco ball hanging off the end
of your Dick? Right? She'd
probably get that checked. Uh,
please include all of the following.
No Mo modal is pronounced modal.
Every pair of me undies is made
from sustainable source modal,
modal fabric that's twice
as soft as cotton. Uh,
nothing can describe the fit and feel
of me undies, but once you try them on,
you understand why they're called the
world's most comfortable underwear.
Um, then if you don't love your first
pair of me undies, they're free.
No questions asked me.
And he says dozens of styles and limited
edition prints to help you make a
statement with your underwear.
Whether anyone could see them or not.
Remember Superman.
I don't like that joke.
I remember Superman worth that.
He's fighting Batman.
You know somebody on Worldstar hip hop,
one of my favorite fucking websites.
You know, why don't you
people funny veins, you know,
music that I am completely not even
aware of. I get to learn about that shit.
And then, uh, to some of the most fucking
insane fights you're ever going to see.
And there's always a tipping point when
you watch fights on Worldstar is there's
always the amazement and then
somewhere it just starts to become sad.
If you just start thinking,
what is wrong with human beings?
Why do we do this shit? Why can't we
just go out to a fucking McDonald's?
Or if I dance club,
you know,
and not have like a 50 on 55.
I do have to tell you the respect I have
for someone that actually would go into
one of those modern day
Braveheart fucking things. I mean,
I don't give a fuck how many martial
arts classes you've taken in your life.
There is nothing that they teach you in
those fucking classes other than to turn
around and run,
which you already know how to do when
you get in the middle of a fucking Malay
like that. It's just
inevitable. The fucking odds,
you know,
that's the fight version of being like
the helicopter gunner in Vietnam where
they had like a fucking a life expectancy
of two fucking weeks. It's just,
you're just standing there and you
know it's going to happen. All right?
You're going to, you're going to,
something's going to fucking hit you.
You're going to get knocked out and I
have to tell you the influence of MMA on
these fucking street fights.
Now, back in the day,
I seem to remember when you
knock somebody out, that was it.
You didn't sit on their chest and throw
another 40 punches to their head wedding
for big John to come over and fucking,
you know,
usher you out of there. There's
no ref, that fucking shit.
We already knock somebody out and
then your boot him in their head.
I mean at that point that's like
attempted murder man. You want,
you're knocked him out. He'd
come up, you can do this.
You sit on that chess and do
a fucking speed back then.
Fucking brutal. But anyways,
you know these me undies,
I'm going to get through this shipping
is free in the u s and Canada and you
save up to $8 a pair with me undies
subscription plan a get the subscription,
you know it's like a
fucking end zone dance.
I always thought it was cooler when
you fucking just scored a touchdown.
You flip the ball to the ref like yeah,
I'm going to be doing this all day
if you knock somebody out. Yeah.
He just turned around like yeah,
my job's done here.
You walk away like Clint Eastwood,
one of those drifter movies, you know,
you sit on that to like,
you fucking just kind
of spazz out screaming.
What did I tell you bitch?
You know with your voice goes up nine
octaves when your voice goes up like nine
octaves like that.
You kind of portray your Badass and
thus he kinda is ye here a level of
excitement? Like, oh my God,
I can't believe I won. That's
what I always hear. Um,
having said that, I wouldn't want
to fight anybody in those videos
and it's not even the fact
that I knew I would lose.
I just know that after I was knocked out,
you do irreparable plucking.
I can't even say the word brain damage,
which is unnecessary.
If I could brain damage, you're knocked
me up. You want, I'm laying there.
Okay. My hands are pointing
out into outer space. Um,
uh, knocked out. You know,
what are you going to go there
and knock my melon around and um,
if I was running for president, I
would bring that up. I see in America,
that goes back to when
you knock somebody out,
you walk away like Clint Eastwood
in a Spaghetti Western. Uh, alright.
Shipping is free in the U S and Canada
and you can save up to $8 a pair with me
undies, subscription plan, get the
subscription or a single pair, uh,
get 20% off your first order. When
you go to Mandy's Dotcom. Slash Bro,
that's the only star Constellation
for for 20% off your first order.
[inaudible] dot com slash bro. All
right, dollar shave club, everybody,
she's crying. Second, two more of these
fucking things. Dollar Shave Club.
Everybody does share club Dicom as a
special offer for new members who join
today.
You'll get a free month of the executive
razor when you buy a tube of Dr
Carver's. Easy Shave. But I've seen Kawis.
All right cause that's how I been seeing,
even though it's carvers,
I like seeing [inaudible] and I'm
a big fan of Dana Carvey. Alright,
so there you go.
This is the first time they've ever done
something like this and once you trade
dollars,
share club dot calm,
you'll become a proud member
like millions of others.
One reason is because they deliver
amazing reasons right to your door for a
third of the price of what the
Gri razor corporations charge.
That means when you
join dollar Shave Club,
you can afford to share with a
fresh blade anytime you want,
which feels fantastic.
You'll get a free first class.
You get a first class share when you
use the executive bleed without hurting
your wallet. What is
the executive blade? Um,
another reason is their Dr Carver's
easy shave butter using it with the
executive makes the bleed glad
gently for the smoothest shave ever.
Dr Carver's shave butter isn't
your average shave cream.
It's a unique conditioning formula
with high quality natural ingredients,
leaving your skin unbelievably
soft and smooth. And right now,
new members who buy a
tube of the shave butter,
get the executive razor for free.
You know,
like they'd never done
anything like this before.
So take advantage of it before
they come to their senses.
And it's only available by going
to dollar shave club.com/bar.
That's dollar shave club.com/bar hey
dollar shave club.com/berm alright,
stamps.com everybody chips to that. This
is the last one, mercifully alright.
stamps.com trips to the post
office are never convenient.
While if you don't like your wife,
they've fucking great.
You know what I'm going to walk.
So why not get postage right from your
desk with stamps dot coms downside calm
even gives you special postage discounts
she can't get at the post office,
including FirstClass priority mail
express international and more.
You'll never pay full price for postage.
Again,
here's our stamps.com works using
your own computer and printer.
Buy and print official US postage
for any package or letter.
Then just hand your mail to the mail man
or mail lady or drop it in the mailbox.
It's that easy.
No wonder have a 600,000 small businesses
are already using stamps.com I use
stamps.com whenever I send out one of my
fucking posters. You know, it's funny,
I have a poster for this,
this tour,
the plowing ahead tour and it was
an old telly Savalas movie poster,
right?
And you know,
I spent all this money having this guy
do the whole thing up and we had the
whole fucking tagline on it. You
know, it looks like an action movie.
Like I'm sitting there, but he was
telly Savalas was holding the gun.
I'm holding a microphone. We both
are baldheaded right? And, uh,
he had a casino.
Ali's should I have like a helicopter
and all this dumb shit that I'm fucking
into,
so it looks like this action movie.
Then we had the all this fucking
just re, you know, silly shit.
Like they tried to internet porn,
they fished out the oceans,
but nothing could stop the
man with no answers. Right.
And then it was like this coming,
you know,
I was supposed to be at this movie poster,
so I don't think the
casinos understood it.
They took away all of the, uh, the,
the words, whatever the fuck
you call it, all the tax.
They took all of it away and they
just have this stand alone poster.
And now I just looked like a magician.
Like is he going to come in and the
helicopter and make a truck disappear?
Like it doesn't make any sense.
And I spent all this fucking money on
it and most of them are just using my
poster for my last tour,
you know,
when I had with what's left of
my hair grown out in a beard.
So I don't even look the same as it's
been a shit show anyways. Right now,
sign up for stamps.com and use my last
name, birth for this special offer,
four week trial plus a $110 bonus that
includes postage and a digital scale.
A call to action for verbatim.
Read this verbatim.
A don't wait. Get started.
Uh, with stamps.com today.
Go to stamps.com before you
do anything else, click on the
microphone@thetopofthehomepageandtapeandbarthatstamps.com
enter
Bar
B, u.
R. R.
There you go. Was that for a beat?
I'm enough. I'm such a control freak.
I can't even handle people who are given
me money telling me what the fuck did
do. Um, 55 minutes. All right.
This whole days get away from me having
been read any of the fucking questions
and I haven't even talked about the
Bruins, how we're one point out.
We beat St Louis and
then we lost to Chicago.
Um, of course they'd see any games
because I was fucking traveling.
Um, you know, it's funny,
I had like five or six country
Chicago fans talk and shit. You know,
it's so funny. Last time we played them,
we beat them. I don't talk any shit.
Do I talk any shit? No. Right? Hate
these fucking people eat these,
these whack them all fans that,
you know,
we could euros today than they ducked
back down. They're nowhere to be found.
You know when you fucking lose like
Chicago's gun and doing the playoffs,
you fucking
Goddamn cons.
I actually liked the Blackhawks had
fans like that make me fucking root root
against them. So anyways,
I'm coming up this week,
my Bruins, my beloved Bruins.
All right, we are playing.
Our next game is uh,
uh,
where the fuck is that? I
think we're playing to, no,
we played Carolina I believe.
I think we played Carolina next street.
I get the schedule right here.
Where is the schedule? All right,
we play Carolina on Tuesday.
It's at the TD bank,
north fucking Home Depot Garden.
Whatever the fuck they call it, the
Carolina and notoriously plays as tough.
They always match up well. It's always
a tough game. And then we have Detroit,
which is huge. They're one point
against the ahead of us on Thursday.
And then our last game is against
Ottawa on Saturday. All right.
So basically the two teams
in front of us are, uh,
Detroit and Philly both one
point ahead of us, I believe.
So the great thing is during this week,
Detroit in Philly play each other.
So no, I think Philly's a
few points they had. So I,
I'm just rude fulfilling to just when
the rest of the way out. Right. I,
I, at this point, I have
to root against Detroit.
I don't have anything against Detroit
other than their fucking country fans.
And they really are conti fence.
You know what I mean?
The funny thing about them is they don't
realize that they're run is over and
that it's now all about Chicago and
La and they're wearing the crown.
You know what I mean?
For some reason Detroit is still living
off like an Aes Herman, you know,
I guess they won one last decade
to Oh, actually they went to, yeah,
but you can just see, you can see
it in Detroit. It's over. You know,
it's something that I'm
going to experience what
Brady and Bella Checker gone
and I'm going to be like, yeah, but
where are the Patriots? It's like, yeah,
but they're gone and yeah,
they're wearing the same uniform,
but it's not the same. I'm fucking
with the, I actually love Detroit.
I love the franchise. I don't
like the fence. Um, you know,
and I've never been that way as I like
to think with all the success that I only
talk shit. If people give me shit.
That's how I try to be, you know,
I don't try to act like,
because my teams are successful.
That means somehow in my own
personal life, I'm a success.
Like some people do those. You know what
I'm really judging all black cocks in,
in Redwing fans, by half a dozen people,
which isn't fair. So, you know what,
good luck to all you. And uh, I
hope to Bruins fucking pull it out.
And if we don't,
we got no one to blame but
ourselves just fucking good Lord.
What a fucking sees it up, down,
up, down, up, down, up, down.
That's what the fuck is spent. Now. I
just need up for the last two, three up,
just fucking these three game winning
streak and no one will remember any of
this shit. Dead Shyness is sitting there
with the fucking hard on being like,
I can finally write an article
about hockey that I understand.
Somebody blew it. Oh yeah, I can write
this off like in. Dang. All right,
let's get to the questions then. I gotta
get the fuck out of here. All right. Um,
the all star Cafe, uh,
on March 28 podcast,
you briefly mentioned you were regular
muncher and Nia was a waitress.
The old state, not the all star, uh,
bef from easy road all star up here.
And then I'll state before she got pink
slipped and now and now and the now
closed down Allstate cafe
on the upper west side.
I thought your listeners
might be intrigued to learn
that your meeting place was
also a meeting place for a young teacher
and her murderer in January of 1973
during a one night stand,
murdering a partner guarantees there ain't
no second night, right? Jesus Christ.
They didn't know that the grotesque
multi stabbing crime got so much infamous
publicity that the pub,
his name from the Wm
tweets to the Allstate,
the murderer inspired the
book and subsequent movies
starring the then scantily
clad Diane Keaton also.
Apparently Kevin Bacon had
once tended bar there too.
I wonder if they fired him also.
I didn't know that.
Jesus, that's fucking creepy. I don't
believe in ghosts or anything like that.
Not even remotely, but that type
of shit is just scary by the way.
I love here in a body history,
even as much as they fucking that
cakewalk thing I was trashed and that guy,
I liked that type of shit.
I'm all right.
Girlfriend bothered and annoyed
by sexy TV show character.
Uh,
dear Billy blank balls.
My girlfriend and I were recently
watching the new season of daredevil and,
and we're enjoying it.
However,
one character electra
was introduced and uh,
she bothered the hell out and
my girlfriend for a reference,
Electra is this character that is sexy,
provocative and an all
around Badass Ninja woman.
Electra is also like a,
that weird sort of,
isn't that that mythology
thing? What is the, uh,
what is that weird fucking thing?
Isn't that where I'm aiming going
to say it because of I'm wrong.
Asked to do with some sort of creepy
sexual relations within the family,
doesn't it, you know, died her father.
And then the other one is son, mother
with a son kills the doubt or some shit.
It's just fucking weird when I see
those types of stories actually start
believing in Adam and eve. Well, yeah,
there was just two people and they
banged and then they had this incestuous
fucking horse shit for a couple of
generations until we fucked ourselves up.
Maybe that did up and maybe that's why
the neanderthals and all like or whatever
the, uh, the original cavemen, their
heads are all fucked up looking
is because everyone was related.
Um, who the fuck knows? Anyways?
She was a cool character,
but my girlfriend hated her.
I noticed that it wasn't anything against
the characters since she couldn't tell
me why she didn't like her
other than she just bothers her.
Other people have told me that their
girlfriends slash wives are the same way
with the electro when watching this
show with their significant other.
I know it isn't just this character
because any female that is in a sexy,
Badass role, I have noticed
women specifically ones
with boyfriends don't like,
uh,
is this just some kind of insecurity
women have that they really disliked their
boyfriends? Seeing someone that may
be sexier than them? Um, well yeah,
if you fucking put it that way, they're
going to be annoyed. Okay honey, you know,
they see that girl look how much
sexier she is. Then, you know,
when she watched his fight club,
you know,
does she say how well fucking much
better or Brad Pitt's looking anyways.
Are they worried that this fictional
TV characters is going to steal me away
from her?
I am wondering if I should say anything
because quite frankly it's starting to
get on my nerves.
She will root against the character for
no reasons besides the ones listed above.
Um, I don't know if I
would just make her move,
make her more pissed off though. Have
you ever been in a situation like this?
Love the show and as always go
fuck yourself. Here's the thing,
one of the worst things you can do when
you get into a relationship with the
woman is to start having your behavior
be dictated by just trying to keep them
in a good mood. All right? I'm not
saying walk around and be an Asshole,
but if you're not being a fucking
asshole and they're just being moody,
fucking assholes. Like you got to
call him out on it. Yeah. Like,
and,
and this is another thing too.
You gotta treat them like adults rather
than treating them like children,
which is what a lot of guys do because
physically we're stronger than them.
So you feel like if you say anything to
them, it's like a yelling at a child.
You're not,
not only is that an adult and a lot of
ways they're more advanced because they
can't beat the fuck out of you.
They have to go,
they have to go with their mental,
right.
That's why they consist manipulate
you like a fucking little puppet there
because they can just play Jedi
mind games because they, they,
they're not gonna they from day
one they're like, all right,
this fucking thing is going to be
stronger than me at some point.
So I need to learn how to control
it. Just using my brain. Right.
That's how you end.
End Up holding fucking yarn owes can
hook no woman's cells anymore. Right.
They barely even cook.
So you end up at fucking brunch.
This is what you got to say.
Um,
you've just got to just hit pause
and just, I would just be like,
what is your problem with this character?
You're ruining this show for me. Okay.
If you look at and look at daredevil,
he's got abs.
You see me acting like a fucking
baby about this. You know,
if you don't like the way you look,
go to the gym at the once you be
inspired by this fog there. That's,
that's what I've failed when I,
when I watch a superhero movie other
than I the other, other than like a,
when the fuck is his dumb horse,
Shit gonna be over and always makes me
feel like, yeah, I gotta hit the gym.
Okay.
I could literally sit there and watch
Thor who's probably a foot taller than me,
a thousand times better looking
than I'm ever going to be.
And all that dude does is make me
want to go to the gym. But then again,
if you look at our roles,
like all I need to do is earn enough money
where I can get a Ferrari in a toupee
and next thing you know, I can bank some
core that's been an a fucking magazine.
And that's basically how it works.
If I drive the car in the
right part of the world, right?
Drive around fucking French
Riviera Jesus Christ,
you have no idea what you're going to
be banging. They don't have that option.
You know what I mean? They can't be
like, well I'm a six, but you know,
if I start making money I can go
get myself a Brad Pitt. You can't,
Eh, you know what? You
can't blame society.
You've got to blame the good Lord
for that one. So maybe that's why.
Maybe that's why.
Because no matter what she does, she
can. I don't know. I don't fucking know.
Ask Her, but you know something
I wouldn't be on, you know,
she's ruining your show. You got to
call her out on it. Um, all right.
Okay. Going bald. Dear Billy bald cap.
I'm 24 and I'm going bald.
This runs in my family is both my
grandfathers were bald so I don't have any
sort of identity crisis about it.
In fact,
I'm leaning into it and we'll
joke about it when appropriate.
My question to you is,
when do I finally start buzzing
my ev buzzing everything away.
The last thing I want to do is rocket.
George could stand the
kid cause stanza look,
but we'd like to have a full head of hair
while I can before I look like I'm in
denial.
No comb overs for this cut.
My hair is thin but still
covers everything on top though.
My Barbara did crack more
jokes than usual at my last,
at my expense last time
I went to get a cut. No,
I didn't provide a picture because this
isn't a fucking Rogaine commercial.
Given your experience,
I'd love to hear your input on what,
when you pulled the
trigger to buzzard all,
all away and possibly the
input of the lovely Nia.
When Jesus Christ, what am
I? You fucking stylists.
Okay,
well I think you know something. If
you, Barbara starts making jokes,
you know what I mean?
I feel like there's not enough time left
on the clock for you to make it come
back.
That's basically like now you're lining
up and the dude across the is talking
shit about how they're moving on to the
next round of the playoffs and you're
not.
So it sounds like it's already over,
you know,
I dunno dude.
Why and what am I,
what kind of a fucking man asks another
man a question like this? Just fucking,
you know,
shave your fucking head or go get
a hair plugs or put Rogaine on it,
or a diet, a different fucking cover. I
don't give a fuck what you do with it.
What is my experience? My experience
was when I was just sick of it,
I was sick of the slow and I
was just like, you know what?
Let's just put this
thing out of its misery.
Um,
and I gotta tell you it's not nearly
as bad as everybody fucking thanks.
Who's kidding? Who? Everybody would love
to have a full head of hair, but you know,
stuff that I gotta be honest with you.
Once you start buzzing in your head,
it's kind of fucking awesome. You know
what's great about having a shaved head?
You're always ready to go.
I got to tell you, as much as I would
love to still have a full head of hair,
I love the fact that
I'm always ready to go.
All I gotta do is throw a shirt on,
splash a little water on my face,
and you have no fucking idea that I was
laying in my sweatpants five minutes
earlier. Oh, speaking of which, I'm just
kidding. I always make sure I get ready.
You know, there was this fucking
person, you know, I went out, you know,
I took some pictures with
people after the show and uh,
okay.
Did these fucking people that have
like this fucking guy comes up,
I can already smell him.
Alright.
And then he goes to put his arm around
me during the fucking picture and I'm
telling you like literally
could make paint,
peel off the fucking walls was
how bad this guy's body odor was.
And he's with other people and
they don't smell. It's like,
why don't you say something to them?
Because I'm not going to say it.
Yeah.
Okay.
You paid money to see me,
right? I gave you show.
And then I come out there
and take a picture and then
I tell you, you smell bad.
I wouldn't do that to somebody,
but Jesus fucking question you was
fucking hilarious about this person too.
I kept running into him.
Okay.
And then this person just loved to tell
a story that somehow involved, you know,
lifting his arms up past his
fucking shoulders. Jesus. Fuck man.
I never noticed how much you lift your
arms during telling a story until I ran
into this guy fucking raped fucking rate.
Yeah.
Just completely fucking unacceptable.
Well into his fucking twenties.
And he's standing, he's got a couple
of friends with them who don't reek.
Oh my God. You know, a bad, I would shade
one of those old school fucking, you know,
the spray on deodorant. And as he was
telling this story, I'd be like, yeah.
And just holding my nose and Jay, I
would just spray under one arm pit, no.
Keeps telling this story and then spray
under the other one and then I just hand
them the cad. Do the math
there. Fuck Go. Alright.
Psycho girlfriend.
Yeah.
Um, alright. Psycho
girlfriend. Uh, where am I?
Okay.
So my girlfriend and I have been together
for about five years and lately I've
been feeling the get engaged
pressure from her family. Well, yeah,
I'm 23 and she's 21. All right,
let me rephrase that. Well, no,
um, I thought you guys were older. Uh,
we've been together since high school
and I haven't experienced much else
besides, of course the young
middle school, tug job girlfriends.
I'm afraid of Sunday regretting missing
out on meeting a ton of different girls.
Like all my buddies have been, I
mean you're only young once, right?
My girlfriend flips out on me about
watching porn because I'm thinking about
other girls and she acts like I'm cheating
on her and half the time when we're
out she thinks I'm checking out other
girls cause you probably are dude because
you want to cause you want
to break up with her as what?
I'm guessing she's a drop dead gorgeous
girls so I don't get what she's so
insecure about. But like I said,
she's crazy. She gets abusive with me.
I just kind of sit there and
take it all the time. Um,
she's Latina by the way. Honduran
Nicaraguan. She's got that wild temper.
Um,
all right.
I was that considered racist to see that
Latino chicks are a little crazier than,
than what? Unlike what pasty
drunken Irish chicks. Oh yeah.
They're always so even keeled.
When I asked for space,
I woke up the next day
and my car was keyed.
She claimed she had nothing to do with it.
I love the girl,
she's all I've ever known and
she's amazing most of the time,
but I'm not sure if I can live like
this forever with their temperament or
jealousy. What would you do
anyways? Love the podcast.
Thanks for the advice and go fuck
yourself. P s good luck with the home gym.
Everybody knows you got no
business in irregularly.
I go fuck yourself. I got business in
a regular gym. Oh, when you do what?
You sitting here and you're a fucking
God. Damn. You know something?
I actually had fucking,
I actually had sympathy for you.
I was going to give you some good
advice. You know what? Go Fuck Yourself.
You know what your problem is in
this thing. You know you're just,
you're allowed to. You're young. I'm
not going to be a dick to you. Okay?
Cause you're young. This is the deal.
All right? You got yourself a hot girl.
All right, and you did not
have set up the relationship.
She fucking rolled all over you. You're,
I see what I do in your situation.
If I was 23, I'd be doing what you were
doing. I'd be staying in the relationship,
wanting to get out, um, and
dealing with this bullshit.
But I can tell you this right now,
her looks aren't always going to be there,
but she's always going to have keys.
You know what I mean?
So that's what you're signing up for.
The looks. Go out the fucking window.
You're marrying the fucking person at
this fucking lunatic every time, you know,
God forbid your mailman is a fucking woman
who's younger than her at that point,
you know?
Yeah.
I th I don't know. I don't
know. I can use too wishy washy.
I can't tell whether you
fucking want to be in it or not,
but I can tell you this right
now. Um, any woman keys your car,
that's it.
It's fucking over.
Yeah.
Okay. That is a, the level of
being a complete fucking psycho,
a complete disrespect for your own
property. And that when she was a child,
she was never told no. The fact that you
would go out and do something like that.
Yeah,
I dunno.
It sounds to me like you want to go
fucking get some notches on your belt and
you're afraid that if you do and you break
up with this girl that she's going to
fucking stab you. Um, I dunno,
I got claustrophobic reading
it if that means anything,
but I'm a fucking load of tech.
Alright. Sketchy ex-girlfriend.
Hey you can t leprechaun,
Jason.
Everybody's staring into the
red head shit this week. Every,
every once in a while.
I got to give you guys shit to get.
Can you be a little more original?
I liked that Billy blank ball.
That was fucking funny.
58 fucking, you know,
fucking redhead jokes in a
row, but I get it. You know,
I get it.
You don't have an hour's time.
You can do a 10 minutes set your a
showcase comic. Uh, all right. Hey,
you cut t leprechaun.
I am 16 years old and my girlfriend
is 15 today. She texted me,
she texted me with a picture of
a tattoo asking if I like it.
Yeah,
it is what it is. The date of her
grandfather's death. Personally,
I hate tattoos and thinks
if she keeps getting them,
she will look like a fucking phone book.
I also think her mother is irresponsible,
spelled with a bunch of fees.
He responsible for letting her
get a tattoo spelled with one.
Oh so young. What are your
thoughts about this and how she,
how,
okay.
What's your thoughts about this and how
she didn't tell me till after she got it.
Thank you. And I love your
shows and your podcast. Um,
yeah. All right. She's 15.
She already got her first tattoo,
which you got to do is close your eyes
and age or when is she getting the face
tattoo and the nose ring and the fucking
Olympic fucking rings in our ears to be
different. Um, yeah, I'm not into tattoos.
You know, I think as a certain
type of person can pull it off.
Um,
and that's not 98% of the population,
but 98% of the population for some
reason has tattoos. Now I don't get it.
I feel like there's a certain level,
Badass dude in a certain level,
badass chick that gets tattoos and when
you meet him and makes sense and it
actually,
you know,
okay,
I dunno if I see a woman and she's a
Badass and she has tattoos that actually
makes them more attractive to me if
she's just some fucking dope, you know,
and she has like some advice
column tattooed on the
back of her fucking neck or
some Chinese sign above her ass
crack, you know, symbol then yeah,
it's just like Jesus Christ,
you know,
like the amount of people
out there that gets sleeves
like back in the day when
you got to sleep, I mean,
you were like some biker outlaw,
you know,
now it's like you work at urban
outfitters, you know, and you,
you're the biggest badass thing about
you is your fucking music selection on
your fucking iPhone. I
have no idea. I know.
Is I got to get a rental car
in 10 minutes. If they don't,
I'm going to be late to my show.
So this is the podcast for this week,
the Monday morning podcast. God bless. Um,
I love when you guys trashed me in
the fucking emails, but yeah. Can we,
can we just keep, can you keep it
interesting for the reader here?
I know I'm a redhead. I know
they're easy jokes, but come on.
What if I did that with my standup act,
you know,
which had come out and see
me if I was out there, go on.
What's to deal with New York,
you know? Um, all right.
Go fuck yourselves. I'll check
in on you on Thursday. See you.