Okay.
Hey, what's going on?
It's Bill Burr and It's time for the
Monday morning podcast for Monday,
July 18th, 2016 what's
going on? How are you? Um,
I hope you're good. I
hope things are well.
Has everything okay
with you in the family?
Um,
anyways, this is
the last a week of I'm writing
for emphasis for family. You know,
we got a table read today and then
tomorrow we punch up, you know,
fix whatever jokes didn't
work at the table read.
And then on a Wednesday we
were, we record it and then, uh,
then I get my wife back.
I'm so fucking excited.
I'm so fucking excited to have this, um,
behind me all this frigging work. And um,
I'm very excited for you guys
to see this sync. Granted,
it's animation so it'll come
out sometime fucking 20,
36 or something. Um,
I dunno. Well that's how it works.
That's, that's how the process works.
But I know the big thing is
actually writing the scripts
and we're finishing it,
uh, tomorrow after the punch up
and then I'm done. I literally,
I have the same giddiness I used to have.
Remember like the second week of June
with just even the fucking nerds didn't
give a fuck anymore. Right. They
weren't cleaning that glasses.
They were just showing up.
They didn't give a fuck. Right.
It teachers would dress and casual.
Everyone just was yet it's over.
It's over. Let's get the fuck Outta here.
You know, it's unbelievable.
I don't get, you know, that's,
that's why I like sometimes when I look
at homeless people because everybody
just wants to get the fuck
out and nobody, you know,
you still want to work and every once in
a while you look at like these fucking
bombs. And I don't mean like people like
try something tragic happened to them.
You know what I mean? I Dunno.
Like some sinkholes swallowed up their
fucking home and then they didn't have
sinkhole insurance and now
they're fucking, you know,
sleeping at a bus station.
I don't mean those people. I mean
the bumps, the old school Hobos,
the guys out there riding
the fucking railroads, right.
Let's stick with the handkerchief around.
It went a little peanut butter and
fluff another sandwich inside of it.
Those guys go, they got to figure it out.
Okay.
They always feel how I feel
right now. You know why?
Because they never have to go to work.
It's always over. It's always over.
And then, you know, what do you do? You
go to a new town, you wash some dishes.
Next thing you know, you
know you're eating beans over
a fire outside, you know,
eat and with the knife
or some shit, you know.
Does that one how they used to do it or
is that just what the actors used to do
in those old movies? Trying
to make an interesting choice.
I'm going to eat with my knife. Maybe
that'll make me the next John Wayne. Um,
yeah, they have it fucking
figured out. You never done that.
You never just walked down the
street in the middle of the day,
in the middle of your
fucking stressful day.
You're coming back from
lunch wondering mentally,
how the fuck am I going to get through
next four, four and a half fucking hours.
He is walked by and you see some
homeless guy just fucking just napping,
laying on a park bench or aren't even
on the sidewalk and just so fucking
sprawled out and just in
such a deep level of sleep.
It yet actually looks appealing
for half a second. You know,
I'd love to interview one of
those people and just be like,
who won the Superbowl this year?
Just to see how out of the loop they
are slash how big are sports? You know,
do you know who tiger woods is?
Do you know what happened to them?
You know, are you aware that
we're at war right now still?
Where were you when it started? Were
you behind the desk? We in normal,
you know, do you have a soup?
Did you sit there and laugh at jokes
that you didn't think were funny,
but just doing it to try to get to the
next level fucking cubicles that what you
did. At what point did you
just decide, fuck this.
I want to take a nap when I want to nap.
Can you imagine if you were allowed
to nap whenever you wanted to nap?
How much better the world would be? You
could just be at work and just be like,
Eh, you know what? I'm got to go lay
it out for about fucking 20 minutes.
Just go over and curl up in a
fucking ball and that'll be it.
You know what I'm trying to
say people's, I'm very excited.
As much as I enjoy writing these
fucking things, it's just great. Dead A,
you know, I'm looking at my dog
right now, just fucking chilling out.
Just fucking laying there. She's laying
there. She's she, I don't even know why.
She's tired.
Fucking tired from all you got damn
sleep and I'm jealousy. You cleo, CLIA,
nothing. She knows I'm talking about
her, but she doesn't give a shit.
She's fucking tapped out.
She's laying on the rug.
There's a little bit of Sun spilling in
from the window and she picked the sunny
warm part of the rug and that is it.
That's all the fuck she needs. You know?
No upward mobility. She's not working
on her next fucking season of a,
you know, fucking the real pit bulls
of the greater Los Angeles area.
She doesn't give a fuck. She's got
nothing on her agenda every day.
It's fucking tremendous.
Maybe that's why their lives are
only 10 to 15 years, you know,
they just get to live
like the all, you know,
cause when you look at your
whole life, if you're lucky,
you get 10 to 15 years total of just
bliss. And the rest of it, you know,
it was just dealing with some cotton,
with coffee breath telling
you you didn't have enough,
you didn't bring the right fucking forms.
You got to go back home and go get
something else and stand in line again.
That's, that's what the rest of your
life is like. But if you're lucky,
10 to 15 fucking years of it, you know,
you get to live like my dog right now,
taking a nap on the sunny part of the rug.
By the way, there's so much
shit going on right now,
like on the Internet, on the inner
web that I just don't understand.
What is the big fucking deal. You know,
that whole George Bush dancing thing,
I looked that up thinking he was going
to be just an absolute fucking lunatic.
Like, oh no, stop, stop. You're
making all white dudes look bad.
Everybody already knows we can't
dance. It wasn't bad at all.
You look like he was in a good mood.
Yeah.
You know his fucking energy. It's
like I get that fucking energy. He,
he showing up. He's a patriotic son
of a bitch. That's his jam. You know,
we sways a little bit and you know
what's great too is in his head,
he's laughing at Obama. Like, go on.
I ha you still have to do that job,
George Bush.
It's on summer vacation and the fucking
look he has on his face says the same.
Look, I have all I got to get through.
I just gotta get through fucking, uh,
basically tomorrow. Get through the,
the next rewrite and then
that's it. And of course,
you know the be a zillion
punch ups and editing sessions,
but like the fucking daily
grind is a, it's done.
That's where George Bush
is at right now. You know,
he fucking launched the
missiles. All right?
Bunch of fucking people
died. He's mentally past it.
He bought his pieces of land down in
South America that sit on aquifers.
You know? Who knows? Maybe he goes
out and he gets a fucking 12 pack.
I don't know. He just looked
like a really fucking happy guy.
Since when does a president have to know
how to fucking dance? He does it. Oh,
his fucking job is to get on
TV and scare the shit out.
Scare the shit out of you about whatever.
The fucking people above them who want
to make money on something. You know,
we got to get these people. We gotta get
those people. We gotta get some people.
There's some people out there to come and
get you going to get you these people.
Malley's playing pool
lock. You Lino whack.
You sitting there on your couch. It's
like, how the fuck do they not like me?
They don't even know me.
I haven't interacted with
these cuts. You know who has,
you have their Fucko. What did you
and your friends do to Piss them off?
You know what I mean?
You went out and you pissed
off another fucking country.
Now you're trying to make it seem like
they're out [inaudible] coming after me.
They're coming after you. You con they're
never gonna get to you. You know why?
Because you have security
and I don't, you know,
I'm just fucking sitting here
sitting here with a Mug of fucking t.
Okay.
That would be great. Collectively
if the world did that, you know,
in the world leaders, right? All of
them, they wanted to start a war.
It'd be like eight people and those who
all the people, little fucker, you know,
the infidels and all that. Everybody
just, all regular people just sat there.
I released that. What's going on? Well
listen dude, if you got a beef with them,
why don't you go fucking settle it?
Cause I've never talked to
those people and then that's it.
Then we watch it on pay per view,
you know, slap fights, world leader,
slap fights, you know, and it
doesn't solve anything other than,
than we just get to enjoy complete
fucking sociopathic money,
power hungry. Fucking psychos. Just
slapping each other in the face. You know?
Didn't we just get to sit in the
crowd eating popcorn going? Yeah.
Oh, oh.
Watching them slapping each other.
That's his, as you know, something,
if we were really civilized,
that's as far as it would go. You know,
we just sit there and watch, you know,
Obama have a slap fight with the al
Qaeda guy or a fucking isis guy and then
that would be it. And there'd be
nobody underneath any of them.
I wouldn't even be Obama.
It would be the fucking,
the corporate cuts who make all the
fucking money off the misery. I'm sorry.
People just that, that
you know, I don't know.
Okay.
I hate how they always act
like the world is going crazy.
The world is not going crazy. You
just keep showing the crazy shit.
It's like these fucking lunatics said
[inaudible] who drove the fucking truck
into the people? It's like,
why? Why did that guy do that?
People never did shit like that,
at least to to the, to the,
when I was growing up, people did not do
shit like that, at least as far as the,
the sheer amount of these
fucking incidents now.
And I really think it's because,
I think it's the news coverage.
They wanted their last act on earth.
They want people to then be like
inside the crazy mind of Jill blow,
he, he was born in there, they get
to do his whole fucking backstory.
I think that that's
what they're going for.
So obviously when something like that
happens, you got to report on it.
But I don't think, I don't
want to know the person's name.
I don't want no fucking thing.
But they should die
completely fucking anonymous.
And I think if they maybe, why
don't we try that? You know,
instead of, you know, the
people who get fucking killed,
maybe they talk about him for
fucking, you know, once or whatever.
But the person who fucking
kills everybody, you know,
they get their own little fucking half
hour, hour long special. You know,
as news people sit there with their
brow furrowed, you know, disturbing,
disturbing
Malema Blahblahblahblahblah
and they fucking talk about
it for 24 hours and they
make a zillion dollars in advertising.
Oh, I'm a fucking cynical con today.
Absolutely. But by the way,
that Bush dancing thing was,
that was not bad at all. He looked
like he was, he was in a great mood.
And you know what? Good for him.
Good for him. That fucking dope
guy say he's it dope. I can't really
say he's a Dopa guy. You guys bilingual,
right? You've got to have
some sort of brains in there.
You smart enough to realize
he didn't belong at Yale,
so he fucking drowned it in a 12
pack every 20 minutes. I mean, I,
I relate to the guy. Um,
yeah.
Anyways. Oh, by the way,
if one more person fucking tweets
me about that stupid suspension,
the Tom Brady Think d,
the sheer amount of people that don't
even understand that at that has nothing
to do.
Okay.
You know, like all of a sudden it was
proven that easy. He is a Chichi cheater.
Now, that's not what that was about. The
first one that was the, did he cheat?
And that went to a court of law and was
laughed out of court. The second one,
all that was was the NFL. They
changed their argument. They go,
we're a corporation. He's our employee.
Do we have the right to suspend him?
And the court was like, yes, you do.
And then they came back and they said,
hey Tom,
remember that fucking trial we had
with no fucking evidence whatsoever?
That kind of evidence that gets
laughed out of court. Well,
we're going to uphold it
so you're suspended. So
that's basically what happens.
I just don't, I don't know people
here. What the fuck they want to hear.
All right. Um,
all freckles has been
working out all freckles.
He's been working out. I told you I was
up to one 86 and fucking change, uh,
stepped on the scale this week,
one 82 and change telling the first
week he can always drop three to four,
because it's such a shock to
your system of like, holy fuck,
we're doing this now. If you just start
eating healthy, working out, right?
You stop beating around
five or six o'clock and just
crush waters and you don't
eat again until late the next
morning. You know, I'm telling you,
you can drop three to four now.
Now I'm in my second week of this shit,
so I want to get down to one 79 and
then the week after that one 76.
So I'm in the mid one seventies
when I go over to Europe.
So I represent my fucking country
properly. Okay? All those European cons,
they want nothing more than for me to
go over there and be some fat. Fuck,
you know, who doesn't know what's going
on in the world. That's what they want.
So what you do is, is you
show up in shape, right?
You go on Wikipedia, you Google
their fucking city, right?
You find out what's going on and
then you just pretend you read,
you sit there with your flat stomach
and you pretend like you've read.
That's what you do. And you
know what? It irritates him.
I'm fucking with you anyway.
So I'm down to one 82 and uh,
one 79 next week, the big
seven, I got to see that man,
that second number's gotta
be a seven. It can't,
I refuse to be an eight or higher
ever. Uh, I just can't fucking do it.
Although having said that at my age,
how slow my metabolism is and how much
I like to fucking eat and drink and all
of that shit, I could easily, I could
hit two bills. Like if I really,
okay,
like just shut it all down as
far as moving around, you know,
I just stopped doing shows and I just
sat here like my dog, I swear to God,
dude, I could be 200 pounds by
the beginning of October. Easy.
Right?
That's not even fucking trying
without even fucking trying.
If I just ate what the fuck
I wanted to eat, oh my God.
Is there a worse site than a fucking,
okay.
Five, nine and three quarter
210 pound redheaded male.
And that's not something that you
want to see. And I don't mean muscle,
I just mean coming at you
looking like, you know,
I work at dairy queen and I'm constantly
taking advantage of my employee
discount. Nobody wants to see that. Right?
It's not a man looking like my legs.
My pasty fat fucking legs as white is
to soft serve vanilla ice cream that I
have every 20 minutes. So anyways,
I'm going to get down to
'em once 79 next week.
Um,
I just been fucking hitting the
God damn elliptical and a dude.
My sciatica is just completely
fucking gone. Uh, I'm going for not,
I'm getting massage every fucking
week, right. That deep tissue.
Just somebody beats the shit out of
you and I'm getting all of this stuff.
All of these fucking wall is crap that
was in my legs from all of these years.
Um,
flying on planes, playing pickup
hockey with no hockey stuff.
You know, they tell you guys that
shit. No, I don't think I did. Yeah,
I had another fucking massage and this
lady had an elbow jam so far into the
back of my leg, my hamstring.
I was like having memories of
every time I fucked up my leg,
she hit a spot and I'd be like,
and then I'd be like, Oh yeah,
that was the time I played pickup
hockey and all I had was gloves,
a helmet and a stick. And I
was playing defense. Right.
And I'm skating full speed, you know,
cause we have the puck and all of a
sudden they steal it and they tried to
fucking turn around and go
back the other way. Dude.
And I caught an edge who's getting hurt?
I suck at skating and could barely go
backwards and I fucking shot up in the air
and landed on my left side ass
cheek all the way down to my thigh.
I landed so hard, I didn't even
hit my head and I still saw stars.
And uh, that was one of those things
where I didn't even try to get up.
I just sat there for a second,
just waiting for everything
to settle afterwards and then
fucking, I got up fast enough before
everybody came over and said, dude,
you are right. You are right.
You don't want to be that guy.
And I just fucking like, you know,
skated over the bench, one leg working.
I was just like, Eh, hey,
oh hey, all the way over.
And I just sat down and like, I,
you know, you know, pick up hockey,
people skate over and they pointed
at you. I shook off like three,
three times and I,
and before I went back out there
and the bruise was so deep,
it didn't show up for like three days.
Like three days later I was on the
road and I'm showering and you know,
I, I s I thought I saw like a bunch of
grease on the back of my leg. I'm like,
what the fuck did I sit on?
And then I saw it was a Bruce.
It literally looked like somebody just
took a bat and hit me right across the
back of my left leg.
And, um, you know, Evan,
this is kind of what I learned. I
thought like when the bruise went away,
then you were all fine. Uh, but
evidently that's not the deal. Um,
the reason why it takes that long,
I guess for it to come to the
surface is because it's so fucking,
whatever you hit was so fucking deep
into the muscle. It took that long for a,
I forget the person explained it to me,
a bunch of busted capillaries
or something like that.
And then when they go to heels,
sometimes they confuse to something else.
I don't know, fuse to a nerve or some
shit. I have no idea. I don't remember.
I don't pretend to remember,
but all I know is um,
a bunch of shit like that
happened slash you know,
flying on planes and sitting on my
fucking ass and writers' rooms and that's
what's going to happen. But
what I love is, you know,
all these people who have back problems
with telling me that all, dude,
you're going to have this for the rest
of your life and blah, blah, blah, blah,
blah. I mean,
I didn't fly helicopter for like fucking
three months during this cause when I
sat down,
my feet went numb and I can't have my
fucking feet going numb when I'm trying to
touch the pedals. There. Um, but no,
I, if you find, if you find a fucking,
a real miss Seuss of
fucking incredible one,
they could figure out what
the fuck's wrong with you.
And even beyond a chiropractor,
they beat the fuck out of you and they
loosen everything up and then everything
relaxes and you go back to being normal.
At least that's what the
fuck happened with me at. Uh,
I flew for the first time Wednesday.
I was tremendous. That was tremendous.
I got, oh Jesus Christ. Look at that.
Is that this? Is that a fucking raven?
Hey. Hey. Get all the chin.
Get out of here.
Jesus Christ.
How old am I that I had a yell that long
in a bird before it left back in the
day. I stepped on a stick in the fucking
thing took off. What does that mean?
Was that a crow or a fucking raven? All
right. We got to look this shit up here.
Some fucking ancient medieval
history shit for you,
Raven. Uh, what did you say here? Raven.
I'm Super
Raven's superstition. All right,
little. What do we got here?
What do we got here? Ravens?
Symbolism. Ravens. Symbolism.
Myths of the Raven symbolisms and lore.
Learn about the lore of ravens Burt. I
know that's what I'm here for. All right.
The Raven often has a bad press for
being a carrion, a carry and burn.
I know what that means.
C, A. R. R. I. O. N.
It is ultimately associated
with death. Tremendous.
Finally getting fucking healthy.
Now I'm going to die and consequently
considered a bad Omand by many or a
forewarning of war. Jesus.
Nia is gonna yell at me.
But there is much more to this egg, egg,
dramatic and intelligent bird than
death, darkness and destruction.
Raven is a trickster or
protector, a teacher,
and a bringer of great magic.
I would love to see the person who wrote
this, like what they would dress like.
I just pictured them in like a
fucking Toga with the leaves.
You know the hats they'd
have leaves on the side.
It's like if you had a full head of leaf
hair and then you went bald and just
fucking wrapped around you. Um, learn
all about the raven and it's Laura here.
Well, that's what the fuck.
I'm here for your comments.
Okay.
All right. So Raven is not only the
largest member of the crow family. Oh,
I didn't know that.
[inaudible]
it's the big brother, but the
largest perching bird in the world.
I thought they all perched the others
who lay down an extremely intelligent
bird. The Raven was once extremely common,
but persecution now finds it only
in remotes areas such as cliffs,
mountains, and moon and
more moons and Moore's.
It's amazing the amount of English words.
I already know what they are, Morris.
I thought those were Africans. I just,
I don't fucking, I don't,
I evidently was a crow cause I don't have
any of those things. There's no clip.
There's no mountain. I have a porch.
The adult is completely black
with a shaggy thre. I don't care.
What the fuck does it mean?
Ravens are extremely intelligent in
some cases, can even learn to talk.
All right. That wasn't a fucking raven.
I was just yelling at it. Hey, hey.
Would've been like, what?
Okay.
That would've freaked me out. I'd be
like, Oh, you know, I was just wondering.
I wonder if you'd leave. There'll be cool.
The wolf and the Raven are often
mentioned together in mythology, lore,
and scripture in nature. The wolf and
the raven have an important relationship.
Wolves use ravens as an Ariel Ariel
spotters for possible sources of food as
well as using them to
alert them of danger ahead.
The Raven also gains from
this relationship with the
wolf being carrying birds.
I'm so sick of reading that fucking word.
What does it mean? C A. R. R. I. O. O.
N. You know it's funny,
the amount of people that are listening
to this right now and they feel superior
to me cause they know what this word
means. Yeah. And what does that getting?
Is that going to buy you a sandwich today?
Did the king flush of dead animals?
Okay.
Okay. So that's what it needs.
All right, so it's like a fucking,
it's like one of those birds of vulture
birds with the fucking red head.
No fucking feathers.
I know why they don't have feathers on
their heads because they're always eaten
at dead carcasses. And they don't
want the maggots to get in there.
So they do whatever fucking bacteria
and shit gets on their head,
just gets burned off by the
sun. Although I can't tell you.
I look like a raven after what? Not a
raven of. I look like a fucking vulture.
If I go to the beach, big
fucking redhead, you know,
and I eat dead meat too. Right? Ham.
That's a dead pig. Jesus Christ.
This is an incredible article. All right.
The Raven also gains from its
relationship at the, okay.
Obviously if the wolf fucking kill
something, what? Jesus Christ.
I don't think I can find two more boring
animals on the planet than those two
fuckers. I think they deserve each other.
They probably both in bed by eight
every night. Um, alright, let me,
let me do a couple of fucking reads
here. You got a lot of advertising.
We didn't have any on fucking
Thursday, so I gotta make up for 'em.
I gotta make up for this shit here. All
right. Hey, uh, hey, I'm no, no, no.
That's a read actually here.
I need the advertising.
Where the fuck is he advertising? All
right. Hey Bill, he's grips. Strength. Ah,
you fucking jerk off. You
did the same one twice.
Is He really going to
be one of these days?
All right. Hang on a
second people. I apologize.
Hang on.
Okay,
content reads. There we go. Our
all. Here we go. Track or everybody.
Smart cars, smart phones, smart homes.
Technology has made everything
wicked smart. But losing your stuff,
make smart people feel really stupid.
Kid Tracker makes lose things.
A thing of the past tracker is a coin
size device that locates misplaced keys,
wallets, bag, computers,
anything in seconds.
Just pair of tracker to your smartphone.
Attach it to anything and it finds
the precise location with the tap of a
button. It's that easy. Lose your phone,
press the button on tracker and your
phone rings even when it's on silent.
All right, this is kinda creepy.
Uh, with over 1.5 million devices,
tracker has the largest crowd
gps network in the world.
So your lost item shows up on
a map. Even if it's miles away,
never lose anything again with tracker.
Why don't I get this fucking thing?
I lose my phone all the
time. Listen to the,
did this show to get a special
discount of 30% off your entire order.
Go to the tracker, t, h, e t r a,
C K e r.com and enter the
Promo Code [inaudible], B u. R.
R the hardest single level I have to
find you'll ever have to find is there a
website?
Go to tracker.com right now and use the
Promo Code Bar for 30% off your entire
order. Again. Hey,
tracker.com Promo Code Bar.
Oh look who's back clip. Debbie. Debbie.
I only land on an aquifer club. Debbie,
back to drinking booze delivers
wine straight to your door.
They send you wine that is
personalized to your palate slash.
Taste through your own.
Through our Palette quiz,
their recommendations become even more
personalized with every bottle you rate
club Debbie, I like to sway one.
That dance works with top wine makers
and growers from around the world, uh,
directly to make all of their own wine.
You choose the type quality of bottles
with no membership fee or cancellation
fee and 100% satisfaction guaranteed. Uh,
their $13 bottles would normally retail
for bucks. Right now kind of Debbie,
how go couldn't beat me is
offering listeners $20 off
your first order when you
go to club Debbie at.com/burr
and it gets even better.
I know you all hate paying
for shipping. So clamp Debbie,
they don't let me go to
build a Burg anymore.
We'll actually pay for your shipping
on orders of four bottles or more.
So take something off of your to
do list. Just go to club Debbie
at.com/burke to get $20 off your
first order. Now that's club
debbie.com/bar all right, score
big everyone. You know what?
You're paying too much for tickets
between all the markups and last minute
convenience challenges.
Even print at home,
even printed home feast
the ultimate fuck over.
You end up paying court side
prices for nosebleed seats.
Score big is here to change that.
Did you know that 40% of all
live ticket events go on? Sold.
And did you know that there's a place
to get these seats? That huge savings.
It's called score big.
Okay.
Score big works directly with your
favorite teams and artists to get their
unsold seats at unpublished
prices. Only with ScoreBig.
Can you name a ticket price
and be guaranteed to pay
below box office up to 60%
off Jesus Christ. They're making
some big claims here. One,
go to score big.com or
download the new score,
big app for your iPhone and
finally event and seats.
You want to make an offer of why?
Why don't you do this with the Superbowl
cause evidently 40% of those tickets go
on sold and you can pay for
less, less than a ticket value.
These guys are amazing to
make an offer with score,
big name and a ticket
price feature. Three,
get an instant answer and save
up to 60% off your ticket.
For what game?
Yeah.
Fuck. Head state versus a Soliloquy,
something or other for easiest for
the easiest ways to save tickets.
Download the new score,
big app for your iPhone.
Enter Promo code birth at checkout and
you'll save an extra 20 bucks off your
first ticket purchase.
No iPhone, no problem.
Get $20 off online. When you go to spore,
scorebig.com that's scorebig.com
promo code bar. All right.
Score a big.com promo. Coper
I'm going to try those guys up.
Jesus fucking Christ. We've got like
20 of these. Oh look who's back.
[inaudible] me on ds live and on and
aqua for Boudou to do me on days.
[inaudible] get some for him and
her wrap up or Twat or your balls.
Then walk into the fucking water
falls. Your balls stay dry.
Even if they're cold, they
fucking shrivel up. Oh yeah.
And pull into your body so
you don't freeze to death.
All right? Whether you're
wearing a suit or sweats,
you spend almost 24 hours
a day in your underwear.
But instead of making a statement like
Superman's tights under his everyday
clothes,
your underwear is probably boring
me undies is here to change that.
Um,
every pair of Mandy's is
made from sustainable source
modal mode out of fabric
that's twice as soft as cod.
Nothing could describe the
fit and the feel of me undies,
but once you try them on,
you'll understand while they're why they
are called the world's most comfortable
underwear. And if you don't love your
first pair of me undies, they are free.
No questions asked me.
UNDIES has dozens of styles and limited
edition prints to help you make a
statement with your underwear, whether
anyone can see them or not. Remember,
superman shipping is free in
the United States and Canada.
You can save up to $8 a pair with
the [inaudible] subscription plan.
Get the subscription or a single pair.
Get 20% off your first order when you
go to [inaudible] dot com slash burner
that's [inaudible] e.com/pur
for 20% off your first daughter.
Hey y'all. knees.com/. Burn. All right,
there's three left and I'm
going to read those later.
Let's get back to the fucking
podcast. Here I am sweating.
Roche didn't bake in boy. Um,
you don't actually checked in.
I checked in on the world of baseball.
I have not looked at all my fucking
Boston red socks, if I can call them that.
Or a game out behind the Baltimore Orioles
and were in between two dirty birds,
Orioles and Blue Jays, right?
Yankees are in fourth Tampa Bay's
bringing up the fucking rear.
Here's what's interesting to me in first
place. You got Cleveland. All right,
you got Baltimore.
They have not won a world series since
1983 you got the Cleveland Indians.
They haven't won since like
fucking was in 1948 or something.
Texas has never won. You
got the Washington senators,
they're in first place. They used
to be the expos. They never want,
they should've won in 94 but the
fucking strikes fucking cutoff the whole
season. The Chicago cubs,
they haven't won since 1907 and then the
San Francisco giants who've won every
other year, this decade. All right, look,
you have to fucking Los Angeles
Dodgers and only game and half out.
I have no fucking clue because they're
not on my cable service because they had
some fucking [inaudible] fight
with somebody. It's just the worst.
So this is pretty cool. Man, what a
great year for baseball, you know,
all right. If I had to, if I could
see Baltimore, Cleveland or Texas,
I would pick Cleveland. If I could
see Washington cubs or San Francisco,
you got to go with the cubs, right? No,
there foofy fucking fans taking their
shirts off at the fucking games.
They don't give a shit. Right? So if it
was Cleveland versus the cubs, you know,
I gotta go with Cleveland.
They just wanted an NBA title.
Let's see them get the fucking, you know,
the monkey off their back with
baseball. And I would root for the cubs.
But I just don't think
that people care enough.
Every time I say may out it up all good.
It's just too fucking happy
there. And I also blame,
I really feel like because they do that
stupid shit and the seventh inning,
that's why the fucking, uh, you know,
the Yankees play, why MCA?
And that's why the red sox play that
fucking horrific sweet. Caroline.
The cubs started it. And because
you created that, and I have to,
anytime I see a red sox game and I have
to watch a woman put her head on the
shoulder of a boyfriend during the
seventh things stretch is everybody sings
that horrifically creepy
fucking song. You know,
I kind of hope the cubs go another a
hundred and fucking six years. 100.
They're up to 108 years.
You know what I mean?
Not even the Phillies went that long.
The biggest losers and professionals
and they always want lost more fucking
games than those cons. Um,
and they went, almost done.
They went from like 1880 to
1980 or like 1882 to 1980.
Let me see. Chicago cubs,
Chicago cubs, last world. Look at that.
Comes right up. 1907 I'm sorry,
1908 would you look at that?
So it's been a hundred
and fucking eight years.
Okay.
They should keep it going at that
point. You know what I mean? You just,
you just be who you are. Right.
Plus the fucking white sox one. One.
I don't understand cities that have
two fucking teams. I just don't get it.
And one of the team wins it and you
don't go to the parade. It's like it's,
it represents your city.
Okay,
well dude, fuck ribs. You mean how many
fucking teams do unique New York City?
Evidently in order to remain successful
for as much shit as New York City talks,
they need two football
teams, two baseball teams,
two Paskett ball teams
and two hockey teams.
Fucking unbelievable.
I Dunno if you come from
a real city like Boston,
you just need four and a fucking socket
team and they'll all went championships.
If you know what the fuck you doing,
you don't have to hedge your bets.
Doubled down in every
fucking sport telling you,
you know, it's really making, my day
is Rappaport. It's just been lately.
The guys just teach us, won't
fucking leave me alone. He was all,
he was another one guy all excited
about the Tom Brady fucking, I was like,
Michael, I agree with the suspension. Uh,
corporations should be allowed to suspend
an employee even if it is complete
horseshit. He, I just
don't, he's a giants fan.
They fucking own the
patriots in the Superbowl.
Why can't he just be happy with that?
You know what it is about New York
fans is when they look at Boston fans,
they don't see the misery anymore.
You know, we can talk shit.
It's fucking great and they
don't know how to handle it.
They want us to be miserable
again and we're not.
And it's driving them nuts in like the
misery that Rapoport has that I'm not
miserable. That's the kind of people
that these New York sports feds are.
That's why they got to get
all of these fucking teams.
They're like a fucking a, they're like
Walmart. They're trying to fucking,
you know, have so many locations.
They put everybody else out of
fucking business. It's just,
it's not going to happen. It's not
going to fucking happen. All right,
so why don't, why don't you get
three teams in every sport then?
Maybe you could run the table in 10
years. You fucking cons. All right.
Um, ah, God. Who would ever
thought as a Boston sports fan,
I could just sit here and laugh
at New York sports friends.
I never thought that that was
going to happen. You know,
here I am all fucking happy.
Ah, fuck. What am I up to? 36 minutes.
Okay, here we go. Here we go. All right.
Hey, let's do some reads here.
Hey Billy, grip strength.
I'm one of your listeners
wrote in last week, uh,
wrote in last week to ask
about his hairy girlfriend.
I'm not sure what he ended up telling
her or if he sent you an update.
But unfortunately I've had experience
with this on a couple of occasions.
Now for those of you who
didn't listen the other day,
this guy was dating this Brazilian
woman, you know, so you know,
she's fucking smoking hot, but you
know, she just had a little issue.
She had a little bit of fern,
her fucking arms and uh,
with a tramp stamp would go, you know,
the tattoo could get lost in the weeds,
if you know what I mean.
So he wanted to tell her to fucking
wax a little bit cause you know,
I mean Jesus Christ, you know,
doing it doggystyle and she's got like
a fucking Afro just above a booty crack.
I mean, yeah. I mean what, what,
what's going on with that? So,
but how do you tell somebody that, I mean,
women can tell guys that in a second.
Like you should wax your back. I
don't know. Yeah, just grosses me out.
And you're like, all right, if that's
what it takes to have you keep fucking me.
Right. You can't tell these
ladies anything. You know,
honey, I love you to death, but your
back reminds me of Gabe Kaplan. Um,
I had an experience with this
on a couple of occasions. Um,
under no circumstance. Um, should
you ever tell her she's Harry?
I was dating an Indian broad for awhile
and she had excessive hair growth on her
forearms, lower back, feet and toes.
But worst of all, nose hair,
let that he said, imagined.
Let that image sink in is
what you wanted to say. Ah,
this chick was super
cool and very attractive,
but the hair situation was bothering
me so I broke up with her at her place,
but made the mistake of telling her why.
Oh God, dude, why would you do that?
Let it be known. This was a bad idea.
Well, no, dude, if you just told her,
you know, there was a
way you don't. Obviously,
if you fucking listen, I'm breaking up
with you. I think you're a sweetheart,
but physically I can't deal
with all of your hair. Yeah,
that's going to devastate her anyways.
Yeah.
Long story short, she flipped her shit
and threw plates, silverware, pots,
et Cetera at me while screaming
and crying. So I left.
When I came back later for my shit,
she had thrown bleach on some of my
clothes and stapled condoms to the wall.
You could say things got hairy, lol.
Why do women just get to just destroy
men's property all of the fucking time?
You don't like if the cops show up
and she's throwing all your shit up,
they do a swayed.com calm down.
I start, just get in the car.
Just get away from her sister. She calms
down. It's destruction of property.
There's like a zillion youtube videos of,
of women just destroying their guys' cars.
I don't understand it. I really think
men should start prosecuting them.
Them them for this shit. We always
just go like, hey, yeah, dude,
she fucking flipped out. Whatever.
I can get another flat screen.
Just get her away from me.
I'm all in all he said, um,
if the listener hasn't told this lady
about his displeasure of her hair,
I highly recommend he doesn't.
What do you fucking told her?
You should, should've just said, listen,
if that's the fucking reason you
were going to break up with her,
you should not have brought
it up. What did you say?
Yeah. Listen. How? Yeah,
we, uh, we got to talk.
Um,
this isn't working for me. Wow.
Yeah. I'm just not happy. Well,
what is it? Did I do something?
I said something. I said, well,
what's the problem? You're too hairy.
You have hairy toes.
You have hair above your ass and it's
coming out of your nose. And I just,
you know, you, you just reminded me
of John Matousek and I just, you know,
it's turned to me like why would you do
that to somebody that what you did sir,
was fucking mean. Um, on once one,
pardon me, actually.
Okay.
Respects the fact that you
actually communicate you
and even was fucking mean is
you're going to get what
you want in life. If you,
if you just don't give a fuck about
other people's feelings to that level,
you're never going to end up
trapped in a fucking relationship.
So it's good that you do
that, but in the future, surf,
you're going to broke at break up
with something, some something.
Somebody because of something physical.
You know it. Keep that to yourself.
You know? Cause who's kidding who? Dude,
that's not the only reason why
you broke up with her. You know,
if you gotta fucking tell her she was too
fucking hairy, if you still liked her,
why don't you just say, listen,
can you do me a fucking favor?
You got hairy toes. Can we start
off with that? Jesus Christ.
I'd say I'm dating a fucking cave woman.
It's 2016 have you watched
any porno in your life?
All right. On a side note, he said,
you mentioned your home
gym and current workouts,
but I've never heard you
talk about dead lifts.
Do you plan on doing them
and if you already do,
what type of progress are you
making? Thanks to go flog yourself.
What is a dead lift?
Is that the one where you fucking bend
over at the waist and pull it up or is
that the one where you fucking Yak?
Like you're in the Olympics and
you lift it up over your head? Um,
both of those look like something I
shouldn't be doing at my age. All right.
Videos deadlift.
Yeah.
All right. Five common
mistakes. The dead lift.
All right, here we go.
Okay.
Oh Jesus. What is this for?
That's still, that's the one.
The old blowout your back one?
No. Have you use proper form?
Does the lifter have an Instagram?
His hips should be the
first things that move.
There's a lot of vital information
missing from this hips.
Hip wide stance, hands just outside
the hip. Full grip of the bar.
Shoulders slightly in front of
the bar. Lumbar curve maintained.
So add shoe back. Yeah. Dude,
I'm going to give a big fuck that to
that exercise unless you can tell me what
the hell it does to me other than increase
my chances of blowing out my back.
Um, I just kind of what for
legs? I go hiking and I do,
I do body weight exercises, you know,
the same way I do grip strength stuff.
I'm really into just being
able to move my fucking body.
I don't need to pick up a car.
Like I'm grabbing it by its bumper
and try to use my fucking proper form.
But um, who knows? You know what?
I'll, I'll look those up. You know,
I'm sure I'm going to get a big
fucking lecture on [inaudible].
Oh my goodness. You don't do dead
lifts. You might as well not be.
We're good at it up.
All right. A deer, a bald ass. Billy Gunn,
uh, regarding your caller.
Who needs advice on getting his
girlfriend his shave off body here. Okay,
here we go. I would like to tell,
tell him to be careful what he wishes for.
I had a girlfriend with really hairy
arms and because of it she had very low
self esteem. Once we got to college,
her friends took her to a beauty
salon and she had her arm hair waxed.
Shortly after she re she started to
receive a lot of new male attention and
pretty soon had little time from me.
Shortly after she told me she
needed to talk though. Jesus. Yeah,
she moved up in the draft.
She had a good combine. Um,
she told me she didn't want to limit
her options in college. Good for her.
He goes, I was devastated. I told
her that since I found her attracted,
when nobody else did that, that
should count for something. Um,
she replied with, we all make
mistakes and walked out. Jesus.
Anyways, consider your moves carefully
before doing something brash.
Thanks for the subpar
podcast. It go fuck yourself.
P S take it easy on guys
writing to you for solutions.
They are obviously at rock bottom if
they are willing to take advice from a
dyslexic freckled, Qantas. Jason is
this guy took two shots at me. MMM,
MMM MMM wow. Yeah. That's
fucking brutal. And that's,
once again, that is something
where where it went,
it was going the other way. Women
would be like, that's brutal.
But then if they read this same fucking
story and as much as they dumped you,
she dumped you when you
accepted her for who you were,
they would all be like, Woo.
That's right. You go girl,
you go get what the fuck you want
life. Um, dude,
that's kind of fucking funny. I mean,
does that fuck with your self
esteem at all? I think it did.
I think that's why you gave me shit.
Not once, but twice at the end of it.
I think you got a little bit of anger,
which I would've had angered too.
Jesus Christ. Do you know what's
funny about that is like she,
if she keeps fucking doing it and enough
time goes by the next guy who dates or
is going to have no idea that
that's part of her fucking genetics.
And then he's going to have a
little hairy baby and be like,
where the fuck did this come from? She
be like, Oh, you know, I don't know.
Okay.
Fucking baby coming out looking
like Robin Williams arms.
Remember his fucking furry
arms rest his soul. Um,
oh my God, that's fucking everything.
Anything happens to a guy just, it just
ends up being funny. I Dunno what it is.
Everything that happens
to a woman is tragic,
but just when shit happens to guys, it's
fucking funny. What are you gonna do?
You know what you're going to do buddy?
You go to the fucking gym, right?
You go to the gym and just go, you know,
just start hitting at a tip non
shit way Outta your fucking league.
You know, do it. Do it for yourself, Ben.
She's reaching for the fucking stars.
So should you take that as an
inspiration and a, you know,
God help the next fucking guy. She gets
with Jesus fucking Christ. And then,
you know, some the whole
time she walks this earth,
she has to live with that secret.
You know, cause I'll tell you,
there's no fucking way she's telling the
next guy that that's what's going on.
If that held her back
right. And you, you know,
when she walks around and hangs out with
all these other fucking beautiful women
now in her beautiful people circle and
they have like fucking no hair on their
arms, there's going to be something
in the back of her head. You know,
at one day she'll have too many white
zinfandels and she'll just say to her,
fucking boyfriend,
you're a good guy. You
maybe she won't. Maybe she won't. Then
some day they have the hairy baby,
the OAH beef, the dreaded hairy baby.
I can't come into work
today. Oh, it's a matter a,
my wife gave birth to a heavy baby.
Yeah, dude, it's fucking ridiculous.
I thought it was a, I thought
it was a little gorilla.
Oh, okay.
Turns out she had fucking hair all
over. She just got waxed. All right,
dear red, red Sonia. I don't know what
that means. I hope I said Sonjia. S O n.
J a. Um, should I look
that one up? I mean,
if it's an insult, I got to see what
it is I want to share on the laugh.
Other than the fact I can't
pronounce it or know what it is.
Red Sonja, what is red?
Sonya Red Sonja in 1985 is a vengeful
woman sets out to achieve a magic orb with
an er. I got to see images of this.
Okay.
Jesus Christ. He's fucking smoking
hot. Um, I don't know what that means,
but anyways, dear red, Sonya, um, her,
the email from the guy with the
Harry Brazilian girls is another one.
Okay.
This is another one. There's
a lot of hairy ladies. Um,
I have a suggestion for the
other guys in similar situations.
Um,
have bill burr address it for you.
Listen to the podcast over the speakers
when your girl is home. That way,
you'll plant a seed in her brain and
hopefully get her to shave with Anne Wax
without even addressing it yourself. Oh,
so play that fucking part of the
podcast when they're around a,
you know what? Women are
way more complex than that.
That's a fucking decent idea. And uh,
cause what's going to happen, she'll,
if she's self conscious about
that, if the light goes off,
she's going to be like, that's first.
She'll be like, that's stupid, Eh,
that guy shouldn't have blah,
blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
And then about a half hour, that bullshit,
you'll finally come around to saying
like, do you think there's like,
I know I'm a little more hairier
than most girls. Does it bother you?
It's still gonna come back to you.
If women were that fucking
easy to deal with emotionally,
we wouldn't die eight years before them.
There's no fucking way
it would be that easy.
Like they're just going to listen to
the podcast and they just going to click
and be like, oh wow, maybe I should wax.
I'm going to do that and
not have a fucking four hour
un meeting with my fucking
boyfriend. Um, anyways, he said,
I've done the same thing in the past with
great success. Okay, maybe I'm wrong.
Wait a minute. Wait A, here's the
replay going over to the replay booth.
A I happened to listen to
an app episode. He said,
I happened in quotes to listen to an
episode about lip hair when we were
driving. Three days later,
mustache was gone. Try it.
It just might work. Holy
Shit. All right, well fuck it.
Give it a shot. I stand
corrected. I Apologize Sir.
I apologize. Apologize. Jesus
Christ. I just pictured the, uh,
the referee coming back saying no goal,
but he actually came back
and said the goal was aloud.
You lost sight of the puck and the
mustache still left. It's incredible.
Alright. All the best from Sweden.
Okay. What am I up to here?
50 fucking minutes. Alright. Okay.
Career crossroads. Hey Billy, fuck
face. I liked that guy. He just,
he didn't try to be creative.
He just went right for it.
I am a 17 year old high school senior,
going to into college, studying pre law.
And ever since I was young I
wanted to go into the military.
My father owns a medical compliance
company and his promised me a job after
college. Should I get a law degree?
However, he was re a Jesus Christ.
You know what? I just realized
I've got to do something. Hang on.
I gotta start this. Fuck.
I got to hit pause and I got to start
this fucking question over again.
I gotta unlock the door here.
Hang on. All right, I'm back.
I didn't need to unlock
the door. She had her keys.
For some reason I didn't
think she had her keys. Um,
and she needed the lovely Nia is going
to come on hopefully in a minute and
dress the fucking, the growing
controversy of the hairy girlfriend.
How do you tell her? All right. So
here we go. Hey Billy. Hey Billy.
Fuck face. Uh, I am a 17
year old high school senior,
going into college, studying prelaw.
And ever since I was young I
wanted to go into the military.
Um, my father owns a
medical compliance company,
has promised me a job after
college. Should I get a law degree?
Why would you get a law degree and then
working in a medical compliance company
or medical? I thought I was thinking
like they supplied like appliances,
like he was selling like fucking
dental drills and shit. However,
he has recently talked about selling the
company and retiring as he is nearing
70 and not getting any
younger. My question is this,
after I finished college,
should I enlist in the military something
that I've wanted as long as I can
remember or should I stick
with the safer option?
Never choose safe taking over my
father's business slash securing a safe
lifelong career. Now do that.
That is a recipe for what if, um,
fuck that dude. You're young. You don't
have any kids. Just risk, risk, risk,
risk, risk. I'm not saying fucking jump
off a bridge here. I'm just saying,
yeah, go big. You go
big when you're young.
You know she never go out with me. Fucking
ask her out. Who gives a fuck? Right?
Oh my God, I can't, I can't try to do
that. That's a one in a zillion chance.
Just go fucking do it.
Listen to how I read out loud
how fucking horrific I am,
and I've been tremendously successful
telling shit jokes now if I can do it,
believe me, anybody can do it. And you
can too. If that's what you want to do,
you should definitely do
it. Um, anyways, he said,
I'm worried that during my
absence in the military,
there's a strong possibility my father
will say it and sell the business.
I'm at a loss because on one hand,
I don't want to sit at a desk 10 years
from now thinking about what could have
been a great experience in the
military. But on the other hand,
I don't want to lose a job at my,
at my fathers and be stuck at a soul
sucking law firm for 30 years in a tiny
cubicle working to make
someone else's dream come true.
I'm really at a crossroads here and I
don't want to make the wrong choice that
could potentially fuck
me over big time. Uh,
what would you do if you were my shoes?
Thank you. And Go fuck yourself. Uh,
I would go into the military.
I'd finished your law degree.
That's what you want to do.
I would go into the military,
join the branch that you wanted to.
I would fucking crush it in the
military and then when I come out,
I would be such, you know, I would
attack being a lawyer at the same,
the same attitude. Why do you feel like
you're going to be stuck in a tiny,
tiny cubicle? Why wouldn't you
move up and become partner?
You need to dream bigger dreams. Dude.
This whole thing of like, you know,
the only way you're going to be successful
in the business world as if you take
a job for your dad. Fuck that
dude. If you go the other route,
you become a self made man. And
when you become a self made man,
you get a belief and a
confidence in yourself and um,
you don't worry. Like you're 17, you're
already, you're already worrying.
Fuck that. You got your
whole life ahead of you.
I would go out and do everything that
you want to do. And then one day,
all 20 years goes by and all of
a sudden you're like, Holy Shit,
I work for myself. I'm making great money.
I can go to the movies whenever I want
to. I can take a vacation. You know,
I could talk shit on a podcast.
Like it just completely opens the
world, opens up for you. But you know,
if you'd go the safe route,
you know, there's that,
there's that does that fucking knowing
that haunting voice in the back of the
head. What if I did this? What if I
did that? He starts sleeping at night.
All right. All right. All right.
Fucking thrashing and Shit. Um,
I think you're going to do great in the
military and I think you'd do great as a
lawyer. And that's what you should
be thinking. You know, that's it.
And you're gonna meet some
fucking beautiful woman and she,
you get married or whatever,
whatever the fuck is you want to do.
Just think positive thoughts and uh,
surround yourself with
people that feel that way.
And if you have a friend that sees
you start to do well and you feel them
starting to become negative, address it.
And if they don't fucking
clean up their shit,
you cut them out of your life cause
those people will bring you down.
Stay here at the townie bar
with the old football jacket on.
Fuck that. All right. Good
luck to you sir. Alright.
Dating an older lady and all
the broad, hey Billy boy.
Fuck nut. Uh, Ben in a serious
relationship with an older woman.
She is fantastic. Cooks
for me, rubs my feet,
gives me sponge baths
and just an absolute gem.
She has a great job,
makes a boatload of uh,
cash I guess. S Carol, E. S. C. A. R.
O. L. E. I don't want to say that word.
And I also do very well for
myself. Money is not an issue.
I deeply care for her and love her.
I'm 30 and she is 45 but she looks
better than most girls my age.
When we first met, I thought she was 32.
So that's what initially
attracted me to her.
She's fucking slamming hot and a great
purse and it has a great personality.
We can joke around and I
can say disturbing things
to her and she just laughs.
Real class act type of broad. Uh,
she was an 18 year old daughter. She
has an 18 year old daughter bird.
As far as I'm concerned. I
don't really give a flying fuck.
My family had some opinions and we're
like, she's too old, blah blah blah.
Fuck them. They have
miserable relationships.
She makes me a better person and I feel
good. Your thoughts, uh, your thoughts,
Billy Little sack Jesus
Christ. Fucking everybody.
They gave me the old
fucking one, two there. Um,
okay.
Well Dude, you sound like you're happy.
That's what the fuck you want. The what?
There's nothing wrong with
it. That's what you want.
There's nothing fucking wrong with it.
She makes you happy. Yeah, absolutely.
Why would you leave?
You know, I don't know.
If you want to have kids that might,
that would be a fucking issue. You know,
at that point you freeze her fucking
eggs and you jerk off into something.
I don't know how it works. I
don't pretend to be a doctor. Um,
I'll fuck you know what? I
didn't read the other Goddamn,
okay.
The other advertisements. All right,
let me just knock out
these last really quickly.
Let's see how fast I can
read these. All right,
this is going to be a fucking
train wreck. Simple faith.
I'm not gonna read these
fests. Simple faith. Everybody.
Thousands of people seeking home
security get ripped off every day.
And the home security industry wants
you to believe it's your only option.
They've got hoards of salesmen out there
trying to scare you into signing one of
their longterm contracts.
You get stuck writing huge checks
month after month with no way out.
It's robbery by contract and
it can cost you thousands,
but there's a better way to protect your
home with simple faith. Home Security.
Simple faith has no contracts.
None. You'll get award winning 24,
seven protection named
best in the industry.
Security professionals watching,
ready to instantly send the puppy, uh,
the police. And it's just 1499
a month, $14 and 99 cents.
That's less than half of
what most companies charge.
Protect your home this smart
way. Visit simple faith. Um,
bird.com there's no slashes, nothing.
I'm going to guess there's a slash there
simple safe slash bird.com but they're
saying simple,
safe bird.com try one or the other for
an exclusive 10% offer and get a free key
chain remote with $25 only.
When you go to simple flight bird.com
that simple faith bird.com MVMT watches
everybody when you're in your early
twenties and thirties, money can be tight.
Uh, if you're not careful, dressing well
can quickly drain your bank account.
Like spending four to 500 bucks
on a department store. Watch.
There's some brands out there that are
charging insane prices for watches that
aren't even worth it. Well, if you
want to look great when you go out,
but still have enough money to buy
him or her a drink, checkout movement,
watches.com I've seen them before.
And these watches are sharp,
originally found by two, founded by two
broke college kids movement watches,
cut out the middleman and they're
big brand retail markups and yeah,
kind of out the middleman in
their big brand retail markups.
In order to give you a stylish watch
for an affordable price movement,
watches just started at $95 a watch with
department store quality for a fraction
of the price. They're
sleek and minimalistic.
A modern twist on a classic style
movement has grown occasionally,
organically, sorry, purely by
support is like you said, join.
They're more than 1 million social media
media followers and getting a movement
watch today. Go to MVMT
watches.com/burr and they'll save you
15% off your entire purchase. MVMT
watches.com/burr and lastly, but
not leastly dollar shave club dude.
Um, people's, uh,
dollar shave club.com delivers amazing
razors right to your door for a third of
the price of what the greedy razor,
razor corporate crazy
razor corporations chach.
That means when you
join dollar Shave Club,
you can afford to shave with a
fresh blade anytime you want,
which feels fantastic.
You get a first-class shave when
you use the executive blade,
and that's without even
hurting your wallet.
And when you use the executive blade
with their doctor cabbies, easy shave.
Whoa.
Dr Carver's shave butter,
the blade gently a,
the blade just gently glides
for the smoothest shave ever.
Shave butter isn't your
average shave cream.
It's a unique conditioning formula
with high quality natural ingredients,
leaving your skin
unbelievably often smooth. Uh,
now's a great time to
join dollar shave club.
New members who buy a
tube of shave butter.
Get a month on the of the
executive razor for free.
Take advantage of this
special offer today.
It's available by going to dollar
shave club.com/bird that's dollar shave
club.com/bar and lastly,
if you want to donate to this podcast
without a cost in your fucking dime,
anytime you're going to buy something
on Amazon, if you go to my podcast page,
you click on, um, the
little Amazon link there.
It takes you right to Amazon. It
doesn't cost you any extra money.
And I get credit for driving traffic
there if you want to. If you don't,
that's fucking cool too. I'm a Nia. Do
you want to read this thing with me?
Yeah.
Okay. All right. Well that's
the end of the podcast,
but she's going to come here in the
end and we're gonna uh, I dunno.
A little bonus, like five minute thing
here. This could go south very easily,
but we'll see what happens. Hang on,
let me hit plus. Right? The lovely knee.
Everybody. Hi, how are you? I'm great,
thanks. Okay, let's get right down to it.
Okay. All right. This guy, he's dating
this woman. She thinks she's beautiful,
but she's Harry this
thing again. Well, yeah,
but I never, you never talked to about,
we never got a females advice on this.
I thought we did. You
talked about it. Yeah,
I remember I said like either like
he sort of gets something wags,
then they go together and it's
funny or he just like gets over it.
You said that on the podcast or
did we talk about that on our own?
Not on the podcast. And you got all mad
at me cause I was like, if she's not,
what do you have against talking
into the mic? I don't know.
You just sit there and go like I know
people tweeted me the last time was like I
can't hear you. So I, you've
told me just to the Mike,
just have it follow your,
your, your mouth. Okay.
But because the thing is I feel like
if a microphone is anywhere near me,
it's going to microphone
my voice. So amplify.
Wow.
It's very rare that someone
makes me look like the smart one.
Microphone. My voice. So, um,
well what you have to know is with
microphones, each one of them they have,
there's ones that are designed to pick
up three 60. There's ones that are like,
these ones are like directly on.
Okay. So that fits directly on that.
The reason for that is if there's other
background noise that you don't want to
pick that up.
There's other microphones designed
where you want to hear the whole room.
These are directly on, so
you've got to speak into it,
but this is not what we're talking about.
Okay. Sorry. All right, so somebody,
somebody got this and she's got
like a like hair on her lower back.
Yeah. Like right with a
tramp stamp would be like,
she could have a tramp stamp and he
wouldn't know cause it's, there's a,
the whole thicket of hair under that.
Yeah. I thought we talked about this.
I thought you stopped saying that. Okay.
I understand that you think
that we talked about it.
Neither one of us can remember if we
did it on the podcast and this is just
bonus time anyways, so
refresh our listeners. Well,
my dating a woman, she's got a fucking
Afro right above her butt crack.
What do you say something wrong
with an Afro? Um, a on your head.
A booboo. I think you
have some answer though.
God Damn, this is just,
this is just a tough one.
How long has he been dating
this person? It can he be like,
so what's with your little
furry back over here?
You're like my little Chia pet in a cute
way. Like, can he say it in a cute way?
How do you say that in a cute
way. I Dunno. Like say, Oh,
you're my little Chia pet back here. No.
Um, you know what? Maybe
he could just sort of like,
this is gonna sound really fucking weird,
but maybe the sort of like stroke
it or whatever the thing is.
She'll probably be like, oh
God no, don't touch that.
I know there's like hair back there.
It's so like weird. I hate it.
And he can go, why don't you get it wax?
And she might be like, I don't know.
Like I'm embarrassed. I'll go with
you. I'll walk something with you.
How about that? I'll wax something.
You ask something and then boom,
I have an idea to what,
how about when you know she's wearing
like a sexy shirt so it doesn't quite
reach down to her pants when she goes
to get up off the probably doesn't wear
shirts like that. When she
goes to get up off the couch.
You just reach up and grab her a
little backhand. Go back down here.
What did you sign on her stomach?
At the beach and he starts braiding
it for her. I know it's bad, it's bad.
It's cause your questionable situation.
Well this one guy was saying
he was dating this woman,
she had like even hairy feet. She had
like hairy toes. Shit happens man.
I know, but what the fuck
N***a you gotta handle that?
I mean ideally yes you would handle that
in a perfect world, in a perfect world.
But you know,
I had girlfriends for years who had a
little like just like the little shade of
a mustache and they just never,
it just never really occurred to
them to wax it until like recently.
And I remember I had a friend,
I saw her I hadn't seen in
awhile and she was like,
do you notice anything different?
And she kept turning her face in a
certain way and I was like, yeah,
you get your upper lip wax. I was
like, yes. Yeah. She was like,
I finally did it. She
was like, I don't know.
I was always just intimidated to
go into the place. And she's like,
but I'm so glad I did. So I have
to, is that what it is? Yeah.
People are self conscious and you
think you'll go in there and you'll get
judgement by the waxing person,
but the waxing person has waxed,
you know Chewbacca down there so
they don't care. That's their job.
So it could be that she's just like a
little embarrassed to go to a place and
have it taken off because
who wants to say, oh,
I have to go get my back wax today before
you don't have to say that you just
walked down and you go,
Hey, can you wax my back?
You don't even have to whisper
it. I know you don't. So, oh no.
But if you go there to other people, see
you getting your back wax? No, no, no,
no. You're in a private room. Oh, whenever
you get any kind of waxing service,
it's not like Steve Ferrell
Clarkson. Exactly. Yeah.
So you are going to private things.
So he just has to do it in a cute,
you know what, this one
asshole did what? He goes,
I suggest you don't tell the woman
that she's hairy. He told the woman,
he broke up with her and said the reason
why he was doing it was because she was
so hairy is that's not the way this do.
Isn't that the meanest thing you've
ever fucking mean his thing ever.
Are you that shallow? Because that's
something that's easily fixable.
Are you that fucking shallow
that you break up with someone?
It's like cause your hair your back.
Like what a fucking ass hole back feet
knows a lot of coming out of the nose and
then the arms. That's
just, that's unnecessary.
It to to say that after the
fact if you love somebody,
even if you don't, even if
you don't love somebody,
you don't do that to somebody. Yeah.
No that's not, that's not okay.
But then show, since she fucking, he came,
she started throwing plates and he
fucking left and they came back.
She had dumped bleach on his clothes
and stapled some condoms to the fucking
wall. The usual destruction of property
that for some reason do use validated.
Do you have?
I have never actually noticed you have
back here yet but I mean back here yet
like cause I go that
something has and all the,
I've actually never not turned around.
Now I don't have back here. Let me say,
well Jesus Christ near your fucking
sleep next to me every goddamn day.
I just never thought to look for
that. Now I don't have back here.
There is a very fine little area
in the lower back tramp stamp area.
Not a lot. You can barely see
it cause your hair so fair.
But like no, no, no.
You have a very small like yeah
that got nothing back there.
There's nothing back there.
I mean there's more on your chest
than on the your lower back.
Very small amount. But the thing is,
I feel like in 10 years that
shit could get a little thin.
In 10 years I'm going to be close to
60 I mean I'd still have you accident.
What? In 10 years? What?
Where my white fucking back
here against my white back.
Cause it bothers you when I wear a
fucking half shirts. I mean, what,
what are we doing at that point? That's
a fair way to look at my lower back.
Let's just do, let's just, no, you don't.
No, you don't know. Okay. You don't,
well I'm, I'm, yeah, I try to keep
very familiar with your lower back.
You don't, Oh yeah, you don't,
you're not a hairy person
so, but if I was hairy back there,
would you say something to me?
Nudge when I broke up with you?
What's so you would have broken up over
cause I want to take in the time to fall
in love with you.
If you walking around looking like
fucking Burt Reynolds and playgirl.
Okay. Oh, I see a Photoshop coming.
Oh my God. That man. No,
that man, wait, shout out to
the MM Photoshop on
sweater. Oh my God, Dude.
That one with me standing
in front of the fountain.
I fucking, dude,
we were in the writer's room when I
saw that and I fucking laughed so hard.
Yeah. Like one of the other
riders was going like, what? What?
And I showed it to him and everyone was
going like, oh my God, that's so mean.
I go, that's fucking hilarious.
And then I love the picture of
you that they found it was, yeah,
it was like when you were
going out to some event.
So you look at the heat premiere.
Yeah, that's what that picture was.
I was trying to be like, fucking,
you know, modest about it.
I didn't want to sit there and
say, you were in a movie premier.
I said you had some big event. You
always gotta just be standing there.
You always have to fucking
drop the Hollywood shit.
Don't Juliet on taxi premiere
for the cinematic film.
The heat where my husband had two
lines. You had more than two lines. Oh,
if you sneezed in that
movie, you missed me.
But now everybody's follow
the MM Photoshop on sweater.
Yeah. Whoever that is,
man. A woman is fucking
hilarious. Wait, wait, wait.
Actually I'm a better one for that,
ma'am. Photoshop. All right, so wait,
where's my phone? Because I wrote it down.
Remember you said the name of
a movie and it was once again,
how you have just sort of clues from the
movie and I don't remember the titles.
All right,
so I'm going to find it because it was
definitely one of your classic ones.
And we're not going to
say what the movie is.
We're just going to have the m Photoshop.
Okay,
wait, let me see if I
can find it. Mark it up,
put it on Twitter and then everyone will
be able to guess, hopefully. All right,
so you called this movie. I'm going to
kill you on Wall Street. They're fuck,
oh, I'm going to kill you on
Wall Street. They're Fucko.
So that's, that's it. That
was a movie. That's a movie.
So people are gonna try to guess what
it is. Mm, Photoshop is going to it.
It's funny. Days later, movie
poster. Days later. You reading that?
It now sounds like somebody else says
it, said it, and it's a terrible clue.
That's not even close. It's sort
of close. They'll figure it out.
All right, well,
okay,
it's uh, 12 minutes past the hour here.
It's time to wrap this up because open
is past the hour, hour and WB. You are.
Our morning becomes eclectic. I
love her. You listened to that.
You think it makes you smarter?
All right. That's it. No,
it's so pretentious to
be smart. Okay. KCRW,
so you get a variety of musical
style. Same liberal viewpoint.
All right. You done this over.
Can I just know I go somewhere to eat?
My hope miracle. You know what it is.
I just, I don't like shit.
That's a hundred percent liberal are 100%
conservative. All right. That's fine.
I like in the middle because both
of them caused me to yell at them.
Bill, I always yell at everything.
It doesn't matter what it is because
nothing is exactly your viewpoint.
I don't yell at you. What? I don't
yell at the dog. That's also not true.
I don't yell at other drivers.
I'm courteous. I'm polite.
Okay.
I don't yell at inanimate
objects like my computer.
I don't do any of those things.
Sure. Well then all right then.
Then I want to know, you're
like a red headed Gandhi.
I definitely was like Ben Kingsley's
more than I look like fucking Donny.
Danny Bonaduce. All right. That's the
A, that's the podcast here for the, uh,
for this Monday. Anybody to
do, Jenny bought a doge shake.
He got a situation with anybody do it.
But dude, we got to take them care.
The fucking, all right, that's it. I'll
talk to you. Fuck hours on Thursday.
Go fuck yourselves.