No, it's just to remind you, you
guys have a haze. Anybody at work,
I used to work in this
warehouse and we were,
we were a bunch of fucking maniacs and
all day long, all we did was break balls.
Uh,
I've told you this shit before because
we were basically mentally smart enough
to work in a warehouse by the time you
went third grade. You know what I mean?
It's supposed to be 10 boxes according
to the packing list. One, two, three,
four, five, six, seven, eight, nine,
10. There you go. One, two, three, four,
five, six, seven, eight, nine, 10, 11,
12. Sorry, sesame street, flashback.
Um,
so we used to fuck around all the time
and our manager had no control over us.
You know, we didn't respect him.
We knew he wasn't gonna win fire.
We wasn't going to fire us. He
didn't have the goddamn heart.
And at the end of the day we got a fucking
job done. So he decides that we're,
the problem is, is that
we're all too fucking young.
There's a level of immaturity out there.
Cause we were all in our early twenties
that we, uh, that he should hire.
He hired this 38 year old guy.
Um,
I actually remember his
name, but I'm not gonna,
I don't name names on this
shit. And uh, Jesus Christ,
that fucking guy's almost 60.
He was like 38 and that was
22 fucking years ago. He's 60.
What the fuck? So anyways,
this guy drove a fucking sky blue Chevy
cavalier stationwagon four door bare
bones factory fucking rims. The
car was like three years old.
He had 8,000 miles on it. Alright.
And this guy was a Weirdo and
he had these fucking glasses,
these black framed glasses
that nobody wore in the 80s.
So we immediately started calling
him warty we'd be, hey woody,
how many boxes we get over there?
And this guy was just bizarre.
And he'd come over, why call me woody?
Are you trying to bring me down?
So he kept saying, you're
trying to bring me down.
Did I already tell this fucking story?
This sounds oddly familiar to me.
So we would just fuck with them.
We would just be like, okay,
at four 31 today, everybody just
start going, what do you, what do you,
what are you, what are you in?
That's what we would do. He would be
picking orders down in the,
in the warehouse area and we would
all be picking orders with them.
And then out of nowhere
we would just start,
God, what do you, what do you, what
do you, what do you, what do you,
what do you, what do you,
what do you, what are you
top of our fucking lungs? I know
it's fucking am as sophomores,
but it would and what, we
wouldn't say it to him.
Okay.
We would just fucking be sitting.
It was really passive aggressive cause
he already talked to management about us
calling them woody. So it's like,
dude, we're not calling you woody.
We're just going woody, woody, woody,
woody, woody, look in your vicinity.
So we do the same thing.
You're trying to bring me down.
You're trying to beat me down.
So eventually we haze this guy so
much that he fucking quit, right?
He and his little Chevy Cavalier fucking
four door sky blue bear bone station
wagon drove right out. And the back
of my head I was like, you know what,
I've got a bad feeling.
That mother coming back,
it was right right around the time
when people first started going postal.
So it wasn't enough that that we
actually drove this guy out of work.
What are they fucking maniacs I worked
with somehow got the guy's home phone
number and the following week he still
didn't have a job and he picked up the
phone. He's like, hello. And there was
10 of us standing around the phone,
right?
We all go, where do you, what do
you, what do you, what do you want?
Okay.
And I always pictured,
I'm slamming the phone down and then
looking up like that dude in a clockwork
work orange when he realizes the dude
who came and fucking kicked the shit out
of him and raped his wife came back.
Um, that's kind of an ugly story,
isn't it?
Okay.
You know, for, you know,
for as much as people sit there and they
talk about this cyber bullying and all
this type of shit and how fucking
horrible it is, which it is obviously,
uh, you know, I don't like how everybody
tries to act like they were a victim.
Well, I mean, weren't
you a little bit of both?
Cause I know I used to get bullied.
Jesus Christ walking up the street
looking like fucking that kid on the, uh,
the f family Griffith.
What the fuck is that?
The honey Andy Griffith. How did I
come up with the family Griffith?
Ah, my fucking brain is
mush. MMM. Yeah. People,
you immediately came walking
up the street. My fucking mind.
My hair was orange when I was growing up.
The guy didn't get the shit kicked out
of me, you know, but then, you know,
I got a little bit bigger. I
got a couple more freckles.
I got got some more confidence and I
just started picking on kids who were a
younger than I was.
So now whenever I see
those goddamn stories,
um, I just, I dunno, I,
I see both sides of it.
I just see like, yeah, you
shouldn't have fucking done that,
but I don't judge the bully
cause I did shit like that. No,
you guys didn't do shit like
that. Go Fuck Yourself. All right.
Why don't you guys, do you know what?
That's the theme of this whole podcast.
Every can go fuck themselves.