Okay.
Hey, what's going on?
It's Bill Burr and It's time for the
Monday morning podcast for Monday march
Seventh 2016 what's going on?
How are you? How was your weekend
deal? Listen to the weekend.
I can feel my face and I
with you [voice change].
Okay.
Oh, what are you doing man?
You fucking some chick on blow. You
didn't do blow when you were with her now.
Now you're with there.
Now you're doing blow.
Okay.
The boy, I can't believe that
shit came back. You know,
I thought coke was just done. You know,
after all the people did what
they did from my generation,
you would think that the next generations
would be like, you know what? Yeah,
I'm going to stay away from that shit.
Right.
It's not our works. One generation
does it. Like my generation,
we were like, wow man, let's
stay away from hey man,
like let's stay away from LSD and
heroin. Cause that's like a bad trip man.
And then we fucked with like coke and
crack crank, all of that shit, right.
That ruined all of our fucking lives.
And then the next generation was just
like, yeah, man, fuck all that stuff.
Let's fuck with crystal meth. Right?
So now this next wave was like,
fuck crystal meth. You know,
let's kick it old school.
Let's go back to the coke.
Right?
You have an entire generation of people
that not only can't feel it faces,
but yeah, evidently they like it.
Oh
yeah. Where do you go from there?
Sorry, I'm trying to update my, uh,
my musical tastes.
I've decided that after fucking 40 years
of listening to the same fucking 10
bands, you know, not 40, like 30
mean Jesus Christ. How many
fucking times can you listen to it?
I always liked those. You have those
people while walking in the circle,
the circle in the jail
at midnight express.
I remember that when they were walking
counterclockwise and then the dude is
going to escape. But you had the drugs,
you know whose girlfriend put
a tidies up against the glass?
He started walking around the
other way. Remember that? Yeah.
That's what I'm doing right now. I'm
walking around the other way and every,
my generation is just going, what are
you listening to this shit for sake,
I don't know how many
times galas a day. Hey,
I've been listening to that for
fucking 30 years. I got to get,
I've got to pull my cell phone.
Um,
I dunno. I, I just, yeah, I would like
to listen to something new. So, uh,
the lovely Nia was watching the,
all the performances from
the Grammy's last night.
So I just started downloading
everything that I was seeing,
whether I liked it or not. I'm like,
I'm just going to listen to this shit.
You know? It's Kinda like when I tried
to put a new hour of standup together,
I'm just like, ah, you know, if this
doesn't, this isn't a good idea,
but I'm going to say it anyways cause
I can't say the other shit cause that's
coming out. So I just start
throwing shit against the wall.
So this morning I was listening to, um,
I listened to a little
bit of the weekend. Dude.
Sounds just like Michael Jackson,
right? I think he does. And, uh,
who else did I download?
That girl looks like m uh,
MC search, right? The fuck's her name.
I don't know if she was singing about a
relationship and she was over it and she
just looked like she had
this high top fade, you know,
but also knew how to like
make a fucking rocket.
She looked really smart, you know, yet
like you wouldn't want to fuck with the,
I dunno, she kind of had it all
going on. It's like, is this a nerd?
Is this a bully?
Is this a rapper or is she a witch? Um,
but the band is fucking great.
So she, I don't, you know,
after all of that shit, I'm probably
not going to say who the fuck it is,
even if I figured it out. Cause I don't
want to shit on people like that. Um,
anyways, had a killer SG though,
the fucking three pickups, you know,
surfing green, they went
out, they crushed it. Right.
I actually saw what's his
face? They're the fucking, uh,
the dude who's getting
the worst tattoos ever.
He's got the Lamborghini and fucking, uh,
didn't like LNL Keyshawn Johnson
chased him up his front door.
The fuck is his name? Justin Bieber. I
actually watched that. That guy can sing.
He's fucking talented. I just
don't, he should just, just do that.
Just do that. Stop filming yourself
playing basketball and whatever else.
It still would mean McGinn
you fucking a GoPro.
Just sing your song and fucking go
home. Why? Well, why won't you do that?
It's actually a talented kid.
Although I didn't like when he threw
the acoustic guitar down in the Gund,
you know what? He fucking Pete
Townsend, you're not okay.
You got the inner ear fucking monitors.
The protecting your hearing. Okay.
You're not, you're not,
nobody's blown up a drum set and part
of the fucking drum said goes right into
your fucking ear. Okay. Nobody's getting
crushed at your fucking concerts.
They've worked all of that
out. You know? Sorry. See,
and then I go right back to the grumpy
old man. I've seen all this before.
I'm just, I'm trying to get the kid
at copy's fucking really talented.
He can actually really
sick. Um, so anyways,
and then I was looking to yell at dude
there. What the fuck's his name? I, I,
for the life of me,
I don't understand why I can't just
download shit and then just find it.
And every fucking time it
goes back to the album thing.
I like when they just list the songs.
I don't need to see the
picture of the album.
Yeah.
Every time this happens I forget how
to do it. Oh, okay. Artists songs.
There we go. Um, oh, and
speaking of which on,
um, everybody was, uh,
sending a bunch of each week when I do
the Thursday, uh, Thursday afternoon,
just before Friday, Monday
morning podcast. You know,
when we go into the greatest
hits of the Monday morning,
podcast is always a little musical
interlude. I do not pick that music.
That's Andrew thumbless and then he posts
on the Twitter site what the name of
the music is. So last week
it was snarky puppy. Okay.
That's who the fuck it was the posted
every week. Just fucking look it up.
All right. At the MM podcast or
some shit. I forget what the,
I don't know what the Twitter account
is. What am I gonna Follow Myself?
Um, anyways, plowing
ahead. So Friday night,
oh, freckles, I took a night
off from stand up. Alright.
Friday night's a big
night to take a night off.
That's like not showing up thanksgiving,
you know, if you'd like to eat,
you know. So I went down to
the Wiltern theater and uh,
with Andrew and I saw mute
math and they will fucking,
unbelievable cannot.
I tweeted, I couldn't,
I cannot overstate how great
a fucking show that was.
And I wish I remembered the
name of the opening band too.
They were all so great,
but what just killed me was I'd
never been to a show like that.
Like whatever that style of music is,
I don't even know what
the style of music is,
but I'm just going from, you know,
the Shit I've been listening
to for 30 years straight.
I,
you're walking in Bajas
Bhavin in cars, right?
I listen to say I listened to the same
90 songs for 30 fucking years in a row.
Um, never to do, be that guy. So just
go into those, seeing those bands,
just how they use guitar,
where it's more used for like mood
wear. But when I was growing up,
like the guitar was like the Dick
that got thrown on the table, right.
Just slapped you right
in the face with it.
There was always the lead singer
and then you had the guitar, God.
And then the fucking dude playing rhythm
guitar who was not appreciated until at
least 25 years into that
bands career. You know,
like Malcolm young really
didn't get his props until,
till like the mid nineties. I feel Brad
Woodford, same fucking thing. You know,
Ronnie Wood,
all of these guys just play in rhythm
guitar holding the whole fucking thing
together. Right? And they don't get
shit for the longest fucking time. Um,
the Jesus Christ mute math live man,
they fucking unreal. So by the way,
they're playing Portland,
Oregon tonight. That's Monday,
depending on when you listen to
this Tuesday, they're in Seattle,
then they're off for a week and then
they start back up again in Richmond.
If a you get a chance to see them, um,
you will not be disappointed. And
if you're an old fuck like me,
they are a great band to go see, to
try to bring you into the modern era.
You know, if you listen to this, c'mon,
you can't tell me somebody a
little bit younger than me.
You haven't been listening to
that fucking Pearl Jam record 10.
You know whether I'll give each other
the high five, the big Bro Picture.
We're all in this together, man.
Right? Um, if you can't tell me
that you haven't listened to it,
how many times do you
go to Gerald Rotary Spa?
Good. Yay. You be cool.
Ooh,
fucking 25 years later. I'm not
saying don't ever listen to it again,
right? Look, you could do
whatever the fuck you want,
but I never wanted to be that guy
going out is JJ music. All right?
Then going into my house, Bob
Ida Book Book [inaudible] right?
Going in there and doing
the fucking jitterbug
that makes said that Jeff Beck is playing
the Hollywood ball and I have to see
that guy. He's like 70.
He's buddy guy is opening up and there's
no fucking way I'm going to miss that.
Um, you know, guys, one of
the greatest, he is the guy,
you know, I think from that whole
fucking era other than Jimmy Hendricks,
I thought, yeah, I think you gotta
give it to Jeff Beck, right, Matt,
in my mind, I'm sure there's some black
guy out there that I'm forgetting.
You know,
who got stolen from bunches as far as
white dudes who listened to black dudes
and then reshaped it. Right. I think
you've got to give it to that guy.
No. Well, you know, it's
just my opinion, you know,
gotta get fucking upset by it. So anyways,
what I'm obsessed with right now as
far as like the drummer, Darren k,
the guy's fucking insane.
And it was funny because, um,
you know, Andrew got to know those guys,
so I got to go backstage and meet
him briefly. And uh, you know,
after the show they were going, hey,
did you learn anything watching our
drummer? And I was just like, no.
And I heard the drum, Darren
goes, ah, like I didn't mean it.
I hope I didn't come off and,
and Celtic way, it's like, dude,
I can't get too fucking far beyond
anything that I'm doing watching him.
It was like watching like Keith,
it was like Keith Moon playing drum and
base and then they have this sick ass
fucking light show going on. And I was
just sitting there, squinting watching,
just going like, what, what is he doing?
I had no fucking clue. Um,
I did take one video while that
while they were playing, cause I,
I I is coolest, you know,
the iPhone is and how great
the video is and everything.
I just fucking hate like
being at something and then
just sitting there filming
it, like I'm working for CBS
nightly news or some shit.
It's like I want to stand here
and I want to take this in.
There's enough other cons
here like filming this shit.
I can watch this, it will be on the
Internet forever. Right. So anyways,
this sunk clipping that they play. And um,
I had no idea what he was doing. And,
and Andrew's going
watch what he does here.
And then he literally has like two
sticks and a two drum sticks in his right
hand and he's playing, this is
going to be some drum geek shit.
So you might want to pass through this.
He's put bay as far as I can tell,
he's basically playing 60th, no
triplets, Dah, Dah, Dah, Dah, Dah, Dah.
Two to two to the three,
four right. But he's only,
he's playing like he's doing
it with two sticks in one hand.
So the one on top sit,
the top of the high hat,
the one underneath is hitting the bottom
of the high head. So up top, what?
He's really just, he's playing like every
other note of the tripled. Like dot,
dot, dot, dot, dot,
dot. Dah, Dah, Dah, Dah.
But he gets that as he's bringing that
stick up. The one underneath hits it.
So that's how he gets the
full 16th note. Right? Sorry.
I know this is really nerdy shit.
And then with his left hand,
he's basically ghosting the off beat
and then play in the backbeat on two and
four and then dragon,
I believe on the final note of a,
the triplet into one.
Okay.
That's what he's doing now. I know
that's drum nerd shit, but I'll,
I'll post the video.
It's fucking insane. Um,
so of course I went to the, you know,
went down to the studio the next
day and I tried to do it, you know,
for like 10 minutes, you know, according
in whatever you learned something,
you know,
the first thing you do is you immediately
try to play it at the same tempo is
the drum God that you saw play in it.
So it was really fucking frustrating.
I think I said, what the fuck, like
10 times. And then I just, you know,
just scrolled through my iPod, iPad,
whatever, my five phone and I'd say,
hey mom. And just started
playing in the same shit.
I've been playing two for 30 fucking
years. I don't know what my deal is.
I can't get out of it.
Okay,
thank God I buy new clothes.
You know, if you should be like,
you should be forced to wear the clothes.
If you don't move ahead artistically,
your wardrobe shouldn't either.
You should be forced to
fucking wear the same shit.
I should be wearing an acid wash jeans
with a fucking half shirt driving down
the street, my rusted out 83 Ford
Ranger. And they'd be like, listen,
if you're not going to progress with
the art of music, Yo, or whatever,
if you're going to watch the
same 10 fucking films. Um, yeah,
I had no idea how far
behind I was. Um, and so,
and I'm looking at mute math like they
haven't been fucking crushing it for 10
years.
I actually went on the Internet and I
looked him up and he like did Letterman
2005. There you go, Bill.
Wait to be on the cutting
edge. So whatever.
I feel like I took a major step forward,
but I want to thank everyone
in the band for uh, you know,
letting us come back and say hello real
quick. Uh, Darren, Paul, Roy and Todd,
you guys were fucking,
you crushed it and thank you to Andrew
for taking me down there and, uh,
pointing out what the fuck was
going on so I could, you know,
so the old man could
figure it out. But, uh,
I will definitely see those whenever I'm
in a city that they're in and I'm able
to do it. It was that good of a
fucking show. And like I said,
they're in Portland than Seattle and
they get a week off then they're in a
Richmond, so definitely check it
out. Anyways, plowing ahead here.
Um, so that was my Friday.
All right. So as a comedian,
there's no way you take a Friday,
Saturday off unless the UFC has a fucking
pay per view and it's caught on my
grandma and Holly home of fighting.
Right? So I'm like, all right,
I've got to watch. I thought
they were both title fights.
I didn't realize that corner's
fight was not a title fight.
I think most people didn't realize that
most people like me got drawn into a
sport. When there's someone like his,
you know, I go in and out of the UFC,
you know, like most shit.
I go in and out of cooking.
I go in and out of being a good
comedian. I'm just, I mean an app, right?
I'm a fucking a Gemini. I'm into it.
I'm into it. Go Fuck Yourself. Hey,
remember that shit? Then I come
back, right. Except with my music.
I just held onto it for just a
little, a little to eat. You know,
you can always get what you will. Um,
what am I talking about? Anyways,
so we have a bunch of people over,
right? We go out, I go to the grocery
store, I get a bunch, I get some booze.
I get, yeah, I get some Gaba
Goo. I get some fucking ige bio.
I get some fucking cheese
and all of that shit.
I go on and get a bunch of ice cream
sandwiches after everybody's all fucking
salted up with the Doritos and we
sit down to watch the shit and um,
what a fucking paper view
man. You know, spoiler alert,
you know, if you haven't heard yet,
I'm going to say who won me
should take beat Holly home,
you know, and Nate Diaz
be Connor McGregor.
It was fucking unreal. My, I'm in.
Anybody else hosts a UFC fight party.
How fucking satisfied
did you feel was unreal.
I had like 10 people screaming,
Oh my God. Over and over again.
Like twice in one night,
flipping the fuck out.
More screaming and yelling during that
pay per view than I've heard in any super
bowl. You know, I don't Super Bowl
party that I'd been to in a while.
Um, it was unbelievable.
But Jesus Christ once again,
why always hate when like when a comedian
is getting ready for a special ors or
a late night spot and they say that
they trained like a fighter at the,
it's so disrespectful to what the men
and women do who fight for a fucking
living. It is dead is the most bad ass.
I'm trying to think of like a more ass
job than that other than, you know,
you're one of the grunts
on the front line in a war.
Me,
your fucking job is you just train your
trading to beat the fuck out of somebody
who's training that beat the fuck out
of you when you both are professionals,
you do it for a living. A
whole crowd of people shows up.
You have ever fight after school and like
10 people showed up was fucking nerve
wracking. Fight, fight, fight.
These guys walk into a
fucking arena shirtless.
Just walk it down there and they got
to stare down some fucking maniac.
I live in there. We're on the
dove on the ground. Right.
And that just taking fucking elbows and
they had the presence of mind to look
over at the clock. Like how much more
of this shit? I had another minute,
38 of forearms to my fucking forehead.
I don't know how they take it. So, um,
yeah,
unbelievable fight.
I didn't realize that a Connor had gone
up in two way classes. Like I said,
I'm a very like novice
fan of this stuff. Um,
okay.
But Jesus Christ
fucking Nate Diaz sitting there and his
whole face is all bloody and he says,
yeah, I, you know, I got this,
I've taken your worst shot.
She can't knock me out. That's
just scar tissue. I've bled before.
I don't know. I don't know how the fuck
you do that. He was bleeding so much.
It looked like both of them
were bleeding to death cause he,
once he got up against McGregor, whether
it was all over both of them, um,
I dunno,
I really don't have anything to say other
than I was blown away by both fucking
fights and um,
okay.
You know, as hard as it is to what
I was was to watch Conor lose.
Cause I mean the guy's
a fucking superstar.
I'm talking shit and
then backing it up. Um,
okay.
It was, you know, watching Nate
do is choking a fucking, I was,
I was fucking unreal.
I don't, I don't know.
I don't know enough about this sport
to talk about it intelligently,
but I will say this,
I hate when someone like Connor
loses and then everybody, yeah,
you fucking pussy say all that
shit on the Internet. You know,
go on Twitter and start
trashing the guy. You know,
I want to talk to people right now. If
you are one of those people that do,
how do you, how do you, like,
how do you do something like that and
like look yourself in the mirror when you
go to brush your teeth at
night, you know, no one,
you haven't had a fight
since like the seventh grade.
You know the fuck is wrong with you.
And if you already talked
all that fucking shit,
that's what it made it
great selling the fight.
I don't know
how great was that fucking life you
just knocked out. Caught him. Oh,
choke dot Connor McGregor. How does
it feel if he grabs it? Mike goes,
I'm not surprised, motherfucker.
Of course,
I don't know about you guys,
but that's one of the fucking coolest
things I've ever seen to fucking choke out
someone who's good is. But Gregor,
they'd stand up all fucking bloody
and just walk around flexing,
not even wiping the blood off, not
concerned about how fucked up your faces.
You don't give a fuck, right. Whatever.
Jesus Christ. The second I got a
little scratch, I would have just, Oh,
I got him. I got me.
Um,
that was great to see me.
Uh, Misha went to, but I,
I as as a fellow fair skin
person, I felt bad for Holly home.
You know,
just to second we start getting beat on
just [inaudible] our face just gets so
fucking red and then our
yellow eyebrows stand out.
I just thought there was a lot
of mean Shit said about her. Uh,
when it came to that, I, I just
really related to it by the way.
What the fuck happened in Nate's,
the side of his face and his neck,
those scratches. How did that happen?
Like somebody took like a
fucking, okay, you got some,
somebody took a knife down the
side of his face and his neck.
He's just sitting there
pawn at it. I, that's,
I've gotten scratched like that
every time somebody's like, exhale.
Just the wind of that made me
go into the fetal position. Um,
but anyways, you know, it's great
as that UFC pay per view was,
it's what just makes me so fucking
sad about what has happened to boxing.
If they could somehow, if all the pieces,
shit promoters in boxing could just unify
and become one piece of shit promoter,
you know, promotional entity
like the UFC is right.
Cause you know, you know you not that
the 11 if you, if you're, if you're,
if you're wearing any
level of show business,
you know the promoters are fucking over
the ex, you know, they are in an, in,
in UFC, it's the fighters,
you know, I know in some,
I don't know anything about it,
but I don't sell some of it.
They are getting fucked and because
they're a complete monopoly,
I'm sure they're fucking with their money.
I'm sure there's a pressure to make
people fight and that type of shit,
which is why they try to break
up monopolies. Having said that,
it's fucking great for the fence because
kids stook the fact that the fighters
have no other options. It's
just the best fight, the best.
Um,
and like last night, like I haven't
had that kind of excitement,
like watching like a boxing pay per view,
like consistently the way the UFC is
consistently exciting like that since I
would say the middleweight division. Um,
yeah,
in the early eighties when you
had Roberto Duran, Tommy Hearns,
Marvelous Marvin Hagler
and sugar ray Leonard,
I'm all fighting each other.
They all fought each other.
They fought each other numerous
fucking times. It was incredible.
Um,
I guess when Mike Tyson came along,
but that was just more the spectacle
of how quick was he going to just knock
these people.
Um, I dunno.
Just seeing a paper view like that and
then seeing that it took fucking 10 years
for the Mayweather Pacquiao fight and
then one of them shows up and he's fucking
hurt and doesn't say anything. He doesn't
say anything and you're still out.
60 bucks is just fucking
brutal. So anyways, um,
hats off to that fucking paper view.
Jesus Christ actually watched
some McGregor fight again.
Um,
I'm fucking believable.
Okay.
I was just looking at
the blood. I'm going,
he's just going to keep fucking punching
him right in that I just keep punching
them right in that fucking eye.
Like who did that to that guy with
the fucking yellow hair bleached hair.
Was it fucking, what
the fuck was his name?
Okay.
GSP. I can't even moon that fucking names.
He just kept punching the dude in
the eye over and over and over.
And then it was always,
I thought that that's what my Greg was
going to do is to keep punching Nate in
that fucking, I added
some. How you doing it?
I fuck you. Sit there with I'm
done. Fucking done. You scratch me.
I am done. Keep fighting. All right.
I just keep saying the
same thing over again.
I was blown away by it and a respect to
everybody who fought there. Um, anyways,
uh, you know, it's weird to is
McGregor is still the champion.
I didn't know that. I thought it, I
thought I just assumed to feel lost.
That's it, right? You're not a champ
anymore, but you don't have the belt.
You're always a champ. Right.
How do I get out of this?
I don't know anything about this
sport. All right, let me, uh,
let me get to the advertising that
always saves me. Where the fuck is it?
Okay,
I forgot six. There it is. There it. Oh,
here we go. But up, up, up the IDs me,
undies, drying up. You fucking
Twat. [inaudible] B and A's is dry.
Don't say that. It's not, um,
beyond days whether you're
wearing a suit or sweats,
you spend almost 24 hours
a day and yet underwear.
But instead of making a statement like
Superman's tights under his everyday
clothes, your, your underwear
is probably boring me.
UNDIES is here to change that. They're
going to give you exciting underwear.
Introducing male panties. Um,
please include the following.
It's pronounced modal.
I don't know how many times I have to
mispronounce this before it gets some
decent copy. All right. It's all
written in lower case. M. O. H.
Dash D. A. L. It doesn't tell me
which one to say to fucking stress.
It's either modal
or muddle.
I was like, no accent is that good.
Every pair of me undies is made
from sustainable sourced modal,
modal of fabric. That's
twice as soft as cotton.
Nothing can describe the fit
and feel of me undies. Oh,
when they get up against your balls,
a smile just comes across your
face like the Grinch on Christmas.
But once you try them on, you're going
to understand while they're called,
why they are called the world's
most comfortable underwear.
Who calls them that? Why me undies does.
Then I called the world.
They're called by you.
You came up with that in the
fucking advertising room.
That's like when Michael Jackson
just called himself the king of Pop.
I'm the King of Pop. No.
Are you twinkle toes?
What else are you you a little teapot.
And if you don't love your first
pair of me undies, they're free.
No questions asked me.
UNDIES has dozens of styles and limited
edition prints to help you make a
statement with your underwear. Whether
you can see them or not. Remember,
remember superman? Some, I think there
was a joke in there and I blew it.
Shipping and free in the U S and Canada
and you could save up to $8 a pair of
the Mi on DC with the [inaudible]
subscription pan. Get planned,
get the subscription or a single pair.
Get 20% off your first order.
When you go to [inaudible] dot com
slash bar what do mean subscription?
What do you have a new pair
of underwear every month?
It's like Columbia records and
tapes. Uh, that me. That's me.
only.com/burger for 20%
off your first order.
Miyagi's dot com slash bar Oh,
here we go. Dollar Shave Club.
Everybody do. You got a lot
of stubble on your face.
You are Harry broad. Do you want to shave?
You taught there is his birthday coming
up and you want to be all smooth?
Well why don't you take
out jog to cabbies,
easy shave butter and put it on you
pussy. You guys have figured out.
I discovered the key to an amazing shave.
Evidentaly it's simple. That's the,
that's exactly what dollar
shave club.com does and why?
Evidently I'm a proud member.
Like millions of others.
They allege dollar shave club.com delivers
amazing razors right to my door for a
third of the price of what the greedy
razor corporations charge and they make
you go to the store.
Those blue blooded cunts,
both my wallet and face
finally gets some release.
Joining Dollar Shave club.com means you
can afford to shave with a fresh blade
anytime you want, which feels
fantastic. It's like new money, right?
You throw it in the fireplace
because you don't know any better.
And for the smoothest shave ever,
usually a fresh dollar shave club
blade with their doctor cabbies.
Easy shade.
It's not your average
shave cream. Everybody.
This is high quality ingredients
that make your skin feel soft,
smooth and moisturized.
Your blade will just glide
gently across your skin.
If you want the most amazing shapes
possible, take it from me or no,
take it from me. Take it from your
friends. You know, take a shit,
do whatever you want to do.
Use a fresh Dr Shade Dollar Shave Club
Blade with Dr Cavies. Easy shave butter.
Two reasons to join dollar
shave club.com/bird today.
That's dollar shave club.
Dot. Good comm slash bar,
dollar shave club.com/burger.
And finally, lastly, I know
I got two more. All right,
so I'll take a break here. Jesus Christ,
we've got three more or we got
to get over the hump here, right?
MVMT watches movement.
Watches was started by
Michael Victor. Michael Tango.
You know what that reminds me? Is that
then that new Tina fame movie, whiskey,
tango, Foxtrot. Is that the,
is that not the worst advertised
movie you've ever fucking seen?
It just says whiskey, tango, Foxtrot.
She stayed in this squinting into
the sun holding a notepad and there's
something on fire behind her.
That's it. That's all I get.
You know, you can't hook her up with
a little fucking descrip description.
Yeah,
I don't know. Maybe I'm old.
Maybe that, maybe that's,
that's the way the kids like it. They
don't want it. They don't want what it is.
Says it wasn't it called as
a slug line or some shit.
Right?
I don't know.
Obviously it's right next to another
fucking billboard and there's like a like
three Japanese looking dudes
holding shogun warrior swords.
And I know what that's about. I
know roughly where it takes place.
You can't just squint into the sun
holding the notepad. You know, it's like,
is she an Arizona?
Okay.
Is Her RV on fire in the
Grand Canyon? Is she in Iraq?
I don't know. Maybe that's
what they're supposed to do.
Like I'm supposed to peak my interest
in. I'm supposed to go on the internet,
but if someone like me who doesn't
know how to look up Shit, you know,
or starts to look something up and sees
a picture of something else and then
clicks on that and then two hours
later goes, wait a minute. It wasn't,
I gotta look something up and you
can't fucking remember what it was.
I'm just saying, I think she's earned
a PR. I think she earned, you know,
a little more respect in that. Right.
Okay.
Dog. She hasn't made fucking
millions and box office.
Can you fucking help her out
with maybe half a sentence?
[inaudible]
alright. MVMT watches everybody.
Movement watches was started by two
college dropouts with the idea to make
quality watches that don't break the bank.
Starting at just $95 this and sold online.
They cut out all the
bullshit retail markup,
supposedly movements sent some watches
over here. Question Mark. Yeah,
they did. Why don't I just
get this generic copy?
Oh, okay.
I'm going to go a little Kanye West
right now and have a fucking hissy fit.
I mean, what? Why can't, why
can't they fucking, you know,
supposedly moving. Why don't
you send some over here? Yeah,
they did and I already talked about
it. Why would you put that in the copy?
You know, I'm going to read it. I'm
like Ron Burgundy. I'm run Berg.
D quality materials and sleek
designs. The perfect everyday watch.
It's easy order online
today for free shipping.
Free returns and a 24 month warranty.
That's pretty good, Huh? $95.
Watch with the two year warranty.
Join the movement and say no to big brand
retail markups and say saying yes to
great style. Check out MV amped delay
mean say no to big brand retail.
If you could afford a Rolex, you wouldn't
go fucking do it. Of course you would.
All right. It's called a spade
a spade. Here, you want a Rolex,
you can't afford one, but you don't
have some piece of shit. This, this,
this is where you're at in life
for $95 dollar fucking watch.
That's going to look like an $800
watch. Okay? We've all been there.
God dammit. Go to MV. M
T fucking watches.com.
There's no fucking in there slash bar
and you get 15% off your entire purchase.
That's MVMT watches.com/burr.
All right. Jesus Christ.
Hey, you know what it did last
night? It rained here in California.
It never rains in California,
but books don't. They
bought the pause man.
It Pauls. Sorry. Um, I was
sleeping upstairs last night.
Um, oh fucking Joey
Rose's swung by the house.
We had a couple of cocktails,
right? And then he went home.
Ubered it like the hipster that he
is over to his hipster neighborhood,
you know, there's fucking
is jugs on or whatever the kids were
wearing nowadays. And uh, I don't know. I,
the only time I snore
is when I fucking booze.
So I wasn't gonna do that
to the lovely Nia soya.
I crashed upstairs and, um,
it started thundering
and lightning at night.
And what's fucking hilarious about living
out here slash terrifying is it never
rains. So when you hear thunder,
you automatically think it's a fucking
earthquake, but your bed isn't moving.
So you kinda like, well,
wait a minute, am I,
I've never heard an earthquake
that I couldn't feel.
And you've got to like do the
math when you half asleep going,
is that like an earthquake? And you know,
in the valley and I can't fucking hear
it. I can hear it, but I can't feel it.
That, that doesn't make any sense. And
then you find, oh my God, that's thunder.
Holy Shit. It's fucking raining out.
Right. What does that in French,
you polit you Plu, I can't fucking
remember. I suck at that shit.
If ned it is snowing. Um,
anyways, they'll starts fucking
rating. And uh, it's tremendous.
It's rained a bunch. It's an El Nino year.
Thank Christ. And, uh, but what else?
Always the depressing thing in the back
of my head is as green and as lush as
the hills. Look right now. Um,
this is like basically the only rain
we're going to get for the next fucking
three years. And I know every country
out here is taking long showers now,
going hey to folk and
droughts over, you know,
I just hope, ah, I dunno.
I hope it fucking rained.
Keeps raining as much as it
possibly fucking cans or it can,
or there's a massive goddamn
plague out here. One of the other,
something's got to give. Right.
That's depressing isn't all right,
let's get into 'em. Oh No, wait, I
was gonna tell you another thing.
So yesterday I was just driving around,
hanging out with my wife and uh,
they got a bunch of open houses
out here so they can't fuck it.
Let's go look at some houses, you know,
get some ideas for our old ass kitchen.
See what a real kitchen
looks like, right? And, um,
I gotta tell you haven't bought this
house and gone through all this shit that
I've gone through. I look at
houses entirely different.
I'm immediately looking at the windows.
Do they have the old ass
original windows? Um,
and I immediately want to go downstairs
if there's a crawl space, anything.
I want to go down there
and I'm smelling for water.
And you can't really do that a lot out
here because then it doesn't rain enough.
But I immediately look
underneath the fucking house.
I look right up it's fucking
skirt, like the home pervert. I am.
And I'm immediately looking
for, all right, let's see.
What does the electrical work look look
like? You know, is it galvanized pipe?
What kind of Shit Hole? You know,
look at how stuff is put together.
Does this look like it had
a permit or not? And um,
you know, all the sexy shit goes away.
Like we have a pool and I'm just
looking at it going like, Eh, it's okay.
And it looks like a piece of shit to
me that looks like you need to Redo the
whole floor of that fucking thing and so
got dump out all the fucking water and
evidently you can't fill your pool
up with water anymore out here.
You have to fly the fucking
water in. So fuck that pool.
I haven't got it in the house. Shit.
You know? Oh, there's a classic.
They're saying it's a two car
garage, but it is if you drive,
if you drive two model t Fords, but
if you have any sort of modern car,
you're not going to be able to get
the all you can get to in there,
but nobody can get out of the cars.
So I was just a negative Nelly and I
actually realized that my house isn't as
bad as I thought it was.
Now that I've fucking dumped every
fucking dime that I have into it, I'm
not made me feel good. I was just
walking in the kitchen. I'm like,
there's no prep space
here. All this disco shit.
I don't see any place where I could
fucking slice an English muffin.
You know what? Fuck this
kitchen. Fuck the pool.
Fuck the kitchen and fuck this galvanized
pipe. Oh, oh look at this. Oh Wow.
Rugs, rugs in every room. Yeah. Take
your shoes off. Why is that? Yeah,
cause the floors haven't been refinished
in fucking 80 years. Fuck these floors.
Let's go upstairs. Oh Great. I see
this used to be an attic. Oh yeah.
You calling that an office? Yeah. Yeah.
I like how you shown it
during the wintertime because
I know it happens in the
summertime. It fucking
heats up up here. Right.
You can grow a fucking goddamn bullshit
Bushel of fucking marijuana up here.
Be fucking three hours.
Fuck this office. Right.
You want to sign up on our mailing list
now I don't put your cell and piece of
shit houses. And then that, that
said I walked and I was done.
And of course I upset my wife
cause all I did was just, sorry,
I accidentally just shut off the
fucking recorder. I actually,
I upset my wife because, you know,
she's like, I like, you know,
I thought we could just have fun and
I understand why you have to go in the
house and be rude to the real estate
people saying I don't like those people.
You know, cause they'd,
they don't encourage you to
sell your house, you know,
air quote for a fucking profits and then
you can buy back into the same market
and then everything you just made
on your house, you got to buy it.
You got to spend again just
to get the same fucking house.
I actually said that to the guy. I think
that that's made my wife mad and I go,
yeah, the only people making money
out here are you in the banks.
And the guy's like, well no, that's
not necessarily true. Do the math.
Tell me how that works.
Okay.
Can we get you on the
mailing list? Um, all right,
let's leave some fucking questions here.
Questions here for the Goddamn Week.
Kiska Kiska say mall
something, right? What is, what
does, I don't fucking know.
[inaudible]
I'm just never going to get it.
You know what, I don't, I just,
there's no reason for me to speak it.
All right, let's, let's plow ahead here.
All right. Um, the March 3rd podcast,
fucking brilliant podcast yesterday,
March, March 3rd, 2016. Thank you.
One of the very breasts and I've
heard hundreds of your podcast.
Nobody drowns in their own vomit
anymore. Great Brain, dude.
Thank you Greg and hamburger. Let me
know if you're coming over here. Well,
that's not a fucking
question. That's just a con.
Yeah, but you don't compliment this
questions. That's it. Well, thank you.
I'm going to be doing Germany
hopefully towards the end of the year.
I'm definitely getting over
there. All right. Um, okay.
Guy who invented the invented email
died.
He said Uncle Freddy died.
Uncle Freddy. Hey Bill,
I'm sending you an email about the
guy who invented email dying today.
This is my way of honoring what he did.
I imagine he'll get very little
press because Nancy just say no.
Reagan died this weekend too.
Here's an article from an is an excerpt
from an article a about him Internet
Hall of Famer re Tom Wilson has died.
Tom Wilson was the man who basically
invented email as we know it today,
including making the choice to use
the at sign in an email address.
He was 74 years old. Tomlinson,
I think I said his name wrong,
the first time. Tomlinson invented email.
A system where a user on one network
could send a message to someone on the
another network in 1971 oh they
left some of it out of their
Thomaston invented a network. I mean,
I'm going to read it the way I see it.
Tomlinson or Tom Wilson, however,
I feel like reading
Tomlinson invented email,
a system where a user on one network
could send a message to someone on another
network while the government,
advertisers and hackers could all
read your private information.
This was invented in 1971 had Tomlinson
had any idea what people were going to
do with his invention. What do you have
made it? What do you have invented it?
And the answer is, of
course he would have.
How else was he going to
get some pussy? All right.
This was his slug like, Hey,
can you meet my fucking friend Tomlinson
over here? I don't want to meet,
and he invented email. Oh my God. Hey you
can I touch your peepee? Um,
that's actually really interesting.
There's Internet Hall of famers
now you have to look that up.
Who's in the Internet Hall of fame?
Jesus Christ. I want to see images too.
I want to see what the fuck these
people look like. Internet Hall of fame.
Here we go. Come on, man.
Internet Hall of fame homepage. Holy Shit.
2014 hall of fame inductees. I didn't
know this. This is fucking awesome.
Internet Hall of fame. Paul
vixy, internet piracy. Well,
let me see the list inductees. All
right, here we go. Here's a list.
Here's a list of who.
Who is it? All right.
Here's some of the pioneers. Look at
these fucking eggheads. Jesus Christ.
Wow. Wow.
Oh my God. I, if I could do
a fucking screenshot of this,
I got to put the link up here. My God.
What is it about being
super smart and just,
I guess everybody gets one gift. I'll
tell these people. This is a rough one.
You know, there's a lot of fucking lonely
prom nights on this page. All right,
Douglas Engelbart and he's as good
looking as that fucking name all he looks
like a sweet old man. Let's see what this
Guy Douggie Jesus Christ, he's
got the old man face in 1963 Dr.
Angle Bard founded the augmentation
research center lab at SRS.
How do you tell a woman that that's
your dream and she's not going to glaze
over. Tried doing that while that.
Fuck it. Ah, Cathy and I. Thanks. Wait,
I'm with you.
I said I want to start the
augmentation research center lab.
Where are you going? Um,
where he pioneered a system for augmenting
human intellect in which workers
sitting at display workstations could
collaborate on solutions to humanity's
problems through a vast
online information space.
That didn't matter that no
one ever fucking uses it.
Look at this guy. He fucking
the, see, this is what all these,
these guys are off and
all these men and women,
their heart's in the right fucking place.
And then these fucking
lunatics in these corporations,
these sociopath's get their fucking
manicured fingers on these things.
All right, Susan Astrada, you could tell
she was a looker back in the day. God,
I bet all these guys fucking jerked off
to her when she came around the fucking
augmentation lab. Susan here yet. Um,
that's probably why she's, this is
probably the woman, why they're there.
She was this,
this woman here was probably
the inspiration for the
fucking a virtual reality
sex suit that they're trying
to work on as strata founded.
C E r f Surf Net,
one of the original regional IP networks
in 1988 surf net serves the academic
and commercial communities in California.
I still don't even know what it is.
As an executive director,
she took the initial national science
foundation funding two point $8 million
and grew the network from 25
sites to hundreds of sites.
I don't know what it does. All right,
let's, let's look at this. Look.
Dennis Jennings.
This guy looks like a fucking NFL ref
from 1958 as the first program director
for networking at the u s
National Science Foundation.
Dr. Jennings was responsible for the
design and the development of NSF net
program.
Yeah.
No way he did that. I have no idea
what any these fucking people did.
Come on man. Let's trying to
find somebody. Looks like, okay,
this guy's not a bad looking
guy. Oh yes he is. He isn't.
He's got a full head of hair, but you
can just see he's a spazz. You know,
he's one of those guys seem sort of
cool until he starts laughing and
I'm all right. Eric Bina
being a co-created with
fellow Internet Hall of Famer,
Mark Andreessen,
the first version of the mosaic web
browser in 1993 I think I've kind of know
what that is. Alright. You know what
and with that, and I'm fucking bored.
Just like the chicks walking away
from these people at the bar. Um,
okay.
Internet Hall of Famer. Well, you know
what moment of silence for Ray Tomlinson,
his heart was in the right place.
Who knew that pedophiles
would use his invention
to send pictures and shit. All right.
From Scotland, dear Billy, big dicks.
I've had been,
I've been working flat out in work back
in Scotland and now taking a three week
vacation in the u s I'm 27 years old
and I've never been across the pond,
so this is a big deal for me.
Well, welcome a chance to see you
nutcases up close and
personal. I'm Planning Vegas,
Death Valley and Grand Canyon to see some
outdoor epicness then onto Chicago to
see the Blackhawks wipe the
floor with the flyers. Wow, man,
that sounds like a great trip.
Then Patty's Day. Oh boy. Um,
then New York City to
pop my wheat cherry. Um,
to a first time timer in the u s what
would be your top three things to do?
I would really appreciate the
advice. Alaska. Fuck yourself.
You're big Nancy boy. Okay.
The three things I would do. Well,
I mean you're kind of doing three,
you're doing some amazing shit, right?
Defi if I was coming to America,
what would I do? Oh Dude, I live here.
I don't know what the fuck to do.
That's like, you know,
you never know what the touristy
shit is to do in your [inaudible].
You take your own place, you take it for
granted. Like when I lived in New York,
I never went to this. I went to
the Statue of Liberty once I went,
when my grandmother visited, you
know, I didn't do any of that shit.
I was just trying to get
to work. Um, all right.
If I had to pick three cities,
I would do shit. Only three.
All right. You gotta go to
New York. I would say Chicago,
but you get enough New York with Chicago.
I would see San Francisco and then
you'd have to do something down south.
Um, you know, just to get, I don't know,
you'd get both coasts and then you get
down south and all of those are their own
fucking worlds. What would I do?
I don't want no black Cox
game is fucking great. Um,
dude, you know what? You stumped
me. I don't know what I would do.
I would go to New York like you're going
to do and I would fucking do as much
shit as I can. You can't miss
there. That was a nice vague answer.
Um, the fuck would you do
okay?
I Dunno. I live here.
I don't know what the fuck would I do if
I went to Scotland. Go ahead, give me,
Give me Your Mushy pee ideas.
I guess I would, I would go to,
I would go to a rugby game.
I think you know something.
If you're going somewhere,
you have way more ideas than
the person who's living there.
I can't believe I can't think of
anything to do. I, I, you know what?
I go to a fucking steak
house. You know what?
I would definitely indulge in the
fucking cuisine over here. There we go.
I'm getting my footing here. All
right. You go into a hockey game.
I'd go to a sporting event.
Any sort of fucking basketball,
anything you can see if you can go
see the fucking golden state warriors.
They one of the best regular
season records of all time.
If you can take it a fucking show.
Go see new mass for fuck sakes. Um,
okay.
I Dunno what I would do, dude.
I'd go down south, right?
I go to a fucking gun range. Do
something like that you want,
this is what you want to do. You
want to do some metropolitan shit,
you wanna do some sports shit and then
you gotta do some [inaudible] backwards
shit. That's what I would do. You know,
go find somebody drinking some moonshine
out of a fucking jar, a mason jar,
and then, you know,
have him fucking smoke a God damn pork
shoulder and go out and shoot his guns.
There you go. Ride some
four wheelers. You know,
do something like that.
I don't know. You know,
a lot of people sleep on like
Wyoming, Montana, the Dakotas.
Those can all be fun to go see.
I don't consider you guys live in
that little ass country, you know?
I Dunno dude.
I've ran a fucking classic American car
and we now went from fucking New York
too. A Chicago. I would drive that
and I wouldn't take the highways.
I try to find some old route and I'd
stop off at greasy spoons when you go.
There we go. Jesus. Oh, there's a
couple of ideas. I'm sorry dude.
I really fucked you over
on that one. Butter.
I don't know.
That's like when somebody,
you remember back in the day
when you actually shopped,
you know you bought cds and stuff.
I used to have all these cds I'd want
to buy and then when I would walk into
virgin I could never remember what
the fuck I wanted. I'm sorry man.
I really dropped the ball on that one.
Alright. To a first timer in the year.
That's not it. A podcast got me
in trouble with fiancee's family.
Uh, hey, they are
billary Berm Clinton. Um,
I fucked up man.
As you can probably guess
from the subject line Q, The
[inaudible]. Um, as a little background,
I'm getting married next month to my
fiance who was wonderful love of my life
and all that. We were visiting her family
last night and playing board games,
which we often do. Oh, Jesus. Oh,
what happened? We had drank in.
Did you get competitive? Huh?
She accused her mom of cheating.
Uh, he goes, I'll spare you the details,
but we were playing a card game
with a bunch of characters.
Everyone gets the same people,
but when you use them is
really the key to the game.
There was a particularly powerful card I
had held onto until the very last stage
of the game. The character's
name was granny Wada,
um,
pronounced Gary water.
I gave you the pronunciation and accent
so you wouldn't fuck it up. Well,
it is spelled w, a t, a granny a.
It's the last round of the game and
everyone's going around revealing their
card. I was last and my
plan had worked perfectly.
As I went to reveal it,
my inner bill Byrd took over and I really
got excited. I flipped it over. Oh,
you did it? He goes, oh,
no. Oh No. He goes, I said,
it's granny fucking.
Then when you drop the f pub, Oh my God,
I wish I had podcast tee
shirts. I'd send one to you. No,
you did. He goes, silence followed
as it echoed through the house.
My fiance's family were stunned.
They're not super uptight.
People, but people just don't,
just don't throw fucks around
during a board game. You know,
from there it only got worse. My
fiance is listen to your podcast,
so she knows I was imitating you.
She tried to stammer out
an explanation all no,
she had to explain away your behavior.
Ah, dude.
He goes, but it didn't really do anything.
I also tried to apologize sheepishly.
Then on top of that,
that move gave me enough points
to win the game over everyone.
So I had to awkwardly mark my
score, which made me the winner.
Wow, dude.
Oh, and you're getting married next month,
so the fucking taste of this is still
going to be in their mouth. He goes,
we left almost immediately after,
and of course I get yelled at all
the way home. I knew I deserved it,
so I didn't even put up much of a fight.
That's your first good move in
this story. Oh Wow. He goes,
my question is,
do I try and go out of my way to remedy
the situation or do I just hope everyone
forgets about it and moves on?
We're getting married in six weeks.
So it's not like I can
avoid them for very long.
I'm pissed because I fucking
crushed the impression to
thanks and go fuck yourself. So for the
Hillary Clinton reference in the opener,
I think she's a cunt to, uh, I
don't think she's a contract.
I just don't think she's an honest person.
And I don't think just because of
the fact that we've never had a woman
president that that's reason enough to
elect someone is dishonest and as phony
as her. Um, anyways, though,
you know what? I would,
I would actually, uh, without your wife.
I would just drive over there and
just say, listen, I gotta apologize.
I listened to this podcast.
I'm a big fan of the guy. Um,
I was making a joke and in the moment
I didn't realize that you guys didn't
listen to the podcast if you want.
And just kept a cue up a
clip where you have it,
which might be a bad thing to do,
but like just have me like
saying something else,
Dr Covey's easy shave butter, but any
might be fuck cause I don't say fuck.
MMM. [inaudible]
just say, just tell him you're
really embarrassed or whatever.
I think if you went over there
by yourself, I think, uh,
especially her dad, cause I
think that's the big one there.
I think there's this something
extra when it's, you know,
okay.
It's always extra. You know, when,
when you're getting married like a,
you know, if you're a
guy, you know, the, the,
the dad's going to be looking at your
twice as hard. And the moms who make, oh,
he's, no, it's relax. You know.
And then the other way around is if you
know they have a son and he brings a
woman around,
like the mother's going to be fucking
looking at her to see if she's a fucking,
you know, an evil little whore. You know,
the dad's going to be looking at you like,
is this guy going to be overbearing
and slap my fucking daughter or right.
Or whatever. You know what I mean? Is he
a piece of shit? Right. Um, oh my God,
dude. Wow.
You said it's granny fucking water.
Oh God. Dude, if you film that, oh my God.
Okay.
Jesus Christ. Dude, I got
to give you, I got it.
My tip of the cap for you there,
man, for doing that. Holy Shit.
I'm getting uncomfortable just thinking
about that. Well, can I, I'll apologize.
Can I apologize to your fiance
for being a bad fucking, uh,
a bad, um, influence? Hey, you know what?
Play this to play this to your year,
your future in-laws, dear future
in-laws. Hello, I'm Bill Barr.
I'm the one who says, granny.
I say this type of stuff. I've been
the bad influence. Don't be mad at him.
I'm sure he's a wonderful human
being. I'm sorry I missed up.
He messed up you a little
kid game there. Um, yeah,
he's got to make a great son-in-law. You
know why? Cause he uses doctor cabbies.
Easy shade. Don't play that to them.
That's not going to get you into anything.
Let's gonna say he listens to morons.
He must be a moron. Are they going
to have half a moron kid? All right.
Not eating birthday cake.
Huge fan of the podcast is a 27 year
old who works in a stereotypical white
collar suburban office.
I thoroughly enjoy.
Listen to you by your biweekly
rants at my desk. Wonderful man. Uh,
speaking of which I work in the corporate
offices have a sales and distribution
company that has about 50 employees,
but only about 15 people work
in my specific office location,
which means that about once every
motherfucking month we gather in the big
conference room and do the cliche
awkward office Happy Birthday Song.
Oh No. With candles and cake
routine and all of that.
What I am by, no me. Okay. Well,
I am by no means a health nut.
I also try very hard to take care of
my body during the workday by eating
properly and drinking lots of water.
I've also gotten really into
bike racing over the past years,
which has taught me a lot about the
importance of nutrition, et cetera. Uh,
so the thought of eating a giant piece
of chocolate cake at two 30 in the
afternoon when my eyes are pre practically
bleeding from staring at a computer
screen all day would do nothing but
make me feel like absolute shit.
And I really have no
interest. Very smart. Uh,
this is why for the past couple of years
I've politely turned down every piece
of birthday cake that has been offered
to me at these affirmation ceremonies.
Unfortunately, I am the
only one of my coworkers,
most of whom are women who has
adopted this no cake philosophy.
So every single time I stick,
I stick out like a sore thumb after I
declined the piece that is passed to me.
At which point I have to deal with this
wave of passive aggression from these
ladies regarding my decision to
abstain from the sacred ritual.
I also share a birthday
with one of my coworkers,
so I am spared some of the awkwardness
that goes along with refusing cake on my
own birthday, but still made
out to be some kind of monster.
Okay, Jesus going on and on here.
While I have no intention of succumbing
to the peer pressure brought forth by my
colleagues,
this might be the best written fucking
letter I've ever had on the podcast.
Is it possible that I'm being rude
by not sharing in the celebration?
What's more is that even if I found out
people did that I was being douchey by
not eating cake, I still wouldn't
give a shit what they think.
Does this make me a
sociopath? No, it doesn't.
It makes you somebody who knows what he
wants and everybody else's, you know,
you just, you just get,
you know what you need.
You just get a little space here,
couple of little verbal, you know,
you know, you know the great ones create
space and all, you know, football,
hockey, basketball. You don't
have to do that baseball.
But you know what I mean? The
great ones create space. Okay?
So what you have to do is you have to
tap into your greatness and you have to
create space. Okay? And
just say, look, people,
it's not that I'm not happy
that it's your birthday.
I just don't want to
become a lard ass. I mean,
I'm not being a dick here,
but you know a lot of you,
I'm not going to say who over the years
your slacks just keep getting bigger
because you keep eating all
this fucking cake. All right?
You blowing out your bodies and
I'm not going to be a part of it.
And a part of me dies every time
I watch you guys eat this shit.
But if that's what you want to do,
by all means go ahead and do it.
But I'm not going to become a fucking
cow like most of you guys are.
Okay.
Yeah, no, I mean happy. You should
have bells around your fucking necks.
All right. There you go. You
just right. We're right there.
They'll never ask you for cake again.
You probably want to get invited,
you know?
Yeah.
That's what fucking, uh, that's what
Sidney Crosby would dope. Right?
Okay.
Mario Lemieux the great ones,
they create space. No, dude,
you're not a sociopath, right? You're
doing the right thing. You know,
I dunno. I don't know why women like
sweet so much. You know, I actually,
I like sweets. I'm just
a big fruit basket. Um,
I actually like sweets, but when
I stay away from it for awhile,
if you really abstain from
fucking desserts and everything,
if you walk into a place that
has a bunch of crazy desserts,
it doesn't even look like, like
edible for human consumption.
You know what I mean? It looks, I
always said it looks like clown food.
You know what I mean? I got clown sneezed,
especially if it's really like a lot of
like fruits and fucking whipped cream
and all of that shit just like
this. It looks ridiculous.
It's all these crazy colors,
greens. And purples, right?
You're doing the right thing.
There's all, I'm saying,
you're doing the right thing. You
know, you're into bike racing,
you're working out, you
know, this is the deal.
Do you actually got a chance of bag and
bag in one of those fucking cake Eaton
brides at you in your
section? Because they,
they're going to see like a half of
them are probably just testing you.
The other half are fucking probably
codependent fucking cake eaters and they
feel guilty, you know? And they
know that after they eat that,
then that sugar is going to be in their
veins and then they're going to go back
to their desk and they're gonna start
eating a handful of fucking cheddar
flavored goldfish to
shoving them down. You know?
I bet if you walked around your little
section and you have your cubicles and
you looked at their keyboards, I bet
they're keyboards are greasy, Huh?
I bet there's crumbs in them. I don't
know. You know what I think? Yeah.
I think you too. Good to work
there. What do think about that?
That's what I got out of that
fucking letter. All right.
There's your podcast for this week. I
want to thank everybody for listening.
Did I read all the, I had to do all
the fucking advertising. God Damn it.
Bill said, ain't running your fucking
mouth. What do I got next aisle?
Trunk Club. Everybody
Trunk Club. All right.
Don't waste a second of the new year
in a crowded mall with trunk club.
You can make 2016 your most stylish
here yet and he never have to go to the
Goddamn Mall. You don't have
to do any work yourself.
Someone else is going to do it for you.
You know it's like you're rich and
you have your own fucking stylists.
It's going to be a game
changer. You get a fresh start.
You start the year off on the
right foot and the right pants,
the right jacket or the right
panty lawns and a mental right
Momento is blown a over
the right shirt she needs.
A trunk club is here to handle your
wardrobe so you can focus on what matters,
what matters, how it going out
there and getting yourself a slice,
a fucking pie. Please include
all of the following points.
Trunk Club takes the hassle man out of
shopping by finding the best clothes for
your style,
you're going to look like a million
bucks@trunkclub.com slash [inaudible] all
you do is Angeles. Answer some
simple questions about your style,
your preferences size, and you're
assigned an expert stylist.
All right? Then you styles goes out and
just picks from the best premium band.
They sent a trunk of that Shit over here.
You keep what you like and send back
what you don't in the prepaid trunk.
They take out all the fucking middleman
from all the bullshit and a, yeah,
for some reason the copy keeps going
on and on. You get what's goes on.
All right. Where do you go?
Take advantage. He'd go to trunk
club.com/bar trunk club.com/bar Hey,
trunk club.com/bar oh by the way,
it's a brand new year, a trunk club.
We'll send you the stuff for free, right?
Shipping's free both ways. Go there,
get some clothes sent to your
house. You like it, keep it.
You don't send it back in the fucking
trunk. Can't make it any easier than that.
All right. stamps.com do you like going
to the post office while have fun?
Fucko cause everybody else is doing
stamps.com trips to the post office.
They never convenient.
So why not get postage right from your
desk with stamps.com stamps.com even
gives you special postage
discounts you can get at the posts.
You like that one needy. Fuck yeah.
Uh, including. Okay.
Use using your own computer and printer.
You can buy and print official US
postage for any letter or package.
Then just hand it to your mailman,
your mail man or your mail
lady or drop it in the mailbox.
That said easy.
No wonder over 500,000 small businesses
are already using stamps.com I use
stamps.com whenever I whore myself
out, sending out my posters.
I'm a moron if I can figure it out.
So can you right now you can sign up
for stamps.com and use my last name,
Barb B. U. R. R for this special offer,
four week trial plus $110 bonus offer
that includes postage and a digital
[inaudible] scale. Don't wait. Don't
wait. Get started with stamps.com today.
Don't go to [inaudible]. Go to
stamps.com before you do anything else,
click on the
microphone@thetopofthehomepageandtypeinbarburorthatstamps.com
and
Burton.
Hey,
yeah. Hey, there's this guy at work.
Work, work, work, work, work.
Oh, you know what? I'm trying
to listen to motto music.
That one I can't listen to. She
sounds like she got roofied.
[inaudible] [inaudible] um,
okay.
She's one of those people.
You have to watch her doing the song
cause she so beautifully like all right,
I can deal with this, but I'm,
when it's just their voice,
like you'd break up with the road
with the phone. What? Rianna yeah,
she called me up and be like, yeah,
we have to break up, up, up, up.
Sorry. All right, shut up.
Don't judge me. I'm an hour in.
I'm out of jokes. That's why.
So this guy works at this fucking office
and he's got into cycling and working
out and nutrition and that type of thing.
So there's like 15 people in his
little area of the office. So he goes,
that means about at least once a
month he has to go down to the fucking
cafeteria and sing happy birthday to
somebody and then they're passing around
birthday cakes. So he always says
he doesn't want the birthday cake.
And then they're like, uh oh you
would fuck a girl eating cake.
You gotta eat it too or will
feel guilty. Yeah. And he's like,
am I some sociopath that
I don't give a shit?
Should I stick to my guns
or should I just have cake?
Oh stick that you gotta stick to your
guns and you should tell people that
you're on a diet. Cause people were
like, oh that's great. Yeah. You know,
cause I had been really trying to lose
weight too. I mean obviously not today.
And you know, they don't
say that as they're about
ready to eat a piece of cake.
What do you mean you can't
go into a crack house?
And tell everybody that you got sober
and the crack heads are going to be like,
ah, that's great.
Well, I mean you can still urray but
you can still say no. None for me.
I'm trying to, yeah,
watch my weight and when they come back,
no, just have one piece. Then you go,
hey
fatty. Yes. I said no does
I know I'm really can.
I've been doing really well this
last month and I'm really, you know,
I really feel good and I'm just, you know,
just now don't put a
fucking peer pressure.
Office offices are the worst for that
type of shit. When I worked in the office,
yeah, it was always someone's
birthday. Someone's always like,
I made brownies over the weekend and
I just like can have them at my house
anymore. You guys eat them and it's, it's,
it's hard cause everyone's just eating.
You're sitting in a fucking
cubicle all day. You're
word is shit. It's probably the
vending machine. I asked your question,
is it true that that bit bitches be
eaten when they're at the office?
Why? Why? Why all
bitches be eating the oil and the
female bitches all be eaten? Why? Why,
why bitches be eating? Why
bitches be eaten? I don't know.
BB Office
environments are so hard to be
on a diet with cause it's, yeah,
it's like food constantly cause it's
so fucking boring to sit there all day.
You just eat, eat, eat, eat.
So no say no to the cake.
All right, one last quick one. All right,
so I got to, speaking of that, this,
this fatty cakes need to take her ass
to the gym. So he looked good to me.
Thank you. But starting today,
since I'm going to my
reunion starting today,
why can't you get in shape
from me? Um, I mean I'm,
yeah. S W
why are you, first of all, don't try to
be like that. Hijack my health goals.
It's not about you. Okay.
About me. I had, you had spent in
there for a second. All right. You did.
How do I help this guy out?
Help this guy out. All right,
so we started backtracking
here in the podcast. All right.
I'm just going to paraphrase this.
A, the podcast got me in trouble.
This dude's getting married in six
weeks. He's over his don't read it.
Just listen to me. I know I
heard you talking about it,
but what did he say really loudly.
He, so they playing a card game. Yeah.
He has the, the Trump card that's
going to fucking beat everybody. Right.
And um, the name of it is,
is granny water w a d eight.
So when he plays at epes Alaska,
he slammed it down and nobody
listens to the police parents,
his future in laws do not
listen to the podcast.
And he just slammed it down and
he goes, I gotta, I gotta read it.
He goes, it's
granny fucking war.
And it was just silence followed
as it echoed through the house.
My fiance and family were stunned.
This, not super uptight people,
but people just don't throw fucks around
during a board game, you know? Yeah.
It only got worse is his
fiance tried to be, oh,
he listens to the podcast and just, yeah.
And she yelled at him the whole way.
What you're doing to people, getting them
in trouble with their future in laws.
I think you owe that young man apology.
I did apologize and I apologize.
I made him a little fucking audio thing
that he could play the to is a in-laws.
Oh, is it filled with you saying
fuck over and over again? Well,
I had to know if that was going to help,
but I had to do it in a way
that they like, you know?
So what a bad influence on, oh, it's
just a silly awkward moment. It's fine.
Everyone will get over it. That's okay.
It's funny story though. All right,
so what are you doing at the gym today?
Back in tries, nods like that today,
which I'm not looking forward to women
always be doing the legs. Okay, I'm done.
Why women be doing their legs? Yes.
Oh for fuck sakes. Jesus,
you spilled the watts lead
glasses of water on the floor.
I tell you this all the fucking time.
You're always leaving glasses of water
on the floor and this is what happened.
How many times would we do you not go for
a glass of water because you put it on
the floor? How many times
are you done? Are you done? Yes, I'm done.
Can you say sorry for
spilling the water in here?
I'm sorry for spilling your water,
but also, no, there's no bugs.
There's no buts in a, sorry.
You read the, sorry. You're not,
I'm sorry. I spilled the one.
That's the podcast. Everybody,
I'll see you on Thursday.