Hey,
what's going on it's Bill Bird and his
time for the Monday morning podcast for
Monday, May 9th, 2016 what's going on?
How you go in there? Fuckos um,
oh, freckles laying on his back
trying to get rid of the cyanic.
It's much better.
Cyanic
oh,
cyanic a lot of people don't know that
was the original lyrics to Panama.
You know, David Lee
wanted to say, you know,
Sciatica and Eddie wanted to, and Alex
wanted Panama and Michael Anthony,
he's like, come on guys know, except
he said it in a much higher voice.
Can we fucking just get along here?
And David ended up giving it to
the brothers and that's what it,
next thing you know, he was on
his own room, just a Gigolo.
So, um, yeah, my back's doing,
uh, it's doing much better.
Slowly but surely I've,
I've kind of found out it's going to
sort of work itself out if I just don't
have to sit on my fucking ass from
here to Jacksonville every other week.
But that's the life that I live.
You know,
this is the weirdest injury ever. Usually
if you're fucked up, sitting down,
you know, and resting is
a good thing. This thing,
I just got to kind of get a lay down.
I'm a mess. I'm taking that
fucking Ibuprofen. I don't
even, what the fuck it is?
Some anti inflammatory thing.
I'm stretching like a fucking NHL goalie,
trying to get everything all fucking
on done down there. But I don't know.
I don't know what's going on. I don't
know. But it is a, it is getting better.
But I um,
I flew all the way back today
from a Jacksonville, uh,
had a great time. And by the
way, here's, here's some, uh,
here's some advice for you when you're
out on the road and you're going to get a
breakfast.
All right?
Unless you're in some mom and pop place
and he could see over the counter,
you can watch them making your food, which
I don't necessarily really like to do.
If you're going to order eggs,
don't ever order scrambled eggs.
I know what you're thinking. Why,
Bill? Why, why wouldn't you do that?
Cause they got a giant fucking VAT
that they've made scrambled eggs or the
fucking oatmeal of eggs. When
you go to restaurants, it's just,
it's like the trailer Zonea it's just
that as you're fucking, you know,
is your fucking eggs.
Especially like this morning,
the place where I went to Jacksonville,
he aided the Chili's restaurant in
Jacksonville, Florida. I know you guys.
You're jealous, right? Oh my
God. He gets to see everything.
So me and Forrest Shah who
murdered it all week, um,
we ordered the,
the whatever,
the American breakfast or something there
and your only option on the eggs was
scrambled. Okay. Now if
that's the fucking case,
that means they got a giant
VAT that was probably made,
I don't know how long ago,
whatever the health code violation
is plus five minutes, you know,
it's been sitting. So you get the
rubber fucking eggs and then bacon,
they just make a bunch of fucking bacon.
They got that sit to the side, you know,
and then they had their bullshit
hash browns, which, you know,
it was already all the whole
fucking thing was already made.
The only thing that really tasted
good was the biscuit. So, um,
if you ever at the airport,
you know,
or if you're going down to the hotel
lobby for their continental breakfast,
um, you always never order scrambled
eggs or the eggs over easy,
get an Omelet, you know, um,
do something like that where they just
aren't going to just have this shit
already made. Um, or you could
do the gross shit with the syrup,
but that's going to fuck your
whole day up. I feel, I mean,
not like I didn't order
a big salty breakfast,
but for some reason as salty breakfasts,
as bad as it is,
I can continue to function.
But if you get a waffle or pancakes of
French toast to that Shit, you know,
you might as well just have somebody
put you in a fucking sleeper hold co's
cause you're going down and you
go down early. Um, so anyway,
just a little travel tip for you there.
Um,
so anyways, you know, all this
past week, uh, the lovely Nia,
my beautiful wife was away and I was
telling you how immaculate I was keeping
this place fucking immaculate.
All right?
And um,
I literally like,
there was no trash in any of the barrels.
All the fucking pillows were all poofed
up look like it looks like a show room.
The living room, right. I made
the fucking bed, you know,
it was spotless. I wiped down my
side of the fucking sink, you know,
brush my teeth and all that shit spotless.
Okay.
I got a car washed and waxed, filled
it up with gas, all of that shit.
Everything was done. Went through
all the bills, got the junk mail,
all the bullshit, the
recycling, fucking everything.
I did everything right. So I'm thinking
she's gonna come home, you know,
cause I was leaving and
right as I was leaving,
she was coming home so he would
just missing each other. Right.
So I was thinking when she came
home she was going to be like,
like, Oh man, you know what? I might
have to bring her in for this shit.
You know what, I'm going to have to bring
her in for this. Hang on one second.
Hold on one second. All right. All right.
So I'm back here. So anyways, let me
keep setting this up. So my whole thing,
Nia,
was that when you came home,
this place was going to be absolutely
spotless. So you'd be like, oh my God,
that's so nice.
And then also you wouldn't feel like
I was just hopeless SAP without you.
Cause that always bugs me. Like
when women go like take, take,
did they fall apart without
us? Like I'm like, I've
never said that about you,
nor have I ever thought that I've
never come home after being away.
And the place has been in shambles
because you don't know what to do. Oh.
So I don't know why. Nothing. No.
But You keep holding on to some idea of,
of something that [inaudible] song
was talking to them like manspreading
well I keep, I gotta be on
the fucking couch. Um, no,
I don't know what you're so concerned
about that for like the place has never
been disgusting or gross
after I have gone away.
So I don't know why you have this
big hangup about, you know, I don't,
I don't get it. You know what? No, I don't
either. Well, I'm trying to think. We,
you fucking will actually let me work
through my shit. No. Okay. Sorry.
What jerk you're telling this
story and then you're out law.
So any adult, because I'm told what
happened. So I'm fucking waiting.
I'm on the road on the road again,
and I'm in fucking Hollywood, Florida,
right? And all I'm thinking is, oh,
the text message I'm going to get.
Oh, it looks so great. It's so wonderful
to come home to a nice clean house.
It looks like a fucking show room.
And what do I get?
I get a fucking videotape from you.
She's in the pantry now. Evidently
something went bad in the pantry. Okay.
Something didn't go bad in the pantry is
just some shit that's going down in the
pantry. There's some shit going down
to the pantry. So here's the deal.
I'm fucking on in the pantry.
Um, I'm here by myself.
I'm writing on the fucking show every
night until seven o'clock at night,
I'd come home, my brain is fried, I come
home, I order a pizza, I pour a scotch,
I eat,
and then I stare at the wall.
I go to bed and I get right back up and
we stare at the next draft in the next
script. That's been my life. So
I didn't in defense of me. Okay.
The one fucking place I didn't go into,
so there was the pantry.
Let's stop saying,
I don't like that word.
I just realized Pantry pantry stuff saying
I don't play Shit. It just, it's uh,
I don't know.
It's too close to panties in this food
and I don't like when food and sex are
combined. Okay. Now I know you
don't like that you pantry here. Oh,
that nine and a half weeks when it's
fucking her with all the groceries on her
was like either eat or fuck,
not together,
you know. So anyways, um,
so she sends me this
video, she's like, Bebe,
how did you not see this?
Right.
It just starts fucking giving me all this
shit. I'm like, what the fuck? All right.
And she pans up to the top of the fucking
ceiling and there was, what was it?
There's the larvae. Larvae.
Little, yeah, little moths. Modal.
What? Go. It's an inside joke.
Oh, go ahead. And inside with who?
With the fucking people
listening to when I,
no. Yeah, there's sort of larvae.
There's, there's mods and stuff.
Because some,
like if there's flour that's been
opened and it's not sealed up properly,
or grains or cereal,
they'll create little mom's like
if you have fruit out for too long,
it'll make fruit flies. So that was
what was happening. Fruit flies.
It attracts them. No, it
creates them from that.
I was just talking the Terminex guy
about it. They just, they, I don't know.
Flies come from apples. Listened. Yeah.
Like if you have fruit and stuff out to
[inaudible] and then fucking nine months
later you get a fruit fly. You're like,
there's no warm in there that's making
it happen. No, that's not what I mean.
It's not a fruit having sex. She said,
well, if that's what you're saying,
you're saying the constant. I'm
saying, I listened. I don't know.
I'm not a fucking term next person.
But he was telling me
that when it's dirty mobs,
fuck on those apples out in the orchard
now and they plant their seed in there
and then it comes out like alien. Okay,
bill, there's not any fruit in the pantry.
Okay, so we have, we have grains and he's
just staring at your crush right now.
It's so comfortable though.
My lower back is so comfortable right now.
Oh, you know what, I figured out a thing
to get for you for that. But anyway,
we'll get back to that.
But if you have grains and cereals out
exposed and like this little closed
environment where it gets warm,
it produces these larvae and
little flies and mobs and shit.
So that's what the guy just told me.
He's not saying it right.
Well how are you saying it?
Are you saying?
I'm saying please tell me how you explain
things and how clear it is when you
explain things.
What I would say is like,
you know if you're having a
cookout and you leave food out,
all of a sudden flies or an ant show up,
but they don't come from the food.
That's what he told me. I'll
be, you keep saying they,
they come in from the apples
and it's confusing me.
You said it came from animals.
I said nothing about
ample line. This one up
though from apples. I would
never say it came from you.
The start throwing apples into the mix.
I was trying to explain to you
about grains and shit. You're right.
Maybe I was saying it's like
fruit flies suck in school.
I can't even hear what you're
saying because you don't listen.
That's why you got damn add.
You don't listen.
You don't listen and you start saying
things and you said them and then you
distribute them to the other person.
Like it's so confusing to talk to you
sometimes because you don't live it so
fucking hard.
It is hard.
How about we were just
watching the Simpsons and you
watch the entire episode in
midway through it. You were like, why
is that happened hanging? I'm like,
where did the blue snake,
like a major plot point that hadn't
been explained not even five minutes
earlier, but you don't pay
attention to, how about this?
How about my fucking back is out and I
was in Jacksonville, Florida this morning.
How about that? What does that have to do
with anything that we're talking about?
Well, maybe I'm a little fucking, you
know, not focusing on a fucking cartoon.
Okay.
You're
such a baby when you traveled
to whenever you travel,
you fucking for like one day like,
oh my God, I do know how you do this.
And then it goes right out your
fucking head. And then the next,
next time I coming back off the
road, you look, oh, let's go. Well,
you know Susie Fricker sees having a
fucking who hot down the fucking street.
You want to go to that? When
I say no, you flip out at me.
I don't know what you're talking about.
Should do you know exactly when you know
who she is to see the frigging, oh yeah,
he's that bright thing.
All right, so whatever.
So she comes home and evidently there's
some sort of bug horror movie and you
know how, what infestation infestation
and you know how the ladies react.
They don't like insects.
You know what I mean?
They don't like insects the way men don't
like cats hate those fucking things.
There's nothing better than a cool cat.
I like a cool cat that chills and
lays in the fucking sun. Yeah.
You know I liked their own new prison
up on you. Yeah, I don't like that. I'm,
when they're practicing
killing it like that,
you just look over and they're staring
at you from the corner now than they stop
and try and play it off. I
don't like, I don't like that.
They stand on your chest in the morning,
waking you up.
I don't like this shit in a box
and then you got to pick it up.
It's just too much. It's too
much. Cleo. Shit's just outside.
But we still got to pick it
up. I know, but I don't have
to. It's not in the house.
I mean, if you're going to shit
in the house, go in the toilet.
I think some people can train their cats
to shit in the toilet. I don't know how,
but, well, I can tell you how they can't
communicate with other human beings.
So they put all their energy into yeah,
like they, they got like that gift.
They have like a like uh,
Asperger's,
Asperger's with cat, some sort of, um,
what's that thing that always talking
about nowadays? Autism, autism,
autistic with people, but okay.
They can communicate with cats.
What the play an instrument
to front up with.
No one in his diagnosis of the
mental illnesses. It's just,
they'll just stop right there,
please.
He's talking about when are you going
to get angry tweets. I'm not marking,
marking any of that.
I'm making fun of people that put,
you can't fucking say anything anymore.
Everybody gets all worried. Oh, I know.
I do benefits for all of those things.
All of those things I know about
my free fucking time. All in black.
Oh Jesus Christ.
I remember when things were
funny. Oh, it was so simple.
Back in the day where you get was you
could just say shingles and one every
fucking jerk off. Didn't have some way
they can just spout about fucking annoyed.
They are,
but everything else is fine as long
as it doesn't come around to my world.
Can I just ask what this situation
is here with the Ziploc bag?
What about it and how you're
keeping your equipment stored? Yeah.
Bill's got this cord and the little foamy
part that you put on the windscreen,
the wind screen and a couple of batteries
and an old zip lock bag that's ripped
and just doesn't even zip anymore.
Right.
So I'm just wondering why
basically because it's still
holds the things and if I
just throw that thing out,
another one's going to break and then
that thing right there is probably going
to end up on the nose of a porpoise
and it's not gonna be able to eat.
It's going to die because everything
ends up in the ocean. Yeah. You know,
they say that put letter in its place.
It's like the second eldest shit that you
throw out the saying you don't pollute.
We all pollute. It's just some of us
do take this on the road with you.
It's not like I was having
an idea that good. I mean,
well I take that on the road that you're
just going to be like babbling about
something that you don't really
know about us at all. I mean,
I don't really flip the chart anything.
Uh,
so you take this on the
road with you? Yes. Alright.
Well as I could maybe get you
a nice, never had a problem
leather Satchel. Really?
You got a skin of fucking
cow because I already,
I already have one that'll last longer
than putting it in this ridiculous thing
that's never going to biodegrade.
What's this bad think and
that they won't biodegrade.
Other thing will be here somewhere in
the dirt somewhere hundreds of fucking
years after we're gone saying you can
have a nice way to carry your things that
doesn't look like you know the bags
that we used to use for sandwiches.
What is your fascination
with just like buying shit?
What do you mean fascination with buying
ships session? I mean, look at this,
look at this,
that you're carrying this thing and I
really wish you guys could see the Ziploc
bag right now. It's, it's a mess.
A man of your stature should not be
carrying around your podcast equipment and
an oil as well. What did you say? Ziploc
bag. A man of my stature. Fuck it.
Two seconds ago I was a fucking
moron. But now, now cause you
to shave from naenae.
So what do you like tonight?
Who We got
Saint Louis Blues meet me in St Louis.
Louis v versus to the Dallas Stars.
Formerly the Minnesota North Stars.
Are these hockey teams? Yes they are. Oh,
if they're not like the kings or
the a Bruins, I don't really know.
Oh yeah. What are your feelings
about the kings and the Bruins? Well,
if it came down to it, I would be a
Bruins fan because I'm from Boston.
So you just say no, you're going to root
for yeah, but the other, the rest of them,
I don't know. Those are my two. What do
you like? I like boltings but I just,
I started pulling for the blues because
the blues had been in the league since
1964. Who's kidding? Who cause the Bruins
didn't make the playoffs. So I was like,
all right,
I got to pick somebody and I'm not
going to jump on the Black Cox and Kings
bandwagon because they were always in it.
So I'm going to for sworn under dog.
And I was like,
well the blues,
they've been around since 1967
so the Minnesota north stars,
but the people in Dallas
haven't been rooting that long,
but I really liked the players and
shit. I like, I like Dallas but I, I've,
I've ever been written for um,
a babbling open.
You're looking a little
bit. Yeah. St Louis. They're
relaxed. They're going to be a,
a kings game that we can go to
cause I really enjoy going to that.
Those two kings games we went to. Yeah.
That they got bounced out. That done.
What do you mean bounced out there? Uh,
they got beat by the San Jose Sharks. Oh,
so they're not in it. It's
over. It's over for them.
The Stanley Cup playoffs. There you go.
They got, they lost in the first round.
What about the breweries? We didn't
make it. We were, oh well then I don't,
we overt, well we, it
sheaves throughout the year because at
least as far as I was concerned about
guided we'll do,
fuck am I going,
I mean with the players that we
had and every that we got rid of,
I thought we were just gonna be trying
to figure out who the fuck everybody was
for half the season. And then
maybe, you know, I dunno.
What about the Toronto Blue Jays and
what happened was we will going to be
making the playoffs and
everybody's all bunched together.
We look at fucking third seat.
Then we'd had a west coast trip and
we got to fucking asses kicked and a,
it all went away and a flyer and
red wings fans talk shit about,
you know how high he didn't
make the playoffs and they
both got the right there.
Fred in the first fucking
round. So I enjoyed that. Okay,
well that's Ronald [inaudible]
Blue Jays. Is that a, is that a
hockey team? Nope, that's baseball.
Oh the Toronto Maple leafs.
The amount of the maple leafs got the
first pick in the draft of the raptors.
Are they have a hockey team?
Nope. Where they basketball team.
Oh Jesus keeps, keeps saying this
shit. You know. And then I'll do you,
you pick something else that I don't know
anything about. We'll see who's more.
Right. Um, what do you went
to that you know about?
Did I just say that as a question?
What are you going to let you know about?
I don't know. Fashion. Okay, go ahead. Um,
oh Jesus. What's the name of the
guy who makes fun of fat people?
He used to be fat.
Ah.
Is that, that's, that's not Alexander
Wang is it? No. Is it Michael Richards?
Is it Michael?
A Michael Kors?
No, he's German. Is it Paul Mitchell.
And he is the head of a very,
very like the most famous
fashion house in the world.
It's not for Saatchi cause
he got shot by that guy. Yes.
No, it's not the Chanel cause that
was a chick and she's dead. Right.
But she has an apartment in Paris that
you can go into if you're skinny enough.
Right. But you're, you're closed.
You're getting there. I Chanel is right.
Chanel's the right fashion house.
A person who you're talking about is that
the cad creative director for Chanel?
He looks like a war criminal. Right?
He's chairman. I'll say you go
and why were they war criminals?
Because they lost,
we would had just as many people going
to fucking Nuremberg. We really would've.
Okay. Dresden, Karl Lagerfeld. Ah, fuck.
I remember when we saw him and the last
time we were embarrassed in the cab and
I started freaking out because I saw Carl
walking down the street in Paris and I
thought he was a cool looking dude,
man.
He's a vampire looking through vampire
war from old queen looking dude.
Yeah, pretty much. That's him.
Name is sports team. Go ahead.
Um, I'll name one of you. Tell me what
it is. They are the yellow jackets.
Somebody but did not make that up.
Yellow check.
I feel like that was a high school. I
feel like that was a fucking fusion band.
Um, what about no, no.
It wasn't like wake forest or something
that's a college basketball team or some
, some sort of jackets. Uh,
the Grizzlies Grizzlies to rotten.
No,
Michigan at some place cold that
would have grizzly bears. Right.
So it's not going to be a southern
Julian good guests. But they moved.
They were initially
initially embed. Oh, okay.
It's a Midwestern kind of thing.
They were initially in Vancouver and
then they went to another in Memphis. Oh,
that says the Memphis grades.
And for some dumb reason they kept the
name kind of like when the New Orleans
jazz moved to Utah,
the widest fucking place ever taught jazz.
Like you'll never see any
jazz or hear any jazz in Utah?
I wouldn't think so.
No Jazz Clubs and Utah.
It's like the New Orleans Mormons,
New Orleans Morgan. I like
that name better. All right,
well we enjoyed you hear neo. Oh, I'm
done. I don't know. Your phone's ringing.
Oh God. Oh look at us. I know.
I get a call her back.
Um, are you done with me?
Are you wrapping up the podcast?
Did you answer questions? No,
but you can come back for that.
I actually kind of tired,
so I think I'm going to leave oh down.
Nice reversal.
I kicked you off and then you're
like, no, let me come back.
And then you tell me to go fuck
myself. You know what? I I enjoy that.
I respect that. So I just came on to
tell the larvae, larvae and then leaving
and get out of here so I can straighten
out my legs and fucking give my,
I feel like Kennedy right now.
Are you even able to do a podcast
in the upright position anymore? Um,
this is why I married you with.
This is the type of compassion
that I've come to expect from you.
You're such a fucking baby. I, I tough
my way through all of this shit. I never,
I never see doctors. I don't take
medicine. That's cause you're dumb.
You're dumb. Well, it's because I grew
up so people don't go to the hospital.
They don't go to doctors. They will
take medicine. No, you're dumb.
We have advances in our society,
but I'm tougher than you.
You're a baby. So fine. Be Tough. All
you want, but like be smart and tough.
Go to the doctor if you're so tough.
Go to the doctor and hear what they
have to stay after school special. Yeah,
I will.
I'm getting their beats stuff by going
to the doctor and hearing what they have
to say. That's real toughness. That's real
talk. That's real socks on. All right.
I'm out of here.
Nini out.
I'm sorry I had to ah,
I enjoyed when you come out.
I like miss you baby. Huh? Don't say Huh?
You heard me listen, I went out. You know.
You know why I don't go to fucking
doctors and all that shit. Why?
Because doctors, they practiced
medicine. They practice on you.
They don't have shit down.
And one of the,
one of the things that they still
don't know a lot about this,
but it's not like they don't
mean it like they're practicing.
Like you sit in here practicing drums,
you know,
that's not the same thing they went
to medical school. I understand that.
So why are you like taking that word?
So literally,
have you ever seen Lars Ulrich
played life and he practices,
he fucks up all the time with
Metallica. Oh my God, Nia.
I'm telling you,
if that's what it means,
you practice medicine and then
you learn off other people.
Just look how much better
hair plugs have gotten.
Look how much better they get
in with the fucking, you know,
cutting part of your eye out
and then you can see better.
You told me you were going to go to a
doctor to figure out what was happening
with your leg. Okay. So I know, I know,
I know you think you know what it is,
but can you please go to a doctor?
And so it doesn't become a chronic
issue. And then when you're, you know,
50 which is, can I, can I finish?
Can I finish Kathy? You're going
to have some sort of handle on it.
He had one of the things that they
know the least about is the back. Okay.
And I'm just, I'm just not going to
just go to a fucking chiropractor.
I'm going to find somebody you know
who has a good reputation of not just
fucking opening people up like a fire.
It isn't fine cause I wasn't done talking.
You always jump in because
you're suggesting that I
just want you to go to some
random ass clinic. I was just
joking around. I was joking around.
I'm holding you to this because
you said you were going to do it.
So are you going to do it?
Um,
I don't know. Film pretty good.
I don't like going like this.
I don't like going to the doctor the way.
I'd only go into the fucking mall.
I just,
the whole idea going over there and
parking and just the whole fucking thing.
I know. I need to fill the shower. Make
sure you show up 15 minutes before.
Oh yeah. Y'All be there. See that? I know,
but once it's done, it's done. And you
need all my first show in Hollywood,
Florida. There was a couple
of ladies in the front row.
Uh, we'll asking if you were there
because they needed relationship advice.
Oh yeah. You know, they were like,
how come we don't have boyfriends?
No, they didn't say this.
That's what they said.
Someone actually wrote me and asked me
about you proposing and actually that's
what I
wanted to do.
I wanted to talk about this email I got.
Should we do it today or
should we do it though?
Fuck his writing you and how
the fuck are they writing you?
Because they read Mike because of
my website, tender headed films.com.
So they were writing me because remember
I was going to do a podcast all those
years ago and then I just
never did it. Um, no,
they wrote this whole thing about how did
you get a guy who was so anti marriage
to propose and all that kind of stuff
and how did it happen? And did I propose?
No, I did not propose. But he'll
propose to me. Uh, and all that stuff.
It was interesting. I didn't
read, I didn't, excuse me.
I wore him down. No, no. See this
is why we have to talk about it.
Cause that's some bullshit. Oh
wait, even put that out there joke.
Where you fucking down.
You love me. You missed me.
You told your Lar Bay story. Now,
the one thing about Showpad is,
is you leave them wanting more to
get your fucking cute ass outta here.
All right, goodbye. I want to
talk about that story though.
I want to answer things in
life. Bait it. Goodbye. Hit the road jack.
Don't you come back? No,
no, no, no. Hit the road.
Deni yeah,
so that's what I came up to.
She fucking shows me this big goddamn
thing about all the fucking, I mean,
granted them as much
as I'm going to bitch.
It was a bunch of fucking larvae.
I swear to God.
She says that comes from apples in flowers
and flower and flower being left out
in grains. What up? You know, if you
agree with her, you can go fuck yourself.
How about that? All right, let's read a
little advertising here for this week,
shall we? Oh my goodness.
MVMT watches, you know,
it's been a few weeks now.
Um,
since they started advertising movement,
watches boxes and Oh my God,
what the f,
I don't even understand this copy.
As promised,
the quality of these watches are there
for an awesome price in the style
department.
The compliments that you'll get wearing
these things are really unbelievable.
You know what I'm doing?
I gotta start this over again.
This is what I'm doing is they keep
fucking having me say that I cracked open
these boxes and I'm fucking where in one
right now and I'm not sort of fucks up
all the copy. All right. I
will read what you write,
but I'm not going to start lying saying
I have on your fucking underwear.
Your watch is when I don't listen these.
All right, let me start over again.
So they don't hear that
part cause they don't,
they don't wanna listen that fuck apart.
They just listened to the read.
All right?
Unless one of you cuts rats me out on
Twitter like the fucking j Edgar Hoover's,
everybody's acting like nowadays.
All right. MVMT watches.
If you haven't had a chance to experience
how a movement watch fits around your
wrist,
well God dammit.
This is your chance movement
watches start at just 95
seat when movement cut out the middle
man with huge big brand markups,
the price of a stylist watch finally
got affordable. Imagine that.
Or Watch with department store quality
for a fraction of the price movement has
grown organically purely
by supporters like you.
So join there more than 1 million social
media followers and get a movement
watch today. Uh, please
spell out MVMT. Okay,
go to MVMT Michael Victor, Michael, Tom
watches.com/burr and they'll give you
15% off your entire purchase purchase.
That's MVMT, watches.com/burr. All right.
Helux or helix.
What is it about buying a mattress
that leaves you feeling violated?
This, that's not a good word
to use with a mattress. Um,
is it the pushy salespeople,
the fake presidents' Day
sales or the fact you know,
you'll regret what you bought.
Um,
as you do the walk of shame out of the
mattress store cause you get violated.
Well, what kind of sex offender is
selling you? Your sheets Hallux. He looks,
those days are over.
Thanks to helix sleep well,
you can buy a mattress online customized
for you for hundreds of dollars instead
of thousands. Go to helix, sleep.com.
Answer a few simple questions and Helen's
creates your custom sleep profile to
build you the perfect mattress.
The result,
our customers report a 30%
improvement in overall sleep.
Your mattress will arrive at your door
in about a week and shipping is always
100% fee.
Um,
you'll have 100 nights to try
it out and if you don't love it,
they'll pick it up for free and you'll
get 100% refund. That's pretty cool, Huh?
That's almost three months. So over
three months, no questions asked.
It's like it never happened. Uh, if
you do like the new helix mattress,
keep it and your dignity.
That's why everyone from Gq magazine
to Forbes are all talking about Helen's
sleep. Go to helix, sleep.com/burr
and get $50 off your order.
That's helic sleep.com/burr.
Hey,
he looks sleep.com/ [inaudible] one
of those pronunciations is right.
All right. Dollar Shave
club, everybody, all my God.
Look who's back.
Dollar Shave Club,
dollar shave club.com as a special
offer for new members who join today,
you'll get a free month of the executive
razor when you buy a tube of Dr
Carver's shave butter. I swear to
God, it used to be easy shave butter.
Um, this is the first time they've ever
done something like this and once you try
dollar shave club.com, you'll become a
proud member like millions of others.
One reason is because they deliver amazing
rate as razors right to your door for
a third of the price of what the
greedy razor corporations charge.
That means when you
joined dollar Shave Club,
you can afford to shave with a
fresh blade anytime you want,
which feels fantastic.
You'll get a first class shave when you
use the executive blade hurting your
wallet.
Another reason is that Dr Kvcc shape
by using it with the executive razor,
the blade just glides gently
for the smoothest shave ever.
Dr Carver's shave butter isn't
your average shave cream.
It's a unique conditioning formula
with high quality natural ingredients,
leading your skin, feeling unbelievably
smooth and soft, and right now,
new members who buy a tube of shea butter,
get the executive razor for absolutely
free. They've never done this before.
Take advantage of it or you'll regret it
for the rest of your life and it's only
available by going to doctors.
Dollar Shave club.com/burr that's
dollar shave club.com/bar and lastly,
but certainly not leastly
are old friends@stamps.com
as America celebrates the
national small business week this week,
stamps.com wants to honor not only,
it's over 600,000 small
business customers.
stamps.com also wants to
extend an invitation to every
small business throughout
the nation to help their business succeed
by reducing or eliminating wasteful
trips to the post office.
stamps.com knows that one of your most
valuable resources as a small business is
time.
You can't waste it making constant
goddamn trips down to the post office for
mailing and shipping.
That's why stamps.com brings all of the
services of the post office right to
your desk. Buy and print official US
postage for any letter, any package,
any glass of mail using your computer
and printer over 600,000 small businesses
are already using stamps.com and
you know what you should too.
I use stamps.com anytime of sent on any
stupid posters or whatever bullshit I'm
trying to sell after my shows if I can
figure it out. So can you right now,
you sign up for stamps.com and use my
last name, birth for this special offer,
four week trial plus a $110 bonus offer
that includes postage and a digital
scale. Don't wait. Go to stamps.com
before you do anything else, click on the
microphone@thetopofthehomepageandtypeinbirththatstamps.com
enter
bar. Ah
Right.
And with that it's over.
Come on, come on now. Delete.
Close the window and onto
the rest of the bullshit. Um,
I had the worst fucking keeps a good guy,
but I had a bad cab driver on the
way back from the fucking airport.
Use One of those.
I'm one of those people that can't
keep a consistent speed, you know,
so you make your car sick.
And what was hilarious was he was driving
a Prius and the way he was driving
this thing, I would be surprised
if he was getting eight gallons,
eight miles per gallon.
He just kept doing that.
Eh,
just stomp and glide. Um, I,
I just amaze me some people like how they
cannot hear, you can't hear the engine,
you know, he can't hear the fucking
rpms going through the roof.
You don't understand that is wasting fuel.
I know.
You know how bad those
cabbies get fucked over.
You think that he would be
concerned about something?
You think if you drove
for a fucking living,
you'd have an understanding
of how fucking works.
MMM.
It was so fucking annoying.
It actually,
it just kind of just became funny and
he was a really nice guy. But, um,
I know some people like, it's almost like,
it's like the driving with a fake foot,
you know, or a mechanical foot like
the prototype and it, you know,
it's either on or off. There's no, um,
consistency of speed. This guy,
he just kept going up to like 65,
70 miles an hour and then glide
back down to like, you know, 52.
Of course I'm looking at my fucking
phone, so I'm starting to get six. Yeah.
You know, it was, it was
a shit show and absolute,
yeah.
Fucking shit show. Oh, you know,
when I went to Florida, by the way,
I landed in Miami,
every time I land into Miami,
I'll you immediately start seeing all
these beautiful women and every time I go
there,
I just hear Tony Montana's voice going.
The city is like one big
pussy waiting to get fucked.
MMM.
And I was trying to bait me into those
two women that was sitting in the front
row to get into that fucking conversation.
Um,
but she did buy the bait. She didn't
take the bait cause they were like,
why don't we have boyfriends? You know
and you should have seen him cause you,
I dunno cause you guys are
you not wearing any clothes
that be the one tag is
beautiful as you are.
No guy wants to put up with that.
You got to walk down the street
like some over protective dog.
I keeping everybody away.
Everybody's
okay.
Well one of them was
barely wearing a shirt.
Granted I wasn't complaining for where
I was standing front but I mean it just
seems kind of obvious. You
know what I mean? You got it.
You got to cover up the goods a little
bit. I mean I would say that to Madonna.
I don't know if she's
currently dating 70 right now,
but Madonna is in fucking unbelievable
shape for her age and if she would just
put on something elegant,
you know what I mean?
Instead of rolling around with half
a fucking pussy lip hanging out.
I don't know why she does that.
She said something late, you know,
as she did yet another thing are all
fucking career has been like one big
publicity stunt after another. You
know, I'm wearing a wedding dress,
but I'm fingering myself at the
fucking award show. Right. You know,
right from there. And
then, oh, it's Jesus,
but he's African American and
now I'm trying to fuck them.
It's just paint by numbers.
Shock.
And what's funny is I actually like
our music borderline feel like,
uh, just keep, you know, that's actually,
I threw out my back doing
that Molly Ringwald dance. Um,
anyways, yeah. And then she
goes on Letterman. She says,
fuck 50,000 times.
She does stand up on the tonight show
was just one big fucking thing after
another.
I saw her latest one was she showed up
to a movie theater and I move out movie
premiere or whatever the fuck she, I
don't know who the fuck knows what it was,
you know,
some fundraiser to get toothbrushes
to some fucking gods for sacred place.
So she shows and she literally has her
titties in her ass out like a see through
dress. And she of course says, well,
what I'm doing is I'm challenging
the boundaries and um, of,
you know, of course women, you
know, got to drag all that bullshit.
And then it's like, no, you're 57. Okay.
Nobody wants to look at that. Okay.
Like it my age,
I am,
I am well into put on
a fucking sport coat.
Nobody wants to see it. It's just a,
yeah, you're not pushing any boundaries.
It's just, it's a, a, you know, you have
it a little bit of a midlife prices.
I think she looks fucking great, but she
looked way better if she fucking just,
you know, you know, put on,
split out a fucking dress,
fucking adore. I Dunno. But then again,
I saw Iggy pop and he
wasn't wearing a shirt,
but I don't find guys
aren't like attractive.
It was just sort of
funny to me that funny.
I just was just him not giving a fuck.
So I guess if she just said, look,
I don't give a fuck. I just felt like
Kevin my ass and titties hanging out.
I wouldn't have a problem with that.
But the fact that she's sitting there
trying to say that. No, no. Wait a minute.
I think she might be right.
Maybe she is right.
Hey, come here. You gotta
answer this question.
Okay.
There's a chance I might be common like
they don't understand that daughter
till she comes here. I'll sing a sing
some of my favorite songs by her.
A bad boy.
Bad girl home by six.
Hey, pick up the mic. I
got a question for you
now you want me back?
Yup. That's like that street joke
I told you. Right? Watch one.
I heard Jackie the joke mental.
The one about the gorilla. No,
the one with the fucking cause.
I like that one.
The married guys walking out of the
house and his wife's yelling at him.
Don't get the fuck Outta here. Get the
fuck out. I never want to see you again.
So he's walking away and she goes,
I hope he had died a long, slow,
miserable death. And he turns around,
he goes out, what now you want me back?
That's stupid. That's a stupid joke. It
just reminded me of that. Anyway, school,
I could have told it better,
but I got, I just got off plank.
Jackie jumped in and tell us a way better.
Um, all right, so my daughter recently
[inaudible] [inaudible] [inaudible]
she showed up at some fucking,
you know, raise awareness thing.
I don't know what it was.
It was a carpet she showed up and she
had a butt cheeks out in a titties out.
Okay. This was the met ball that
happens every year in New York City.
And that's for the mets.
Yes, it is. Go math, but it's
just for one of them. I know.
It's for the fucking
museum. Yes. The hacky date.
Every person in their twenties
goes on in New York and Madonna,
let's go to a museum.
Um,
Garla only the Creme de Creme dialing.
I invaded.
So Ralph Lauren pretends to fall.
He sniffs or butter on the way down.
So what happens? You know, this super
rich people, they're all freaks,
aren't they? I guess it wasn't at
the point of eyes wide. Shut it.
I don't know what the point
of I wide shut was. Well,
what happened was Stanley Kubrick died.
He died halfway through.
I saw a great fucking movie on a plane
called the insiders. It's a movie made by,
uh, some Korean director, man. It was
fucking phenomenal. Really enjoyed it.
Okay. Had One of the best
fucking fight scenes that I,
I've seen, cause the gay was
missing a hand, you know,
so he had to like fucking,
you know,
everybody knew one handy
was throwing right.
And it was multiple attackers.
It was the shit.
I almost gave it a standing ovation
on the plane. If it was pre nine 11,
I could've done it. But I started
to do and they're like, sorry,
I had to sit down. Okay.
It's another freedom lost.
So anyways,
so fucking Madonna shows up. Yeah. Sorry.
Okay.
So she says that she's trying to fucking
push the boundaries of or whatever,
the fucking sex and that type of
thing. Okay. So I was going like,
Duncan, mind you 57, no wants to
see me without a shirt on grants.
She's in better shape than
I am. But like, you know,
Almond must my sport coat years, like, you
know, covered up their freckles. Right.
So what I'm saying is you're in your
sport coat you, yeah, yeah, yeah.
You get to a certain point, you get
to your forties and stuff like that.
Women Dress elegantly and men dress like
gentlemen. Yeah. In other words, yeah.
You cover up, uh, you know the fucking
battle scars of what you've been through.
Okay. Do any fucking wine
and cheese plates? No.
What I'm saying is, so I was saying with
mark, but Donna just put on a nice dress.
You could look really elegant. Right.
That's not really her vibe. Yeah, I know.
I know.
But you know something,
it's like he like look who's
can do Michael Jackson. He,
if he was still alive [inaudible] the
short pants with the glitter socks.
It's like, come on dude. Some points
you've got to update the look what is,
what is your point? What
this whole Madonna thing. And
so I, as I was saying that,
but then I was like, wait a minute. But
when I saw Iggy pop with no shirt on,
I thought it was bad ass that daddy
didn't give a fuck. So that, that's,
that's bullshit. So I should be actually
applauding Madonna. Wow. Look at you.
See that? That's not, that's not okay. I
was going to say, you're going like wow,
look at you. You're really known
as DME. So my apologies to Madonna.
Feels like I'm shot.
Take it.
Look at my fucking 57
year old titties teeth.
She's my age with 10 she's 10 years.
We're 10 years apart.
So She's 50th wait what?
I, I'm 57 years. Wait.
Yes she is. She was born the
same year it was Prince Oh shit.
The same year as Michael Jackson.
Michael Jackson was 58 prince was 58
and tick but was 58 I never know how old
Madonna is ever. And that was like
in 1957 Oh my God. You're right.
She's gonna be 58 right? Had
no idea. And August, yeah,
she'll be 58 so 1958 as far as music goes,
was kind of like 1943
1943 was Janis Joplin,
Jimi Hendrix, Jim Morrison,
all born 1943
and then they all died in 1970 and then
people started to understand drugs.
And you know, bringing a jump rope on
the road and maybe becoming a Vegan.
So now they live longer.
Michael made it to 50 prints,
made it to 57 but don is still going okay.
Right.
So all of them in their own way kind
of went on stage with their ass hanging
out. Right. Um,
okay.
Where are you going
to fuck it. I want to do
some questions here. Okay.
Say you brought me into, show me that
you've evolved and seeing your own. No,
I was trying,
I was trying to seek,
see if that was a double standard women
and showing their bodies and you know,
double standard also works with women.
The way they look at guys in certain
situations too is you guys aren't like
perfect. No one, no one is claiming.
Perfect. Okay. Well the media just
seems to cover your complaints
and then this chest to ever have a voice.
Uh Huh.
Thank God you have this podcast. I
know. No one would hear me. Okay.
Listen, you got to understand
the world doesn't live with me.
They don't have the privilege of
living with me the way you do.
So I need to do this once a week.
That's a fucking beautiful watch. Who
got you that? You did? That's right.
Asshole response to stinky
German from last week.
So this poor bastard,
um,
he's German, right? Yes. And
uh, so he lives in Germany.
He's old school. He didn't
leave and try to be like, hey,
I wasn't part of that Hitler thing. Right.
He's still listening. His grandparents
said, you know, I don't know if it's me,
but this guy's making a lot of sense.
So,
so because of the mistakes of
his forefathers and mothers,
the gods have cursed him that he just
sort of smells a little musty and east,
she's tries showering, it has all this
shit. He doesn't know what the fuck to do.
So evidently this,
there's this other musty guy,
formerly musty guy heard about this.
Okay.
That's you look into his diet. Yeah. We,
we've talked about that in halitosis
and maybe you have a fucking as a sinus
infection. I don't know what,
but he just, he just smells bad.
Then no matter how much he showers.
So this guy says, yeah, anywhere.
Where's the yeah. Was
quite, it's quite a mystery.
I'm boy, I tell you, I'll tell you
this person's in response to this.
This is a formerly musty person,
so I hope this helps the, uh,
the sour kraut
cheeses.
See,
that is my best fucking fun ever.
I'm sorry,
but that shit was great. All right. That
was pretty good. That was pretty good.
That was good. That was
good. All right. I'm gonna,
I'm gonna.
He said,
I'm gonna and keep this simple because
we all know if you're reading issues,
I admittedly have,
I've been a fan for years,
but this is the first time I feel
the need to chime in on something.
Last week you read a question from a
German guy that had a musty body odor and
did not know what to do about
it. He said, growing up,
I dealt with the same bullshit
that poor SAP is going through.
I always smelled musty. I could not wash
it away, no matter how often I showered.
This is brutal.
I feel bad for these people.
I tried everything and
finally realized it was, eh,
it was antiperspirant
for some weird reason,
my body reacted when I put
it on and I smelled musty.
I actually stopped wearing deodorant
for a few weeks in the winter,
so I did not smell like a complete savage.
After that period of time,
I began wearing deodorant, only
skipping all brands with antiperspirant.
Uh, happily the stinky,
musty odor went away.
Hope this works. You Stinky
Fuck, love the podcast.
Your comedy and F is for family
and go fuck yourself. Yeah.
So basically what I got from that is
maybe his body is having a reaction to
something that he is using.
I don't know.
Cause your body should sweat the
weight to keep you cool. Right.
That's the whole point of sweating.
So anti perspirant I know maybe
people who sweat excessively,
they don't want to be sweating
through their clothes or something.
So I don't know. But it sounds
like that person to go to a doctor.
Well they haven't been able
to figure out what's going on.
And he's in Germany too. And those
guys don't fuck around over there.
They're very efficient. Yeah, no. Oh yeah.
I mean the cars, the trades,
the rocket side trick, you know,
if everybody could just forgive him
for that one crazy 10 year period,
I think they got a little
sideways. They'll never,
they'll never live it down. No,
you can't. Sorry. You know
what? It's on video. That's why,
you know, other countries could do shit.
And it happened before like a certain,
something that happened in 1915
that we always see advertised. Uh,
my vote dear bill on Capitol Hill. I don't
know what you're talking about. Well,
you should. You know what if there
was movie cameras around you? What?
Movie Cameras. Yep. Motion picture things.
Have you ever heard of vermin supreme?
Um,
he's been on. I don't, I don't, I don't
believe that this is somebody's name.
I'm going to look this up before
you guys make a fool of me,
which is not hard to do.
Why don't you read it first?
Because then I start commenting and then
halfway through I realized it's a prank
phone call. Vermin
supreme. It's coming up.
That's vermin supreme.
Vermin supreme as an American performance
art or artists and activists who has
run as a candidate and very
low various local states.
Um, okay. Let me see what this,
what's up with this guy? Okay.
I never heard of this guy.
He's been on the ballot in New Hampshire
and his platform has a lot to do with
dental health. He also has a plan
in place for the Zombie Apocalypse,
which involves setting up thousands of
treadmills to put the zombies on to help
power the new world. He wears
a giant boot on his head. Oh,
I've seen this fucking guy.
That boot that's right.
And carries around a rubber toothbrush.
Here's an article on him.
He also has promised free
ponies for everyone. Oh,
so he's a whack job.
I don't know if he's a whack job,
because that's a really funny joke though.
The zombies on the treadmill.
Are you looking them up? Are you
texting? I was looking at Madonna photos.
Okay. We were back here and we've
now, we've moved on. We've moved on,
but I just was looking at photos.
I'm here. I'm a don't preach
Amin. Trouble dealing dope. Do
you know any new Madonna songs?
I just said, I'm sorry. I did my
fucking, I did TV. Your, your, your,
your vocal warmups. Yeah. This was
not a good luck at the met ball.
It was just I, yeah. Oh, ladies,
can we stick together first of all and
just get something right? Yeah. Home.
But now it's not, I'm not
being catty. She just,
it's just so thirsty. It's
just, I don't [inaudible]
and I love Madonna, but this is
just too much. Or you're done.
Yeah, I'm done. I'm
sure her kids enjoy, uh,
wife's family is a bunch
of dramatic babies. Oh God.
You're the baby. And we go, hey
bill, I'm sick of this election.
I hope Trump wins. I know he's
a jerk, but I hate Hillary.
I think Bernie is a nice guy without
a clue. He says a lot of great things,
but he's going to raise taxes.
He talks about
making college free, but his taxes, we'll
make it. Oh, nothing is free. And that,
yeah, that's never going to happen. But
nothing that, you know, free health care.
It's not, it's not free. Somebody
has got to fucking pay for it.
He talks about making college free,
but it's taxes will make it harder for
people like me to pay my student loans.
I make 95 grand a year.
I have a kid,
a hundred grand in student loans between
me and my wife. We live comfortably.
But if you take another 20 $504,000
from him a year, I will feel it. Yeah,
definitely. I am already only netting
60. What is the fuck is all of this?
What's the plan?
The family has a venture.
Dramatic babies. All right.
Blah, blah, blah, blah.
MMM,
okay. So we'll get into, we'll get
into his family here somewhere.
I'm not opposed to giving money
to help people who need it,
but when is enough enough?
$1 trillion on dumb shit every year.
And you need more from me. Fuck off
Bernie. I love how he's blaming Bernie.
You know, Bernie didn't create
the fucking situation. Um,
he's trying to get us out of it, I
guess. I don't know if it's gonna work.
I don't think, I mean, I don't know if
people work with the guy, but oh God,
what a fucking decision this year.
Um, so I make this point to my wife,
my wife's family. I didn't yell. I
didn't say fuck off Bernie. I just said,
I don't think we,
the people should have to give more
money if they're wasting their money.
They already get, well, my
wife's family lost their shit.
They said that I'm selfish
and that if I vote for Trump,
I'm endorsing hate and greed and fascism,
a really question mark. They endorsed
Obama and I have a problem with him.
Hatefully blowing up kids and
wedding parties with drones.
Why doesn't that make them hateful?
Um,
they then went on to talk about for
30 minutes about hate and how theirs,
they were scared about what would happen
to the country and they're scared about
how children would grow up in a country
with anti quote Hitler minus the
concentration camps.
I told them that comparing an Egomaniac
to Hitler is unfair to the victims of
the Holocaust.
It trivializes the actual evil of Hitler
and embodied her mother and father were
both taken aback and said that my way of
thinking could potentially be dangerous
to their grandchildren.
What period the fuck period is going,
period on period. Well, you dope.
Yeah. You fucking opened up your fucking
mouth about politics. Talk about Paul,
know who he is and he's young. He
doesn't know. Well, you know? Yeah.
And how did you learn? How did you learn
and how did I learn by bringing it up.
By doing that? Yeah. This is the
deal. You know, you can't talk
about politics and religion
and shit like that.
Those are going to say get got
it got really heated. Yeah,
right before they said that shit.
Well you can't. And also you just,
yeah, I don't know. He
gotta be, if you really
are going to vote for Trump,
I just,
I think there's only certain sections
of the United States where you could say
that where you'll get a, yeah, I get it.
Oh, well, tell me more about your opinion.
I feel like if you say, you know
what, fuck this, I'm voting for Trump,
most people are going to be like,
are you fucking kidding me?
So I'm not surprised at that,
but
no. Yeah, you really a lot of shit. One
Oh own. I was, I made fun of him when, uh,
you know, I got some shit for it. For
making fun of Trump. Yeah. From who?
People who support Trump. Oh,
well, okay, fine. Yeah, they have,
believe it or not, there's people that
I know it has a lot more than I thought.
Remember when we was first talking
about running and we're both like,
this is never going to happen.
This is a joke. This is ridiculous.
And now here we are. And he used like
the only Republican left standing.
So I mean, I guess I underestimated him.
Yeah. He's like the less humble party.
He's like the Leicester City
of Pollock politicians. Um,
but here's the thing though,
I, but I think like, you know,
Hillary Clinton is the fucking devil
because she's acting like she gives a fuck
and she's, you know, she's one of those
Bilderberg people. I don't like her.
I like Bernie out of all of them.
I liked Bernie Sanders.
I just don't think anybody's
going to fucking work with, well,
the California primary is coming up, so
he's, he's not throwing in the towel.
Ernie, Bert I have. Do you know something?
But we got to vote. We have to go.
I have to vote for a person that I feel
is actually truly gives a shit about
regular people and yeah,
that would be him.
Whether he's going to be successful or
not. And I know what a lot of people,
well,
you're going to put Trump
good. The office. I've always
voted for the fucking third wheel.
Every fucking God damn time.
Well, when the primary happens,
we got to vote for him.
That's the only way that he'll listen.
I don't have to do anything that you say.
Okay.
But I don't know what I'm going to do.
So basically his, this guy's in law.
Do you know what? We just did
eight him, you know, we just did.
We just did with this guy did,
which is what we just fucking talked
politics and gave endorsements to.
Bernie said,
we shouldn't have done that.
I still haven't made up my
mind that I'm going to do that.
Why are we were giving endorsements
just by talking about it,
by saying that you're going to do it well,
it's how I feel like that guy that fucked,
we like those,
those people that you see on Facebook
and they go, Hey, do you know me?
I pretend to be a doctor on his soap
opera and I think this is who you should
vote for. I apologize
for that. People. I, I,
I try not to say that eventually when
she was going to come up doors thing,
anybody where we'll, let's just
leave it. I'll tell you what,
I'm endorsing a nice fucking
cold Budweiser. When I sit
down to watch game five,
that's what I'm endorsed. What
is, what does he want to know?
He was just sort of like,
what the hell? Now My,
now my inlaws don't want
me to have children with my
wife because they think I'm
evil and they're gonna.
I'm gonna raise a little evil.
Trump's might think about Trump is his
fucking about lack of compassion for
fucking people.
When you sit there and say take his coat
and like riling people up like that was
just says that he says really,
really awful things.
But the thing I like about him is he
lets me know that they actually count the
votes because no super rich
people want that fucking guy.
And I always thought for years
my conspiracy theory is like,
they don't count these fucking thing.
They do. Oh, it's pretty fucking close.
And they put the money on both horses
and then that fucking fine. But uh,
the fact that he's actually doing well,
he's speaking a lot of
people out there need,
it's going to build a wall and he's
going to have the people whose wallet and
pay for it telling you these talking
mad shit. I don't know. I feel like I,
all those years of watching the apprentice
and celebrity apprentice are now
coming back to when you tried to find
a CEO for a company that doesn't exist.
It's all coming back
to bite me in the ass.
I've been supporting him
this whole entire time.
I'm partly to blame for this bullshit.
So what does this look?
He can't be a complete moron. What is
this kid saying? What does this point?
He's just is, no, he's
just saying what the fuck.
So we just will not talk about
politics anymore around your inlaws.
I'll tell you that much.
But then he said looking
forward to seeing you in Dublin,
myself and some friends that
will be coming from Belfast.
Well I'm going to be doing
Belfast too. So you don't, yeah,
you don't even need to do that. Yeah.
And we're putting together the dates.
I'm definitely doing Dublin.
Definitely doing Belfast. Yeah.
I'm doing a little 10 day tour over there.
Cause skin,
it's not a good time to go to Scandinavia
this time of year because they
actually have sunlight and it's
warm out. So when I usually, well,
because they're going to want
to be outside. Okay. Yeah.
Yeah. If you go in December
and it's already fucking
dark, go to movies and stuff.
Still though,
I would imagine just cause it's sunlight
most of the time doesn't mean why would
I listen to the promoters
over there? I'll, I'll listen.
When is this happening?
I'm going to go,
that's going to be happening individually.
Like I think it's going to start on the
31st and it's going to go into August.
Very excited about that. Exciting
things are happening. I love Ireland.
Oh No,
I love the people of Ireland.
Look who you're with or potato face
himself through advice with neighbors
emotionally. Germany. Oh mighty Billy.
I don't actually don't even know that
cause I never done the whole a CFC if
they're always like a more German than
Irish cause I am German, Irish Catholic
podcasts. It doesn't get any
wider. I wasn't getting any wider.
All mighty Billy Ball bags. Uh, alright.
And vice with neighbors. Question.
I live in an apartment complex here in
the lovely state of Oklahoma and I have
this neighbor who lets her dog
out on her balcony every morning.
Somewhere between the hours
of four and 5:00 AM oof.
The dog barks aggressively
for hours afterward.
Of course it wakes me up.
Poor thing.
The dog that is and this about this
poor bastard or lady Oklahoman.
Um,
Oklahoman Oklahoman.
Uh, where am I? Okla Homo Sexual? No,
no. Isn't that one of the
characters on your Nashville show?
I want to write a song with you.
We'll likes about us. They gay cowboy,
the gay cowboys to gay cowboys.
Cutting edge character.
That's the first gay cowboy ever
in primetime in Bram time. Yes.
I've been prime time
during the lunch hour.
It was just littered with
them when I was growing up.
Those people on Captain Kangaroo, right?
Ernie and Bert isn't what they said.
All those guys. Right.
All right. Question.
I live in an apartment complex here in
the lovely state of Oklahoma. Okay. Yeah.
The dog parks aggressively for hours.
It wakes me up and I have to go.
I have to work at 8:00 AM I filed
complaints after an altercation in which I
went out and scream, shut your fucking
dog up before I make you shut him up. Oh.
Was that your opening line or something
along those lines? My muscles.
My message has not been heard by the
apartment costs and she continues to let
the dog out. What should I do?
Sincerely, a blue collar working man,
just trying to get some fucking sleep.
Who is also Saint Louis Blues gave the
stars of fucking Molly whopping today.
Hope you watched it. I miss that. Um,
well fuck urine here in Oklahoma,
man. You know what you need to do?
Take out your side iron.
Hey, hey, hey. Hey, eh,
take the fucking dog out the bell bow.
Don't even joke about it with rubber
bullets. Don't even joke about that.
Who is your super,
you know,
he put rubber bullets in the gun
and every time the dog barks,
king very signed a dog barks, you shoot
it and its ass and it starts to Oh,
when I bark and then it'll shut
up. No, you can't do that. Uh,
you would get arrested for that.
So why don't I would just go down.
I would buy a month's worth
of cube steaks. Right?
Why does it does a dog shit
and Piss on the balcony?
Is that why she's letting it out there?
Cause that's gross. I don't know.
But that is so fucking not acceptable
because you know what's probably the
fucking dog gets up at Ford 5:00 AM
is keeping her up to him up so they,
oh my God. No, it's you. Gotta you gotta
call them on or something. Oh wait.
Did he say that they're not
paying attention at the,
like when you say it's not going over
well with the people in the apartment?
Well he has like, she just has a
neighbor. I can't, I don't think that, oh,
it's an apartment complex.
Yeah.
You got to say something to the
management company. Oh look,
there's no fucking way. He's the only
person that's annoyed by this. Of course,
I would go around and I would get a
bunch of signatures and then I would,
you know, try to have everybody
all get together and say, ah,
that bitch needs to shut
the other bitches. Oh, cleo.
No,
what's up buddy?
Okay.
Yeah. This little bit, no. Why are you,
it's time for this one probably to go out.
Speaking of all that. All
right, well you do that well,
I will wrap up the podcast here. No,
you take her out. Um, sorry. Hey,
is it Jacksonville this morning? That's
my, uh, that's my excuse. All right,
well that's going to be there.
The, uh, the light on weight,
so we didn't offer any advice besides
your horrible joking advice. Of course.
I just said you get a bunch of signatures.
He can get enough signatures,
not going to do shit. You got to go
to the management company and be like,
this dog is barking at four or five
in the morning every morning. Oh,
he said he already did that. Oh,
and they're not paying attention.
He said he's in this fucking, what do
you think signatures are going to do?
Any technology like to hear him about fun?
No, that's not it. Oh wait, I missed one.
He said, I have this day. I live in an
apartment complex. The dog barks. I've,
I filed complaints. Yeah. Like nothing's
happening. Um, that sacks. Wow.
So you have to do this thing.
I'm not going to pay my
fucking rent. There you go.
I'm not paying my rent until you get
this one. Yeah. To shut this damn dog.
Oh yeah. Cause that's not fair. Yeah.
How about that long? She's lived there.
That sounds like something an older
person would do to just like put their dog
out on the balcony and just let it bark
all morning cause it probably goes out,
takes a piss,
takes a shit and then once to come inside
and meanwhile the owner has gone back
to sleep. All right. Well obviously I
was joking. You don't shoot it the dark.
No, you don't. All right. That's
right. Cleo is the other one.
Um, all right. Virtual
reality headset, blow job.
Uh,
all right.
I know you hate technology but we'd
like to hear your opinion on this.
My girlfriend,
half jokingly promised me a double
blow job from my 30th birthday.
Um,
I do not expect this to happen,
but I have been joking with her that the
date is approaching and she should have
a girl lined up,
et cetera.
I have also been talking about virtual
reality slash Vr headset as I'm thinking
of getting one, I don't know
what that is. Yeah. What is that?
She asked me the other day, would I be
able to watch porn through it? I said yes.
She then said instead of the double by,
why don't you wear the headset
and I can give you normal.
Oh by while watching a porno. Wait, what
do you what? What are you saying goodbye?
Oh Bj. Yeah. Oh, you know what?
It was underlined in red so I couldn't
see the bottom part. I was like,
why does this by,
Oh my God.
Your reading skills are atrocious.
Yeah,
and by what actually mean that there
wouldn't be a guy and a girl doing it.
I was even, I was thinking about
like his girlfriend would be like by,
she was down there with another chick.
I am stupid.
See this people, you too can be
successful in life years dumb as me.
She then she then just instead of instead
of a double Bj, he read this again. Wow.
Why don't you wear a headset and I could
give you a normal BJ while watching a
porno.
Why can't you do that now with a TV?
Because I feel like that's
something like weird Tron,
futuristic shit where you put it on this
opening Pandora's box or is this a way
for Vr to be seen as a techie sex toy?
You are really asking the
wrong person that question.
You know bill doesn't know what
looking forward to see you in Dublin.
Myself and some friends
will be coming from bell.
Oh this is the I that was the one.
Okay. Um, is this the same? No,
I read the ending to the other one to
that one and it was weird because the
ending was in front of the other one.
Oh fuck you and fuck everybody else. Yeah.
It's all fun. It's all fun and games.
Until I stopped podcasting. Oh, I've
had enough of this sensitive deep.
No I'm not, I don't care. Um,
it is a slippery slope but I feel like
that could be really kind of cool.
Does she get to do it too?
Like does she get to watch some
porn while you like go down on her?
That'd be really trippy.
It would be trippy.
But the thing is then then
when ends up happening is,
is then you end up getting like a that,
that disconnect.
Right. And now you don't want
to do anything that's the
one of you is wearing the
helmet. Yeah. That's weird. Oh my God.
I have to like see you. So that's,
I got, that's a dangerous, yeah,
that's like one of those things like
do you think I could do heroin once and
like be all right with
that? No, I saw something,
I'm
trying to think where I saw it.
Saw what in one of those Asian countries,
because they're always ahead of us, they
have better cell phones. There was a, uh,
a guy trying out like a
virtual reality sex suit,
which I had a bit on this thing in like
the late nineties when I first heard
that they were going to do
that. Um, and by the way,
the fact that you haven't already
called me out going like book bill,
How did you just stumble upon this?
I'm dead honest one.
I don't remember the waiting for the
rest of the story cause I felt like there
was more, could have been while I was
watching Internet porn probably. Yeah.
But they don't have advertising
advertisers for that.
It was like a story on
the side of the thing.
They have all those and how do you
know them? Yeah. Right back at you.
So yeah, but they don't have any, I don't
have ads like that. Right. That's true.
Well this is what it was. It looked
like a fucking dude. He was like,
let go mummy suit,
who's hilarious.
Literally was all wrapped
up in toilet paper.
That's how I remember it because
it was so horrifying. It was just,
it was one of those things,
whatever I was looking at that then
came up and I went, wow. Right. He was,
and it looked like
mmm.
His hands with to his side. He
had on the fucking, you know,
I'm old and I can't see anymore those
glasses, those cataract glaucoma,
cataract glasses from the drug
store. Yeah. So he had on those, he,
I think he was all wrapped up because he
didn't want anybody to see who he was.
Yeah. Maybe that's what it was.
Okay. And then there was this thing,
obviously his dick was in
it. Oh my God. And it just,
the same way your hand would be going like
bang, Bang, Bang, Bang against yourself.
It was this thing.
It was the most fucked up thing ever.
Would you ever use one of those flesh
bought things? You know how porn stars,
they get mold. Those things are so
fucking gross. I think those things,
those things is so fucking gross.
A long time ago I did somebody podcast.
I'm not gonna say who, but people
who listen to podcasts, no. Who is,
he had one of those things and it look
like some Jeffrey Dahmer body part
automatically.
Who your tax just sitting.
I don't think you'd do cause I
know who you're going to guess.
But it wasn't that person. Um, it
looked, no, it just looked like and it,
did he say that?
Did it feel like every,
it can't feel like a real vagina
obviously, but like it's, it's just,
it's, I, I can't believe that it does.
Like shit like that doesn't cause
you to either be like become like a
necrophiliac or some sort of perk,
feel Yak.
Why would it make you feel a necrophiliac?
Cause you fucking something that looks,
looks like a body part and it's not alive.
Women have like dildos and vibrators and
stuff and it's like the same sensation.
So why wouldn't a one of those
fleshed bought things feel like,
isn't that kind of like another Madonna
Iggy pop thing by looking at it the
wrong way maybe? No, I don't think,
no, I don't think you're looking at it.
I remember back in the day, back in the
day, don't like the idea of a fake vagina.
You don't,
you're not comfortable just sitting on a
table and it has a handle on it and I'm
holding it. No, that's not
your thing. You're not into,
that feels like Henry
portrait of a serial killer.
I remember back in the day,
right when you actually had to go
to a porno store to get your porn,
and they had like, you know, always,
always behind the counter and
they would have shut up there.
They had this, it was like what's in the
box? It was literally a head in a box.
The chicks, Bob was like, [inaudible] you
stick your Dick in it. You know? I'm like,
somebody's going to buy that.
Yeah. It was in like the same box,
like a basketball came in
and someone's gonna take it,
grab it by its fucking ears that are stuck
to the side of its head and then just
going to go home and
fuck ahead just to head.
Now there's no fucking way
that that doesn't fuck you up.
Psychologically.
If you do that long enough,
then you go out with a real person.
It's already annoying that they
have to buy a dinner and that the,
there's a whole body attached to it
and you have to talk to it. Yeah,
and they all, they're thinking of just
grabbing you by your ears. Water, water.
I want to alert. It's over.
Yeah. It's fucked up. Well,
I still feel like we're
going back to the question.
I feel like they can experiment
with it like once or twice,
but it can't be like a regular thing
that they're doing all the time because
then yeah,
that'll completely fuck up your sex life
because then you'll just be looking at
everything you do.
Like it's supposed to be this
hyper reality dual reality.
Virtual is just not good.
You don't, I was just saying this out.
Let's just fast forward here. Okay.
Now. So that becomes the thing, right?
Which you know what's gonna people
are gonna do it and then we're,
it's going to become is porn stars will
be making all of that fucking money.
[inaudible] and it basically
you have a girl fucking, ah,
they'd probably just
be like the whole suit.
It's eventually just going
to be the whole suit. Right.
What are you talking about?
Like the whole, I'm talking
about like in the future,
like when like everybody has like a
virtual reality sex suit that's will
actually helped the population problem.
Right?
The virtual reality sex suit [inaudible].
Okay.
And then porn stars will
then have their likeness,
they'll do a POV porn and then they
get money and then you have to like
subscribe to that.
So you can do,
you can do a virtual reality thing where
you at with any porn starts with like
asa, Akira and then he, and then
here's what happens. Yeah. Okay.
Who's going to be the first celebrity
that crosses over and eventually,
right,
because they're sick of doing superhero
movies and they don't want to do the
grunt work of an independent cause.
Like you notice now they're all
doing ads over here. Back in the day,
all the celebrities did ads, but
they did them overseas, right?
Remember we used to go over and we all
look at so and so doing a fucking watch
thing or look at her doing this thing,
but they'd never do them here
because it was that whole, um, um,
stigma that if you did a commercial,
you're a sellout, blah, blah,
whatever the fuck it was.
Or it's like you're doing a commercial,
you're a movie star. I'm, where
we start is not even on TV.
Forget about doing an ad. Now
that all went away, you know?
So I'm saying eventually
somebody famous would do it,
right? You could, yeah.
Get a suit and program it so that you're
having sex with like Lindsay Lohan or
something and the first one, the first
and the first level will go down.
Now be one of those reality TV show stars.
Right.
You know when the reality
show goes off the air,
like Jersey shore, they were all
fucking huge. Now it's just disappeared.
Where the fuck are they?
Right.
You could probably talk a couple
of them and is doing it right.
Are we pitching a show right now?
I think or some kind of
like high tech concept.
We'll that will probably make a lot of
money that's going to end up at sounds
like a movie.
It sounds like.
Like a what was bad and this
is what's going to happen.
You're to have these self driving
fucking cars.
Huh?
You're going to have self driving fucking
cars and people would be laying in
them in virtual reality suits having
sex with any famous person they want to
write and bill have like,
because you don't need to steer in
wheeler gas or brake or anything anymore,
you literally feel like your suit
in there and then when you're done,
you roll rollover up from that
seat into like another, like a, uh,
like a freshen up like tub or some shit.
So I think we're totally going in that
direction. I think you're right. We'll,
we'll, we'll see it in the next
generation. Before it was just, yeah,
the fleshbots stuff or just the mold
of the vagina or the deck or whatever.
And then it's going to be this virtual,
it'll be super expensive at first
is going to go into a complete,
it's gonna be like one flat screen TVs
first came out and they have 14 grants.
So don't buy the first virtual
reality sex suits virtual way to the,
like they'd come down to like 800 bucks
at best buy. Then you get them right.
Figure out how to like make
this technology and just
like patent it and that's
how we'll make our,
yeah, yeah. We're going to figure out
how to do that. I can't even read copy.
We're not calling it that.
That's what's going to happen.
I've already selling it right
now with these self driving cars,
like the interiors of cars.
What they're going to have now,
they're going to have office ones.
They're gonna have sleeper ones.
People just want to sleep,
going to work.
They're going to have one second to catch
up on your emails and all of that type
of shit. Yeah, the different those
that'll be like the different, um, the,
the social one,
the social and office one, all of
that type at all. I don't know.
And then eventually is going to be like,
well, why are you even going to work now?
Because everything's automated. And then
there's robots, right? And then one day,
the whole fucking thing just turns on us.
What if there was a company like in
some really random, not really random,
like a Japan,
by the way.
Neither one of us is high right now.
No, not at all. Completely that
high. It's the middle of the day.
Never been more sober. What if there was
a company somewhere and like, I dunno,
not Japan,
but like Eastern Europe that said,
we want to do this deal with you where
we have these like sex dolls with your
face on them and they offered you like,
yeah,
an insane amount of money.
No, no, to do it. Oh,
and you could buy a bell birth sex doll.
Do you realize the photoshops I'm going
to get and I'm going to have to re tweak
now you asshole.
Oh, you're right. Oh, they're going
to be horrifying, but hilarious.
Like a bill. Birth sex.
Um, what'd you do? Yeah,
they come out of like somewhere
random, like, you know,
Norway or just something
or like, you know, yeah.
One of those plays random like
Norway, love Norway. That's
my random enough like,
you know,
turns Minnick Stan or one of those fucking
places. I'm not even saying it right,
but just a random little pocket
that was just like, you know,
we $5 million
that we want to make sex
toys with your face. No,
you wouldn't go for it. Can you imagine
that phone call out of nowhere? No. No,
I wouldn't. No. I can honestly
tell you that I would know.
I know you wouldn't like,
yeah, I would think so.
How the fuck did we get all the way
over here? See this white light,
the questions? Great questions because
of the person in their virtual blow job.
Look,
we'll buy according to you.
I never claim to be smart since
beginning of these podcasts.
I don't know. I, I, I don't
claim to be smart. And with that,
go fuck yourselves.
I'm sorry.
The podcast was so late. Um, I was flying
back from Jacksonville as I mentioned,
um, rural times, several times.
I complained about it. And, uh,
I'll be checking in on you on Thursday.
I'll see you go blues.