like a boss.
So Oprah had an in depth interview
with Lance Armstrong was a dumb,
I was actually fucking hilarious.
I was watching it with the lovely Nia and,
uh,
I was just laughing my ass off.
It was,
it was phenomenal.
Like she's sitting there
going like, um, so will you,
will you basically injecting,
you know,
fucking horse Jizz steroids
into you for every race?
And he's like,
yes.
Did you ever take banned substances to
enhance your cycling performance? Yes.
Yes or no.
Did you ever use any other banned
substances like testosterone, uh,
cortisone or human growth hormone?
Yes.
In all seven of your
Tour de France victories,
did you ever take banned
substances or blood dope? Yes.
For all tours. He's like, yes, I was.
She's like, did you consider a cheating?
And he's like, Eh, at the
time, no. No, I didn't.
Who said to me earlier, you don't think
it was possible to win without doping?
Not In their generation.
And,
and I'm not here to talk about
others in that generation.
It's been well documented. Um,
I didn't invent the culture,
but I didn't try to stop the culture.
And that's that,
that that's my mistake and that's
where I have to be sorry for it.
And that's what something in the sport
is now paying the price because of that.
And so I am sorry for that.
It's like a course he didn't,
you know what pissed me off about lance?
I guess it was kind of a good move on
his part that he didn't go like Oprah.
Did you do any research into this sport?
Did you notice the top 20 guys?
We're all fucking doing this shit to,
you got to fight fire with fire.
You can't bring a knife to a gun fight.
If everybody else is jacked up,
I gotta be jacked up too.
For Fuck Sakes.
[inaudible]
the worst thing. No, I didn't.
I actually like the opera in interview
and it was kind of funny watching her be
dumbfounded
by this guy's complete lack of,
uh, you know, just not giving
a shit when he was cheating.
Um, and then the whole thing was
funny to me, cause I, you know,
I'm old enough to remember when Oprah
used to interview fucking midgets who want
to fuck their mailman's
brother. You know, so I dunno.
They don't know where to go. They
need a mother and, and unfortunately,
what about the father?
[inaudible] you
don't necessarily need a mother.
They need a parent. May Be, why can't
anyways,
they do the whole interview and then
they go on ESPN.
Yeah,
Rick Riley's talking about Lance Armstrong
and I guess Rick Riley was backing
Lance and he was just having this hissy
fit about his reputation because he
backed Lance Armstrong.
Sorry Dude.
Oh sorry dude.
14 years he put egg on my face and I
would even ask him off the record, Hey,
just tell me off the record
if you're doing this stuff,
because it keeps coming up and up and
every time he would be more and more
adamant that he wasn't doing it, then
you can defend me. Don't worry about it.
Like anybody gives a flying
fuck about Rick Riley.
Yeah.
And when Lance Armstrong, when he finally,
you know, came out that he did it,
did anybody go like,
oh my God,
now what happens to Rick Riley?
Like he made that whole fucking thing
about himself. You know, he made,
he said they go,
he made me look like a fool.
I was typing things,
supporting him. Rick, relax.
Nobody's blaming you. Nobody
gives a flying. Fuck this.
This really isn't on you.
This is about lance. This
isn't about you. Okay,
so why don't you just close your laptop,
fucking relax.
Like he felt betrayed. It's like, Rick,
what are you fucking special?
He lied to the whole world.
He's not going to lie to you
like a brick. You listen. I know.
I just went on national
television and said that I, uh, I,
I don't cheat in those races,
but I, I actually am cheating.
Ah,
I've cheated every race and I plan
to continue cheating in the future.
And now that you know that,
um, I have to kill you.
You know,
I don't know.
I was really hoping for more on all
both of those subjects. I would,
I was hoping that I was going to
have something a little more funnier.
Kenny,
we
came back for me now,
I never really left.
It's illegal.
We shouldn't have it just out.