Hey, what's going on? It's bill burn.
It's time for the Thursday afternoon.
Just before Friday.
Monday morning podcasts and
just checking it on Ya.
I'm checking in on you
because I give a fuck. Right.
I care about you. Oh, who gives a fuck?
I do. Um, how's your week going?
Everything going good with you.
I hope it is. Um, all freckles.
The pasty old fucking man,
48 years old.
My back feels better than it has since
that since I don't know when, um,
just been going to the chiropractor
and getting this fucking,
the shit beat out of me in
massages is finally a, I dunno,
it's fucking great. I guess my
spine was compressed and twisted
for, for decades. So, you know,
after having professionals beat the shit
out of me for like weekly for like the
last since May, I guess. Um,
I dunno. I think I finally,
I undid the, they undid it or whatever.
But now, like when I go to stretch,
when I go to a, you know,
you know the whole thing,
you lay on your back and this young people
won't know this because they just get
up off the couch and start running.
They're fine because they're young,
but old people, you know that
she lay on the floor, right?
You get down on the floor, right?
You make that noise and you keep
going down and getting up.
It's the same noise. Ah, right.
You get down on the fucking
ground and then yeah,
you bring one of your knees
up to your chest, right?
And then you bring it over to one side
and then you have your arms sticking out.
You know,
like almost like you're doing like some
sort of old time you football move right
high stepping over somebody.
But when I do that on the ground now,
I just bring that over in my back.
Just cracks from the lower back to
about three quarters of the way up.
And that never used to,
I wouldn't crack at all.
It was just all fucking jammed
in there. And um, feel good,
man. I've been working out, I host been
eating like a fucking animal though.
Went to a barbecue Sunday, so that's
all she wrote with that. Right.
And I did a show,
so I ate barbecue and then I also
fucking eight and a comedy club,
Green Room. I was working down
there and have most at the, uh,
the comedy and Magic Club and,
um,
which is really fucking cool to go down
there now because whenever I look at the
pier, I'm like, that's the
thing I fly over. Right? But,
you know, as I'm coming down,
you know, does the Hermosa Beach
Pier and then Manhattan Beach Pier,
when you get to that one, you gotta
be down around like, you know,
like 300 feet. And that's when
you call lax and say, Hey,
I want to fucking skit adol underneath
the fucking jets there. Right.
And I never knew any of that. I never
knew where the beaches were. I mean,
look at me,
this Red Eddie cut.
Know where the beaches are.
The only reason why I know where the
beaches are is so I know how to drive in
the opposite direction.
I fucking hate the beach.
I fucking,
oh my God,
I hate the beach.
I love the fucking beautiful brown
people that go there, you know,
tanning themselves up. God bless you.
I sit there like the boy in the bubble,
you know,
and one of those Ford Astros' with the
slide and fucking door with the AC on
looking out like the boy in
the bubble. Right? Um, I,
I fucking hate it. I get there.
It's hot as fuck. It's boring.
I'm terrified to go in the ocean.
I'm not fucking going in there.
It's Goddamn sea monsters and
they're going to fucking grab you.
You know what? A bunch of editing,
what kind of a fucking moron. I just,
I'll never get over there at the fact
that people just swim in the fucking ocean
and the oils a shark attack
today. Yeah. You know, it's funny,
somebody goes to the fucking zoo and
they crawl into the fucking cage and they
get attacked. Everybody's
general consensus. Consensus
is yes, it's a tragedy.
And what are you going there for? What'd
you think was gonna Happen? You know,
you go to the beach and you
go into the fucking ocean,
everybody acts like it's a big,
it's a big surprise out of that happened,
I can't believe it.
You went into an unnatural environment,
right?
And do something where there was a bunch
of shit there that could kill you when
something did or took a chunk out of you
took a fucking bite out here. You know,
when you've come stumbling out of there.
I don't know why.
It just makes me think of an unfinished
cigar when somebody gets bit right.
You know what? I went to
this fucking party, right?
And I brought in Sony for my birthday
and got me this really incredible box of
cigars. So I, uh,
I immediately call all my friends
because you know, or whatever. It's like,
cause I'm not gonna smoke all 10 of
these fucking things. First of all,
that's not what cigar smoking is about
to social thing. Right. And secondly,
I don't want to smoke all of them because
I'm trying to keep the habit at bay.
All right. Special occasions
once to twice a month. Right.
So I brought it over there and
there was a bunch of hover and cons,
who all showed up.
Everybody acting like they're fucking
cigar smokers and some handing them out to
these people,
I don't fucking know.
And I turned my back and
like 15 minutes later,
like three of them have
been stomped out there.
Like they weren't even halfway done
fucking idiots anyway. So then I just, I
figured that's, you get bit by a shark,
you know, he'd come in,
it takes like, you know,
the bottom 30 you off and
you come out like a, like a
fucking unfinished. The gar.
No, I don't fucking know. It
made sense to me visually.
That's what I thought of
at all going to be relax.
This podcast doesn't even count. This
is me just checking in on you. Oh,
Billy back brace. Huh? I took it
off like fucking Forrest Gump.
I actually feel like I could run,
the only downside to my back feeling as
great as it does right now is I have to
fight myself from doing
something really stupid. Um,
but uh, but as always, I was psyched.
I didn't have to use any drugs.
I stayed away from all of that shit.
And it reminded me of that guy
when I used to watch that doc,
the doctor drew show,
the celebrity Rehab,
and there was that guy from taxi who since
passed away and he kind of got hooked
on painkillers and shit. He's
always bitch about his back. And a,
I remember I had, for whatever reason,
I was just thinking about that. Go, man,
I wish that guy went to a
fucking chiropractic and
[inaudible] Seuss instead of
going down the fucking painkiller
route. I don't know. Who knows?
He might have fucking done heroin first.
He might've fucked up his
back nod off on heroin.
Although they tend to
stand pretty upright.
They have to keep that back straight
and then their legs bend. I don't know.
But as always, I don't know what
the fuck's going on. Um, yeah.
So Monday night, Sunday night,
sorry, I went to, uh, went
to the comedy Magic Club,
uh, worked. And that's not an easy
room. It's not an easy room to do. Well,
and as those people have
seen a ton of fucking comedy,
you know Jay Leno goes down there every
Sunday so they used to see in the top
notch shit.
So you know,
if you go down there and you have
fast that you get a bump. So it had,
I had a good set.
Fortunately I had something in
the middle of my set though I was,
I was leaning on the mic stand
and they had, and I had my,
my arm sorta like instead of
leaning onto how I usually do,
I had my arm up and something
was like pushing into my elbow.
And when my hand was like that,
I went to close my make a
fist and like my middle,
my index and my fucking
ring finger wouldn't close.
It was like in slow motion
really freaked me out.
I don't know what the Hell I did, but
what I'm basically telling you, people's,
I'm falling apart. Um, but my
back feels good. So anyways,
so that was the first night
of me like an asshole.
But I still work out every day,
fucking crushed in the elliptical.
I give it back at night,
a little bit fucking drink
here are fucking cheese stick,
whatever the fuck I have. Right?
But uh, then Monday last second,
a buddy of mine called me up and said,
hey,
sting and Peter Gabriel a plan at
the fucking Hollywood bowl, right?
So I said, you know what, I bet
Vinnie call Udas playing drums.
I got to go see that.
That's like a bucket list.
He's one of my favorite
drummers of all fucking time.
And he's one of those guys
who just keeps getting better.
He's an absolute monster.
I mean,
the guy's like pushing 60 years old
and he could still like blow away young
drummers in their teens.
You know what I mean?
A lot of young drummers just thinking
of all the young guys are the shit and
they're all fucking flashy. And
then as guys get older, you know,
they stopped practicing or whatever.
He's one of the few fucking guys,
there was no drop off.
He just kept getting better and better
and better and better. So I say,
fuck this, right? So I
called up somebody, you know,
who was in the know and I was like,
Hey, is Vinny play in tonight?
And they were like, they got back to
me and I was like, fuck, that was the,
that was the game right there. I was
like, I gotta go fucking see it. Right?
So I go on the hub of the stub there,
they'll stub hub and just pay through
the fucking nose, get as close as I can.
So now I'm all fucking excited.
I'm all Dow low, right?
And I'm fucking going, oh my God, you
look at, they got to drum kits up there.
I'm guests,
Peter Gabriel's going to open do is set,
then stings going to do with
fucking set and then a, the end,
they're going to come out and sing,
fucking have on the Gila, whatever.
They're gonna do some sort
of encore together, right?
The fucking show starts.
Okay.
And the, uh, there was so
many fucking people on stage.
I didn't know what was going on.
And Peter Gabriel all of a sudden is like,
you know, you guys like right in front of
us, he sings one of his fucking, I dunno,
world music songs. It was amazing. And
his voice sounded fucking incredible.
And I'm like, okay, Peter
Gabriel and his giant band here,
this giant ass fucking band
with two drummers and shit is,
is going to fucking open and then stinks
going to come out and we get to see
Vinny, right? He finishes
the first fucking song,
he walks off stage and then
all of a sudden staying just
walks out and he's like,
what the fuck? Right? And he
starts playing the Afi Abba.
You right. You start singing that
song. And I'm like, wait a minute,
where the fuck's and I realized he's
been playing the whole fucking time.
He's just behind these,
this fight on what the fuck it
was somebody amps or some shit.
So I could see was like
the top of his head,
but there was like video
screens and stuff. So,
of course I was standing
on my tiptoes to watch it,
but what killed me about his
playing is, uh, you know,
every great musician has a voice, right?
I know this is like hacky to say that,
but that fucking guy,
the bell of his ride cymbal and when
he plays the cross stick on a snare,
it's just undeniably you're like,
that's fucking Vinnie call you.
And the fact that he was making that
noise that close to me and I was
immediately hearing it and just all
the Times that I've listened to, uh,
all the music that he's made
with staying in everybody else,
the fact that they were actually
reproducing it live right there,
it was fucking nuts to me. You know, like
they're playing this, these songs for us,
this is fucking incredible,
right? So then the consequent,
and they just keep flip
flopping back and forth.
So stink finished his fucking song.
And then Peter Gabriel came back out,
but staying stayed
in fucking played bass on Peter's shit.
And then they just kept going back and
forth. And occasionally Peter did too.
And then instinct to a couple,
occasionally sting would walk off and
Peter would do his thing and then vice
versa, whatever. And finally
in the middle of it, um,
well maybe towards the
beginning and I can't,
they talk to the crowd a couple times
and they basically said that they would
just,
that a,
they both had bands in there kind
of competing with each other's band.
And Peter Gabriel's band was the red
band and strings was the blue band.
And then I then I finally know
to sell one drum has got red,
the other Vinnie's playing on
blue drums. And I, you know,
the way he told the story,
they would just, you know,
having a battle of the bands and they were
like, why don't we fucking go on tour?
All I can say is it was
an incredible night.
They played like all the fucking hits.
Peter Gabriel played big time
sledgehammer, shocked a monkey,
a red rain, um, staying played, fucking,
uh, sending out and it's so as
bunch of shit off. 10 Summers tails,
uh, some shit off of soul
cages. It was some police stuff.
It was fucking amazing. It was
fucking amazing. And uh, you know,
definitely a bucket list night.
But of course I was in the
crowd and at the Hollywood bowl,
the either drink wine,
which just gives me a brutal hangover oil.
They had these giant fucking beers.
Um,
which I gotta be honest with just does
nothing to me. It's just this, it's like,
it's like somebody just handed a job here,
why don't you drink this?
I give fuck and I get,
I get really nothing out of it.
That's why I like whiskey, you know,
it gives you all right there Fred.
And it's just a couple of
swallows. Um, but anyways,
Jesus Christ, the level of
musicianship, the backup singers,
one in particular was just, they kept,
you know, given her solos and stuff,
she was incredible. Um, got
to watch sting played bass,
got to watch them up close.
And the weird way he kind of comes
from the side rather than might've.
Bass players are kind of have their hand
up top rest of their thumb on the low
eat or whatever the fuck that string is.
And he's,
he looks like he's coming at it
from the side like a fucking crap.
It was really interesting.
But uh, anyways,
it was like some of the best
musicians you ever going to see.
So that's what I did Monday.
And then Tuesday we came in,
we did the Polish up after
the table read of episode 10,
and we recorded episode 10,
and that's it.
Or fucking Billy red faces on
fucking a summer vacation here.
And I got a nice, um, I
don't know where I got,
I got about nine days before I go off to
the European tour and I'm going to work
out like a madman still, you know, have
a couple, two, three drinks, whatever.
It work hard, play hard. What are you
gonna do? And I plan to have a nice,
um, I want to have a healthy
fucking tour over there. You know,
my wife isn't going on this run.
She's going to meet me over
there afterwards when take
a few days to hang out.
But uh, during the whole
run, it's a thrash.
It's like a different
city every fucking night.
So it's kind of boring and pointless.
You're really just saying to the
person who isn't doing shows like, Hey,
do you want to,
uh,
do you want to go over to Europe and
like pack and unpack every fucking day?
And they're like, yeah, no, I,
I don't in barely see anything.
That's what I'm offering you. So
what I want to do, the first side,
I'm working with Joe to Rosa in Dublin on
one of the shows. It's an earlier show,
which is odd to me, but whatever.
It's not my fucking deal. Right?
So that night's a wash. I mean,
we're going to get shit faced. Um,
then the next night I'm in Belfast
and I got to drive up and drive back.
So that night I'll fucking take it easy.
I can hear all the Irish people bitch.
And I already asked that being
a pussy drink every night.
I can't do it cause I got to make sure
I have good shows and then I got Gallway
but a chill for that than London.
Chill for the first night.
Second night I'm going to maybe,
you know, knock a few back.
And then I go to Scotland,
I believe, and uh,
two nights stair I'll just fucking chill.
And then the third night, you know,
that's going to be hard because it's,
it's the whole fucking,
the festivals going on over there.
Somebody may mean a ton of comedians.
That might be a rough one. And in
Germany, I don't gotta worry about Shit.
Who's kidding? Who? I've got to go out
and have some beers that you, okay.
It's going to get a little rough once I
get around Scotland. Who's kidding who,
but, but the, the first half of it. Oh,
that first half I'm going to be healthy.
Um,
does the Amsterdam in there?
Okay.
All right. You know what? This whole
thing just went off the rails. Okay.
For the first few nights in Ireland,
I think it's got to be okay one night
in London. Other than that, yeah,
it might be a little rough,
but if I can eat well,
the problem is when you go over to Europe
though, there's just this, just fuck it.
There's no treadmills. They, these
people just don't work out. It's weird.
They're not like necessarily fat,
but they're not in shape,
be that they're just sort of people,
you know what I mean? Like, yeah,
those arms, you know? Yeah.
They're connected to your torso.
They got like,
like, I think ellipticals
are illegal in England.
I don't know what the fuck it is.
Everybody's so jammed in there and that
little island, um, I'm fucking with you.
Obviously they have gyms over there,
so I'm going to try to hit treadmills
and shit as much as I can. And, um,
I already know how I'm going to open
my set when I'm over there, you know?
Um, it's, it's gonna be, it's
gonna be a great fucking time.
I can't wait to do it.
And I'm so site that we got the
first big chunk of work done on a,
on f is for family. I feel I
can, could finally fucking, uh,
could finally fucking chill out a
and coming up this week, by the way,
next Monday night is the second,
uh,
the two year anniversary of
the goddamn comedy jam and a,
they're going to have it at the rock
seat down on sunset boulevard. And,
um, rumor has it that I'm,
I might be down there,
I've gotta be down there for that show.
It's next Monday night if
you're in the area and uh,
I'm going to be busting out the fucking,
I'm going to bust out the
fucking green sparkle Ludwig Kit.
I'm going to bring it down there for that.
And I bought it two years ago.
I've never played it. I got this
71 Ludwig, it's fucking gorgeous.
And right as I got it,
I had it all set up and everything we got,
we had the water damage on the house.
Fortunately thank Christ it didn't come
down in the room with the drums were so
immediately went out and I got drunk
cases and I put the fucking things away.
And then, um, you know,
that was a year getting the house
fixed and they stayed in cases.
And then the next year my truck,
shit,
the bed I had to get the engine rebuilt
because it was going to do is put them
in the cases and take them
over to rehearsal space. I
was never able to do that.
And, uh, then my truck was better. And
then I started writing on f is for family.
So and just like that fucking two
years goes by. So I busted them out.
71 Ludwig Kit, I got the fucking Pisces
symbols, that whole bottom set up,
the 15 inch high hat, the 24 inch
ride, complete fucking overkill.
And I'm going to play a couple songs.
I actually sat down and played drums
today for the first time since like March,
I played like a drum kit,
you know,
other than a cup that I think I took
two lessons. But that's, you know,
different than sitting down and playing.
And I'll tell you right now,
I fucking sign, oh Jesus, I'm sorry.
Just blew out the uh, you're saying, oh my
God, that was fucking terrible. Terrible.
I better get my shit together by Monday
night or I'm just going to look like a
dose with a really nice kid
who can't fucking play. Um,
but I'm really looking forward to
doing that. And now let me do a little,
let me still read here.
The one advertising advertisement
that we have here for this week.
It's our old friends.
Oh, a little bit of Zip.
Yeah.
What are you hiding?
Are you hiring?
Do you know where to post your
job to find the best candidates?
Posting your job in one place isn't
enough to find quality candidates.
If you want to find the perfect hire,
you need to post all you need to post
your job on all the top sites and now you
can with fecund zip.com you can post jobs
to 100 plus job sites including social
media networks like Facebook and Twitter,
all with one single click.
Find candidates in any city
or industry nationwide.
Just post once and watch your
qualified candidates roll into zip,
right. They're easy to use. Interface,
no juggling emails or calls to your
office. Quickly screen candidates,
rate them and hire the right person fast.
Find out today why zip?
Yeah.
Rat root has been used by over 800,000
businesses and right now my listeners can
post jobs to zip recruiter up for free
by going to ziprecruiter.com/ [inaudible]
that's
ziprecruiter.com/borough one more time.
ziprecruiter.com/ [inaudible] all
right. There you go. Sorry about that.
I fucking thought I had the levels down.
I guess when you scream zip recruiter,
it's bound to go off the
rails after awhile. Um,
all right. So what else did I
want to talk about? Anything. Um,
somebody said that the New York Times
did this article and for the love of God,
I can't,
it they did it.
And talking about the legalization of pot
and was saying in states where weed is
become illegal, that, uh,
prescriptions have gone down drastically,
obviously for pain,
anxiety and all of that other stuff.
And it's really starting to become the
wonder drug man that all the hippies
always said. And I always
fucking was like, no, booze
is legal, blah, blah, blah.
And now it's really looking at like,
booze does way more fucking damaged. Oh,
but it's so delicious. Does way
more damage than we does. So,
according to this New York Times article,
according to this person who said it
was in New York Times article, um,
that the pharmaceutical lobbyists are
now going after legalized marijuana in
every state and that they're going to try
and start trying to fucking, you know,
basically go, oh my God, it's the
devil and Blah, blah, blah, blah, blah,
and get people to stop using it and
have all this shit about side effects.
But they start showing commercials and
all that. But I got to tell you, um,
the fact that this is the prop,
well maybe they won't.
I was gonna say the problem that they're
going to have is now that the cat's out
of the bag,
okay.
In these states are making
so much money in tax revenue,
right? Like this, this whole
thing going on in Denver,
because it's legal at a state level,
but not at a federal level.
You don't pay federal income tax. I don't
know. It's this weird fucking thing.
So nobody knows. Oh, I know
banks won't accept the money,
you know,
cause the banks,
federal banks or whatever can't accept
the money or whatever. So what these,
these people who grow the wheat are doing,
they're just buying up land.
So in Colorado, from what I
earned, once again, I never read,
I listened to people and
whatever they say to me,
I just considered it as as a fact,
right?
It's so much easier than doing research.
And you know what's great about it?
If you fuck up, it makes other
people feel smart, you know?
Nothing, nothing. Structure Ego
like correcting another human being.
That's a human being. That thing
can speak. It can drive a car.
Maybe you can fly a plane to be right.
I mean,
anybody can be right when there's a dog,
you know there's a fucking dog in the
room that doesn't do anything for you,
you know? But if it's another
fucking person, right,
who's got a thumb and shit
and can like hold a hammer,
if you fucking rad that just,
it's the greatest. I actually, ah,
that was,
it was actually 1897 yes.
1890 set Spanish American war.
Anytime you get to do that and then you
get to watch them be all fucking mad.
Like when I was talking about George Bush,
I thought everybody was making fun of
him because he did. He didn't dance well,
I didn't realize it was some
memorial service for, you know,
fallen officers or, or, uh, uh, an
officer in particular. I didn't, I didn't,
I didn't look, I just watched the
fucking video. Oh. And it just rolled in,
you know, everybody, oh, let's, let's,
let's fucking correct old Billy red beard.
You know,
everybody had a great fucking time doing
that. Um, but I'm off the rails here.
Okay. I still have to say, you know, you
know, as much as that was inappropriate,
which it was completely inappropriate,
obviously it was fun to see him, you know,
it was fun to see that he's
enjoying his retirement.
It's like when you see Letterman,
he let the beer go out.
He got rid of the fucking two
pages and it doesn't give a shit.
And when you looking at him, a lot
of people were saying, you know,
maybe George was a little drunk.
And, uh, you know what good for him,
good for that fucking guy
because that fucking guy,
he held it together for
eight goddamn years. Ya Know,
granted he gave a speech,
the way I read advertising,
granted we went and into Iraq because
there was weapons of mass destruction and
we never fucking found Eddie.
I love how that fucking story goes away,
but if you make fun of
fat people as a comedian,
all of a sudden you get in trouble. And
was like, what about this fucking guy?
This guy was playing fucking patty cake,
Patty cake bakers man at a
fucking funeral. Good Lord.
That guy is like, he's like, when
you talk about failing upwards,
I think, you know something.
There's something about that guy.
He's just smart enough to
know that he's not qualified.
And I think that that's why he drinks.
I think that's why it's to shit
that fucking vibe. He just, he,
he's kind of like Rodney, like he does
everything but tugs on his collar.
Like it'll tell you it's a rough
one, you know? Um, I dunno,
we'll see. We'll see what
the fuck happens. But what,
what was I talking about?
Oh yeah. In New York Times
they were saying that, yeah.
That these pharmaceutical
lobbyists, you know, we're,
we're going to be trying to fight
back to win back some of their money,
capitalistic society here. Right? What
do you do? Somebody's taken into year,
you're cutting into your territory. What
do you do? Yeah. You go on the offensive,
you start making up shit about him. You
lie, you know, that's what you do. So,
um,
I was going to say now that the cat
is out of the bag legally with weed,
um, and I think it's going to be
really hard. I was going to say,
because not only is it appearing to have
all these positive effects medically
according to stuff that people said
to me that they sit allegedly said
scientists did.
Um,
it also makes you feel good. That's
a rough one. You know what I mean?
Whereas all that other shit,
a lot of the pharmaceutical stuff
just sort of like numbs the pain,
all of that stuff.
And then you all of a sudden you get
onto the harder drugs and all that.
It's really fucking evil. You
know, I got a friend of mine,
she had problems with there. She couldn't
something going on with the shoulders.
She couldn't pick a fucking
arms up past the shoulder.
I refer to this same as suits that I
went to and she immediately was getting
results and she, she
was, according to her,
was stuck going to these
fucking doctors. I'm, look,
I'm not totally shitting on doctors
and stuff like that, but, uh,
I don't know.
It would be nice if the mainstream medical
would kind of let these other people
come in. You know what I mean?
It's just that I think the,
the people outside people outside of the
mainstream medical basically hospitals
and shit, I didn't know what mainstream
medical means. It just sounds right to me.
Right? Oh Jesus. I am so out of my fucking
element. You know what? It feels good.
I feel like I could start swinging
my arms at a funeral right now. Um,
when you get outside of hospitals
and stuff, you could actually,
most people you'll find don't
know what the fuck they're doing.
But if you find that gem that's outside
of the fucking studio system, basically,
they actually can cure, you know,
where a lot of this other shit is.
Just treating it and treating it and
treating it and treating it until you then
get symptoms for something else and
then treat that, treat that, treat that.
You know, I dunno. It's, it's
a fucking shady think and uh,
it's a big fucking problem and it
requires a lot of reading and research.
And I have to be honest with you,
I did none of that before I started
talking about seven minutes ago.
So there's that subject.
What are we up to here? 27,
almost 28 minutes.
Um,
this is all drum nerd shit, but I saw
Steve Smith is playing with journey again.
I'm going to have to go fucking see that.
You know,
I've never seen him when he
played with vital information.
I've never seen that guy play life, got
all this fucking DVDs and all that shit.
There's another one I got to check off
the fucking bucket list. But uh, um, if,
if that, that sting Peter Gabriel
tour is coming to your, uh,
neck of the woods, do not sleep on
it. Like I've never seen like staying,
having so much fucking fun and I've
never realized how like goofy and silly
Peter Gabriel was. He's got all
these sychronized dances and shit.
It's fucking hilarious.
And he's funny as hell and like sting
was just like really just taken a back
seat when letting Peter Schein
and all of that all, you know,
all that fucking drama that you
always heard in that band. The police,
it was great seeing sting just fucking,
I mean granted the guy still,
he looks better than he looked
when he was in the police.
It's fucking ridiculous.
Jesus Christ clean living
and fucking yoga and,
and whatever the fuck he does that
tantric where you come for like fucking 50
minutes, whatever that
shit is. It's unbelievable.
I mean the guy looks better than
he did fucking 30 years ago.
His hair somehow grew back.
I don't know.
I don't know what the
fuck this guy is doing.
He looks like it's a combination
of like a teen idol and he,
he's in like Mad Max all at the same time.
He never kind of would like,
as far as like his wardrobe though,
I will say that guy is never
sort of advanced past, um,
uh, that synchronicity tour, you know?
And when he yells, he always has to
put an o at the end of it. You know,
when he did Roxanne and then when he had
wanted to do a call and response with
the Cra, what the crowd
is going rock said, oh,
like where do they all come
from? He loves the, Oh,
I bet he does that. His castle, you
know, his wife yells up, you know,
up the fucking goddamn stone stairways,
what do you want for lunch? Lunch, lunch.
And he's up there has said which show?
It's fucking driving her nuts. Fuck does
he put, oh, at the end of everything,
just fucking say sandwich. All
right, you fucking cunt. What?
You get knighted and all of a sudden you
can put an o at the end of everything.
I don't know. Anyways, what am I doing
here? It was a fucking great show. Um,
all right, so I still have to go to
work tomorrow. Now we do the animatics,
I'll take you through the whole process.
Everybody over the next year as we wait
for this fucking thing that come out.
So once you write the thing, and once
you record it before the animated,
they have these things called animatics,
which is just rough sketches.
Okay. Of the scenes, the way that they're
going to drop, draw. Like, you know,
they look at the script and says,
you know,
frank walks into the house so
they know it's in the house,
but there's a lot of other stuff that
is sort of variables about where people
are standing and where they're sitting,
how they're eyes are moving and
all of that shit. And it's that,
this is where it gets a
little bit tedious. But, uh,
it was much harder the first season,
the second season.
Now everybody kinda knows how
everybody creates and shit.
So we go in now and we'll look at the
animatic for like the second first or
second episode. And you just look at, you
know, is the scenes go and you'd be like,
all right,
frank needs to be standing up here or
sue needs to be doing this or whatever.
And um,
I have to be honest with you,
I am decent at arm gestures,
but I'm really bad at the directing shit.
Like this should be a two shot that
should be a master and all that. Um,
not only make bad at it,
I have no desire to get good at it.
So that's a tough thing.
Like I don't give a shit that is that
there's nothing more boring to me then
that just sitting there going like,
this should be over this guy's
shoulder and this should be a two shot.
Can we Dolly in? Can we get
a fucking whatever the fuck
they say. And I just said,
I just glaze over.
It reminds me of when,
for whatever stupid fucking reason,
my junior year of high school,
like
I took Algebra two and
fucking trigonometry and it
was just like I fucking had
to go to summer school after Algebra.
I barely got out of that shit.
I got a fucking d minus in geometry
just because my teacher was cool.
I flunked it.
She gave me the d minus,
so I didn't have back to back going
to summer school and did this.
I mean I was lost by, I was done. I
was done three weeks into September,
Algebra two and trig was fucking over
and I ended up in fucking motherfucking
summer school again.
I swear to if my geometry teacher
didn't hook me up with a d minus,
I have had like a dynasty. I would have
three years in a row, a summer school,
fucking dope. Um, I dunno,
I'll tell you this right now.
This is how dumb I am is,
I can't even remember why I
even just fucking told you that.
What the hell was I talking about? I
just sat up in my whole memory, went,
what the fuck out of
his? Say what? Yo. Right.
Then I started talking about some, I
don't, I don't, I don't remember. Um,
but you know what the great thing is is
I don't have to remember anything else
who gives a shit because this is,
this is the a,
this is just me checking in on you.
Just peeking into your cubicle or maybe
you got an office. You've got a door. Huh?
You feel good about yourself. You
liked that door. You put stuff on it.
Do you close it and say,
no calls makes you feel good.
Then you close the door and you snicker
to yourself. Like I just said, no calls.
I'm the no calls guy.
Hold my calls.
Um, anyways. All right, that's
it. That's, that's a podcast. Uh,
please go see Peter Gabriel and sting on
tour and the amazing Vinny Coley, Yoda,
and everybody else in both of those bands.
Uh,
I should have known more than
names. I should have looked
it up, but, uh, you know,
I'm running around like a fucking
loan to tick. Um, and that's it.
If anybody can find that New York Times
article, I would really love to read it.
And um,
I'm also going to try to read up on all
that whole fucking European Union thing
for when I go over there just in
case anybody's a cut to me, uh,
about not knowing what the fuck's going
on in the world, which, which I don't. Um,
I do know that there was some sort of
fucking failed coup attempt in Turkey.
Jesus Christ. The only thing scarier
than trying to overthrow the,
the government is attempting
it and then failing.
This is one of the scariest
couple of paragraphs I ever read.
Turkish President Tay.
Yup.
T double why p Ertegun tapered again,
I'm declared a state of
emergency on Wednesday is he
widened a crackdown against
thousands of members of the
security forces judiciary to you,
you're airy,
civil service and academia
after a failed military coup.
All right, here's where it gets
scary. Erdogan, how you said,
said the state of emergency lasting three
months would allow his government to
take swift and decisive measures against
supporters of the COO and was allowed
under the constitution.
Yeah.
They're about to kill a
couple thousand motherfuckers.
Jesus.
That right there is that definition
and Odot, Jesus in the old right there,
Fred, right? There's no
code lotion in there.
MMM.
You're not cold. Lotion is, is
is your final meal on death row.
Yeah, man. We'll make you whatever you
want. Uh, you guys are sweet art. Yeah.
And then we're going to electrocute
you. Ah, Jesus. Then. All right. Um,
that's the podcast. Just checking in
on you. I'll see you guys again on, uh,
talk to you again on Monday.
And uh, um, that's it.
Thank you to everybody who helped
fix my fucking back. I feel great.
I'm in a great mood.
Please enjoy this music.
And then we got 30 minutes
of some throwback podcasts.
Greatest hits from a podcast in a year.
All right,
see
you.
[inaudible] [inaudible]
so I got that out of the way.
Then I had two days to hang in New York
and then I came down in New Jersey and
I'm like, this is going to be great.
I got the pressure Letterman off me.
That's off my fucking back.
And, uh, now what? Now.
What do I do? I get to go to one of
my favorite clubs in the country,
the stress factory I was already talking
to while Vinnie brand, the club owner,
he's got a boat. We were going
to go out on his boat on Sunday.
Everything was going to be great.
All the shows were fucking sold up.
Had a great time.
And then what happens?
These fucking nerds on the
weather channel. What do they do?
They turn out all the lights in this
studio and they put a flashlight under
their Chin
and just start scaring the living shit
out of people and you know what kills me
is every fucking time people buy into it.
I was joking about it all weekend.
I'm like, nothing's going to happen.
I'm in my whole tell them I don't
even have a fucking snickers bar.
Nothing's going to happen.
You're going to be fine.
All these people going out
gathering up fucking food for what
people do. You realize how long you can
go without food. Food is no big deal.
You need water. That's what the
fuck you need. That's what you need.
I'm actually looking here on a,
who gives a fuck.com?
How long can a person survive
without food and water? Uh,
basically it depends on a number
of factors such as body weight,
genetic variations, other
health considerations, whether
you're a fat fuck or not.
Uh, most importantly the presence
or absence of dehydration.
As long as you got water people,
you can basically go 46
to about 73 days without,
without food.
Then that was based on a 10 individuals
who died on a hunger strike and they all
died between 46 days and 73 days.
As long as they drank water.
If you don't have water,
I believe you dead in about three days.
All right,
so enough with the fucking milk and eggs.
Yeah,
Ali soccer moms now for the next fucking
three weeks. Who wants, who wants cereal?
Who wants to wait?
What you have in theory all and you're
having an Omelette isn't going to go to
waste.
He's fucking people telling you to fill
up your goddamn bathtub full of full of
full of water just in case
Jesus fucking Christ. I'd rather
die than drink out of my bath tub.
All right.
I wash my fucking dog in there.
Yeah.
Not Drinking out of that thing.
What?
Can I just stick my head out the
window and drink the raindrops?
I think those windows be cleaner.
Okay.
Then the God damn tub that I watched
my dog in and then hit with chemicals,
love stomach cancer.
By the time to fucking rescue boat comes,
you just get water.
Everybody get water.
Get yourself a couple of fucking zag
nut bars and they'd go down, go down,
go down to a Goddamn fucking
seven 11 and go buy an $8 Poncho.
You find you're in a house.
You find
he's fucking people. Whether Chino much
they cost me half my God damn gig money.
Yeah.
We could've had shows.
We could add show Saturday night.
It was raining hard Saturday night.
It could have done both shows.
Everybody could have
got their fucking labs.
Everybody goes home and then
at night [inaudible] Boegli
the fucking hurricane or hurricanes
come through the northeast. It's like,
it's like an old price fighter.
By the time it comes to us,
it's all fucking punch drunk and people
have no business standing out in it
cause they should've gotten knocked out,
have no fucking problem than they just
sit there laughing at it. All right.
Yeah.
That's what it is. That's what a
hurricane is in the northeast. It,
you know when it's down south,
it's Cassius clay.
Right before he becomes Muhammad Ali.
By the time it gets up to Jersey
in New York, it's fucking Ali.
When he fought Larry
Holmes every fucking time.
Yet these people,
they all run out
the weather channel.
How long you guys,
you guys think Fox News
lies to you or CNN?
Depending on what side of the
political fence you're on. You want it.
You want to see some lies
put on the weather channel.
Anytime there's a storm
scaring the shit out of you.
Every time there's going to be,
it's going to be four to six Sanchez.
Holy Shit.
That's almost up to my calves.
How will I ever get to where the food is?
46 inches.
Jesus Christ.
Yeah.
Who are they talking to?
80 year olds.
Okay.
Even then, you know, 80 year old
people, they'll be fine. You are.
They're already wearing a sweater.
Okay.
They're dressed for a blizzard year round.
Does anybody you work
for the weather channel?
Does anybody who listened to my
podcast? Can you please tell me? Well,
who's behind you? I think the
supermarkets are behind that, right?
Ralph's Shaws,
Gelson's fucking whole foods.
All of them. That's their payola. You
know with the big time corporations,
they wait for the political elections.
That's when they start throwing their
money around and start calling up a truck
full of hookers to go blow some
Bible belt and Douche bag, right?
I'm married. I got five kids. I love my
wife and I love Jesus. Support the troops,
right? And then what do they
do? They throw a big pile
of money at them. Have two,
three whores dropped to their knees
and next what? Next? What happens next?
He comes on his blue blazer.
That's what happens.
Everybody goes all over his red tie
and then he goes out. Jesus Christ.
All right, you got me, you
own me. You got video of it.
Just tell me what you want me to do.
I will pass any bill you want
me to pass for the love of God.
Don't let my wife see that.
Yeah.
That's basically how that
works. Well though, let's,
let's stay on track here. Okay.
The fucking weather. She, does
anybody listen to my podcast work?
Did they ever work?
Can you give me any sort of anonymous
behind the fucking scenes over there? Why?
Every time it's just going to rain.
Okay.
Do they scare the living shit out of us?
Why is that?
You know,
how often are they right?
It always is.
It's always downgraded to a tropical
storm. By the time it comes here,
someone was telling me the entire
east coast, the way it's shaped,
that's from years of hurricanes comes
riding into Florida and Georgia,
South Carolina gives it a nice fucking
uppercut to their southern balls and then
slows the fuck down right
over the Carolina, Virginia.
Yep.
Then what?
Trimet hits DC. Barack Obama's out on
the porch drying off his nuts with those.
Nice. When that Nice
Hurricane Wind, right?
Oh Jesus. I don't know what I'm talking
about. I just want to fucking go home.
I was actually thinking, you know, when
you, you know, when you fuck up in life,
feel like God, if I could just go back
48 hours, Howard do this differently.
There's an Avis in the lab of my,
uh,
uh, Jesus as a callback. Remember
this time we left this comedian,
he was always late.
We had a car service to the airport.
We were so sick of waiting for and
we were going to miss our flight.
We just took off with that
and we said fuck them.
And we got halfway to the airport and he
calls up all pissed off. It's like, Yo,
where the fuck boy you put a fuck. Why
you like dude, we waited for 20 minutes.
You didn't show up. And
he's like, I was in the
yeah.
And that became the catch
phrase for the rest of the tour.
I was in the lobby anytime you fucked up
and people will call it calling you on
some shit. You went over your time. No I
didn't. Yes you did. I was in the lobby.
Oh. And it made us laugh. I
don't know if it made you laugh.
I don't give a shit what he
expected from me. I'm, I'm stranded.
I feel like I'm being held hostage in
my captures. Forgot about me, you know,
or maybe it was just all a practical joke.
I have no idea.
Yeah.
So whatever.
Here I sit.
Yeah.
You know, is there anything sadder than
a stranded comedian with no shows to do?
Yeah.
They got a 24 hour gym downstairs.
I haven't used it.
Yeah.
Um, but talking to you guys about all
the way to eat, the way to lose weight.
I haven't been doing it dummy pizzas.
I had fish and chips today
at fucking to hamburgers.
This is all during the hurricane.
Big Bad hurricane Irene
fucking over rated.
Ugh.
So I'm sitting here, I realized,
you know, tomorrow I'm like,
finally I'm getting the fuck out of
here. Go home. Could see my girl,
I can see my dog,
right?
Yeah.
Can have a good fucking time,
you know,
can cruise around in my hybrid.
That's what I was looking
forward to doing. And, uh,
all of a sudden I realized that
was stranded here. So what do I do?
Do I handle it like a man? What do
I start cursing like a little bitch?
You know what the answer is? So once I'm
done having my fucking temper Tantrum,
excuse me, I a sufficient
chips. I say, all right,
I'm going to rent a fucking
rent a movie here in the hotel.
So I go to rent a movie.
It's called catching hell to documentary
about the guy with the glasses who was
at the cubs game, who, uh,
reached up for that foul ball that Moisis
I Lou was allegedly going to catch.
So I hit the info to watch the
trailer and they're talking about,
they got this guy on,
they're gone and says how you
worked for sports illustrated?
And his assignment was defined,
this guy,
whatever the fuck his name was, Steve, Ms
Arac, I don't know. I'm not from Chicago,
so I don't give a shit. I don't know what
his name is. Alright, his is, he goes,
my assignment was to find this guy
and he goes, my heart sank. You know,
because I actually felt for this guy,
I didn't want to go see him and
I said to my editor, editor,
why can't we just leave this guy alone?
Can we just leave the guy alone?
And he goes, no, go find them.
And then they shot showing
the highlights of this dude.
And for those of you don't know the play,
basically the cubs have won the
world series since 1908. You know,
they're a game away from going there.
Five outs away from going to the fucking
world series. Sorry to all the cub fans.
Just hit fucking mute for
the next 10 minutes. Um,
yeah,
they got the five outs
away. So some dude, right?
A lefthanded batter hits a slicing
foul down the left field line.
It's right there.
And uh,
the cubs left field or Moises Alou, he's
got a chance to make a play and all the,
all these fans reach up to
grab the ball. But the, the,
it just hits one guy and a Moises Alou
flips out cause he doesn't catch it and
he sort of yells towards the fans. Like,
what the fuck? I could have caught that.
And then after that the
wheels start falling off,
but they got a double play ball.
Gonzales could have made it buddy boated
it and first and then they let up eight
runs,
they lose the game and then they lose
games seven and then everybody wants to
murder this fucking kid.
So this guy is basically sold that.
They're going to basically interview
the guys as far as I could fucking tell.
Am I Jesus Christ? That's fascinating.
I won't let me watch this. God,
God knows that got the time.
Let me watch this movie.
All right. So I go to order
it and it doesn't allow me to,
so I got to call downstairs
to have the uh, you know,
I don't know what somebody had kids or
something. He didn't want to run a porno,
so had to get that,
you know,
switched over so I could actually
be an adult and pick out a movie.
So I watched this fucking thing.
All right. About the cubs,
about their history,
about their curse,
about this poor bastard that
got used as the scapegoat.
This is what I was sold. This is
the bill of goods. I was sold.
Okay. After 36 hours of being lied
to by the fucking weather channel,
I want some truth in my life. This is what
you're telling me. This thing is about,
this is how your advertising
and I want to see it.
Do you know what the first
15 minutes of that movie was?
It was taking me through the red sox
in 1986 as they excrutiatingly slowly
replayed the bill Buckner incident
and I'm sitting there watching it.
All of a sudden I'm looking
at bill Buckner. I'm like,
what did I order the wrong fucking thing?
I don't want to see this shit.
Do you understand? This is like my
baseball nine 11 I don't ever want,
you know that like the 10 year anniversary
of nine 11 is coming up and like they
, I don't want to watch any of that. I
don't ever want to see that footage again.
Like how the fuck could you ever forget
it? It's absolutely fucking horrific.
Horrific.
I don't want to see it.
I don't need to see it to remember it.
I'll never forget. It's our Pearl Harbor.
My grandmother still doesn't like
Japanese people because of Pearl Harbor.
Okay.
If she can remember that shit,
I don't think I've got a problem members
something 10 fucking years ago. Okay.
So now, anyways, total
total fucking tangent there.
So I'm watching this thing and for the
first 20 just to warn red sox fucking
fans,
the first fucking 50 minutes of this
movie is the bill Buckner thing.
The thing that we left behind.
It's so funny because Paul Versey just
texted me then the night before during
the hurricane,
typical fucking Yankee Fan.
Typical Yankee Fan living in
the past, right? He texted me,
he goes, hey bill, what was, what
was worse for a Red Sox Fan? He goes,
Buckner or Aaron Boone
just out of nowhere.
We weren't even talking baseball.
And I was just like,
I was like neither do to that.
It's like,
I don't even think about that shit
anymore to be honest with you.
And then he gets mad at me. A typical red
sox fan, terrible fucking answer. Blah,
blah, blah, blah, blah. It's like, I
don't know what he wanted out of me.
So I just texted him
back. It's like, dude,
I haven't thought about that shit since
2004 it's over. You know what it is.
It's Yankee fans used to be able to bully
red sox fans about that shit because
we hadn't won one forever, you know?
So they just, I think that they,
they miss,
they're kind of like our big brother who
just beat the shit out of us forever.
And then one day we were the same height
and kick the shit out of him, you know?
And then they just stay. It was
over. We're not scared anymore.
We expect to beat you.
It's fucking over.
And I think they still
don't know what to do.
You know?
Wait a minute,
we used to tease you and we used to
always win and yeah, now you don't,
now you don't.
Now we've got this,
the biggest choke of all fucking
time has hung around your neck.
That'll never be beaten.
When do you guys think another
$220 million $10 million team,
whatever the fuck it was with five first
ballot hall of famers are going to lose
four games in a row,
have to be an up three games to none.
I'm asking you to a fucking team that
hasn't won a world series in like a
hundred years. Right. He had just
asked me about that and I swear to God,
I had not thought about Buckner.
Yeah.
Since like oh four it was fucking,
it was over. It was great.
I don't even give a shit now. I don't
even give a shit. And I gotta tell you,
it's phenomenal to sit down and watch a
red sox game and expect something good
to happen.
And when something bad happens,
you get upset at the player rather than
some sort of specter or some sort of
ghost or some overly Boodley horseshit.
Right?
So
I'm going to watch this fucking thing
and all of a sudden out of nowhere,
this show and I made two,
they broke,
they almost broke down bill Buckner more
than they broke down the poor cubs fan.
And in the end, the dude doesn't get
the interview. There's no interview.
They just taught all that.
But what I still recommend it,
I'm still wrecking recommending
it because they show,
um, they talk to the people. Some people,
I guess they found that people
who like through bear at him,
they talked to the security guard.
He was removing them,
giving them shit that he now feels bad
that he did and they have the footage of
him.
Okay.
Going out of the ballpark and
putting the jacket over them.
It's fucking amazing what
happens to this dude.
And uh, I, I totally
recommend it, but I just,
they should have been some sort
of warning for a red sox fan.
It was like walking,
go run into your old psycho girlfriend,
somebody who stopped you or something.
Just somebody who just hadn't
even thought about 2047 years.
I haven't thought about that shit.
I haven't even thought about that.
And fucking seven years and all of a
sudden this documentary about the cubs,
they just go blow by blow through
the Buckner thing. Cause they,
I guess they wanted to show
how Buckner was used as escape goat,
despite the fact Bob Stanley
through the wild pitch.
And now this kid was used
as a scapegoat for the cubs,
despite the fact that Gonzales
booted a fucking double play ball,
which would've got him out
of the [inaudible]. Um,
I dunno, it's, I, it's
definitely interesting, but
I was, I was more than upset.
Yeah.
That and, and Eleanor and they
even show the Aaron Boone home run,
which I don't even remember because
that was basically annoying for about 12
months,
you know?
Huh.
Because it was immediately rectified
and,
uh,
but it was just one of those things. I
don't know. I don't fucking know, but I,
I gotta be honest with you,
I never really felt bad for cubs fans.
I never did because, you know, they
didn't have that anger did the Midwest,
I don't know what it is. They're
positive. I don't know what it is.
They just didn't have that
anger or misery, you know,
with the red sox back in the day, it was
every Yankee success was our failure.
And with the cubs, they
just, you know, hey,
let's play two zippity Doo Dah.
I was like a big fucking keg party,
you know.
It's like they didn't even give a shit.
Even their curse was stupid.
The curse of the goat.
It was just fucking stupid.
MMM.
Made no sense. It's a ballpark. You
got to go. It doesn't belong here.
It's going to shit all over the place.
Get it Outta here. I curse you. Really?
MMM.
Any fucking waste.
So they actually bring up what like
scapegoat am actually ruining this entire
thing.
You probably don't have to fucking run it.
They start talking about what is,
how they came up with that terminology.
The scape goat and it went
back to religion. Oh Gee.
That I guess back in the day, I don't
know what the hell religion it was.
They're all fucking stupid when you really
get down to it other than they're due
on to other stuff that every religion has.
Um,
they would basically have a goat.
They bring a goat in and I'm thinking,
all right, they're going to sacrifice
it or whatever. And they wouldn't have,
the priest would lay his hands on a goat
for once instead of some unsuspecting
child.
Oh, a little molestation joke for
you. How'd you guys like debt? Huh?
Do you like dead on your Monday? Do you
think that that was crossing the line?
Well, fuck you. I'm
stranded in New Jersey.
Okay.
Fucking New Jersey, Huh? Jesus
Christ. What a bunch of animals.
It amazes me about New Jersey is
how they still support Jon boat.
Jon Bon Jovi or the Bon Jovi ban.
To the point that that band
can sell out giant stadium
still.
Yeah.
Unbelief. Let's Jersey Foya. It's
70,000 people singing, singing along.
Lay Your hands on me.
Your love is not bad medicine.
Zach
[inaudible].
Whoa.
Fucking acid wash as far as
the eye can see. Dirty Jersey.
Actually I think New Jersey underrated
is New Jersey. It's fucking phenomenal.
All of these New York's snobs,
Paul Versey being one of them.
I'm really trashing him this week.
Paul versus your typical New York snob
and I hope you're listening to this. Paul,
our help on somebody sends this to you.
Um,
yeah, he's, he's a snob.
He's one of those guys who just thinks
because he's on the other side of an
imaginary line that all of a sudden,
I don't know what that
the trees are greener.
The grass is Grad or know
what the fuck it is. You know,
I really realized like most New Yorkers
Judge New Jersey on their drive to
Newark Airport, when they go by all
those chemical plants, look at it.
It's so fucking shit hole. Oh, right.
Despite the fact that all some of
the most major celebrities live here.
What do you think they live
next to the plant? You know,
all those fucking guys down on Wall
Street, the children of the Illuminati,
they all live out there and red
bank with their fucking, uh,
Rockefeller estates. I know, but they,
they got New Jersey license plates.
Therefore it must suck. Anyways,
let's get back to the
scapegoat. Um, so basically the,
uh,
you know,
the priest would take a day
off from dental and kids
and he'd lay his hands on a
farm animal and one would think he
would grab the horns and then start
fornicating. But this, that's another
story. What they would do with the,
with the goat is he lay his hands on
it and he would basically, somehow,
I guess after everybody
confessed to this douche bag,
he would then place all of the sins on
the goat and then they would just banish
the goat and send it out of town with
all the sins in everybody's souls.
We're going to be clean again, but this
is the funny thing. As the goat left,
people would line up on either
side of the street and they would,
they would heckle the
goat and jeer at them. Eh,
you fucking adulterous paces shit.
Yeah.
Why don't you check off again?
You cut just yelling about the sins
that they did. I don't know what it was.
Yeah. It keeps stealing from the
pot at work. You selfish prick,
yelling at a farm animal.
You know, I swear to God,
I would love to have a segment on here
of all this stupid fucking things that,
that, that they do in religion
that people, you know,
there's no fucking way,
there wasn't somebody like me back
then going through, this is fuck,
why are we yelling? At a goat, you know?
I mean, I hope you, you banged somebody
fucking wife. You stole money from work.
You know,
you're booted an old lady in the ass.
Do you really think it's in the
goat now and it's just walking?
I just don't fucking get it. Even if
they filled you head up with it as a kid,
at some point you gotta be looking
at it like this is a fucking goat.
It's got nothing to do with it.
So anyways,
they would just cheer at this thing
and they'd send it out of town and then
everybody would be absolved. And I
don't know where to go. Would go.
Sometimes they say they take the goat
and they would throw it off a cliff,
you know? I know it's extra painful
for me because I fucking love goats.
I really do.
I was actually feeding some this morning.
I don't know what it is about them. I
think they're fucking hilarious. You know,
I got this buddy. He lives out here,
right? It's got this giant house,
there's all this fucking land and he's
got farm animals, farm animals on it.
And I'm thinking he's got these fucking
things because he's like me. He's,
he likes, he thinks goats or
funny or whatever, and it isn't.
I found out that there's tax laws
out that if you farm on your land,
you only have to pay
property taxes on one acre.
So he went out and got these goats.
He doesn't even give a shit about him.
Yeah.
Can you fucking believe that?
He's got like 10 goddamn goats and he
has to go out there with this bucket of
feed every day.
He's got to feed these things and it's
hard as an in it. That's what kills me.
Okay?
It's just just pay.
It's just pay the taxes.
If I,
it would be worth it to not get up there
with that lunch pail a cheerios every
fucking morning,
okay?
Jesus fucking Christ. What is wrong? It's
just money. It's paper. Who gives a fuck?
You just, you know, work a couple extra
hours. Fuck it. What do I owe you?
You sit down,
you write numbers on a piece of paper,
you stick it in a magic envelope,
you'll fucking Likud you send it out next.
Jesus Christ. You're gonna sit there
and have a bunch of goddamn livestock
is fucking guys swear to God.
Okay.
If, if, if you had a Giraffe, oh, what
do you guys want? What do you guys want?
Hang on. This is the hotel.
Yeah, sorry about that.
I had to go answer the phone.
I couldn't even figure out
how to work the fucking phone.
He's probably somebody above me.
I was probably yelling too loud.
God knows what they all mad about.
Yeah.
And now just think about some of
the Shit I've made fun of. You know,
Jesus beastiality and Bon Jovi
and they all hold the same
weight here in New Jersey. Um,
the hell was I talking about? Oh yeah,
this fucking guy. I swear to God, if he,
if he would get a giraffe, you
get like five giraffes. If,
if he only had to pay
like a quarter acre tax,
that always amazes me when people
like that in the money, you know,
I mean, I obviously give a fuck about
money. I want to have enough to survive.
But,
uh,
the amount of shit that didn't
work and I never took it back,
just blows my eye.
I've probably kept at least 25 grand with
his shit. That doesn't work in my life.
I just gotta you gotta be shit
they see as what the fucking prime.
He's fucking pieces of shit and I go off,
then my girl goes last year, return it.
Ah, I'm not doing that shit. Standing
down there with the sales slip,
like some angry old fucking lady.
I'm not doing it.
Who the have would be calling me now?
I'm all self conscious.
I would have or if I'm too loud,
knock on my door. I sweat it.
Got Up. But it was the Bon
Jovi Shit. Um, anyways,
let's get on with the podcast.
This is the money morning podcast.
Everybody if you to this podcast
welcome. Um, this is, yes,
and if you're thinking this is extra
dirty and extra angry this week. No,
this is how it is every fucking week.
All right. Do one of these every week.
I do them on Monday mornings because I
know most people hate their jobs or they
hate their commute. They hate their
spouse or they hate themselves,
you know, and they
need, they need a break.
And it's also a great way to whore
out wherever the fuck I'm going to be.
Uh, speaking of which I
am going to be in, uh,
Columbus,
Ohio at the funny bone down at the mall,
not bragging on the, uh,
September 9th, 10th and 11th.
That is my next gig. I'm going to try
to go to that, uh, Ohio state game.
You know, it's in September. That's
always a dangerous one. You know,
to go to a college football game in
September. Who they play it. Huh?
They playing Wentworth
technical institute.
You know, I'm new to college football
the last couple of years and ever deadly.
That's what they do.
They've got all their cupcake games
in the beginning of the year. And, uh,
I guess these other colleges,
uh, they pay money to,
to play these giant teams and get
the living shit kicked out of him on
television just to,
I don't know what to expose to get TV
exposure for their school. I have no idea.
Speaking of scapegoats,
their entire fucking division three team
goes out there a bunch of up against a
bunch of roided up division one guys
or whatever the fuck they're doing now.
I don't know. And then they get the shit
kicked out of him, but I don't know,
every once in awhile an
Appalachian Mountain state
community college will beat a Michigan.
So I don't know who they're playing that
weekend, but I'm going to go down there.
I was looking forward to it until I spent
fucking 14 straight days on the road.
But, uh, anyways, the podcast.
Um, anyways, if you want it,
if you want to me to read any emails,
any questions you have in a year,
underrated overrated,
send them to
bill@thempodcast.com if you'd like
to follow along on the podcast, go to
www.themmpodcast.com.
Now,
a lot of you guys keep just
typing in mm podcast.com and like,
what the fuck?
I can't find it.
It's the [inaudible] podcast.com
like the Ohio State University.
Okay. That's what it is. That's where
all the youtube videos videos are.
That's where you can contact
me and all of that stuff.
We have a donation button
if you'd like to, um,
donate any sort of money
towards the podcast, we'd
greatly appreciate it. And uh,
we also have the podcast select and
this is where I interview interesting
people.
I've only done one of them,
but I like to speak of them as if
it's a giant library. I got one,
they're 99 cents is a great
to contribute 99 cents,
and he gets something if you want
to listen to NFL football star,
right tackle [inaudible] from Salaam.
Talk about trying to rip
somebodies voicebox out as they,
as that guy tried to fucking break his
arm, that interview was there and a,
I will be doing Monday morning podcast
selects as I meet interesting guests.
That's how I'm doing them. All right. When
somebody, uh, somebody different. Okay.
Because,
uh,
I don't want to interview other comedians.
I just feel too many
podcasts of doing that.
I've done too many podcasts
talking about comedy.
I don't have any comedy stories left.
I really don't.
And I gotta be honest with you,
aside from a couple of
people who are really good
interviewers, the Mark Marin's,
Joe Rogan's and that type of shit,
uh,
I probably should've saved
most of them for, ah,
the unmasked that I did.
Yeah.
With, uh, Ron from Ron and Fez,
I dunno where he can find that,
but I did one of those this past week and,
uh,
I just been running my Yap all
fucking week. Liz, why don't,
why don't we get to something entertaining
here? Uh, somebody sent me a, um,
this youtube video or this week,
you really have to watch it. Okay.
It's one of those shows. It's
basically, it's a rip off of the view.
It's for broad sitting around and they
got, you know, the same thing. You know,
they got the older one,
they got the sexy one,
they got the one who was fat and then
got her fucking stomach tied up like a
goddamn balloon. Not now. She's dropping
weight faster than a junkie. Right.
I don't even know if that's true.
I just looked around him, you know,
they got the racially mixed chick and
they all got on their fucking shoes.
Right. The little outfits.
Uh, hang on a second.
Hang on a second. Somebody's knocking.
I'll let you know what this is.
Yeah.
All right.
You guys aren't going to believe this
shit that was security and they just said
that they, they had a noise
complaint. It was a lot of, uh,
the guy comes, I go to the door. Right?
This is so pathetic that it 43.
I'm getting reprimanded.
I feel like I'm in fucking high
school and I talk like it too. Um,
let me just the levels here or maybe
turn up yours cause I don't want to get
kicked out of here.
Um,
until you open the door and there's a
security guard and he goes, uh, you Ben.
And I'm like,
no.
Okay.
Cause I know he,
I know that he knows my name is bill.
Well this is the thing when
security interrogates you,
you never offer any information,
you know,
are you bent now?
And then I just looked at him like,
is there anything else I can
help you with? And he's like a,
he looks down on a piece of paper.
Oh are you bill? And I was like, yes,
yes I am. And he goes, uh, yeah, we, uh,
we get a noise complaint from
people on either side of you.
Uh, these are VIP rooms on either side
of you. And uh, talking about, uh,
three loud, there's a lot
of cursing. And I'm like,
all right. He goes, is there anyone else?
No. Oh wait, wait, wait. He told me,
can you step out in the hall?
And I go for what? He goes,
I need to step out in the
hall. And I said, for what?
And then he just goes into a Spiel,
you know,
what the fuck do I need to
step out in the hall for?
Am I gonna be able to hear you better?
You know the rack like your God
Damn State trooper with you,
you're fucking sport coat on.
But as the name of the hotel on the Lapel,
I'm supposed to step out in the hall.
I don't know who you are,
right?
I'm such a Dick. It's ridiculous.
Right? So I made them basically say,
I just didn't doorway. And he asked me,
he goes, is there anybody else in there?
And I was like, no. And then yeah,
that's what he basically
said that I'm being too loud.
Jesus Christ. I was cursing, I
think it was when you realized,
he said there's people on
either side trying to sleep.
And I was singing Bon Jovi songs
at the top of my fucking lungs.
All right.
And I was also talking about
beastiality and I was trashing Jesus.
You know what? This hotel is cool as hell.
Cause when you really think about it,
they probably should have
kicked me up. Um, all right,
so this is going to be my voice for the
rest. This is bill on punishment voice.
I'd like to apologize to everybody
here at the Sheridan. Um,
anyways, you know what some rich
costs on the other side of the door,
that fucking piece of one of those
really fancy glasses that they think came
from France but actually came
from a fucking pottery barn. Um,
if you can hear me,
go fuck yourself.
This is what you get for nuke in the
economy. Um, all right. So anyways,
so I'm watching this show, these
four fucking broads on it. Okay.
Listen nothing to Irb. Oh, he told me this
is, this is your one and only warning.
Next time you'll be
rejected from the hotel.
He had such hacky security,
uh,
like terminology, you
know, I don't fucking know.
I T do you know how bad I just want to
yell content at the top of my lungs right
now and get ejected from the fucking
hotel just so I can get out of Jersey?
Maybe I should call up Paul version.
Tell me to, you don't fuck that.
That's what I'm gonna
do after this podcast.
I'm calling up Paul [inaudible] and
I'm having them come down and get me.
All right. You know, fucking
threaten me next time I come up here.
What do you my fucking Dad
fucking douchebag
Christ. I swear to God. You know what's
funny about the male voice is it, uh,
is it carries you have another set
and there's a couple next door.
You can never, the woman's voice,
you just hear the guy every
once in a while ago. Uh, Lou.
Yeah. Well the WHO? Yeah.
You'd never hit the broad, so
I'm probably going to get kicked
out. What do I do? Go Fuck Yourself.
I'll take a cab back to New York.
Yeah.
Then they prop.
Of course,
they probably won't show up
because they're still afraid.
Afraid of the weather channel. Um, anyway,
so these four fucking brides are on TV,
right?
And they ended up there talking
about that guy that doing that story.
You know that story where that
dude got his dick cut off.
I'm gonna have to raise the levels here.
There we go. How's that? Is that better?
All right. So they're talking about
that guy who got his dick cut off
his wife, drugged him, tied him to a bed,
cut his dick off, threw it in a
garbage disposal and turned it on.
And it was basically because
he wanted to get a divorce from
her. She mutilated. And um,
she ended the guy's fucking
life and he solved quality.
Life is over and these women are
talking about it and lo and behold,
it's fucking hilarious to them.
They had all they could do to keep a
straight face during the first minute of
setting up the story.
And then all the jokes come and they're
laughing their fucking asses off.
It's the funniest fucking thing ever.
And this right here.
It's because of that type of shit that I
don't feel that I am massage monistic I
just don't,
I think that I am just like women.
I trashed women the way they trash guys.
It's just nobody pays attention
to the broads. They don't.
Do you think of a guide mutilated a woman
in any shape or form that four guys on
a pregame NFL show would be
laughing about it. You know,
Sharon Osborne was the guest and she goes,
somebody asked,
do you think the guy deserved? And she
goes, well, it depends on what he did.
You know,
I mean that thought is totally overlaps.
The thought of those morons in the
Middle East who cut women's clits off,
you know,
it's fucking medieval thought
and it's just considered silly.
I don't know what it is.
I don't know.
But it maintains what
I've always fucking said,
that women will do it to you exactly
what they don't want you to do to them if
you let them.
And I think why so many guys are miserable
in marriages is they get married to
fucking young before they really know
how to stick up for themselves in a
relationship. And that's why
before you know it, yeah,
married and all your shit is either in
the basement of the garage and she's
barely touching it and a,
and you're wondering what the fuck
happened to your life. You know,
I dunno.
The video is,
is going to be up on the [inaudible]
podcast.com. You know something.
This is actually,
I like this talking like this.
This is very challenging to try and
be funny with a late night DJ voice.
All right, this next chunk of the
podcast goes out to the ladies. Ladies,
if you're out there and you're single,
hang in there,
there's a date rapists on the horizon.
This next song right me by
nirvana goes out to all you.
Um,
I know there's somebody,
some Vanderbilt on either side
and may going Keith cursing again.
Um, anyways, uh,
being on the road or do they want to
talk about bitches laughing at Dick being
cutoff already talked about that,
wanting to go home, talked about that.
All right. Last week, uh, I was,
I was showed that youtube clip about
that guy running on that soccer field and
getting, uh, you know,
getting beat down by the cops and then
the crowd overwhelms the cops and beats
down the cops.
And I wanted to hear from the police
officers to just ask basically why they're
such dicks when they pull you over. I'm
not in a judgment that way, but just,
I'm just basically asking the
question the way all drivers talk.
So we have a kite responding here. He
says he built, not all cops are assholes.
Some are just lazy. Uh, the summer
after my sophomore year, oh, no, no, no,
no. This is a different one. We'd
have fucker's the one from the cop.
That's the one I want to hear. Oh,
here we go. Here we go. Here we go.
Let's see if I can read this before
being ejected from the hotel. Uh,
you're not going to be the
worst is if I do get injected.
This guy's gonna be standing here,
uh,
with this security fucking
jacket on in my hotel room,
watching me gather my things.
So once again,
I already have a game plan for that.
If I come,
if there's another knock at my door,
I'm not opening it.
I'm going to look through the people
and I'm talking through the door.
So we opened the door please.
And I'm going to go, why?
Uh, uh, cause and I'm just
going to ask him straight out.
Am I being ejected from the hotel?
Uh, yes sir. You need to let me, uh,
and I'll just bolt the door and
I'm going to be like, listen,
I'm gonna gather my things. I'll be out
there in five minutes. You just sit tight.
All right.
You with no fucking badge.
All right. What are you going
to do? Take off your shoe?
Is that what you're gonna do? Train.
Throw it through the crack in the door.
It's not going to hit me.
What
a fucking asshole. Can you step out
into the lobby until the hallway police
go fuck yourself.
Huh?
You fucking half a cop.
You half a security guard?
Well I step out into the
hotel. Yeah, no I won't
locate then I'll just just stay there.
Then you douchebag.
Um, anyways, this plow ahead.
So here's a cup a day. Um,
okay bill.
Uh,
the thing about this job is basically
that we have no fucking idea who we are
dealing with at any given time.
Just because someone looks sweet and
innocent and just because the situation
isn't likely to escalate doesn't mean
that they're not capable of murder or that
the situation may go pear shaped quickly.
I don't even know what that means.
Yeah,
pear shaped. I didn't want to
shape is a pair of shape. Like
what? What, what shape is it before it
goes pear shaped? Is it an apple shape?
Listen Buddy, he can't talk
shop cause you're gonna lose me.
I'm not that bright a guy. Um, anyways,
I can't tell you how many times
that someone said to me like,
I'm going to do anything. People. Oh, what
about that person running upstairs? Hi,
can you reject that eight, eight year
old on the fucking hotel. All right.
[inaudible] you know, I feel,
I feel like right now like, uh,
okay.
Either I'm announcing a golf match or um,
Um, I'm reporting live from
a hostage situation. Okay.
There talking to him right now, he still
has the weapon up to the woman's head.
You can clearly see that
she's frightening. Okay.
There's somebody flanking him on
the left. Oh, he doesn't like, okay.
He's fired a shot. It missed and hour
they just took them down. Oh my God.
He's been shot in the head
and they have the woman. Um,
anyways, here we go. Plowing
ahead here. Um, so anyways,
the amount of time just got pulls people
over and the person behind the wheel
says like, I'm going to do anything.
People think that I know. Oh,
the people,
the drivers and stuff think that I know
them their whole lives and know that
their Cape, that they're incapable
of harming anyone. But I don't,
I always think back to the academy and
all the videos we watched of cops getting
killed or nearly killed because they
made one mistake or had a lapse in the
paranoia that keeps us
safe. See that? I knew it.
I knew it was something that they
showed them at the academy. I said,
another thing to remember is that there
is a gun at every call and every traffic
stop the gun on my belt.
No Man is invincible and a lucky
punch can knock me unconscious,
leaving me vulnerable to take to them
taking my weapon and killing me or others.
For this reason, we like to keep some
distance. We don't like to be touched.
And above all,
we can't allow people to get the
opportunity to take control of our weapon.
Um, so when someone's Sir a squirrely
or not listening to my commands,
they may get cuffed and put in the back
of my car until everything is figured
out. They may not like it, but I am
going home at the end of my shift,
not to the morgue. Um, that
leaves another point of control.
No one likes to be bossed
around and told what to do.
But when the police are there,
were there for a reason someone called
us or we have a reason to believe that
we're needed. Once we're there, we have
to be in control. We call the shots, not,
um,
not forgo or to be on a power trip,
but because if we lose control,
we're fucked. It's our ass.
If someone gets hurt and our president
and it's literally our ass if we get hurt
or killed, if someone thinks that they
can do what they want or walk over me,
how am I supposed to do my job? Uh,
as for the videos you recently posted,
those cops with the name changer
were absolutely terrible.
If there is a lawful warrant for
that guys arrest despite the reason,
uh, it is their job to arrest him. Um,
the suspect knew about the warrant.
I didn't know what video is.
It didn't take care of it. Now he asked
to see a judge. They should've just,
they should have used much more
forced to take them into custody.
But the reality of it is you can't
just be able to keep passively Redis
resisting a cop until, until
the cops let you go. Uh,
they can't let you go.
All right, here we go.
The video at the stadium was disturbing.
They shouldn't have been obviously
jabbing the guy with their buttons,
but they had the right to
take them into custody.
People running around sports fields
isn't and shouldn't be tolerated.
Are they supposed to stop the game and
wait for him to be finished with running
around?
What if he assaulted or killed at athlete?
Then everyone would be crying
that the cops didn't do anything.
There was a great point. Also,
when we deal with people,
90% of the possible danger
from them is their hands.
If you're laying on your hands and I
can't see them, I will expect the worst.
How am I supposed to do? How am I
supposed to know what they are late?
That they aren't laying on a weapon?
Uh,
when I want your hand gimme your hand or
I will use force to get them out. Yeah.
There you go. Uh, one
last thing is tasers. Uh,
they are amazing tools. I had been
tased and training and yes, it sucks,
but it beats getting thumped or
shot. Uh, we're in the old days,
that guy may get the crap beat out of
him or his brain can cause now he gets an
electric ride for five seconds.
It's also amazing because the suspect
can be cuffed while being taste basically
less chance for everyone to see,
to get seriously hurt.
Why should I risk getting seriously hurt
or killed going hands on with someone
when they can just be taste. Um, that,
you know what somebody told me a
long time ago, if you want to make,
if you get pulled over by a cop,
a great way to help them relax and maybe
bring down them being a dick to you is
a, have your hands where
they can see them. You know,
if it's during the day, I always put
them like right on the steering wheel.
I get pulled over a lot, by
the way. Uh, not as much. I
guess back in the day I did,
cause I used to just drive 80 miles an
hour anywhere I was going, you know,
there's only so many fucking
farm she can look at. Um,
yeah,
it was funny. So I'm still nervous
about getting thrown out of here.
And the only reason why is because some
of the roads are washed out and I don't
know where the fuck I would go,
but I don't know why I'm nervous because
I am now speaking in a speaking tone if
I'm not allowed to speak.
Okay.
No, this is actually great stuff. What
if I show the hotel security my hands,
maybe he'll allow me to stay.
So anyways,
um, yeah, I,
I put my hands right on
top of the steering wheel
where they can see them. Um,
if it's a sunny day, I have one hanging
out the car window where they can see it.
And the other one I just put on top of
my head like an ape chilling out in, uh,
in the zoo.
You know,
when they sit there and they just have
that one arm draped over their head,
uh,
I sit like that
and then when they show up, I just had
my hands on the steering wheel and uh,
and you know what,
there's still assholes.
Yeah.
You know, it's kind of a
crap shoot, you know, so,
but I think this guy run
up a lot of great points.
What the fuck is he supposed to do?
And that's a great point.
If the guy ran on the field and
did something to an athlete,
then they would blame the security and it
would be screaming and yelling at them,
you know,
which probably goes back to the weather
channel then if they don't scare the
living shit out of people that they
would get blamed for not warning people.
But I think it has more to do with a
scaring people, gives them great ratings.
Um,
yeah,
so I don't know any more cops want
to weigh in? I, here's one for you.
I want to know what do
you guys think about that?
You can anonymously
talk about this as cops,
that kid who got shot on
the subway platform and died
new year's Day in Oakland,
um,
that do definitely wasn't being compliant.
He definitely wasn't given them
showing them his hands. And this guy,
I don't know,
he's like the Manchurian candidate.
All of a sudden the guy said the wrong
thing. The guy's laying on his stomach.
One cops got his foot on his neck.
I mean that the dude is down.
Yeah.
And all of a sudden this
one kid just stood up,
takes out a gun and just shoots the guy
right in the back. And I do, it's like,
what the fuck you shot me?
And he ended up dying.
Um,
you know what about [inaudible]
that one? That's, that's, that's one.
This is what I should say for the podcast
select cause that's what I want to ask.
And I didn't want to like just have
somebody go on there and honestly and just
say what you think about it.
Should have that cop gone to jail because,
uh, he got what basically usually
happens when a cop shoots somebody.
Is he
it off? Um, I dunno,
but
I don't want to, I don't want to do
this whole cop thing attack and cops.
I'd like to try to create some sort of
forum where you can actually anonymously
present your side and that worry about
pissing off other cops or worry about
pissing off victims are in that type of
shit. Cause I think it's, I don't know.
It's one of those things for
some reason I guess I know why.
The reason is it's too much shit at
stake so people don't talk about it. Um,
that could have been a lot more fun topic.
I didn't have to speak
in my time up voice.
This is officially the
first mm podcast timeout on.
Oh wait a minute then fucking
old bastard downstairs.
You know something?
I think I'm allowed asshole.
Yeah,
I think that that's what it is. You
know, on both sides of the country.
I've been told that I'm too loud. I
need to shut the fuck up self. You know,
at some point you've gotta look in the
mirror and realize that you, all right,
let's plow ahead of here. All
right. Advice for the week. Bill.
I have known this young lady for a few
years and we're very fond of each other.
Uh, but she has had, she's had,
she has a possessive boyfriend
with a stupid haircut.
And a couple of times when she's broken
up with him, she's come to me. Uh,
but then she goes back to macro man.
Uh, this is the thing that bothers me.
Whenever things have got
gotten sexual between us,
like I go down on her and
blow her fucking mind.
This guy has definitely got confidence.
He goes, she never returns the favor.
She gets disgusted.
She even gets disgusted.
If I sulk in my seat that I didn't
get any dude sulking is like,
I don't, I'm not gonna sit here and
act like I know what turns women on.
But I can tell you the exact
opposite of turning a woman on.
If you want to have the exact opposite,
Spanish fly would be sulking.
Nothing makes her pussy dry up,
like sulking,
just letting you know
right there. Okay. Um,
but nothing that makes it wetter with
complete indifference. Um, anyways,
once she said callously Oh,
after she did,
after the guy went down on her and
then she, he didn't get a blow job.
She wants callously said,
have a wank to alleviate my horniness.
After having her completely naked on my
chair worshiping her and pleasuring her
holes to Jesus Christ, buddy,
they got 'em at yelling.
That one right there would
have kicked me out. Uh,
it was just me with the Styrofoam Cup.
Another time when we had intercourse,
we were drunk.
She stopped me halfway through and
she even stopped halfway through,
uh, shit doing you a favor, a hand
job. She's never made me come.
These are only the only examples
of when she tried to get me off.
And I'm a good looking chappy,
so it's not that recently I
boycotted her body. I said,
let's be friends to be strictly platonic.
I won't even play with her.
NORCS I'm guessing her
titties. Uh, this is,
this has had the result of her trying
to rekindle things like the old magic.
Um, if she's not that into me, what the
fuck is going on? I'm finished with her.
But any insights you can give is a
treasure. All right? First of all, dude,
you're not finished. What? They're, um,
just halfway through writing that you've
probably realized what a PSAP you were
being. All right. Okay. First of
all, who's kidding who? You're,
you're fucking with the
psycho. All right. And uh,
I don't know if this is a very, there's
a very touchy one to talk about here,
but um,
this girl strikes me as one of those
girls who wants to be put in her place and
wants to be bent over something and once
a guy to tell her what the fuck is what?
Ra. Okay. Consensually.
Do you understand what I mean?
Okay. Don't take this the wrong way.
Going in and just fucking give him a
forearm. Give her a forearm shiver. Right.
I'm not saying to do
that. All right. You know,
some girls are cons and they know their
account and they want to get us to
basically tell them that it could be this.
I have no idea.
If I could tell you one thing right now,
sulking and keep coming back for more.
You'll like Charlie brunch keeps
pulling the football and uh,
you know, if you want to fuck
this girl, walk away from her,
stop returning your phone calls
and all that type of shit, you,
you basically started to do that when
you boycotted a body. But then you said,
let's be friends. That's
a weak move. Okay.
What's this girl I think wants to
see you be a fucking man. All right?
And you're not,
you're going down on her,
you're pleasing her and
she's doing everything.
Everything she can to disrespect
you and you're allowing it.
MMM.
And I think that's turned on or off.
And I think she's a fucking statistic.
Psycho. So she's getting you off. She's
leaving you with blue balls, you know,
I don't know.
That might be it.
Or she might be fucking angry at something
else and she's taken it out on you.
All I know,
dude is walk away from this girl.
Just walk away from her brother
for some fucking reason.
You still want to bang her one more time,
blow her off,
blow off her texts in or calls
for like a week and a half.
And then randomly answer one.
And when you pick up the phone,
just just have a whatever
vibe. Hey, what's going on?
And we're being McCune and make calls
and me or make ticks and the busy,
what's up? You want to
hang out now? Why not?
Yeah. You know, I don't know. What
do I want to hang with you for?
Get blue balls.
You know,
you're fucking selfish. You're fucking
annoying. Leave me alone. You know,
that's probably too angry,
but just, I'm sorry guys,
I'm fucking angry right now that I
have to talk like this. Um, yeah,
just blow her off and just be,
you know,
and when you go to meter
meter in a public place,
don't go over a place
where she can immediately,
she's going to dress extra sexy when you
come over there because she's trying to
get that power over you again.
Meet her in a fucking public place and
be talking to her as you kind of glancing
around the room,
you know,
sort of head on another girl while
she's standing there, I'm telling you,
you know, and when she asked
you to go home with their, don't
just say I'm cool or whatever,
you know, fucking blow her off.
If she ever calls you again, she
wants to hang out or whatever. Tell,
tell him to come over to your place.
And the second she starts acting like
a Douche, kick her out. I don't know.
I had sheets.
What sucks about a girl
like that as immediately you
got to try and get into her
head. Then you've got to start
playing games. It's not worth it.
There's too many decent girls out there
who will, when they take the dick out,
they will fucking complete whatever you
want. So I would just walk away from her.
MMM.
Let's be friends. Jesus Christ, buddy
that and sulking you need to take.
Those are the two parts of your game.
You need to work on this off season.
All right? And then maybe next
year you'll get the ring. Okay.
Good luck. All right, next one.
Bill. I'm a cubicle dwelling,
suffocated engineer in Texas.
I was rushed through the college
machine with all the rest of the cattle
destined to find a job, dimes, some
pleated Khakis and live the rest,
live the rest of our lives. And he's
steadily paid servitude of the man.
But a few years ago out of college,
uh Oh,
but a few years ago out of college
and I hated, like you saying,
I'm a few years out of
college and I hate it. Uh,
I wish I'd followed my desire
to be some sort of a writer.
And after listening to your podcasts
among others and hearing from friends that
I should have, I wish I'd given stand
up a shot. Well, now I'm 30 years old,
staring down the barrel of 35 more
years as a cozy smug engineer,
making six figures, but hating five
out of every seven days of my life.
I don't have any wife or kids,
but I feel like I'm too old to jump
back into being a starving artists.
What do I do?
Yeah,
dude, this is on you. All right?
I would never tell somebody who's got a
six figure paying job to jump into this
fucking awful business. All right? Um,
but I would never tell you not to do it.
All I got to tell you is you can't
half ass getting into this business,
all right? Or you are going to be,
you think you hate in your life. Now,
uh, just picture hating five
out of every seven days,
except you're making fucking,
you make it low five and you're old now
and nobody wants to fucking book you and
you don't have any wife and
kids. I'm telling you, all right,
I'll give you this advice. If you
decide to become a fucking comedian,
there's no turning back, all right?
And you've got to go into it.
You can't even consider quitting.
And it has nothing to do with fucking
talent and has to do with desire.
I'm telling you. Um,
that's what I would say.
So what I would do if I was you,
I would keep my six figure job and
I'd start doing some open mics.
That's what I would do.
All right.
And if you feel in your heart as you're
standing on stage that this is what the
fuck you want to do with your life.
I would do it in a second
because six figures, seven
figures, if you're miserable,
it's not going to be worth it.
All right?
But I don't know if you
know you're into comedy,
you know, the way I'm into playing
drums, drums or a hobby for me,
I absolutely fucking love them.
But there's no fucking way I would have,
I was about to climb into a van
with three other fucking guys,
you know, and eat pasta. I want, I'm not
going to do it. It just, I don't know.
I actually played drums and
I realized I didn't have it.
You know, I didn't, I didn't have it as
a musician and I didn't have that drive.
Um, but when I got on stage, the
first time I did comedy, I just, I,
I never look back and I was just
like this, I'm doing this shit. So,
um, they go, so you have
to answer those questions.
So the best way to do it is to sign
up for some open mics. All right?
See how it goes and see how you feel.
And like I said,
if you feel like that's what
you want to do, then I would,
I would work towards it, but I would
not quit that six figure paying job. Uh,
you don't just quit your fucking job.
You don't build up your time so you can
swing out of that job into some fucking
paid gigs. That's how I did it. Um,
I kept my day job until I moved to New
York City and I had saved up a bunch of
money. Um, you know, I
had paid off all my bills.
I didn't have a car payment,
I had nothing.
And I moved to New York and I had a
nest egg of fucking money. And uh,
and yeah,
I've told these stories before.
I hate fucking spaghetti
every goddamn night.
Three pieces of bread filled up my stomach
and I just did stand up every night and
I just did. I just wasn't doing standup.
I was working towards
getting better at it,
analyzing what I was doing wrong,
and um,
you know, but I would, I would
never tell you to quit your job.
And I would also never tell you that you
can't start comedy at 30 years of age
because you can't. All
right, so there it is,
but at the ball's in your fucking court.
All right. Youtube videos of the week.
Uh, we had an earthquake
here, um, this past week. Uh,
best earthquake reaction.
This is hilarious.
It's like three guys on the MLB network
or something like talking about baseball
and all of a sudden the hurricane comes.
Uh,
it's fucking hilarious because people
on the east coast don't know what an
earthquake feels like. A, so they're
sort of looking around like, um,
wait a second is, does anybody else
feel like something moving? Uh,
in defense of them was one of
those little shakin ones. Um,
somebody sent some home videos
of Peyton manning as a kid, uh,
running around whining
or whatever. But, uh, I,
I'm too hard on Peyton manning is fucking
ridiculous. How hard I am on this guy.
Bought A,
everybody wind is a kid,
but at this still funny as
a patriots fan to watch. Um,
and here's two that I
get. Um, it's called fuck,
fuck the police one. And this
is hilarious. This is some guy,
I dunno if he's in Brooklyn or what,
this black dude who knows his rights
has been harassed by the police.
She can tell his entire life or whatever,
but he's screaming at the cops.
That's the mistake he makes.
They don't arrest them, but the shit
he's saying, if he would just say it,
if he just said it, I think he would've
been fine, but he's screaming it.
Uh, and it's really funny.
It's actually, it was,
this guy goes on for
like 20 minutes and uh,
I've said before,
it's all about not losing your
shit and this guy loses his shit.
But I don't think he ever gets arrested,
but it's fucking hilarious. Um,
and he has a youtube video of the week.
This was actually suggested
by Paul Versey, uh,
oh out will forte. And this is
a, a sketch with Peyton manning.
Peyton manning is fucking
hilarious in the sketch. Um,
it's basically will forte,
you know,
everybody comes walking in there like a
basketball team and they get their asses
kicked and well forte comes in and
basically tells people that they shouldn't
quit and that he had a coach and they
played him this song one time when his
team was down by 60 points and by
listening to the song and amped,
I'm all the way up.
And then he basically puts on some
fucking songs from the 1930s and starts
dancing to it and it's fucking hilarious.
Underrated for the week. Will Forte,
the guy is fucking hilarious.
And uh,
please watch the director's cut of
macgruber. Highly recommended that.
And what else do we got here?
We got the a woman cuts,
guy's Dick off all the four
broads laughing at that.
And then I got one other one here. What
the fuck is it? Hang on, hang on, hang on.
Um, I'm the worst. The fuck did it go?
All right. Oh wait, don't say it
too loud. Don't curse too loud.
We will eject you from the Sheridan.
Um,
I'll future gun owner.
I'll creepy game show host is another
one that we have creepy fucking game show
host.
She used to see this,
I can't believe that this guy actually
was allowed on air and I showed it to
Bobby Kelly and he was laughing
at just this guy's fucking,
the game show was basically a mother
and a daughter. You know something.
They already showed this on tosh point.
Oh,
I really try not to do that because
I figured everybody sees them,
but we'll put it up there just in case.
But Bobby Kelly actually
showed me another one.
I don't know where the fuck this took
place. It sounds like it's in Scandinavia.
And this guy calls this kid up to sing
a song and he basically just starts
kissing his back. It's
unbelievably disgusting. Uh,
nibbling on his ear in the back of
his hair is this kid is singing.
It's fucking brutal. Um,
all right. Overrated.
Underrated for the weekend. Then I'm
going to fucking rap this pie. Holy Shit.
Hour and 15 minutes. Time flies when
you're whispering in a super eight, um,
overrated hand sanitizer.
I've been sharing the company restaurant
with a bunch of coworkers who believe
using hand sanitizer is the equivalent
or even superior to washing their hands
with good old soap and water.
It's not the rubbing alcohol and the
hand sanitizer kills the bacteria and
destroys virus presence on the hand.
And that's about it.
It does not physically remove the genital
grime deposited on the hands after guy
has finished jiggling his junk to
get rid of the last drops of Piss.
These people also use other commodities
such as the company refrigerator,
therefore effectively covering every
goddamn thing that they touch with their
dead penis and vagina cells.
All right, guy, he's not short.
If descriptive adjectives,
uh, overrated launch,
people dump all kinds of chemicals
to make them look pretty. Personally,
I prefer a clean water over a pretty
long, uh, overrated. The overnight,
the other night, and decided to have a
nice wink and crash out for the night.
So I hop on the generic porn site and
started browsing. Next thing I know,
two hours have passed. I was
still awake, hadn't banked,
and barely even had a Fleetwood Mac,
soft rock,
half Chubb, et Cetera. Uh, I
didn't even watch a full video,
which I think no one really does
total fucking waste. Instead,
I just use the girl's section of a
Hurley catalog I had laying around,
which worked pretty well, just
so we all know. All right.
Underrated the paper.
Grocery bags,
plastic bags are given to you by default.
And all the grocery stores I've been to,
they should give you paper,
and if you want plastic, he should
have to ask for it. Uh, all right.
This ends the, uh, comedy,
the Monday first Monday morning podcast,
comedy timeout.
And I feel lucky because I did
not get ejected from the hotel.
Um, that's it. I hope you enjoyed
this weird ass fucking podcast.
This podcast was like a nirvana song
started off loud. Then it got quiet,
but never got loud again. Um, so I
guess it isn't, it's like the first
don't feel shut the fuck up. All right.
Go fuck yourselves. That's the podcast.
See Ya.
[inaudible] [inaudible]
[inaudible].