Hey,
what's going on it's Bill Burr and it's
time for the Monday morning podcast for
Monday, June 11th, 2018 what's going on?
How are Ya?
How's everybody doing?
I'm a fucking old man.
It's 50 year old. Oh,
I remember when podcasting
started back in 2005
I just want to throw that out there cause
I know there's going to be a bunch of
fucking old podcast people going.
Well it should. The puck
is, it's been ruined.
Japan since 1968 and I
studied my poor kid asleep.
Full use before years in [inaudible]. When
mind is you get these many, many hits.
His Huish judge on who gives a fuck.com
I actually look at the numbers every
week
and I feel them.
We put [inaudible] [inaudible]
come on chanted. I'm, I'm providing
computer. Will you shut
the fuck up? I love people.
Look at their fucking podcast numbers.
You notice everybody seems to
be in the top 10 everybody,
you know it's like five talked
about this before. It's like a,
it's like back when I
used to do college gigs,
every college I went to
somehow they figured out a
way to fudge the numbers that
they were number one in something.
You know the number one a
fucking school for mathematics,
the number one school for engineering's
doesn't have to have mathematics in it.
I don't know.
Right.
And then we're just so you get down to
a community college and they'd be the
number one commuter college, uh, you know,
with fucking the best deal with
triple a or some shit. I don't know.
Some other one. Number one is something
you got to hang your hat on something.
If you're a college to try
and get people to go there.
If I, if I was a dean, do they have
deans at like community colleges?
I would just,
I would go on fucking TV and say,
listen,
why the fuck would you go for years
when you can only pay two years?
You know, you want to go to Harvard, fine.
All you have to go as your junior and
senior year go your freshman and sophomore
year over us over us.
We are number one and being fucking
10 times less per year than Harvard.
You got the grades,
you know you're in.
Come on down and teach us dummies,
my dumb students.
How do we have fucking loafers with
those socks? Whatever the fuck it is.
You smart people to do your freshman
and sophomore year here translate,
translate,
fucking transfer over to Harvard.
And then you go and you can
graduate from Harvard wide a dad,
Ya de judge you or whatever they'd fucking
school song is. What is this school?
So my dad is rich and I
did real bad in school,
but he has money. So, um,
fuck in here now, let's see.
That's a stereotype. I searched.
Well, I knew, I knew a I,
one kid in my high school,
he got into Harvard and he did it with
fucking grades and no social life.
He made the sacrifice. The rest of
us didn't want to do it. You know,
like that little fable there with the
fucking ants saving all the food and the
other animals like, hey man, I'm just
jumping around having a good fucking time.
You know, you know who wrote that story?
I bet somebody who couldn't fucking,
who was really socially
awkward at a party.
So he was looking at the fucking,
was it a rabbit toward us in the hair?
That's not the story. I don't
know what it is. But you know,
people who are outgoing,
they,
they get fucking annoyed
by people who are outgoing,
who are out there having a good time
talking some shit, hooking up, right.
Sing songs.
They in the life of the party,
they stand on the side and the
fucking wall and they write scripts,
you know, so that's why now, I dunno
what the fuck happened back in the day.
Used to have cool people movies.
Now I'd be cool person has this underlying
insecurity that they're trying to
overcompensate for.
That's all right. Shit.
I think,
you know what I mean?
Some people just are
the life of the party.
So anyways,
now that I'm a senior citizen,
I banged out 54 pushups on my birthday,
a boy,
and then immediately just
fucking collapsed onto the
carpet and was like out of
breath. Like, I ran 54 flights of
stairs, but I did it, man. I did it.
I don't know what it means.
It's still means I'm 50,
but it made me feel pretty
good about myself. Um,
I had a great birthday. I want
to thank my lovely wife. Um,
she surprised me with tickets to the
French Open Roland Garros module to Limu.
Um, we fucking, we went
there and I got to see, uh,
what the fucks his is his name there. He's
the only one left. He just won his 11th
Rafael Nadal. That's right. I'm
not the biggest fucking tennis guy.
And I knew that he had won
this thing a couple times.
I didn't realize he'd already
won the fucking French Open.
You'd already won it 10 times.
And I saw him when his 11th.
And what's really interesting is that guy,
um,
he wanted oh five oh six oh seven oh
eight and then Federer, one oh nine,
then he wanted in 10, 11, 12, 13 and 14.
So he won it four years in a
row, Mr Year. And then when it,
five years in a row and then two
years, 15 and 16, he didn't win it.
So people probably all thought,
all right, his run is over.
He's one of the greats of
all time, but now that he's
older, blah, blah, blah, blah,
blah, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
And he fucking comes back last year
and this year to go back to back again,
winning 11 and I was talking to somebody
last night and we were trying to say
how, how, what, what do you compare
that to in a different sport?
You know,
you can't really say it's like winning
an NBA championship because there's only
one of those
where with tennis majors there's,
there's four. So it's like they
have four sort of Superbowls.
So we kind of said,
I guess you'd have to go to golf,
compare it to golfers were, um,
you know, there's four majors in
that sport. I don't fucking know.
It was kind of saying, well, maybe it's
like Lebron going to the NBA finals eight,
nine years in a row.
And it's like, well, no,
because this guy actually won the thing.
Um,
I can't believe people give Lebron
Shit after losing to them. They,
people forget so quickly.
You know,
how ridiculous it was that Kevin Duran
went to the warriors and then the very,
you know, and then he wins a
championship. People like what the fuck?
And they need to scan and say, ah,
this is how it is. This just how it is.
Like when they first put led a little
fucking TVs in the back of cabs and people
like get these things the fuck out
of there and then making me car sick,
then I got right.
And then later on they just put them
back in again and nobody said, oh yeah,
I guess this is just how, I guess
this is just how it is. Right.
Um, all right. Uh, I don't know what
the fuck I was going with that, uh,
tennis golf majors to shit.
But I mean,
just the fact that this guy won 11 in
a row and I basically got to see on my
birthday the greatest,
um,
I guess you'd have to say the greatest
player ever on clay. I got to see him.
I got to see the fucking Wayne Gretzky,
the Bobby will, uh, uh, tennis and, uh,
he was playing this other kid.
Now he broke him his first game of both
sets and the kid had a bunch of unforced
errors and uh,
you know,
you could see he kept that the guy who
lost it seem like he was a kid and he
just had to go there, experience it, lose,
make a bunch of unforced errors for
the next time when he comes back.
And in the end, right, these English
dude comes out who won the French Open?
Uh, I dunno it from the way he
was talking was like late fifties,
early sixties.
And he came out to say a bunch of great
shit about Raphael and they dowel.
And then when he talks about the other
kid, he was just like, go. And, you know,
we would have liked to see more, we
ought to say more tennis said, uh,
I'm sure he's,
uh,
a little disappointed in his game
today as were the rest of us.
And everyone's just sitting
there going like, dude,
you didn't need to fucking say that.
I couldn't tell if the guy was nervous
that he just sort of talked himself into
a corner and he meant to say, um, he
has nothing to be disappointed about.
I don't what I'm trying to give
him the benefit of the doubt,
but everybody's just kind of sitting
there like, Eh, I kind of, uh,
of put a fucking damper on things. I mean
minutes about done here. Right. Sorry,
got the bootleg recorded here. Um,
which I have on my stomach too soft.
He started hearing grumbling.
I apologize. Um, anyways,
um,
I was able to watch
game,
uh,
was at game three of the NBA finals
when I was in London at about two in the
morning. I was able to watch
and I was able to watch my God,
the fucking Washington capitals.
Okay.
Win The Stanley Cup
through Josh Adam Meyers.
Cause I couldn't get it on my phone cause
I couldn't remember my password from
fucking, um, you know, my cable company.
I could've just gone on to NBC sports and
just sat there and watched it. But my,
my daughter and my wife were sleeping,
so I was laying a bed while in bed
wide awake with the lights out,
just hitting refresh on my phone,
looking at the score.
And uh, when there was a few minutes
left, I text Josh Adam Meyers and he goes,
dude, he goes for fuck it. He was the one
to tell me was just going to NBC sports.
And of course it didn't work out for me
because I knew my password. And he goes,
oh, call me up. I'll answer
my computer, I'll facetime
and, or some shit. So I said,
all right,
but here's the thing,
I'm going to be in the dark and
I can't say anything because my,
my daughter's sleeping in the same room
and everything. So he goes, all right,
call me.
So I snuck into the bathroom lights
still out because the only way to turn on
the lights in that fucking hotel room
as I had to have the bathroom door open,
which would have woke my kid up.
So I'm sitting in there that like
a dark in the dark, like a creep.
The only thing that's lighting
me up is off of my fucking phone.
It looked like a horror movie and Josh
was just laughing at me and he's like,
can you see, can you see it?
And I just put my pasty white,
the hand up to the screen,
given the thumbs up.
And I actually watched the final
three minutes of the Stanley Cup. Um,
and I have to tell you, uh, this
guy on the Internet put it best.
He said in talking about Alexander
Ovechkin, he goes, I don't,
can't remember the last time. I was
just happy for a complete stranger. Um,
that was watching the capital's when
was everything that you fucking watch
sports for? It's everything that
I love about sports. And, um,
do you know anybody that says,
you know,
Russian players don't give a
shit about the Stanley Cup?
Just all I need to do is just watch him
walking around with that thing in Vegas.
And how cool is it?
Like they actually know it would've
been great if they wanted it at home,
obviously,
but like if you got a win it on the road,
Las Vegas has to be the place you want
to be if you're going to go party. Right.
And,
um,
I say it every year at the Stanley Cup
is the greatest fucking championship
trophy and all the sports
simply because there's only one.
And you grew up as a kid watching all
your heroes hoists in that thing up.
And when you're in the
million to one odds,
whatever the fuck it is that you actually
went in, when you hoist thing up,
you're holding the same cup. You know,
Maurice, which Shard Gordie Howe,
Bobby or Wayne Gretzky,
Mark Messier, Mario Lemieux,
all of these great big,
same fucking Cup Eisenman
all of those guys,
you hoist that fucking thing up, said
Dave, you know, Ciara, right? Tries.
I had to throw another Braun in there.
Um, it's the coolest fucking thing ever,
you know, however, I would not drink out
of it. I can tell you that right now,
because I didn't spend enough
guys who've, uh, you know,
over the years,
hockey,
former hockey players that
have told stories about some
of the shit that happens
to the Stanley Cup. He
goes, yeah. And one of them,
I've vaguely remember somebody saying,
I would not drink out of that thing.
This stories of strippers sitting in the
top of the fucking thing and bending it
or some shit like that. Um, I dunno.
And then each player gets it for
like a week. It's so fucking crazy.
So crazy.
And then there's this guy,
there's gotta be a fucking
movie about that sometime.
The poor bastard who has to
follow the cup around all year.
Somebody must have done
a documentary on it.
Vaguely remember seeing some shit
like that where you get a follow what,
you know, go up to fucking
a titty bar and Saskatoon,
whatever the fuck that cup ends
up for the week. Um, but anyways,
congratulations to the Washington
capitols in their first Stanley Cup
championship. And, uh,
what is it, 44 years,
45 seasons. Um, and as I tweeted,
one other great thing is,
uh,
NHL has another great
hockey city in Las Vegas.
And after all those years of taking
these cities that just, you know,
there was the initial excitement and
then it just kind of fizzled. Um,
they kind of hit a home run in Nashville,
in Las Vegas,
and I got a feeling that Seattle's going
to be huge just because those fans are
maniacs,
you know?
And I'm sure they'll build a stadium
to make him sound even louder.
Why
do I always give them shit? You know
what? Because it's fun because it's fun.
Oh, I heard Edelman got
busted for something. PDS is
something like that. And, uh,
now they're gonna,
he's gonna appeal it.
And what I'm going to love about that
and is now everybody's going to be like,
she, that's why they beat Atlanta
and Dah, Dah, Dah, Dah, Dah, Dah,
and all this fucking shit
because of the Patriots.
That's how it works.
You'll just look the other way when 30%
of the Legion of boom tested positive
for fucking steroids. Ah, that's all
right. That's all right. That's Seattle.
That's okay. I At pee, Dee sent to my
house in my wife's name did for my wife.
She was taking a pop tart out of the
toaster and she hurt her shoulder and she
needed a fucking steroids to get back
in shape again so she could make some
fucking lemon Marangu Pie.
Anyways. Um, if I had to guess, you know,
we had that horrific injury and
he's doing the Andy Pettitte thing.
He's fucking trying to get back.
He took some fucking roids and you go
kite took something and go kite is what
I'm thinking. Um, but I do know anytime
anybody seems to appeal these things,
I don't think that ever
goes back the other way.
But I'm glad that I'm not in the u s
to listen to ESPN and all these fucking
guys. And they'll say, oh yeah, yeah,
they should take away all their titles
because they got caught there to play
or get caught doing what a player got
caught on. Every other fucking team
has done. Um, so anyways, enough,
uh, enough with the sports
shit. I am in Patty,
Amy and Patty and I am
bombing with my French.
They didn't brush up as enough as I
wanted to and it's making me discouraged,
but I'm hanging in there. I
got my, uh, I got my fucking,
uh,
what do you call it?
Rosetta stone in that
Shit I'll do when you,
when you go to the fucking French Open,
all right? And you have your ticket,
you go in and you got to have
the fucking thing scanned.
And then after he gets scanned,
you get this little fucking,
it's like a ticket the size of the, then
they put in your fucking wiper when you,
when you pay for parking. All
right? And then everywhere you go,
you have to take that thing out and they
have to scan it to know where the fuck
you are at all times. You know, I
went into the Goddamn gift shop,
bought a little fucking
2018 Roland Garros Mug,
and he goes, I need to, you know, let
me scan your ticket. And it's just like,
I wish you just said no,
you're not scanning my fucking ticket.
I'm paying for that.
So now what does that add?
Does that add to my whole
fucking information online?
He's into drums. He does this.
He drinks too much whisky and he,
he can't lay off of a mug when he's
in some touristy fucking place.
Now I'm going to get
all these fucking ads.
Now I'm going to get all these ads in
the side when I go to fucking porno sites
and shit about mugs can be funny if there,
why don't they have a gift shop on online?
Poor porn.
Why go there were good.
Um,
actually they'd probably
do. Um, so anyways,
every fucking place you
went yet to keep taking out,
keep taken out and put it away, whatever.
So now, finally I'm going, you know,
I bought like a fucking still water in
a crepe for my wife and I had to get the
things scanned. You know
what? I'm in another country,
so I'm on my best behavior.
Normally I would be like,
why the fuck do I have to scan this?
But the only reason why I didn't say
this is I didn't know how to say,
why the fuck do I have to get
this thing scanned, you know,
in French on Francais, right?
So now I go to walk in,
it's five or three French time and
uh, the match starts at three o'clock,
right?
So we go to go in and guess what I can't
find because they've had to take it out
of my pocket 58 fucking times.
I can't find a ticket.
I need to get into the goddamn match.
But I have that other thing.
And the ladies that come
starting, sir, you could not
get into the bay, but it's a,
but dude, I was fucking shit. And
I'm just like, are you serious?
Then she got mad at me. She's
like, yes, yes. I had to go
all the way the fuck back,
wade through all of these goddamn people.
Then go to customer service. Oh my God,
the fucking Tourette's that was going
on with me as I walked all the way back
past all of these fucking people. Um, I
got to give it up to the French people.
You know, you guys, you know, you
don't smell as bad as everybody says,
but I will say this when you do.
Holy Shit Dude.
When we walked out of the stadium,
there was this guy like fucking,
he was probably really good six feet in
front of me. And I said, Jesus Christ,
we actually made,
he went left down the stairs.
After one flight I would write and I
tried to get away from the guy. I said,
can I have my shirt up over my nose so
bad? This guy smelled. I said to me,
and because she's closest guy
smells like fucking plate.
How do you smell that bed?
Sitting watching people working out?
Maybe because he was walking down the
stairs fast. Who's creating a breeze?
And it was passing through his fucking
French arm pits. But Holy Shit.
Did that guy stick?
Yeah,
yeah.
Not as bad as a homeless guy, but
like he smelled like he, you know,
freshly homeless, good.
Three, four days, you know,
maybe a tornado hit his fucking house and
Fema hadn't come over to help them get,
that's what this fucking guy
smelled like sitting, you know.
And tennis is a really snobby
fucking rich person's sport,
especially down below, you know,
up top, it's a bunch of animals.
That's where we were sitting
in. If you ever go, uh,
we got front row in the upper deck,
get the second row upper deck,
cause front row they had this glass thing,
but you know that you partition
that you look through.
But on top of it they have this solid
thing that all holds it together.
And I was like in America this
would have been clear plastic.
So I had to look over and duck under it,
the whole fucking match,
which was still fine.
Um,
okay.
So anyways, but down low is
where all the fucking, you know,
the coaches are the super fucking rich
people and they go there and like fucking
outfits and they're big dumb
hats and all of that shit.
But all the animals were up top,
you know,
doing the wave and shit when nay dow had
some problem going on with the servant
hand or his arm. I don't know
what the fuck happened. And, um,
but anyways, I always, it was,
it was an amazing fucking time.
So I had to go all the way
back and I got the ticket.
Then I came walking up and I,
you know,
after all that flipping out and
all of that fucking bullshit,
I still made it in the time
to see the match as always.
99% of the time I flip out
later on if there's a solution,
whatever I thought was going to
happen because of the inconvenience,
never fucking happens. And, um,
I thought I was going to leave
all of that behind in my forties,
but evidently it's to continue. I started
strong the day I turned 50. Fucking,
it just continued on. So, um,
I'm going to rent a fucking bicycle
today and I'm going to ride around Paris
with my, uh, my daughter goes to
sleep and we just been having the, uh,
the best time here.
As always.
I'm going to take a well deserved
fucking little vacation here.
And,
um,
the hardest thing for me on vacation is
not to just plant a bunch of shit every
day. Um, you know,
then, then it just becomes a
thrash. It's funny, like we, uh,
we drove by,
was it that Notre dam or some shit like
that and the guy driving us was going,
you go, you know, it's beautiful.
You got to go in there and blah blah,
and I swear I'm just not into that shit.
Those old churches and stuff,
you walk in and I just look around
and just say, yeah, you guys,
you guys really decorated the shit out
of this place, didn't you? You, uh,
no negative space scenarios all
just filled up with the most gaudy.
Um, you know, you know, like,
you know, like the Migos dress,
that's like the Church version of that
where you just can't have enough fucking
precious stones and or
like how those, you know,
that new thing where
you get a Lamborghini,
then you do the fucking shiny wrap
that you put around it. It's like,
it wasn't enough that it was
a fucking Lamborghini. Those
old churches, it's like,
it's not enough that you have
90 foot fucking ceilings.
All right.
Then you got to have a bunch of sad
broken hearted people painted up there in
like real gold
and all of this crazy hocus pocus shit up.
They're like,
I don't have any desire to
do that, but um, you know,
if there's no line, I'll poke my
head in and be like, wow, wow,
this old church looks exactly like
every other old church. It's creepy.
I'd feel like I'm going to
catch tuberculosis because
it's cold and damp in here.
And uh,
the vibe in here is not the
vibe where good things happen.
So I'm going to leave now. Um, yeah.
So I'm going to, I'm going to fucking
ride my bike around today. Uh,
like the big fucking Nancy boy that
I am maybe burn a few calories. Um,
I brought my little exercise
bands over here cause I'm old. Uh,
my shoulder feels fucking great.
Uh,
but I got a problem with my
fucking left foot. You know,
it's just always something. It's always
something. I'm an old, I'm an old man,
people, I'm 50. How the
fuck did that happen?
You know,
it's actually got to be kind of,
be honest with six kind of a cool age
to turn in a lot of ways. You know,
God knows I had a bunch of friends
that didn't make it this far.
So how the fuck can I sit here and
bitch and I like a nice round number,
you know, 30 sucked. 40 was
like, Whoa, fifties been cool.
Um,
but I'll tell you 60 is going to crush me.
You know what's great about 50 you
can lie to yourself to your forties.
I'm a young 40 something and blow blow 50.
It's like, no dude, you're fucking old.
So I am old and uh,
I've got to embrace it.
Maybe I'll start dressing a
little more dapper on stage.
Give myself a little pocket
square, hanging out on my
button down. Um, all right,
let's read a little bit of
advertising here. Oh look who's here.
These guys have been with me since
my forties dollar shave club. Dude,
if you ever fucking shower or brush
your teeth or try to make your hair look
presentable, I do most of those two.
What a three bet.
Here's some good news.
Dollar Shave Club has a lot of self bought
a stuff to help you out to Ali shape
club. Yes. That's dollar shave club
delivers everything you need to look,
feel and smell your best. You name
it. They got it. Shampoo. Got It.
Conditioner check bodywash. I said we
got everything. Toothpaste, hair, Gel,
even a wipe that will leave your
tush failing. Tingley clean.
It's sort of the poor man's birthday.
You'll be a big fan of their amber and
lavender calming body cleanser after you
try it the first time.
Does that really work?
I wish I had some of that yesterday when
I couldn't find my tickets at a tennis
match. They should just have
that in a miss for someone.
Angry bald shithead like make shows up
and they just hit me with the fucking
amber in lavender. We got an amber
situation over here. Amber alert, right?
Lavender, Louis, uh,
good luck finding a product
that's that great at the store.
All of dollar shave club's products are
made with top shelf ingredients that
won't break your budget.
You failed the difference.
Plus shipping is included
in your membership.
And here's a great way to try a bunch
of dollar shave club products for just
five bucks. You can get their daily
essential essential start set.
It comes with body cleanser,
one wipe Charlie,
they're amazing,
but wipes they're world famous,
shaved butter and their best razor,
the six blade executive,
uh, and add in shampoo. Molly executive,
sorry to keep the blades coming for few
more bucks a month and add in shampoo,
toothpaste,
or anything else you need.
Speaking of your next
month for a limited time,
only use the code [inaudible] at checkout
to get $5 off your second month of the
club.
That's code bur bur are a dollar shave
club.com to save $5 on your second month.
Join the club today. Um, all right,
couple more movement watches.
MVMT spring is right around the corner.
I think it is spring.
I think summer's right around the
corner and movement is dropping all new
sunglasses or a what
does that little nets.
So now you say that Lunette
so late to get your,
get you ready for the warmer weather.
Um,
talk about individual styles and events
you have coming up that you want to look
good in shades for. Uh, or the next
sporting event that I'm going to,
is it 24 hours lemons.
And when I inevitably lose my ticket,
I would like to have some lavender,
miss a nice movement,
watch a pair of aviators
and or, uh, one wipe cherry.
And then maybe I'll be able to keep
my cool over there. Um, we just go,
what the fuck? Talk about individually.
It has shades of Blah, blah, blah.
We just go to our goto shades photo.
Who's we?
Why are they always doing this? If you
want this shit that they're selling, just,
you know,
for their goto shades,
the guys that movement don't just
make great watches. Hello Nini.
Thank you for an awesome birthday.
Yay.
Thank you for a day to you.
Happy Day.
Abria bread they to you add me
De de,
de the
baby.
They to your day to you and you like that.
You're like,
I just pick the one thing like I was in,
was it run DMC and then
how they used to do it?
Sure I'd finish your sentence right.
Huh?
You want to come up with a rap right now?
I want to use to say baguette.
Baguette. Okay. That's it.
That's the end of the Rad. Um,
you didn't feel my flaw there.
I want a, that's me robbing.
He was dead. No JC scared.
Right now we just go to our,
it just go to our shades for it.
All the guys that movement pay,
any of the guys that move with, they
just say, just don't make great watches.
If you thought that was the
only good thing they did,
they also make awesome
sunglasses or Lou nets.
So sewing all a solar and just
reached a ton of new styles.
Our friends at movement. Yeah. To watch
guys. They kind of felt the same way.
So they thought screw it.
Who they were feeling Sassy that day show.
They didn't say fucking,
how about we make quality trendy
sunglasses at a fair price?
Why is screw it in quotes?
I think that's cause they said pocket.
These things aren't plastic.
They acetate Acetate as,
oh,
they're acetate. Yeah, I
thought it was mine. Uh,
you can get them polarized and they start
at just $70 and I said Tate Acetate,
acetate.
These are seriously,
that's when you go to look it up to see
how you say these are seriously my goto
shades.
Talk about movements.
Various can these fucking assholes,
right?
The copy talk about varied
selections and styles.
Well there's aviators.
There's the one Tom Cruise war in in uh,
was it losing in a risky business?
Why are you blaming them for
the value that you can read?
There's another round with this Gabi.
What he taught,
I know they're not there is talk about
movements, various selections in style.
Oh they keep doing that.
Okay. I know I can't read.
Talk about how awesome we are talking
about Mvmt is various saves lives and in
styles.
Finding the perfect parents.
You know Audrey with free shipping
and free returns. I liked,
I like your yeah I liked
that ray and make it,
I like that root cause
then I don't have to do it.
Talk about movements,
very selections and style week.
Matt Black to really fun retro round
shades and how finding the perfect pair is
risk free with free shipping and free
returns. So you can't do it. Yeah,
that was good. That was good. Okay.
These are high quality premium Acetate,
Acetate, acetate frames,
no cheap plastic here.
You got to see these. They have lots of
styles to choose from. Classic, Trendy,
round Ada. Ada married, polarized
for him and her. See She,
they just talked about it.
You talk about it and show stuff.
You talk about them.
Tell me what to talk about.
You're sure to find the perfect pair.
Get 15% off today with free shipping
and free returns by going to move
into.com/burr. That's mvmt.com/bird
joined the movement. Nia,
did you have fun at the tennis
match yesterday? I know,
I know. It's really hot.
How bad did that guy smell when
we left? Hey, this thing go.
All right. You call me. Stinko um,
let me just read it so much fun.
Oh,
you say that was one
smelly motherfucker number.
We shot down the other stairs only
to meet him again down the bottom.
Um, stamps.com the u s postal service
is an important tool for any business.
stamps.com is the easiest way to access
all the amazing services of the post
office.
stamps.com never closes.
Print postage for letters or
packages at your own convenience. 24,
seven print postage for any male
class right from your computer.
The exact amount of postage every time.
Never underpay or over pair again.
I just mailed all of my
posters to Dublin and, uh,
to London using stamps.com
it was very easy. However,
I mailed to many to Dublin.
It was an 8,000 Cedar. I was like,
what? What should I send there?
Like 500 stupid.
The magic number is 200.
There's 200 people. You'll sell 200. If
there's 200,000, you'll sell 200. I don't,
I can't understand it. So, uh,
by the white people who the, uh,
the poster that I have,
it's only available at my shows because
I've tried to sell stuff online and then
I have to fucking sit there and deal
with like, I'm not from Swat. Hulu,
I'm from Swahili. I didn't get my
fucking poster. And then you know,
half the time people give you the wrong
God damn address and say, what am I?
Amazon and all the year ideally, yeah,
that's a language just that way.
And we'll,
if we in that no where she just stopped.
That's a language that was great.
You just shut me down out
because my name is Swahili, so,
okay. Evidently this whole
podcast is about, you know, is it,
can you make a Swahili dish? It's not as
where he lived. That's the language. Well,
I can make a French dish.
Okay. That's a language French.
It's also addressing,
I can mail any letter.
It's also a kiss.
It's also a type of fry.
What do you guys
have anything else? It's also
a, what is that old school sex?
They have French tickler.
Oh, it's also a tech work.
It's also a cuff on your shirt.
You know what I,
this is good cause I just finished
watching Kanye west side family feuds.
I feel like I'm answering
family feud right now.
He was on work promoting his new album
now for saying that he loves Donald Trump
and now, right? Well
that was a controversial,
what are you got a new album or something?
Um, I think babies should be
illegal. Why? Here's my new album.
Oh that sounds pretty catchy.
I use stamps.com I already did all this
and right now you too can enjoy the
stamps.com service with the special offer.
That includes a four week trial
plus postage and a digital scale.
Go to stamps.com click on the microphone
up@thehomepageandtypeinboroughthatstamps.com
enter
[inaudible].
All
right.
Ninny it's,
you know,
I love being here in Paris and
whenever I see your beauty in Paris,
I always think when
the moon hits your eye,
like a big pizza pie,
that's Italian.
Why would I be singing that here?
What's a good French song? Prayer, Raj,
and are you are very classically beautiful
place. I've always told you, you're,
it's your cheekbones. That's
where the late hits, when
you go to look to the left,
it's the rate in the rate lit restaurant.
I'm just like, there it
is. We had a great time.
That's how I ended the
freedom of my single life. We
had an awesome time lesson,
so fun.
And we ended up meeting up with friends.
We ran into a friend at
the royal and gals. Uh Oh,
that was so fucking random.
So random.
There's about a hundred gift
shops at the Roland Garros.
We just happened to run into them,
but we went into the bad one.
The one that everybody goes into this.
Yeah.
You want to go to the boutique
boutique once there's an Adidas store.
I saw that the way up, but I was trying
to beat the crowd. Oh, how funny was that?
Were like, we gotta get away from the
crowds so we can get a fucking Uber and,
and I went right when everybody
else went left just to, you know,
get a few blocks over it.
It gives somebody a chance and you know,
all the streets are blocked off.
And we ended up going from Roland
Garros and just walked past,
I thought it was a parking garage
to another. It was another stadium.
And I looked at soccer magical
yet I was like, oh fuck.
And then next door was
another soccer stadium.
Like this is like stadium row over here.
Um,
and of course we call the Uber and the
guy couldn't come down the street and it
just was a whatever it was. Yes, we did.
And we went out to dinner and had a
lovely dinner and then we ended up meeting
up with the friends that we ran into
at Roland Garros plus another friend of
yours, plus some friends of mine.
So we all met up in a, uh, yeah,
it was four couples and we just ended
up having this table at this cafe.
Late night. We shut it down,
sang me happy birthday. Yes,
we've got some champagne.
Oh, it was awesome.
It was so much fun.
By the way,
one of the only times anybody's ever
sung happy birthday to me and I haven't
been embarrassed. It's happened
three times in my life. All right,
there it Royal Albert Hall.
So it was twice the same birthday.
And then,
uh,
last year when I was onstage in Montreal,
uh, they all sang happy booms. One of the
coolest things that ever happened to me,
the crowd all saying it, and the fact
that they sang it to a Bruin fan,
that we could set aside our differences
to celebrate one bald heck in that
moment,
you know,
which gives me hope that when Donald Trump
goes to talk to old petty fucking fat
face over there,
can you imagine like you be in that
fat when all your people are starving?
Now granted, I know is people are
starving because of our frigging embargo.
They tried to make it seem like he's,
but he is like a dictator.
So of course he's going to be like,
oh,
fat and eat lobster and Doug and
drinking the best wine every night.
We're talking about Kim Jong, right? Keep
going. You've got to have the right name.
That's there.
All Kim,
John [inaudible] and
his dad was Kim Jong Il.
I was going to say, imagine his wife
calling for dinner. You uh, yeah.
Um, Hey Kim. Jon. Hey Alyssa.
I'm Tryna tell you something.
That picture that I posted of you
on my Instagram for your birthday.
Go over 5,000 likes. That's what
you're really into that I you, yeah,
like certain tweets. Yes I do.
I am. I meant to all of that.
I'm an influencer so I
honestly I'm into it.
Do you want to tell the story
why you want to tell a story?
Why you marked that whole
influencer thing? What is my story?
You don't remember when we
first heard the term influencer,
you are going to do something and
then you couldn't because they wanted
influencers. Oh yeah. I was asked to
be a part of a name. Any names I won't,
I was asked to be a part
of a storyteller show. Um,
and what was the saying?
Yes.
And the theme was like cultural
diversity and families and stuff.
So it was like, oh sure. Right
up the oil. We there. Yeah. Yeah.
We have an interracial relationship
with a biracial child is kind of, yeah,
I can come up with something for that.
And then the person who asked me said
that they had to disinvite me because they
wanted more influencers.
So network wanted more network,
wanted more influencers and you know,
so they got,
they replaced me with someone who had
apparently more quote unquote influence
and effect just means more friends
or whatever the fuck it is.
People on social media. Um, and I didn't
even really dig into this person was,
but apparently they were terrible and
the whole show was like kind of awkward
and not that great.
So it's fine.
But I was so offended that I wasn't
seen as an influencer when I have like,
you know,
I,
I'd healthy following on Twitter and
Instagram that I just decided that I was
going to be an, and I'm one
of the greatest influences
ever. I am an influencer.
Like that's,
that's the bottom line.
Like I feel like at this point I don't
even need to keep telling people anymore.
It's just who you are coming
out of your pores. Yeah.
Like naturally people want to be like me.
So
it's weird for some reason.
I don't know.
Just looking at your firm is I want
braids right now. Well that's the thing,
like if I have it,
you want it wouldn't influence it.
And what is is you didn't even tell me to
get it. You just had it and I was like,
I want that. Could you see how good it
looks on me? And so you're like, wow,
can I look like that? There's only
way to find out. It's just to get it.
And then you're like,
oh I don't.
But I tried and it's like that's
really what it's about justice,
what an influencer does. Yeah,
exactly. You just exist in this space,
like your own site guys. Like you are your
own movement. You are your own moment.
It's just something could, could you teach
this to somebody else? Oh God, no, no, no,
no. You either have it or you don't. So
I, if you want to become an influencer,
I'm not really quite sure what to tell
you because it's like you already have
some sort of falling. Is it
a, is it a gift? Well, how
would you describe like, yeah,
it's just, it's a, it's a state
of being, you know what I mean?
It's like you're just always influencing
all the time, so I can't teach it.
I can't explain it to Zika
texting or tiring. It'll,
you know, it really doesn't,
you know,
because it's like breathing
[inaudible] you go people and some
inside tips on how to be a fucking
influencer. Yep. I can't believe that
people walked away from a, you know,
you just influenced me to try to read
up more on influencers. All right. Hey,
people giving me a, send me
some parish tips here. Okay.
By the, did you read that
thing about the wine country?
The email that I forwarded you,
one of our listeners wrote in maybe.
When did you send that off? Evidently,
I'm not an influencer. All right.
It's just an email from your
husband that says wine country.
You know, you'd think that one
wouldn't you? At least open.
I know you don't open the ones that I
send you that they have the subject.
Are You mad at me?
All right.
Paris chips,
they go right into the,
the junk bugs right in the
fog in trash or were there,
hey, thank you for the best birthday.
That was the best birthday I've,
I've ever had.
I've had two back to back
last year it was the, uh,
was the selfish one where I was,
I was in Montreal and I went to an f one
race who I don't even know who won that
the Lewis Hamilton wanted again. I gotta
look that up. I'm a little behind here.
Um, but this year was
the best. Uh, all right.
You know what it's about the song
happy birthday. It's really long.
And it almost sounds like
people are making fun of you.
Happy Birthdays are the Yarra
douchebag.
Yes,
you are.
And then in the end it's always
speech, speech. So I actually,
I thought what I said at Royal Albert
Hall was really nice and I was like,
I did it, I got through it, knocked it
out, thanked everybody and I'm done.
And then as I'm walking away, people
would go speech, speech, and then I go,
I try, I should just fucking
gave one. I still get angry.
Let me long God I Paris tips.
Hey Bill,
I am a fan from Perry.
I heard you were visiting
our lovely city soon. Uh,
this is my French accent. Uh,
makes sure that you start by,
let comp twice in Sasha Ma,
uh,
Metro Audi on as we get
our for a nice meal.
Then take your lovely lady to the cafe
Laurel in Rue dauphine for a league
drink and some jazzy entertainment.
That sounds good.
They have a nice garden where you can
smoke a cigar and sip on some scotch.
Slash. Wine. Also, don't
learn French. It's useless.
Better learn Chinese instead.
Uh, enjoy your stay and go fuck
yourself. Let's go do that. All right.
Thank you. Thank you for that tip. Now I
want to try, was that guy in influencer?
Now he's more implemented
in former suggester.
Can we please label everybody
that if I can. He's a suggestion.
Wasn't yesterday. That'd be funny
if that was in a shop. No, I am not.
I not a suggestion. I was
mute. I am a presenter.
I was presenting information that
you can do. You know, I mean,
it was a suggestion. That's really what
it was. Not Bad does adjust things,
but you're suggesting even
in this age of me too, Hey,
I suggest you come over here and
you ride.
It was just a suggestion.
My associates, um,
crazy lawsuit. Crazy law suit. All right.
Hey there Billy birthday cake.
Wondering if your friends in the comic
community passed this on to you. Oh,
please don't let this be performer getting
sued and Oh, oh, this is a long one.
You know what? I'm going to go take
a shower, take a shower. Uh, I see.
Take a shower and something Douche.
Um,
all right. Wondering if your, uh,
friends in the comic community
of Wa Nini of why influence out,
uh,
wondering if your friends in the comic
community pass this onto your backstory.
This guy, oh my God, he touched
my hair and then you hit it. Uh,
this Guy Matt acts like the TV show who
started a page in the 90s called the
best page in the universe.
Um,
he became famous for calling out
Christopher Reeves for not caring about
paraplegics. Tilly
became one himself. Well,
I mean, Jesus Christ, if out of all
the things to call people out on, uh,
basically lambasted him for
being a selfish piece of shit.
Jesus Christ,
I don't understand.
He never sold me on the aggressive
manner of hating Reeves.
The only way he keeps, he does this
without looking like an asshole,
just as if he was also in a wheelchair,
you know,
and live at the top of a flight of stairs
of some shit and nobody never made a
ramp for him. Then I could see him
being mad at Christopher Reeves,
but even then it would
still be misdirected.
It's still should be aimed at people
like myself that then go over there and
help build them a fucking ramp anyways.
But I appreciate it.
A different point of view on topics.
No one questioned. And so I had,
okay, but I appreciate a different point
of view on topics. No one questioned.
And so I had some respect for this.
He also had a post called something like,
I can draw better than your kids.
And then posted pictures,
kids made and trash them are I like this
guy now because this guy's just being a
cunt. Um, he's just,
maybe he's the original troller I like it.
He's going to,
that was like 15 years ago.
I hadn't heard of him since college
until I read about this lawsuit.
Apparently this same guy who made a
career trolling the people on a personal
level across the Internet became offended
by a comic who decided to troll him.
Oh No, no. We had no sense
of humor about himself.
Or is this more trolling? Is this
guy the Andy Kaufman of the Internet?
He's sued the comic for $20 million,
which is basically way to
bankrupt the comic for whatever.
Literally had the judge
essentially threw out the case.
Um,
on the advent of your 50th birthday,
I just want to thank you for not turning
into a huge hypocrite like Maddix.
I'll do it. I want the most hypocritical
people you ever gonna meet doing yoga,
meditating, and then slipping out?
Cause I, cause I lost my ticket
saying this whole system
is fucking stupid. Dude.
Did you really build a system that makes
sure that when you get to your seats
that mother fucking assholes not sitting
in it? You fucked up, take your medicine.
And I didn't act like a big fucking baby.
Um,
even if he thought he was being wrong,
he should have taken it
like a man realized that he
had to come in after years
doing the same thing to others.
You don't feel like this is the
final act of his performance.
And now he's gotten you up in arms.
Uh,
you're a fewer years older than me and
I've definitely taken a page on your book
in terms of allowing myself
to stay true to who I am,
but also allowing myself to grow
into a more well rounded person.
I'm an o and a fan or
a from back in the day,
and it's my favorite content ever.
But when I see comments
online that sounded like they
came from the crowd at the
virus tour,
I just feel bad for these miserable cunts.
Thanks for everything and happy birthday.
All right.
That went a little left there. But
I know what you mean about the, um,
that happens with everything, by
the way, not just fans of the OB.
And Anthony showed this,
I mean, go on Youtube,
there's always going to be the initial
thing that you like and then you look at
the comments and I forget what comic
did that Pitt, but he was just like,
you know,
yeah.
You scroll down like three
or four comments before it
spins into like somebody
dropping the n word or some,
you know, thanks a lot. Obama,
like somehow that'll be
watching like slap fights.
At least that's the shit that I watch,
which I do not understand those
for the legs of me. First of all.
MMM.
The fact that if they hit your ear,
what that's gonna do to your hearing,
you know? Do you know that was a
thing that like, I gotta look this up.
Moms used to do that. That was like a
disciplinarian thing back in the day.
You block she mothers box
boxing.
Okay.
Their children's is just too specific.
I don't think I'll get anything. Ears.
They would just, you know, it was like
kill a con how he used to do that.
That screen well, Huh? Oh
Man. Just hit boxing the ears.
Okay.
Boxing hears the other Victorians.
Uh,
Anthony.
Joshua says there's nothing wrong with
parents giving them which one should I
click on here?
World champion boxer.
Antsier said there's nothing wrong with
parents giving their children a clip
around the year.
Boxing child's ears can cause deafness.
Yes it can.
MMM.
That's, look, this one up here. Oh,
unable to open this because of legal.
The fuck does that mean?
All right. Boxing ears.
Let's see if this one will
open up. Come on, come on.
Come on. There we go. Alright.
I'll phrase it confused me while reading
Alice's adventures in wonderland was
the rabbits explanation of why the Queen
order the Dutches to be executed in
chapter eight.
What that I've never seen
Alison wonderland is a queen
in Dutchess and La Shit.
People get an executed I,
you know something, you know,
I think there's so much death in old
fairy tales, the original ones too,
because so many people just
fucking died back then. Anyway,
so it really was a part of
life. Um, the rabbit, I mean,
it's still a part of life, but it's,
it's way down the fucking road.
But everybody had like a brother
who died of like a fucking appendix,
ruptured appendix or some Shit,
get some sort of flu, a, all right.
The rabbit explains to Alice,
she box the Queen's ears.
The actions of boxing is,
is something I had never heard of.
So I decided to look into
the meaning of the term.
I found that boxing of ears is a hard
simultaneous slap of both of yours.
Yet the violent act was a popular form
of child punishment during the Victorian
era.
Oh my God.
In an 1878 issue of the London
reader of literature, science,
art in general information,
the punishment of boxing ears is debated.
The article warms is 1878 people like,
dude, what the fuck are we doing here? Uh,
for not only his deafness caused by boxes,
which ruptures as they continually
do the drum of the ear,
but the inflammation of the internal
cavity, which is so frequent,
a result may be followed by disease.
Of the bone giving rise to absent to
abscess of the brain and having a fatal
termination. I like how they took pick
the euphemism. They're on the same year.
Kids are going to fucking die.
The article explains,
school boys is suffering from the chest
dies meant by school masses and fears as
noted above, that the effects
of the slabs may be longterm.
I swear to fucking God if my,
if I have had a teacher that
boxed my ears, oh my God.
I mean how angry with children back then.
Oh my God.
Like I literally have to
walk away from this article.
Ah, man, I wish they was, you know,
some fucking kid back
then just fucking snapped
was just big enough.
You know,
it just beat the shit out of his teacher
and boxed his ears like nine times.
Made him a deaf fucking bastard. Um, yeah.
So whenever I watch those slap fights,
it's just like you're going
to make somebody deaf.
They put something in their ear.
Forget about just taking a concussion
for no goddamn reason. I mean, we'll,
we'll slap fight competitions like
what is the fucking prize money?
Um,
anyways,
continuing on a Bayer and Monsanto.
Whoa.
Jesus didn't, uh, I guess see what
time I've done here. 53 minutes, right?
It didn't mean Santo changes their name,
like Jefferson airplane or some shit. Um,
bear in Santo. Hey there,
you over the counter cunt.
So bare and Monsanto are merging and
reminded me of the time you mentioned an
article where bare admitted to knowing
and allowing the distribution of some
aids infected shit. Found the
article for this sounds official.
First of all came from me and
then you described the Arctic,
the subject of the article
as aids infected shit. Well,
let's check out the link.
It is from CBS news.com.
So all right.
Bear admits it paid millions in HIV
infection cases just not in English.
Oh my God.
Yeah.
Dude, I swear to God. At what point,
how much money do you have to pay
politicians where they feel like they have
enough money and they don't
need the corporate dollar
and that they can actually
start to dismantle or a restructure?
These corporations,
these corporations are going to kill us.
Not Isis, not fucken, uh, the Russians.
None of this fucking shit.
All right. When I say kill us,
I mean no human beings left are
going to be the result of because of
corporations. All right? And
what, how they view people,
how they view the environment, how
they view money in their whole idea of,
of what is a is worth.
I mean,
I know I've just never heard a corporation
ever being like, you know what the,
the,
the costs to innocent people or the
environment is too high for us to do that.
Maybe they do.
It'd be refreshing if you have an article
like that that wasn't actually written
by someone from that corporation
that's lying. All right.
Turn to the read the
English speaking media.
You'd never know that bear just paid tens
of millions of dollars to end a three
decade long scandal in which the company
sold HIV contaminated blood products to
haemophiliacs thousands of
whom later died of AIDS.
They just killed thousands of
fucking people or admitted to it.
But that doesn't mean they actually
said that they did it. You know,
that fucking legal thing.
Um,
ironically bears new hemophilia who feel
your iPhone app got some coverage ads.
Did bears hemophilia research grant,
are they covering their tracks to
the University of Florida? Go gators,
but you have to pick through the French
and Italian news meeting to find out
that bear is finally writing
checks to people who got aids.
I've got HIV that turned into aids
in the 1980s the cutter biological
unit of bear ignored
federal law to recruit
prisoners,
intravenous drug users and
high risk game in is donors.
I'll they ignored that of the blood
cutter then used to make factor eight and
nine the clotting product that he will
feel the x need to order, need in
order to not bleed to death. Oh,
so they pulled the Bella check
whether they were like, all right,
you guys are all filling.
Need the team on the sidelines.
You can no longer do that.
And they just ignored it.
MMM.
All right.
The German group bear in three other labs
will pay tens of billions of euros to
hemophilia ex who accused them of
having sold in the 1980s blood products
contaminated with HIV. A source
close to deal told them. So did it,
was it that they knew that it had HIV
in it or did they just went to high risk
people to get blood?
The figure of tens of millions of euros
in compensation is not totally wrong.
She had it bear in the U S company.
Baxter are the two main parties
to the agreement. She said,
a company spokesperson said,
how are the company accepts
no responsibility in this
case and continues to
insist and it always acted responsibly
and ethically that's how they get out of
it. It's like, all right, we'll
admit that we did that shit.
If you say it wasn't our fault and
that we always behaved above board.
You know what that's like?
That's like when they send somebody to
jail and innocent person to jail and then
they're like, all right,
we're gonna let you out.
But the only way we can let you out as
if you sign this paper saying you won't
sue us because we fucked up.
MMM.
Anyways, found the article.
I might just read some of it.
They're still in business. They're still
in business. Can't bring down bear.
That's our medicine, but
maybe our food supply. Nope.
Then you got, I don't know what
this guy's talking about now.
MMM.
Then you've got Monsanto who can't be
sued because Obama signed that laws saying
that you can't soup and Santo now there
was super team corporations are like NBA
team side.
You got room in the chopper for me,
Bill just guy was all over the place.
All right,
and why did Obama sue that sign that,
so that, why did he sign that bill?
Everybody?
Is it because he's a liberal targe snow
flake or whatever people get wears a
blue tie or is it because he's grossly
underpaid for his fucking job and,
and I bet those guys
funded is fucking campaign.
So then he had to do them a solid,
it's all the same shit.
They all make 500 grand grand a year and
then come out of office worth hundreds
of millions of whatever. Fucking 70 80
million bucks. How does that happen,
everybody?
Although recently I saw Bill Clinton when
that fucking piece of shit brought up
the me too thing. You know with
Monica Lewinsky. I love level.
They tried to make that a me too thing.
You know what I mean?
It's like she was in her twenties.
She was a college graduate.
She never learned that she should.
That's what I was saying on stage.
She never learned that you shouldn't
blow a married guy in his house with his
wife and kid down the fucking hall.
She didn't know that.
Now she's coming back being influenced
by his power and it was, you view people,
people,
we get the fuck outta here.
You are a driven young adults who somehow
in your 20s got a job in the fucking
White House. Okay. You weren't some
dopey founded a bus station. I Nia.
Hi.
Um,
some of them monocle Wenski thing where
now that she's trying to like turn it
around that he used his
power and influence.
It's like you were a college graduate
working in the White House. Right?
I don't know.
I thought we had dealt with all of that.
I know and he got punished for it,
but in that thing he said Clint was like,
I left the White House. I was $16 million
in debt. You know what I mean? He's,
if that's true. I think he's the
only fucking president ever did that.
Oh Geez. She's, she's getting
ready for nap time. Alright.
Um, big band drumming. Dear bill,
I'm 17 years old and I played
drums every day. That's awesome.
It's my life and I'm in every band,
jazz concert and marching. Good man.
And I play percussion for the
chorus and for the school place.
Kenny Aronoff is my era. Well, that,
I was going to say that sounds like his
autobiography. Uh, how we started out.
Thank you for that dream interview.
I have it on a playlist with music.
That's how much I listened to it.
Oh, let's go. I'm glad you liked it.
You know Nia not for nothing. People say
actually do a good interview. Oh yeah.
From Kenny Aronoff to Danica
Patrick to my lovely wife. You know,
I said to you guys up, no, no.
Let you guys, I love it over the plate.
I learned that by going on Cronin.
That's what he does. Amy and
Andrea, they, they, they just,
they just lob it over to
you. All right. Andy Rector.
My Day was telling me about,
my dad was telling me about
the scar movement in the 90s.
I just watched swingers and discovered
this band, squirrel, nut zippers.
Oh my God, let's say takes
it back to your college days.
It's really takes me back to my early
thirties and I was in my late twenties.
It's really different
than anything I've heard.
I discovered that I don't like all scar
but I like these guys cause it's more
big band than scar. I really
think you uh, enjoy the drumming.
It's really a cool mix
between big band drumming,
punk and almost some premise tape drumming
stuff because at the time work, uh,
did you get ever get into any of that?
I remember that big bad voodoo
daddy and that type of stuff.
I liked it a little bit but I was
a little too old at that point.
That was actually kids music to me.
Um,
this is what our lovely daughter does
before afternoon that she screams bloody
murder. Um, and then falls asleep though.
Then talks to herself when she comes
down and then falls asleep. Anyways,
I doubt this will get read
because it's too nerdy,
but maybe just maybe thanks for
the laughs. All Billy rim shot. Um,
no, I like all that stuff. I
mean, I like when Robert Plant
book, Jesus, I liked him.
Robert Plant did that. The honey
drippers same with Paul Shaffer. Um,
I've always liked big bands in that type
of stuff and I really liked the way all
of that music is the score on
that separately and all that.
I just liked the way it was produced.
It sounded really live.
And um, and also, you know,
when you get that many people
in a band and they can all play,
it's always sounds great.
So
I'll be back in the day, he was also in
swingers. Okay. I did not know that. Um,
where make a gun out? I'll goes, oh yeah.
Oh yeah, they were, uh, they were great.
They are great, I should say. Right. What
did they figure out? A plea. All right.
Being rude to wait.
Staff. Alright man. Hey,
their ability bath salts.
Your YSI talking about Nia being
slightly rude to wait staff.
And it made me
a heads of word got cut off something,
a podcast.
I've heard years back about raising kids.
Essentially a group of economists gave
their opinions on what you can and can't
change in children supported
with studies and evidence.
One person suggests with evidence that
there are only a small number of habits
that kids pick up from their
parents. Those adverts are
drinking, alcohol, smoking,
and how we treat others. Wait,
staff, family, et Cetera.
Well,
those are kind of big things.
As a former bartender who's dealt
with incredibly rude patrons,
I would love to hear you and Nia debate
if she is actually being rude or not.
If she feels she's not being rude,
which she'd be okay if she
saw her daughter treating
a family member the way she
treats waitstaff,
absolutely she would love in the air.
Can't wait to hear her thoughts.
Here's a link to a podcast as a new data.
I think you'll dig it ab a great
summer and I hope you get sunburned.
You some of them on vetch,
um,
near do you feel as an influencer,
why can't you just influence them
to make better, better service?
I am not rude ages and
something goes wrong.
I just let them know and underrated
that and that like, I'm so sorry.
I'm so sorry.
I asked for his actions that I don't do
that cause what am I apologizing for?
Unlike no out of this. Can
you change it? Thank you.
What do I had to,
I had with like,
you want me to fucking the weight
or because he did something wrong,
like he's blowing me.
No,
I'm just saying it's throws a
little sugar on it in the end.
I feel like I'm very sugary.
I'm not no terrible.
Take it back right now.
Like, no, it's not like that.
You did one time it was
called and you said,
can you have them go back and heat this
up? And they say, Oh my God, I'm so sorry.
You and you're like, yeah. Cause it's
like, yeah. As they went to take it away.
And I was just like,
Jeez,
you remember everybody was at the table
like God damn near know everybody.
Who was everybody at the table? I got
Danny. And what have been your family now?
That didn't happen? Nope, I
don't, I don't remember it.
So maybe it didn't happen, but
like what? That didn't happen.
I don't remember it. Maybe it
did happen. That was hilarious.
Or the pork course that didn't happen.
I don't remember that.
Yeah. Maybe it did happen.
I don't recall ever being,
behaving in such a manner that it
would be like so, so freaked out.
You're adorable. But
even when you live, um,
yeah. Um, I, I go the other way.
I'm too nice and we'll eat fucking
whatever the fuck they send me.
You're not seeing when,
and they send me the wrong thing.
I still eat it because I don't want, cause
they don't want them to throw it out.
Oh,
who was I going to throw it out?
They may put it to the side and maybe
somebody lunch and the later on.
No.
Yeah.
You're telling me if somebody brought a
plate of food out into public and they
said that's not what they want and
brought it back, you'd be like,
Oh fuck it needed somebody may it.
Why do you know they haven't put their
fucking mouth on it and was like, oh,
this isn't Ravioli. This is French
toast. I thought it looked weird.
And then you go over there and
you get the old breakfast. Herpes.
That's the podcast.
I get to find out where my lovely
little blueberries crying downstairs.
She's phones. Oh, she's in the bedroom?
Yeah.
Okay. Alright, well I gotta
get off my day here of what? To
Lamont Jumbo Belguim
home.