Like a boss. I didn't realize this,
I guess like a year ago or two years ago.
You know that actress Shelley Duvall,
who crushed it in the shining?
Dammit. Let me open up God damn door.
Well, she's in her sixties
now and I guess she's having,
I don't know what she's having. She's
having some sort of mental issue.
I don't know what it is. Okay.
But she's old and she needs
medical help. That scumbag.
Dr Phil,
who I called it the second I
saw that guy I called it I,
I was at, that guy looks like a fucking
crooked cop. The second I saw him,
I was like, that guy looks like he
planted a fucking gun on you. You know,
he fucking shoot you over some routine
fucking traffic stop. And He'd pull out.
He do that to a white person. That's
how fucking nuts this guy is, right.
He's not your standard, you know,
bad cop going after minorities.
This guy would do it. This guy's like
a see it as a serial killer look,
doesn't he? Um, anyways,
that piece of Shit fucking interviewed
Shelley Duvall and talked to her is if he
was trying to help her.
Okay.
And she was saying all of this stuff
about how Robin Williams was still alive
and fucking, you know,
the earth is flat and just all kinds of
stuff like that where it's clearly like,
oh my God, all right, shut off the
cameras, shut off the cameras, come on,
let's not do this to her. And he's sitting
there talking to her life. So like,
he's going to try to help her.
So like you think that a
Robin Williams is still alive?
Okay. Um, I'll think you need, like he,
he was acting the entire fucking time.
Like he was trying to help her rather
than completely exploiting this famous
actress who's now in like, you
know, this mental condition.
It's just photos. It was, I
don't, I don't, how do people,
how do you still sit down and
watch that guy's fucking show?
Fuck that guy and everything.
He's fucking connected to
Jesus. You don't have enough
fucking money. You can't,
you don't drag enough fucking penniless
people onto your fucking show.
You don't have enough honey booboo,
people coming on your fucking show.
You got to do that.
Jesus fucking Christ. But you know,
I've been meditating and I guess I'm
not supposed to get upset about this.
I should really, you
know, I should expect it.
I should expect that behavior out of him.
So you're saying that you're hearing
these voices in your head are or
[inaudible] I don't. I'm making up
all of this shit. I couldn't get,
I couldn't get,
yeah,
I don't think I got 20 seconds.
30 seconds to do it the second she said
the Robin Williams thing and then they
cut to him. Go. So your,
and once he did that I had
to just so I shut it off.
Shut it off, shut it off.
Okay.
Dr Phil, have you no shame.
Yeah,
I swear to God, that fucking guy.
I'm trying to think what
he wouldn't interview.
Okay.
You know what wouldn't
you like? First of all,
I love that people watch those shows is
I is if they're like watching somebody
trying to help somebody, they're not,
you can't fix somebody
in a half hour episode.
Oh that time when he had that girl
on that little girl on there, the a,
you know, catch me. I'm sad how my
dad, that one that went fucking viral
did, did you say the, the,
the are laughing. Yep.
So the audience are a bunch of homes.
Yeah.
[inaudible] kicked me out.
Got You. Outside.
What does that mean and what I just said.
And then he has her back on again.
He's like, people thought, oh,
the explorer Naruto we took
out the studio audience. Yeah,
but you still broadcasted it. Yeah.
Danielle cheesier park
back. Where does everybody,
there's no homeless. I'm getting
a lot of tension on the Internet.
No. Before I came on here.
Thank you for that.
I don't know, but you know something.
I'm a hypocritical cut. All right.
Because I still watched the, uh,
catch me outside. How about that?
I just kept seeing it on Twitter and I
was like, I have to see what that is.
And I'm not gonna lie to you. I
did watch it and I did enjoy it.
So maybe I've got to knock
back my criticisms. Criticism.
Why don't you just exploit people that
still have their whole life ahead of
them. Jesus fucking Christ. I don't know.
Did I become the asshole by the end of
that? I don't remember. I don't again,
I don't know where the fuck
that whole thing went. Um,
do you want to take the top five?
Cause I think they could bring cameras.
I thought really? Cause
I think I flipped you.
You want to do it again then you
don't get all tall. Please vote.
This is not the place and this is
not to sit down. All Right Dan,
let me now.