Yeah.
Hey, what's going on it's Bill Burr and
it's time for the Thursday afternoon,
just before Friday,
Monday morning podcast and
ahhh just checking in on you.
How are you?
How was your week going?
What are you paying attention to when
the news that's causing you to yell at
people you don't know
online? Huh? What's going on?
Did you hear about this?
Somebody did this and
then someone said that,
and the results may surprise
you all fucking day. You know,
I walked through the God Damn airport
and I'm just looking at all these fucking
people looking on their phones
and you know what I see, I see me.
That's what I see. I'm
like, I'm doing that.
I'm just sitting there
staring at my fucking phone,
looking at somebody's flipping
a fucking water bottle.
Somebody fucking Duncan a basketball and
everybody running away like the world
just ended somebody fucking
playing the drums. What am I doing?
You know,
I'd sit there and read a book,
you know, so I look smart,
but no one would even notice. They're
all fucking staring at their phone.
So what is the point of reading in public?
If other people can't even see you're
doing it because that's why you're doing
it, right. Nobody reads in public.
You what kind of a fuck you some fucking
asshole walking down the street with a
book. You know, you're just
across the street like we get it,
you're smart.
MMM.
Well maybe you do read in public.
Maybe that's what you're supposed to do.
You read in public so you get
credit for it's everybody.
It's like that time back on the Seinfeld
episode with Jason Alexander wanted to
get credit for tipping. They didn't
seem so he reached back in to do it.
Then they thought he was stealing.
I think it's like the literary version
of that or maybe it isn't or maybe it is.
Um, anyways, I have something
to promote here. Um,
all things comedy network. I need you
guys to get behind this, you know,
if you feel like it and no pressure here.
Alright,
10 Alexandra has a new
special out that you can,
you can actually stream
it right now. Um, at uh,
ATC specials.com.
It's called a senior class of earth.
And Ted is just one of
those guys, man, I sweated.
He's just one of those comics
that every comic loves and uh,
but you know, you know,
this business is for awhile.
They like this person,
then they want this person.
And he just was never that person,
which I can relate to.
This industry was never looking for
a bald, redheaded mail, you know,
so I, I had to carve out
my own path. You're like,
how making his special about me and
my struggles. You know why that is?
Because I'm on social media all the time
and it's fucking frying my brain. Um,
do you guys could go on and check out
his special, it would be a be great.
You'd see. Great. There's
actually this fucking killer clip of one
of his jokes where he compares the fact
that he's in his late forties and his
girlfriend's in our early thirties and was
saying that, um, he was comparing
his sex drive versus hers,
which is in the prime to when Shaq
played on the Celtics where it was still
shack,
but it didn't look like Shaq anymore.
It took them like half the game
to warm up all of that stuff.
It's such a fucking killer joke.
And, uh, when you watch it,
what I love about Ted is
there's no wasted words.
And even like,
even like the physicality of his jokes
propels you towards the punchline. He's a,
he's an absolute master. So, uh,
please check that out. And with that,
and with that, did anybody watch
the Monday night football game bad?
Put it up,
put it over the Kansas City chiefs
against the fucking Denver Broncos
and um,
Jesus Christ.
I thought that announcer
was going to fucking faint.
I have never heard an announcer. So God
damn excited about a regular season game,
but that my home's,
he's like shove type Blah homes.
Captain Comeback.
Fuck something else.
Mo did everything that he did, like when
he was rolling. I'm not saying that guys,
and good, he's not going to be a fucking
star. One of the guys said, you know,
he came into the game as a legend.
He's been playing for a month.
Right?
Everybody flipping the fuck out. I know
why it's a God damn business. Right?
You know, Brady's fucking older than
dirt. This other fucking guy is like,
you know, uh, drew Brees. It's like
a year or two younger than Brady.
Yeah.
Peyton manning fucking were top so old.
I can't even get through these fucking
names without on a Peyton manning fucking
retired. They need new people. All right,
how many yards are these new people going
to throw for when you can't even like
start the hug them and then stop and do
the, you know, you know the me too thing.
Now we go to hug a friend of
yours and you start saying, oh,
well you get all fucking nervous.
You know,
that's the way defensive lineman grab
quarterbacks now and they still get a
fleck.
So anyways,
the guy fucking rolls out.
He's a right handed quarterbacks.
He rolls out to his left,
this guys breathing down his neck.
He dives at his ankles and right
before, uh, my home's goes down,
he switched the ball to his left
hand and threw it like four yards in.
This guy caught it, which I, I've
saw Brett Farve too, that I've seen.
[inaudible] I've seen people do
that before on this guys, I gone,
I hope you realize what you just saw here.
I think the NFL game, uh,
he'll like, listen man,
you got to hype this fucking Kiddo.
Okay.
You gonna have to hype this fucking
kid up. And as always, you know, I'm,
I'm the fucking Grinch.
A sports don't ever listen to me.
I'm always telling everybody to
fucking relax and not be excited.
I'm taken all the fun out of it.
But Kansas City, as of right now,
he has the worst defense in all of
football and everybody's freaking the fuck
out.
I mean,
they should be freaking out cause my
homes is looking like the real deal,
but it's just like you're not, you
don't, if you don't fix that problem,
you're not going to do shit in January.
Yeah.
So I dunno what all this
screaming and yelling is about.
Okay.
I hope you guys realize what part,
what I just said here on this podcast.
People go,
that was like one of the greatest Monday
night football games of all it is like
was it seemed like what happens every
time I sit down to watch a game,
somebody up by 10 and then goes into
a fucking shit, I don't know what.
And then they lose the game when I
was a kid. Like that didn't happen.
Like it happens all the fucking time.
One of the greatest
modern guides of all time.
It reminded me of three regular season
games I saw the day before. You know,
if that was,
what about the fucking Bengals falcons
like that wasn't I guess cause it didn't
happen on Monday. I Dunno.
Why am I such a jerk?
I have no idea. Um,
anyways, well, you know,
who knows.
I'm going to be taking a a,
it's Wednesday right now and I am taking
a red eye flight out to Springfield,
Massachusetts to do shows
in Springfield in uh,
Boston. And then down in, in, in
uh, Connecticut and Paul Verse.
He's going to be Ami with
all on all the shows.
And then I'm also working with the Sim
Boston guys that I started out with.
I'm working with Frank
Santa Rally in Springfield,
Tony Vee at Boston Garden and then
Dan Smith Down in Connecticut.
So it's going to be a,
it's going to be a lot of fun and I want
to thank everybody that's bought the
tickets and a or freckles is going to
try to go out there and not put on 40
pounds because of, um, you know,
I'm going to go back there. It's going
to be all the old haunts, you know,
you go back east, they got the
fucking insane Chinese food, uh,
the pizza, all of that stuff. So I gotta
like ice cream joints that I used to,
all this shit that I,
I'm,
this is what I want happens whenever
I go back to Boston is I, I,
because I left in 95,
I,
I go back to, uh, you know,
I started acting like I'm 22 years old.
The way I'm eating,
which somehow back in the day,
you know,
you'd go out and drink a 12 pack and then
hit Mcdonald's at the end of the night
and go home and the next morning
just wake up and go unload trucks.
His stomach was flat, you know, you
just shook it off back then. You know,
it's like doing your first burnout in
a brand new car, like the car getting,
you know, probably wished you didn't
do it. Probably not happy it did it,
but it can shake it off. It's
still looks new, you know,
now I tried to do that shit. There's
like fucking parts left in the road.
Um,
anyways,
so it's so Ba October and
I wasn't going to do it,
but now I'm going to do it.
Oh, well fuck it, do it.
You know, I'm a binge drinker. I
gotta stop with this shit. You know,
I'll do it. So now I'm on the wagon,
a lump date, but they [inaudible] do,
you know,
it's funny as peep,
there's like two different ways of saying
you're on the wagon. There's like, um,
you know, like, uh, you're on the
party wagon or your, your your,
whenever I'm, the way I say
it, if I'm on the wagon,
that always meant like you're not on,
you're not party. He fell off the wagon,
meant you started partying again.
But then other people call the wagon,
the party wagon. So I dunno, it's
just one of those things, you know,
it's kind of like that word
cock with white people.
It met Dick and with book black, older
black people, I should say it meant pussy.
You know, just a complete inverse. I mean,
it's sort of an extreme example,
but
I remember saying that
in the writer's room
and an f is for family and they
were like, that's not true, is it?
And then they end up having this fucking
snoop Dogg song from the early nineties
where you first do a
woman's pussy as his cock.
So fucking weird. Oh, people, people
have different ways of saying things,
don't they? That was sort of my
Mr. Rogers moment of the podcast.
I know there's a bunch of people
right now fucking Google in that.
Go ahead and Google it. Go
ahead and go. You know what?
I'll fucking go, Glenn, I'll,
I'll read, I'll read it to
you right now. This could be,
so maybe this could be something
interesting. Um, by the way,
have you guys been following anybody
like I told you, have you followed,
been following anybody
sarcastically on Twitter,
watching them make all of these news
events about themselves, you know,
telling you how difficult it is to
be beautiful, you know? All right,
let me see here. Cock. Oh,
Jesus Christ. What fucking,
this is going to be on my search engine.
Alright. Cock a doodle. Cockroach.
Cox, spar cockroaches. Cockapoo alright,
cock meaning
posy.
Thank you. I'm 50 years old. I
just searched that. All right,
let's see what happens.
We'll the FBI show up at my door and
we're waiting and we're waiting because
bill has the worst Internet
service and there we go. Uh,
cock means vagina. Let us explain. La
Weekly wrote an article about this. Uh,
let me see here. Okay, now this is the
one coc meeting vagina. Let us explained.
Now I don't want his fucking
subscribe to the La Weekly. Okay.
Rodney Carmichael's early high school
years were awkward. Like many young men.
He wasn't sure how to talk to girls.
This less of a problem for a
stepbrother who gives a shit.
Okay. All right. He
never met a grown person,
but recalls that his stepbrother
promise she was cute. Even better.
She'd seen comical from afar and
thought the same thing about him.
So their phone calls slowly.
Miranda meandered from
getting to know you phase too.
Clumsy Highschool attempts at flirtation.
Then she asked a question that stopped
him in his tracks. Do you eat cock?
Wait, that's not a fucking clumsy
flirtation. That's fucking direct.
It's like a fucking military
due. Cocked for private. Alright.
Carmichael was confused,
uh, to the young black man.
Everything to that point had suggested a
typical teenage heterosexual courtship.
But the question threw him for a loop.
He's like,
I didn't know if she was talking
about minor Hersey. He remembers.
It was kind of nerve wracking.
His confusion was understandable.
He didn't use the word cock much himself,
but he had heard it by white
folks in the media, Hbo,
old playboy who was slang for penis when
it was used by some of his famous rap
Fay favorite rappers. However, it meant
something else entirely. Take Miami Rep,
act two live crew.
That group obsessed equally with
bass and female anatomy, uh,
and most famously by most famous hit me.
So horny also had a song called
HPC in which they chanted head,
booty and cock. Uh, what
you like, Foote, fellows,
head booty and cock.
Oh Jesus Christ.
I don't remember that song. And two live
crew. Jesus Christ. What? Okay, snoop dog.
When I bust my ass up,
I'm raising up off the cock.
Snoop Dogg wraps in his
iconic 1993 hit gin and juice.
Yeah.
MMM. All right. So we've
got enough exam examples.
So no surprise that flooding caught
courtship quickly wound down nobody's cock
was ever eaten, but comic definitely
wasn't alone in this confusion.
There were surely many casualties in,
in an era when hip hop,
sudden popularity forced this old bit
of slang into a head on collision.
With the broader culture for one
group of people cock preferred to male
genitalia for the other referred
to female day. We go, ah,
and that's one to grow on.
See everybody, you know,
every once in a while
you learn something here
on the fucking Thursday afternoon podcast.
What do you think about that? Huh?
All right.
So you gotta be asking yourself the New
England patriots or play in the fucking
Indianapolis Colts.
A rivalry.
Arguably the biggest rivalry in the NFL
during the Peyton manning was there.
Maybe, you know, I always thought
the Steelers ravens was a good one.
Yeah. Who the fuck knows? Anyways, it was,
it was a big driver, but now, you know,
it's a different time. Andrew Luck, you
know, took a year off getting healthy.
Now he's
back. Who knows what happens. I love
what the Patriots did on Sunday. Oh,
by the way, I did I fucking call the
fucking Broncos at what they covered.
They still blow the fucking game,
but they,
I was so hoping they were actually
going to win the game. Um, but anyways,
uh, the Patriots did so
well against the dolphins.
That's the team that I want
to show up on Thursday.
But these Thursday games a weird cause.
Everybody's fucking tired.
They usually sloppy shit.
And um,
I dunno,
I keep,
I keep hearing Edelman is going to be
back and then other people say isn't going
to be back. I don't know.
But if he's back, you know,
we got that dude, you know,
who likes to party like
me. Um, in from Cleveland,
it help our defense can get a little
pressure on the quarterback. Something.
I don't know if we've got a shot.
We got a shot to go on a little run here.
We'll see.
We shall see what happens.
MMM.
So I went to the gym today,
right.
And uh,
I forgot my headphones.
Okay.
And um, you know, so the plane, you
don't gym music and shit. Right.
Okay.
And Dude, I got to say at my fucking
gym, it is so funny. It's such like a,
like I've, I've, I haven't been
in a gym in like 11 or 12 years.
I always worked out in my garage,
but now cause I need to do the lat pull
downs to finally build strength up in my
shoulder so I can finally
do a pull up again.
So I don't lose like 200 bucks when I
turned 70, cause I can't do 10 pull ups.
That's the bet. Um, with
Virginia that I have. And um,
so I joined this gym and I
haven't been in the gym so long.
Like there is just so many different
fucking workouts, Eh, cause you know,
back in the day they used to be,
I'd go to a gym and I'd be like,
that guy doesn't know what
the fuck he's doing. You know?
And that person really
knows what they're doing.
I should ask them for some
tips on how to work out.
But now I haven't been in there so long
and there's just so many. I mean when it,
last time I was a member of a gym,
like I don't think there
was even kettle balls.
Forget about all of this other shit where
people stand on things like trying to,
uh,
you know,
it's like they've got half a beach
ball that they're standing on it while
they're doing curls and they're also
working their core. I mean, I don't know.
So then I see people doing other
shit and it's just like, okay,
so is that a legit exercise or is
that person just fucking weird?
I saw a guy on, on, you know, instead
of doing dips, he lifted himself up,
he locked his arms out
and then he was just like
scissor kicking side to side.
Like he was running in the air and
I was like, is that for your ankles?
Like what is, what does that, I
imagine that's something for your core.
He wasn't bringing his legs up though.
It was like he was just
sort of running in the air.
Like you know those douchebags who do
pull ups and they act like they're walking
upstairs, you know,
like one person did it,
it was cool and then 40,000 people did it.
And that just immediately became
Douchey, like rollerblading. Um,
okay.
Oh, what did I hear this guy say
today at the gym? It was a self,
I was going to fucking write it down.
I forgot.
He was just talking about a show
that he liked and I was just going,
there's no way that wasF is for family.
He said,
I just thought that they were really
delicate with the, some sort of,
something sort of subject.
This was a guy talking.
I liked that show because they're really,
uh, they cherish something, blah, blah,
blah, blah, blah.
I don't know if he was hitting on the
woman he was talking to or whatever.
Tronic like we was fucking sensitive,
you know,
but I know they weren't
talking aboutF is for family.
And speaking of F is for family.
Uh,
Netflix put out their first bit of
social media about a season three,
which I'm very excited about it.
Um,
it, uh, dropped I think 11:00 AM or
something. I guess it's the next day.
So you guys probably already
saw it if you haven't seen it.
Vince Vaughn is doing a
voice to season and um,
it's probably the most
fun I've had in the, uh,
in the recording booth was
somebody, he, that guy is like,
he's completely in his own lane.
He is a fucking monster.
How funny that guy is.
And um,
I did my best to try to keep up with them,
which I don't think I did,
but I'm once again just another,
you know,
huge person to add to the cast
and obviously added the funny,
that's why I think this
is our best season and um,
and it's obviously his
production, um, company,
wild west fill that whole fucking reason
that the show exists to begin with.
So a, I want to thank Kim and
I want to thank all you guys.
If you're even thinking of watching it,
hopefully you will watch it and then
we will get to do it all over again.
And hopefully this time next year
I'll be talking about a season four,
but let's not get ahead of ourselves.
The Yankees,
I don't know what happened.
It's,
it's the fucking day before.
Oh No, it's today. It's happening today.
Maybe there are they playing right now?
They're playing the Oakland A's and
I have no feeling about this game.
I have no idea who's gonna
win this fucking one. But, uh,
I'd like to fucking check in here.
What do we got yanked
the,
is
the Yankees,
are they going to play tonight?
What time?
It's on TBS.
All right, I'll have to check
this out. No, you know what?
I'll actually be going to the fucking
airport so I'm going to miss it.
Maybe I'll watch it on the plane.
Should be some Yankee fans on there,
right flying to wherever the fuck
I'm flying to. Um, do you anyways?
I got some ad reads to read here,
but I don't have them with me,
so I'm just going to say I have them and
then I'm gonna I guess we'll drop it in
through the magic of fucking,
I don't know what magic of editing.
Yeah. So I'm definitely gonna do the, uh,
the sober October thing. I gotta do it,
man. I, I don't know what
my deal is. What is it?
When if you drink,
you just fucking take it to the end,
but you can also just stop.
Where did,
where does that exist on, like
addiction, you know what I mean?
Like, I can literally just stop
drinking and I let have alcohol sitting.
I just walk by it everyday.
I don't even fucking see it.
But then when I get back on,
then I just fucking, I dunno,
just slamming them, man. I'm thinking.
I used to be my last one. This will be
my last one. And I'm just like, I'm,
I'm still not, maybe it's my tolerance.
It's like I don't feel anything.
And then the next day I wake up, I'm
like, oh my God, I feel like Shit. Whoa.
I was way drunker than I thought.
Um,
I'm always amazed at those people
that can just sip, you know,
maybe it's just how I'm wired.
Like if I'm playing drums,
I'm gonna fucking play drums.
If I'm going to go do a tour,
it's going to be really fucking long or
some shit. And if I'm going to drink,
I'm gonna drink.
So
I dunno. I'm just too
fucking old for it. And, uh,
okay.
I Dunno, but this is what always happens.
Now I'll, I'll stop for awhile, month,
two months, a fucking year or whatever,
and then I just, I just get bored.
MMM.
There's gotta be like a,
okay.
It's gotta be a hobby.
They can come up with dude.
These fucking people like chasing
you around the fucking Internet.
Look at this art deco bar cabinet.
I looked up maybe getting an art deco bar.
Hilarious.
As I'm sitting there talking about,
I'm not going to fucking drink anymore.
I looked that up like fucking six
months ago and they just keep,
no, I just clicked on it just
to talk to you guys about,
and this will just never leave.
I don't give a shit what I w I could be
looking up something about platypuses
and in the side of my fucking thing,
it's going to say art deco bars
look at d sinks. Oh my God. They are
beautiful. Expensive as shit
though. Jesus. Fuck you.
Why are you paying all of that?
My God.
Oh, but they are beautiful.
That's my favorite shit.
I think also because I grew up watching
bugs bunny that I like art deco shit is
if you watch bugs bunny, there's a lot
of all the buildings and stuff. You know,
which people you know really hate it.
To be honest with you.
When they first came out,
they didn't like art deco.
They never liked the new shit. You know,
like me, I never liked the new shit.
What did I just bitching about?
Bitching about fucking Patrick.
My homes wasn't even veteran about him.
I think he's fucking great, but she that,
that announced it. My God, I, I,
there was a couple of times like,
I think this guy's going to faint.
I let him think he's going to
fucking pass out if this guy,
if he like hands off the ball,
then they're given case keen.
I'm no fucking respect whatsoever.
That guy,
I only went to the fucking NFC
championship last year, right.
Only beat the saints in the last
play of the fucking game. Right.
Granted that was the saints
fucking up. Oh. Speaking of which,
that guy plays on the
colts now, I believe. Um,
but uh, I don't know. Yeah, I guess
when that Shit first came out,
people just did not like it on any
level. A look at that one. Jeez,
look at this other thing.
You can't fucking see unique
art deco whiskey bar cabinet.
Now how in the fuck am I supposed to not
drink when there's bars like this that
I can buy? Well what makes this a
whiskey bar bill? Well you know what,
you put whiskey than,
Oh there you go.
Yeah,
he has little fucking holes in it.
What?
He reached down and you get the bottle
like that comes up like Michael Jackson
used to come up out of the stage.
I don't know.
I don't like shopping online.
I'll tell you what I need man.
I need a fucking fly swatter
and mosquitoes. It just
off the hook right now.
Did I say off the hook that I
say they're raising the roof?
Did I used to watch fucking Arsenio Hall
talk show back in the [inaudible] they,
I think I did. I think I did. Um,
yeah, these things are like, they are
not taking any prisoners. This is a,
this is special forces mosquitoes.
I got like welts on me and shit
and they are fast as shit. Oh my,
my hand eye coordination
isn't what it used to be. Um,
but [inaudible] really makes the
flyswatter is, is the holes in it.
You know what I mean? So as it's
moving through the air, it's like,
it's like the stealth bomber.
Nobody can here, you know,
even though it's got a fucking jet engine,
uh, sounding again here, it's that data.
They can't pick it up on radar.
Is that what it is? I don't know.
I bet they can know.
You know,
we don't admit it because he
spent so much money was like,
oh we can't find that thing. And
then they, they take pictures of it.
Oh that's what it is.
Okay. It looks like a, uh,
it looks like if someone
was going to carve a cock,
meaning a dick in a life and they didn't
quite finish that in quite rounded off.
Um, but anyways, the fly swatter
cause it has all those holes.
It's like a Prius when it first
starts off. You know, you can't even,
like if someone's trying to
run you down with the Prius,
when they first left the curb,
you wouldn't hear it.
By the time you really hear that engine
fucking turned on, it will be too late.
That's what it is. The flyswatter
is the Prius of, um, of fly killers.
Okay.
I think right. Cause what else you got?
You got that tape and you hang down. Um,
I always thought that that
was just brutal. That fucking,
that's like that mouse thing because you
just go into the glue trap and they're
like fucking ripping themselves
apart, trying to get out of it. Um,
there's no need for that.
All right. Just get a cat,
those creepy ass fucking things.
MMM.
Yep. You get a feeling like somebody's
stealing from you. You know,
you got just tells you I
don't trust this person.
I've always felt that way about cats.
I don't fucking trust those things as far
as I can throw on and I would throw in
because it's going to land on its
paws anyways. Right. Um, anyways,
I have a plane to catch everybody.
This had gotta be the biggest bunch of
nonsense I've ever said in my fucking
life. Um, I'm going to be at the, uh,
Boston Garden on Friday night and I'm
getting together with some friends I used
to play with back in the day to gym
during the day in the arena. This time,
unlike the forum, I will not
be going for fucking, you know,
three and a half hours. Uh, I, I'm,
I'm going to do with like 90
minutes or something, get in there,
have a good time and then just fucking,
you know, leave them wanting more. So,
um, I want to thank everybody. Boston.
I sold more tickets than I've ever
sold in my life. I can't believe it.
I'm actually in denial about it so I can
fucking mentally get through it. And um,
it's really going to be crazy because
I actually started my standup career at
Nick's comedy. Stop on
Warren Street, March 2nd,
1992 and 26 and a half
fucking years later, you know,
to be right down the streets. Pretty
cool man. Pretty fucking cool. Um,
but it ain't going to be cool for
freckles. Has a bad show. So, uh,
I will be making sure.
Well that's good now cause now it's sober
October and now I said it to you guys,
you know,
and I love that Rogan does that shit cause
it makes me want to fucking do it. Um,
so if you guys can come up with a good
rhyme for me, maybe I'll go for November.
You know, remember
sober, remember November?
No, it doesn't have a good
ring to it. What would have,
I'll let you guys come up with a semi semi
your pitches and I'll see if it works.
And if it doesn't, I'll blame
my binge drinking on you
guys. All right. That is it.
Have a great weekend.
You constant. Once again,
thank you to everybody who's
coming out to Springfield, um,
Boston and Connecticut. And please watch
Ted Alexandro special and all things,
uh, ATC special. Sorry,
senior class of earth streaming
now. All things company. All right.
All right, here we go. Here's
the first sweet. All right.
Thought the behave every one at some
point as wish they could just have beer,
wine or liquor delivered.
Christ.
I'm trying to get sober while someone
finally decided to do something about it.
Um,
introducing Southie.
The alcohol delivery APP saucy
delivers your favorite wine,
beer, and liquor, right to your door on
demand. Now, if you're in Los Angeles,
the bay area, Chicago,
San Diego, or Sacramento,
you're thought the order will arrive at
your door and under 30 minutes ready to
drink.
If you break out into the
fucking dts in that 30 minutes,
maybe you got a problem for the rest of
us saw. See, we'll deliver beer, wine,
and liquor to your door in days or less.
Nationwide. There were no order minimums,
no delivery fees, no running to the
store. If you've got the saucy APP,
you've got to fully stock bow on
your phone. No delivery minimums,
no water minimums. Folks, you've
got a keg party, they'll handle it.
And for a limited time, you can get $15
off when you download your thoughts,
the APP and enter your Promo
Code Bur bur that's the thought.
The APP spelled s a,
u c e y and enter Promo Code Bird,
sorry,
Promo Code [inaudible] for $15 off.
Get the saucy app today and use
Promo Code Burr a write my
book EAI you flow can doin.
I'm sure watching football is fun,
but it's more entertaining when you
have your fucking weeks paycheck on it.
Now when you have some action
on the caves, guys have,
you've heard me talk about this for
weeks and some of you are still on the
sidelines,
whether you're an expert or a rookie,
you should be betting at my bookie.
If you're the kind of guy that fucking
likes to bet a little win a lot like
playing the numbers on roulette,
you can create a big parlay.
Pick three teams to win
and if you hit all three,
you'll turn a hundred dollars into 600
if not, you're going to lose 100 bucks.
It's not just football. You can bet all
major sports. Take MMA this weekend.
Conor Mcgregor, by the way, inside story,
I heard all that bullshit about him
partying. All that fucking room is inside.
I heard that the that isn't true.
He was in great shape whether he went,
so we're not,
I don't know,
steps into the octagon on Saturday
for his first UFC fight in two years.
You can bet on things like whether he'll
win straight up or whether Kabib Khabib,
we'll deliver a first round knockout.
I recommend these guys
because I really trust them.
This is the one bet I know you'll
be happy with all season. My book,
he has been in business for years.
They've got great online reviews and
their mobile site is easy to use.
If you're on the sidelines. Now is
the time to get in the game. My book,
He will still match your first deposit,
dollar for dollar,
but you got to join now because
they're pulling that offer.
Logged onto my bookie right now and
double your money. Use Promo Code Bar B,
U R R and you'll get
your first deposit match.
100% that's promo code bird. You play, you
win, you get paid. All right, who's next?
Oh, by the way, since I
fucking recorded this podcast,
congratulations to the New York Yankees.
Huh?
We're going to go head to head again above
fucking time. We'll see what happens.
It's a short series. Anything can
happen. All right. He looks Hellickson.
There's nobody on the planet
like you. Oh, you're so special.
So why would you buy a generic
mattress built for everyone else? Um,
he looks Hellickson. Sleep matches
your body to the perfect mattress,
so get the best sleep of your life.
They Dillup delivery.
They've developed Jesus.
Nine different mattresses tailored to
specific body types and sleep preferences.
Just go to helix,
sleep.com/burr take their two minutes
sleep quiz and they'll match you to a
mattress that's perfect for you.
Contouring to your body to provide
unprecedented comfort and better sleep.
30% of Helen's sleep customers report
better sleep after switching to their
customized mattress from helix sleep.
Right now,
they're offering up to $125
off all mattress artist,
whether you're a side sleeper,
a hot sleeper, a power bottom,
or like a plush or firm bed,
they got the mattress that
will fit a fit just right.
Get up to $125 off helix.
sleep.com/ [inaudible] that's
[inaudible] dot com slash bar
$425 off your mattress order.
Hey, he looks sleep. How's
sleep.com/pro oh look who's here at
[inaudible] [inaudible] the red sox
and the Yankees, dude. Dude, dude.
[inaudible] Mandy, she too fucking
hammered. Give me your keys.
You got to shit your pants watching
this shit. No matter what happens,
ESPN will say,
this is it.
It's a couple of fucking
$200 million teams.
What about the fucking a me on days.
The lounge pants are made from the same
Mike Bro. Modal fabric is there on these.
They're making lounge pants. Oh my
God. You mean for lounging around?
I want to get some of these.
Let me tell you,
you'll be in fall heaven when you cover
your entire bottom half with fabric that
is three times softer than cotton.
You thought your balls felt s felt soft.
Wait till you feel your knees.
Uh,
[inaudible] always love celebrating the
fall season with fun Halloween Prince.
Check out their latest Jack
Lalanne or prince in undies.
Socks and bralettes
pronounced bralette. Uh,
the best part when you join the
membership, you can get all this stuff.
Lounge pants, teas and undies. Um,
everything me undies makes
for less than anyone else.
Special member pricing is just one of
the many perks of joining the membership.
Talk about why me undies are the best
underwear. Feel free to improvise. Well,
you know,
my balls used to be sad and you know,
feeling like they weren't respected
as they were shaped when they were up
against cotton.
You know,
and then one day I came in with the
micro modal or whatever the fuck they're
making this shit out of. Am I, I've never
gotten along with my ball bag better.
Um, we really still in the honeymoon
phase of this underwear. Guys,
I've said it time and time again.
I love these undies.
I said that they are the softest underwear
I ever put on and they come with fun
prints that I can match
with socks or my bralette
eight man tits hundred percent
satisfaction, gay guaranteed.
You're going to love these undies, but if
you're not into what Mandy's, we'll go,
we'll do whatever they can to
get you into the right pair.
If they can't keep them
and they'll refund you.
So it's really is risk free to
try the best underwear ever, uh,
me and has a great offer for my
listeners for the first time,
I'm sorry for any first time
when you purchase any of these,
you can get 15% off and free shipping.
This is a no brainer.
Get 15% off a pair of the most comfortable
on d she will ever put on to get your
15% off your first pair of free shipping
at a hundred percent satisfaction
guarantee,
go to [inaudible] dot com
slash [inaudible] that's
[inaudible] dot com slash
[inaudible]
[inaudible] [inaudible]
hey,
what's going on?
This is built bar and this is the
Monday morning podcast for Monday,
October 4th, 2010 and I'm
doing it really, really late,
super late, super, super late.
Like that whore you banged a
freshman year of fucking high school.
You know, we'll stop stressing out about
it. That's what's making it not happen.
You're not fucking pregnant. And was that
girl, everybody had that girl, right?
The one girl who gets fucking pregnant
like eighth grade, ninth grade, you know,
you go back for your 10 year high school
reunion and she's standing there with a
22 year old you like look at you.
Good for you. Why you still got it?
Actually that's my son.
Um,
that's right.
She's standing there with their three
kids and they all have like beards and
mustaches are a full rack of titties.
Um,
anyways, I'm super late because, um,
I hung around for an extra
day in buffalo and uh,
consumed about 9,000 calories.
I went to a,
the buffalo bills New York jets
game and then afterwards I went to
the Buffalo Sabre Philadelphia
flyers game. And uh,
I just had a fucking
awesome time out there, man.
I'm the first night actually
worked in Albany, New York.
I was working the egg and I want to
thank everybody who showed up. Man.
I had a great turnout for both
shows. It's my first little, uh,
my first little dip into the theater
market. Stuck my little toe in there.
You know? Yeah. MMM. But
I gotta tell you, man,
I had the scariest fucking flight I've
had in like 10 years flying in from
Chicago to Albany, right. I live out here
on the fucking west coast now. So yeah,
for some goddamn reason,
Los Angeles is this international airport.
But well that's not true.
It's because it's the other
side of the country. I mean,
I can get a fucking direct
flight. So like, uh,
I dunno Bakersfield, I'm trying to pick
some fucking obscure city, but whatever,
to get to Albany, I got to fly into
Chicago and then I that which was,
which was no problem.
Then I flew from Chicago to Albany
and when we came in on final approach,
I don't know what happened,
the guys like,
we're coming in for final approach and we
just was, we were in this fucking soup,
we were in this chop or whatever the
pilots call and we're just going up 500
feet down 600 backups,
seven and we're just in this shit.
And, uh, as I, as I've stated
before here on the podcast,
I don't mind turbulence when
I'm way up in the fucking air,
I don't give a shit drop a thousand feet
worth 30,000 off the fucking ground.
I don't care.
Right.
But when you're like coming in on final
approach, all of a sudden drop in five,
600 feet, you know, you start hitting
TV and tennis like back in the day,
like Fred Flintstone when he didn't want
to get busted for whatever the fuck he
was doing. Right. And he started
driving around the neighborhood last.
So in the end tennis, what that was
he doing? Was He cheating on Wilma?
Am I doing some, some stand up
comedy material from the 1980s?
Is that, is that what I'm
doing? Who was the deal?
Um,
so we're just in this shit and this
guy says we're in final approach. Okay.
And like 15 fucking
minutes later, I'm, I'm,
I'm just looking out the
window doing what I always do.
Go and give me some lights.
Let me see some fucking lights of the
city so I can figure out how high up we
are so I can figure out how
much I need to be freaking out.
And we just kept flying through
this shit and it was like really,
really bad to the point I was actually
feeling a little bit queasy, right?
And this guy's not saying shit and I'm
thinking, fuck, we're flying into Albany,
who flies into Albany, you
know, is that the the fucking,
is that Tom Brady flying that
plane or do we got the backup?
Why don't we know his fucking
name? Albany. The studs.
They fly into JFK, they fly into
Laguardia, they fly in to Newark.
They don't fly into Albany.
Right.
So I'm sitting there freaking the
fuck out going out. God, we've got,
we got the fucking backup to the backup.
We've got Trent Dilfer is backup pliant
flying the Goddamn plane. And uh,
so I did some, I haven't done in awhile.
I started praying to God, Huh? Oh Gee.
He h that's how bad it was. Either fucking
hedge my bets going, hey, you know,
I been talking a lot of trash about
you on the Monday morning podcast.
Wait a minute, do I even need to explain
it considering you know everything?
Um, now, seriously. I was like, all right,
all right, sorry for this. Sorry for that.
Sorry for my ceds.
And I'm really starting to get nervous
because we're still fucking, you know,
people's stomachs to drop in
and I'm really fucking praying.
And then all of a sudden
I heard this woman, uh,
puke like 10 rows back,
right?
Everybody is like visibly nervous and no
one has let out the bitchy scream yet.
And then I just hear this lady
like 12 rows back here, right?
So I start laughing my fucking ass off.
It's exactly what I need.
A little bit of humor so I can just
completely pave over any sort of emotion
that I'm feeling. And then we were
back in the fucking chop again.
And then the pilot finally
comes on and says, yeah,
they have us in a holding pattern
because you can see there's a storm.
And what I didn't get was,
why didn't you fly up above it or fly
east of the shit or get away from it?
We just stayed in it.
We were flying in circles in
this fucking storm and we would,
we would get to the point where it was
sort of tolerable and then go back into
it again.
And uh,
it was really getting bad and I was
trying to read a magazine and made me like
car sick, which I guess is air sick when
you're up there, but it's the same shit.
And uh, and then I heard this guy
like two rows behind me, you know,
he let out this really bitchy like,
Ooh,
as we were going over the thing and I
actually made me fucking angry, you know,
Christ's sake hold you
fucking get yourself together.
Fucking start making those noises,
making everybody scared you asshole.
So we did that, but that's what
it was for fucking 40 minutes.
We were in this shit
and people were puking.
People will make an woo woo,
like literally like that and a,
and I'm sitting there trying to fucking
remember what prayers you're suppose to
say from back in the days when
I was an altar boy. Right?
You're fucking rang the bells.
And on the third day he said,
this is what I've done for you.
I can't remember how
to say this is my body,
which will be given up for
you. That's right. You ring
it. Dang it. Dang it. Dang.
With the fucking the bells there. At
least that's how we did it. You know?
That's the only lame attempt at my church
we made to try to fucking compete with
whatever was going on fucking
in the inner city. Right?
They probably had Aretha Franklin
headline in or some shit.
You just had me looking like a
young fucking oop Cunningham,
whatever the fucking goddamn dude's
name was. I never watched that show.
The Andy Griffith show.
I always found it depressing watching
those broke ass southern people that town
drunk, who's never
funny to me. So anyways,
we finally fucking land and everything
was good and go to Albany. I do the Gig.
Everything's fucking great.
Then I go out to buffalo,
driving across the state in New York.
Absolutely gorgeous day. And this second,
I even get within the facility,
first of all,
every time he was a
fucking five hour drive,
six hour drive from Albany to
buffalo. What? Uh, I dunno, I dunno.
I Dunno how people drive, but a,
you can go a lot faster than that.
Three hours and 50 minutes you pussies.
So I go in there and the second I
get into buffalo, it's like fucking
pouring down rain. I'm sorry. I
thought I hit the stop on here.
It just immediately was the most
miserable fucking weather. And uh,
I ended up doing my show and
I don't know what's going on.
I'm fucking tired and I
lost interest in this story.
What do you think about that?
Yeah,
how do I regroup here? You don't fuck me
up cause I thought I stop my recorder.
God dammit.
This is why I don't do my podcasts on
the same day that I fly is because I'm so
fucking sleepy that I,
I can't, I can't focus.
I keep trying to fucking keep
the momentum going and I,
I just can't do it. I just
can't fucking do it. Let's,
let's just try to hit the highlights.
I get to Buffalo,
I do the Goddamn show. I
have a great time. And uh,
the other comedian I'm working
with, me and Paul Versey,
we're like, well, you know,
this is buffalo. They are known for their
wings. They're always talked and shit,
right? Philly cheese steak. You go to
Philly, you get a cheese steak, right?
You go to fucking Atlantic City,
you get you, you get fucking,
you get your dick suck in the alley.
Right behind the fucking blue
and beige Trump casino. You do.
You, you do what the Ryan when in Rome,
you do what the Romans do. So fuck it.
We're in Buffalo.
Let's go get some goddamn buffalo wings.
Let's go get some wings. So a, there's
two places to go. You either go to Tufts,
he got to anchor bar and Tufts was right
down the street. So we said, fuck it.
Let's go there.
And I gotta tell you,
you want to talk about living up to the
hype. Best fucking wings I ever had.
All right.
[inaudible] had a crunchy outside.
You don't like when people don't know
how to make the wings around the rest of
the country. When the crunch, the
outside is crunchy, that means a,
as my dad would say, Christ, you're
cooked. They shit out of that.
Um, yeah. Usually that means
somebody over cooked it. Oh,
is my debt eloquently puts it.
Cook the shit out of it.
That's what he's always here. Christ,
you're cooked his shit out of it.
Um, face all twisted up. Anyways,
that's back when you could curse in
restaurants, you know, tell you it's so,
we lost so many rights after nine 11,
I swear to God.
Remember you used to be able to walk
into Mcdonald's and you get your French
fries and they would call and he
could just yell at the manager, Hey,
hey fucking dude. Yeah.
Yeah. What the f well,
they're fucking cold. I'm sorry sir.
Let me get you some other ones. Yeah,
you do that.
Okay.
Right. Isn't that what you were able
to do or those my drinking years,
I can't remember. That's how I, that's
how I did it. So anyways, once again,
I've lost my train of thought.
I don't know where I am. Yeah.
So we go in there and,
and, and they're literally,
they're fucking crunchy on
the outside and they're,
they're juicy on the inside and
they got unbelievable sauce.
Then we got the duff beer. It
was the shit. Now, evidently
when Obama went there,
there's, there's another place.
It's a place called anchor bar.
And I guess when Obama went there,
he flipped a coin. He went to duff.
So we went to the same place the president
went to. But then afterwards, um,
ah, fuck it. I got to tell
that part of the store out.
Jesus. You know what this is?
This is like, uh, the
first draft of a script,
except this is all I got budget for.
This is [inaudible] be like a fucking
Edward Movie Cut. That was perfect.
Moving on. So the next day I go to the,
the bills game. All right.
And I'm, I'm, I'm uh,
I'm doing my little hundred dollar bet.
I'm picking three games
against the spread. Once again,
this week I went one and two. I went one
and two last week. So I'm two and four,
a pitiful two and four.
Even if I teased my teams last week,
I still would have lost with the fucking,
uh,
falcons beaten the saints and over
time. So this week, who did I have?
First of all, dumbest get you can do
as a gambler is I bet with my heart.
So I'm sitting there going,
right, the bills are getting five.
I know every football fan and out there
right now is going, oh gee. She said,
that's cause you know the fucking final
result. All right? I'm thinking all right.
The jets had been playing great.
They should go in and absolutely destroy
this team. It's fucking raining hour.
It's a divisional Ravelry.
This is the exam.
They got a couple of
injuries in their secondary,
these exact kind of a fucking game that
goes the exact opposite way, right?
And plus I hate the jet. So I say,
fuck it, I'm taking the pills.
And then I also took the Bengals
against Cleveland. I lost that one.
And there was one other one that I took.
I pick the fucking ravens.
I got to stick with the Ravens.
Man.
The Ravens had been good
to me and solve the lions,
but I think the cat's out of the bag that
the lions can actually hang so then it
can be getting fucking 13 point
spreads anymore. But anyways,
um, so I show up there, right?
And I'm walking into the stadium.
It's fucking rain and out. Ah, Jesus.
I fucked this part of the story up
to you know what? Fuck this podcast.
Great. She had cooked
the shit out of it. Um,
yeah,
it was fucking raining on.
This is one thing I've learned that when
you go to a football game and you're
dealing with the elements,
this is the more of a douchebag you
look like the warmer you're going to be.
All right. I saw the rain
and I said, fuck this.
And we went right to Dick's sporting goods
and I'm like, I'm buying that fucking,
I'm going to buy a raincoat with
the matching raincoats slacks.
I don't give a fuck.
I bought a pair of a wool
socks and I was good to go.
So I'm with Versie and you know they
only had like two raincoats left and they
were the exact same color.
This fucking grapes,
slush puppy purple.
So we both have matching
extra large fucking,
we got the jackets and the pants like
we're working at a fucking airport and
what green we're bringing in
the fucking soul plane. Right.
That was a purple airplane.
Right. That's what we look like.
So we show up to the game,
right.
Neither one of us is comfortable because
neither one of us is a jets or a bills
fan. So we're in enemy territory and
a, it's fucking drizzling it out.
It's fucking cold. So I proceed to put
on this Barney the dinosaur outfit,
right? And right off the
bat, Versie starts pumping
outgoing, man, I'm just gonna.
I'm just gonna wear that.
I'm just going to wear the top.
I'm just going to wear the top, trying to
act like it's not raining out that bed.
The reality is, is he didn't want to go
through the hazing that he would have to,
if the two of us walked in with our purple
on Purple fucking raincoats times two
, we would've got a ton of shit. And
I was prepared to take it. I had,
I had a whole fucking silly walk I was
going to be doing. I don't give a fuck.
So he punked out. So, uh, we ended up
walking in and put my head's cold, right?
All I have is a baseball cap on. So
I'm like, fuck, I gotta buy a head.
Can I buy a bills?
Who gives a fuck there?
And last pace being owned by a
bill's head. And then I saw this,
this one with the Patriot logo on
it. I said, fuck it. I'll get that.
Once I put that one on, I'm nice
and warm. We go to, we'll call,
we pick up our tickets.
We go into that high school football
stadium that they have out there that I
actually love. It looks like
an old school football stadium.
You know what I like about
that football stadium?
That's about the size of a football
stadium that holds real fans.
You know what I mean?
All these,
these new ones that hold
like 100,000 fucking pets,
all the bandwagon shitheads you know
when you're all in for the real fucking
fans show up. Oh and three, right?
So we walk into the Goddamn
stadium with love and life, right?
I'm already laughing at [inaudible] cause
I know damn well what's gonna Happen?
He's going to walk out there.
There's going to be some shitty little
plastic seat that's going to be covered
in fucking water and the only way he's
going to be able to absorb it is through
his God damn jeans and his fucking bbds.
And he's going to be sitting there with
a wrinkled up nut sack that's going to
be getting hypothermia by second quarter.
Why do I know this?
Because I've been there.
So we get a couple of beers,
we get this fucking beef on a stick
or whatever the fuck they call it.
We're good to go. We
go in there, sit down.
He sits basically down in
a fucking puddle. He tried
to stick a newspaper down,
which is a very absorbent and uh,
I don't know,
we sat there and I had hope for about
eight seconds in that game and the jets
came down and just fucking Jew.
They just kicked the shit out of him.
Christ.
They kicked the shit out of 'em and uh,
it was just over. So we'd, so immediately,
our solution is just to start drinking
the way we drank at the masters.
We're like, fuck it, let's, let's,
let's get going here. Right?
So we'll make a trip after trip and all
of a sudden I gotta take a Piss. Right?
So I go and I'm standing in
line and all of a sudden this,
this fucking six foot five
goofy looking jackass,
one of those guys who's like six foot
five, but you still think he can take him,
cause he's just covered in baby fat.
You know,
he's got a couple of whiskers on his
chin and his cheeks are rosier than Saint
Nick. Right? And he's got this
Jersey on and this big stupid,
I'm a buffalo bills fan with the
horns on it. The stuff, you know,
he's the Wacky Guy, so I'm
not even thinking shit, right.
This is bill's jets. I don't have a dog
in this fight. I'm not talking any shit.
I'm fine.
I forgot I was wearing my patriots hat.
And all of a sudden this big goofy jackass
starts going, well, what's what? Yeah,
were you're a patriots fan. He liked
the rats. We got to ran away the rats.
He likes to fucking read this shit,
right? And I'm like, yeah, you know,
whatever. He starts giving me shit.
I start giving them shit back.
Then the weirdest fucking thing happened.
By the time I get in to
the actual men's room,
I've talked, I've given these people
so much fucking shit that actually,
there's bills and jets fans
at a bills and jets game.
They're playing each other.
They stopped giving each other shit
and they teamed up together and started
giving me shit. Right. And then I just
said, I don't know what I was thinking.
I felt like I was on stage cause it was
like a crowd. I wasn't thinking like, Hey,
you know what bill?
You really haven't had a fight outside
of your family since maybe playing
fucking street hockey in the sixth grade.
If I didn't give a fuck,
I'm in a goddamn bathroom waiting to take
a piss in a goddamn trough by the way.
And uh, and then they just started
giving up fucking this one dude.
Such go on Tom Brady Sucks Dick.
He Sucks Dick.
And he's like miming it like ridiculously
well. So I'm like, Hey, you know, buddy,
you do that real well because I learned
it by watching Tom Brady or Michael.
Yeah. Did you rent that porno? You
fucking fag gets a little uglier.
Gets a little uglier than this other dude.
What the fuck are you doing?
I came up with the hell he was saying
to me and I just said, look, I'm sorry.
You guys have never won a super bowl,
you know,
then the jets fan pipes in.
I go,
do you realize the last time
you guys won a Superbowl,
Charlie Chaplin was still alive?
Do you understand that?
Do you know what cars look like the
last time you won? You fucking morons.
And then, uh, then this other guy got
the two, we've won three super bowls,
I'm sorry. Right? And then the guy goes,
well, you didn't play in the games. I go,
neither did you. Then he's just standing
there with this dumb look on his face.
I go, that's right. I keep staring
forward. You've got nothing
forgetting that I don't know how to fight.
So all of a sudden it's my turn to Piss.
I take my dick out, I'm ready to Piss.
And one of these fucking pussies pushed
me in the back hoping that I was pissing
at the time. Fortunately I
wasn't. So I turn around,
I put my dick away cause I'm a
gentleman. I said, well Gee, I go,
is that how you guys do
it out here? Really? I go,
which one do you guys pushed me like I'm
gonna fuck like I'm fucking Jackie Chan.
And for some reason none
of them said anything.
I don't know if it was my purple on
purple rain coat or the look of fire in my
eye, but I'm a fucking 42 year old
balding redhead talk and Shit in there.
And none of them said anything.
So now it's kind of funny to me.
I felt like I was in like the world
series of poker and I went all in and I
didn't have a hand whatsoever.
So I don't know who the fuck pushed me,
but that's what I mean. Come on.
Bitchy is move with the fucking week.
How do you do that? How do
you do that? How do you,
how do you push another man when he's
got his Goddamn Dick out trying to piss
into a fucking trough? I mean,
how do you get lower than that?
Do you guys have any ideas?
How'd he get lower than that?
So then after none of them said anything,
I go back and I started taking a piss.
And then that other dude who was miming
somebody's sucking a dick unbelievably
well right next to me.
Well,
one of those stupid hats that has the
toggles on the side and he's still trying
to give me shit and I'm
gonna go fuck yourself.
And then he just starts
screaming over and over again.
Are you looking at my deck?
Are you looking at my
deck like maniacally,
like five times.
I just sort of stared at him like,
why do you keep going this, this gay
angle? Like why is there always a,
I dunno.
I think he was one of those guys.
He was kind of in the closet and then,
uh,
so he just goes to football games and
he gets really drunk trying to just kill
the families. I think he liked
me. That's what I'm saying.
So if he's listening to
this, I'm sorry. Uh, I'm,
I'm spoken for you fucking pants.
You fucking believe that.
First of all, what's wrong with me? I
really replay it, all of that in my head.
Cause once I got out of there I was like,
I really started thinking like, what?
What did you think you
were going to do in there?
They're not Clint Eastwood yet saying
things. Clint Eastwood would say, what?
What the fuck is wrong with you dude?
Like,
I don't know if I've said
this before in a podcast,
a public bathroom is the worst fucking
place to ever get into a fight.
There is nothing soft.
There's everything is porcelain pipes
that concrete floor and then it has a mist
of piss and shit. It's just the fuck it
is the worst. So the worst place ever,
you know,
not to mention it usually starts evidently
when one person has begun the pissing
process.
So, uh, you know, older little bit wiser.
So then I'm standing in line to go get
some more alcohol cause God knows that's
what you need after an incident like that.
And I was just kinda just sitting
there thinking like, all right,
now how should I have played that
w it should have ended when the dude
with the water buffalo hat started giving
me shit.
What I should've done was roll with it.
I Shit you liked the Patriots.
I should've been like, hey,
you know you guys scored 30 on his last
week, man. You guys look great man.
I bet the jets,
I mean I bet against the jets.
I hope you guys should have just
ended it with that and did it. I've,
I sh I should have,
I should have extended an olive branch.
That's what I should've
done in the future.
That's what the fuck I'm
going to do because, uh,
that was a, a, that was a potentially
ugly situation, but fortunately,
mmm. Yeah. I think the people
who are doing it, you know,
had jobs and no one wanted to get sued
and no one was willing to take it to that
level. Uh, and when I say fortunately,
I mean for me and my face,
yeah.
Oh,
do you know how bad that would have been
to get stomped in that fucking purple
on purple rain coat laying there
with my dirty fucking patriots hat
and my team wasn't even playing.
I, I would've lost the lawsuit.
They would've been like, let me get
this straight. You're a patriots fan,
you're a patriots hat to a bill's jets
game and you somehow manage to get the
shit kicked out of you. What
the fuck did you say? You know,
that's one of the great things about
being a guy is you actually have to take
responsibility for your, for your
actions. See, what would it be like?
There's no excuse. There's no reason.
I don't care what happened, you know,
and he had a girl, which is true,
you don't in a fucking girl,
but there's no learning in that.
There's no lesson. Okay. You know,
even my best friends would have been like,
yeah,
those guys are fucking assholes in the,
but you know,
they wouldn't have been an awkward
pause and it would have been like, dude,
what the fuck he talking shit for by
yourself at a game when your team isn't
even fucking play. What's wrong
with you? You're 42 years old,
get your shit together. And they
would have been right. So anyways,
fortunately the bills, uh,
are smart enough to stop
serving alcohol at halftime.
So when I went to go get
more beer, um, there, there,
there wasn't any to be had.
So I walked back there and I'm laughing
my ass off telling Versie the fucking
story and he informed me that fucking
Sanchez threw a bomb to that fucking drunk
driver there. And um,
and I was just like, God,
Jesus, here we go. Here we
go with the fucking patriots,
let up 30 points to this fucking team.
And the jets are raping them like
this other patriots that bad.
I say we were in [inaudible] nine and 17.
Now I'm thinking fucking seven and nine,
so,
uh, whatever. So that was rough.
And then I ended up getting into it with
some other jet Fan. I'm just a dick.
I'm a Dick when I'm sober.
And then you add alcohol and that goes
to the next level. And then I don't,
when I go to a sporting event,
I become another person entirely.
I don't know what it is. I just,
uh, I don't know. I love it.
I love being at the game.
I met the stadium,
I get excited and then
I'm a dick and I say,
I say things that I shouldn't be saying.
And I just started giving this lady shit
and she was bragging about the jets and
I just kept asking her over and over
again, what is it like to share a stadium?
You know,
why couldn't she just sit there and
enjoy the fact that she was winning?
Why did I have to ruin it?
Why is my level of hatred for
all New York teams to that,
to that level? It's pathetic. It's
really pathetic, but it is what it is.
So anyways, most people would call it
a day after that point, but not me.
Not for Z, not us. Fuck Dad.
We're going to the sabers
flyers game after this,
there's more bears to be drank.
So,
and we got to check out
this fucking anchor bar to
compare their wings to Duff's
. Right. We're fucking doing
buffalo up. That's what you do.
You sit out in the fucking shit.
Uh, whether you watch the bills,
get their ass kicked,
you almost get beat down with your
dick out in the fucking bathroom.
And then you go get some wings and
hit the Sabres game afterwards.
If there's something else to do out
there. I didn't see it. Alright.
Nagra falls. What am I
fucking honeymoon anyways?
Who goes to Niagara Falls
for their honeymoon? Huh?
How far back into this staples
warehouse are you working that,
that's where you go. That's what
I want to know. So anyways, uh,
fucking cruise back to the hotel.
Get Out of our fucking, uh,
uh, Barney the dinosaur
fucking raincoats and uh,
I had to get directions. We fucking
flew down to the, the Sabres game.
This is what kills me. We, we go
to, we go to anchor bar first.
I was thinking the game was at seven and
eight. Turns out it's at fucking six.
So we're pulling into anchor
bar at a quarter to six,
getting ready to have some fucking wings.
We're still,
we're just having a great time doing,
I can just put the windows down.
I could smell him. This is going
to be the shit right? Just lit.
I literally gained like 20 pounds
yesterday. So right as we pull in,
the radio comes on and says,
you know,
the Sabres sabers already dropped the
puck and 15 minutes. So we're like fuck.
And we start driving really fast,
not knowing where we were going to go
because the plan was to get wings and then
you know, with sauce on a face, beer,
woo shavers play. That's that. That was,
that was the game plan.
But now we have to fucking start driving
and we ended up pulling over and uh,
these three black dudes walking across
the street roll down the window. A,
do you have any idea where the sabers,
ah, look at me breaking down stereotypes
and it turns out, uh, the dude,
we're after actually African
or we go where, you know,
how do we get to the HSBC us as
see fucking arena. And he's like,
oh dude, he's very far
[inaudible] I carry,
I can't do an African accent,
but I could just tell the way he was
rolling his eyes that it was really far.
But I was thinking, wait a minute, this
guy's walking. Does he mean by bus?
Who the fuck knows? Whatever. Long story
short, we ended up getting up there.
So we just think we're going to walk up.
It's a preseason game.
We're just going to buy tickets
at the booth. No can do.
I think I bought a bad pack of batteries.
They said fucking Duracell on him.
I think they will bootleg
these God damn things.
They're only good for a half
a fucking hour. All right,
let's pick up the pace with the damn
story again. So we walk up there, it's a,
it's a preseason game and we go up
to buy tickets and they're sold out.
Unbelievable for the Sabres
flyers that were like, fuck,
they're going to drop the
puck in five minutes. We go,
we got to go scout some tickets and I
didn't see anybody selling near the arena.
And I came walking out and I see this
nerdy looking white dude with a sweater
walking up and I just yelled,
who's got tickets? And he's girls.
I got two right here.
I got two right here and then we'll
fucking bottom off 60 bucks a whack.
Sat right on the club level.
They've got everything from Sushi to,
I don't think I have Sushi,
but they had like ice cream,
which is really fucking
ridiculous at a hockey game.
Maybe you get an ice cream sandwich,
but they had like, it looked like a,
what's that Italian rest? That
restaurant? The Italian uh,
ice cream. That's dish gelato.
They get like that level ice cream.
You know, are you really going to come
back with that on a cone licking a cone?
As you watch two people beat the shit
out of each other. Um, so anyways,
so then we get,
it's just first of all,
the sabers arena is this shit.
All right.
For the exact opposite reason.
Reason that I love the buffalo.
I love the Buffalo Bills Stadium
because it reminds me it's white.
It's what football stadiums
look like when I was a kid.
And I'm not insulting you guys out
there. I think it's the shit. I like it.
I hate those brand new fucking stadiums
that are the size of a god Damn Mountain
. I hate him. I can't stand them.
They're too fucking expensive.
They rape you in the ass for four tickets
because they gotta pay for the Fat Fox
who sit in the luxury boxes,
who don't even give a shit about the
damn team and they want to sit inside and
watch your game. Fuck all those
places. So, but the Sabres,
as far as a new arena, man
that's right up there with, uh,
as far as the new arenas,
girl was the best one I've seen.
I like the Minnesota wild.
The Phoenix coyotes had a really nice one.
And the worst one I've been
to was the Boston Bruins.
We have the worst brand new fucking
arena you are ever going to go to.
It's like a bomb shelter.
They went out,
they went down to the fucking Grossman's
hardware and they bought up all the
cinder blocks in the state.
That's what they did.
And then they just glued them together
and painted them yellow and fucking black.
There you go.
That's where we can put the Bruins
and the 17 time world champion,
Boston Celtics. There you go. Give you
some yellow plastic seats. Have Fun.
Everybody put the sabers arena, man.
It was, it was, it was beautiful.
Scoreboard was to shit. And they had
the, uh, the sabers head hang on.
That was fucking awesome.
And it,
when the game was nine to two Sabres
kicked the shit out of him. And, uh,
you know,
I was made fun of those people who listen
to the radio when they a watch a game,
like what? You can't see what
the fuck's going on? Well,
evidently I couldn't because I
saw what I thought was uh, uh,
Daniel Carsello getting
beaten down to the ice.
I saw this saber and this flyer go at
it and they appeared to both drop the
gloves and the Saber guy
went, what? Dash where?
Dash twice straight in this guy's face.
And by the second one the guy was
falling backwards to the ice and he did,
you know that final UFC,
you're not knocked out enough.
I'm going to punch you as
you're on the ground overhand,
right where [inaudible] to his
fucking face. And I was like, wow.
Wow. Who was that? Who did that?
And who was that? Who got fucked up?
And then five minutes later Carsello
was over by the penalty box and he got a
game is conduct. I go, did he do that
to Carsello and was he embarrassed?
So he came out and he tried to do a
handsome brother thing and fight him.
The second the dude came out and,
uh, turned out it wasn't him,
it was somebody else. And I heard
he didn't even drop the gloves,
which is explain why.
What does we're dodge would doge happened.
How do you do that?
How do you not drop the gloves
when someone else drops the gloves?
Even if you don't want to fight,
can't you just fucking dropped the gloves
to hang on and turn the other way and
give up the back of your head?
How I would have fought in
that bathroom. Oh, the noise.
Can you imagine the noise
of five people trampling me?
The echoing the perfect acoustics
of a fucking goddamn men's room.
Um, anyways, so, uh, and then we end
the night, the end of the night we, uh,
we saw a great God damn game,
saw that six 48 psychopath that I
want to see Chara fight on defense.
And then we went,
uh,
we left and going down to anchor bar and
we show up and get this for the third
time in the history of that place,
they ran out of wings.
They ran out of winks. Like,
are you fucking kidding me?
Went down there to watch the giants game
versus a big giants fan.
Right. So we go, fuck it,
we'll stay here anyways.
And uh, I dunno, ask Paul about there.
I don't want to trash the place
cause I know which legendary,
but go on Paul's Facebook page and ask
him how he enjoyed the mixed drinks there
because, uh, he had a little issue.
He had a little bit of an issue there.
You know what I mean? You
know the deal a, let me get,
let me get absolute, uh, on the rocks
and the, Eh, absolutely. You know,
and then you just see them pouring it
out of a fucking jelly jar and you're
like, what? What kind of absolute
is that? Eh, ah, absolutely.
Uh, my friends, vodka daddy
makes down the street.
You fucking pricks. So we actually
didn't have a good time and anchor bar.
We showed up and uh,
they were out of wings and then
they tried to pass off some shit.
Vodka is the real thing.
Is that how they do it at the anchor bar?
I'm still going to go back
there and try their wings.
I gotta I gotta check it out. I
mean, I liked everything inside.
You go inside there and they had like
fucking, it was like a motorcycle museum,
like real motorcycles above it.
They had license plates everywhere
from like Hawaii to like the northwest
territories. They like license
plate shaped like a bear in there.
That's how far north these fucking ice
road truckers come to calm down and get
the MCL, some fucking buffalo
wings. So we did it up.
We did Buffalo,
you know,
actually if I got into a fight and
lost but didn't really get hurt,
that really would have made,
that would have been great.
A little bit of blood in my purple fucking
raincoat. The fuck is wrong with me,
but let's get to the questions this week
everybody. This is actually a really a,
considering that that happened. And, um,
I let me, I just, I had
somebody sent me a great
podcast question about
that under the new topic,
sports cuts. Um, and by the way,
I'm going to get out of the sports
talk after a while, cause like,
remember when I went real hardcore
conspiracy theory and talked about banks
every week and then that got boring.
Well,
the sports thing is only going to be
interesting for so fucking long, but uh,
we are, we're really in the throes of
it right now. I know for a lot of you,
this is like during the soprano's when
Tony was in that fucking a out of body
state where he walked around, didn't talk
like Tony Soprano. Remember that shit?
Do you, okay. Um, let me adjust the levels
here. Hope these aren't too loud. Okay.
So here you go. Sports
cuts a bill. Um, all right.
Anyway,
uh,
all of your jets hating
made me want to email you a,
I went to the jets pats game for week two.
I'm a patriots fan by the way,
and I love to hear you.
Uh,
your take on fans who attend football
games, it's fucking incredible.
I went with my girlfriend who
was wearing a Brady Jersey.
Now know that this is an
away game. Everybody, okay.
They went to New Jersey to watch the
New York jets play in giants stadium.
It's [inaudible] which
fucking middlish shut up. Um,
we pull into the parking lot and every
and people were literally moving their
chairs into the open
parking open parking space,
not letting me park saying
patriots aren't allowed here.
And He, the guy writes, ha ha ha,
I get it now. Can you please move?
No one would fucking move. It's amazing.
It's like, okay, I fucking get it.
You hate the patch now. Get the
fuck out of my way and let me park.
So they finally move and we get out
and start walking towards the stadium.
Uh, he goes, these people
start following us,
calling us every name you can think of.
Um,
and he's like, like, really?
Do you have a f? Do you, what?
Do you have a fucking family or anything
else in your life? You take this game,
this seriously? I would've said something,
but there were like nine guys. Well, Hey,
welcome to my world. Welcome
the Meyer with. He's just thank,
thank God you weren't taking
a piss at that time. Uh,
but they were like nine guys in
like six girls calling me up,
patriots loving faggot. Then
he writes faggot. Really?
So we keep walking and pass some normal
people who heckle in the right way.
You're going down, Brady sucks.
I get that. Ha Ha. It's fine. Um,
best come back by the way is just to
keep walking through the parking lot,
responding with 1969.
They hate that, but I only pull
that card in response. Okay.
So now we're going up the escalator.
Some guys going the other way on the
escalator and starts screaming you Rhombus
is ugly as that fucking
Brady Jersey you have on. Oh,
they're saying that to your
girlfriend. Wow. Go Back to Boston.
You faggot a what the fuck?
Uh,
then at our seats there was a fucking Jew.
Stupp roid head screaming his
fucking face off, turning red,
punching the shit out of the seats,
screaming the entire game.
There was a fucking dad and his 12
year old daughter in front of us.
Anyway, I just love to hear your take on
these fucking lunatics. Like I get it.
You love football,
but really,
is there nothing else in your
life that you take this seriously?
Um, all right. Um,
while you're talking to a guy who's
been on boats, I've never gone,
I've never called someone a
faggot and I never do that.
There's more of us than you.
So I'm to try to intimidate you thing.
I'm more of the,
uh,
loan wise ass talking shit to someone
who can beat the shit out of me.
But this is what you got to understand.
All right?
Just to avoid these
situations as sports fans,
um, this is, this is what I've found.
You can, all right, first of all,
if you're going to go into
another person's stadium, okay.
And not only were the other team's Jersey,
but the Jersey of a team that is
literally kicked the shit out of the other
team.
I mean,
the Patriots since 2001 have basically
kicked the shit out of the jets twice a
year. Every fucking year for
almost 10 years, or the very least,
we've won like 80% of the fucking games.
Um,
so that jersey, it's like, you know,
you got to understand that you're,
you're bringing up a lot of bad
memories. Um, and I'm, yeah,
those people who actually
don't let you park there. Yeah,
they are taking it too far.
There's a little bit on both sides,
you know what I mean?
It's like you kind of,
you know,
slicing your leg and then jumping in a
shark infested water and then getting
upset that you get your
fucking leg bid off. I mean,
I think it's bullshit. Uh, I don't know,
but I do get it. Like people
should get shit. Okay.
That roided out guys. Who, who's
punching the back of the seats? Like the,
I mean that's, that's kind of par
for the course. I hate to say it,
it is par for the course.
Like the eagles fans really get,
our Philly fans get way too much
credit for psychos. They kind of act,
it's kind of like racism, how they act
like it's only white people in the south.
You know,
like that's where it is and it's Kinda
like Philly gets all the shit or credit
depending if you're proud of it and not
that like only moron asshole fans are in
Philly. I mean, I've been to
games in Philly, the word,
one of the worst experiences I had was uh,
going to a San Diego chargers game once
again with my Patriot fucking hat on
like an asshole. You'd think
I learned from that. Um,
yeah, my take on that is,
yeah, you know, there should be
this fun talking shit and then there's
the talk and shit where it's not fun.
Like someone pushes you away trying to
take a piss or they start, you know,
seeing your girlfriend's ugly or whatever
the fuck they were trying to say there.
Um, but you know, if you wear the
Jersey of the o team, you walk in,
you got to expect that someone's going
to call you a pussy or probably throw the
last bite of their hotdog at you. What's
going to happen? People are drinking and,
uh, you know, a lot of people
don't like their lives.
They don't like who they're married to.
Maybe they don't like their job. Um,
or maybe they're just a
Dick, who knows? But, uh,
you gotta understand that basically,
you know,
you wore the Jersey of a team that's
won three Superbowls into the stadium.
Have a team that,
like I said,
Charlie Chaplin was alive the
last time that jets wanting, okay,
Harry Truman was alive.
Dwight d Eisenhower was alive the
last time. The jets wanting all right.
And I'm not trying to give the judge Shit,
I'm just,
I'm just trying to show compassion here.
Brett Farve wasn't even alive the
last time the jets wanted. Okay,
so you gotta, you gotta be a little more
compassionate to the jets fan. I mean,
like the Dallas cowboys were considered
bridesmaids could always get to the big
dance, but could never win it. The
last time the jets, when the Superbowl,
you know,
Richard Nixon was president.
Spiro Agnew was vice president.
Cost of a new home was $27,500.
That was the average price.
Average cost of a new car was $3,270.
The last time that Jay,
I'm not giving the judge Shit here by
bringing out these staggering facts.
I'm just trying to say, you know, you
gotta, you gotta show a little compassion.
You have to understand that these poor
bastards, the last time they won it,
the population of this country
was only at 202 million.
Do you want to stand that
they have one in a long fucking time.
Price of gas was 35 fucking sense.
Do you really think that you're going to
walk in with the Jersey of a guy who's
created them so much fucking misery,
who was a haircut that they can't stand?
Who's banging the hottest fucking
broad in the planet right now?
You don't live in the life that
they want to live, but can't,
you know as they strain in the upper deck
to try to figure out what the fuck is
going on? Yes. You're going to get
called a faggot. Do I think it's right?
No.
I wish there was friendlier ball busting.
I really wish that more people knew how
to break balls and including myself.
More people knew when to shut
the fuck up like me, you know,
like I should have, I should have
tapped out buddy and I didn't. So, uh,
anybody have any odd, bad sporty, uh,
what's your worst experience as a fan?
Like I could tell you,
like back in the day,
I would wear like a red sox
hat to a Yankees game in
Yankee stadium before 2004,
I would do it because,
you know,
we had,
what did we do to them
except blow leads and lose.
But once we fucking hung the biggest
choke and professional sports history
around their goddamn next,
then it became a different thing.
And then we won it again.
And then all of a sudden I noticed it
started getting hostile. I was like,
all right, this isn't cool
anymore. This isn't being taken as,
this isn't a funny thing anymore.
This I'm not the fucking, uh,
the fucking happy go lucky kid
who's just hoping to see it once.
I've seen it twice since
the last time they won it.
And I notice simply
got ugly this same way.
The Patriot's stadium went from a,
an absolute fucking zoo to being this,
this sort of classier place to go see
a Goddamn game when we were winning.
And that was the thing. Anybody can be
classy when they're winning, but you know,
you see who your fans really are
when you're fucking losing. Yeah.
Like when the Patriots,
I mean,
red sox finally beat the Yankees and
that they didn't like when a rod slap the
ball down. They didn't like
that. They didn't get that call.
Like they had been so many other
fucking years. That goddamn fans,
Poland routine fly balls into
the fucking stands for home runs,
Reggie Jackson leaning into the ball.
They always get those calls and all of
a sudden they didn't get and they threw
fucking tamper tantrum started
littering the field. Right.
The classy Manhattan nights that
they are. So, I dunno. Yeah.
Um, yes. Basically all sports fans,
behavior needs to be a needs to improve.
And uh,
it starts with me just like
that Michael Jackson Song. Huh?
Starting with the man in the mirror.
Um,
no one did. They push me purple on purple
rain coat. I wasn't even fucking ticket,
I would have pushed me too. All
right. Question of the week. Uh,
somebody wrote bill, why do
you hate stoners? Oh yeah.
Cause last week I was making fun of my
stone, a friend. Uh, I don't hate stoners.
I was,
I'm,
I don't like stoners who call me up and
trash my life because they don't like
their own. All right. Stop making it
about yourself. All right. And uh,
this person actually wrote and thought
that I smoked weed, which is a,
that's one of the things that is a known
unknowing about stoners is after they
smoke long enough,
they think that the only way to have
creative thought is to be sucking the Dick
of that plant.
Okay.
Well I just lost my stone or
pop. I just don't, uh, um, I
don't, you know what it is.
I don't like the fucking, I don't like
putting smoke in my lungs. Yeah. I just,
you know, there's two things.
You don't want your lungs, okay.
You don't want smoke and
you don't want water.
So I wouldn't slowly inhale
a glass of water, you know,
and slowly drown myself over 60 years.
I wouldn't do that either. But, uh,
I have to admit I've tried
weed a couple of times.
I didn't try it till I was like
37 to how hilarious is that?
And then I finally tried it and it
was exactly what I was afraid of was I
fucking loved it. But, uh, I just
can't, I just can't get that,
that image of that person smoking through
the hole in their throat. I just, yeah,
I don't want lung cancer, so
I don't fuck with it. But uh,
it's a lot harder to see your
liver shriveling up as you booze.
MMM. Anyways. Hey Bill,
have you seen the uh,
the infomercial for the I renew bracelet?
I'm sure you have.
It's this magic bracelet that makes you
have better balance, strength, endurance,
and sleep better. Hell, you might even
be wearing one right now to bring up,
to bring the funny out in you.
Uh,
it's a little piece of rubber with a shiny
piece of metal on it probably cost $2
to make a hundred of them. Yeah. Um, it
channels your body's energy or some shit.
Maybe it works. I don't
know. You know what's crazy?
People are buying these
things for $20 a pop.
Someone's getting rich off this gimmick.
God bless them for finding an
angle to make some dough. Uh,
I think it's in the same category
as the $50 gold coins for 10 bucks.
Yeah,
it's exactly at,
I think whoever came up with that as a
genius and those really bad actors where
they,
they act like they can't stand upright.
Yet somehow they were able to make it
to the mall to go on film with those
stupid braces. And the second they put
the bracelet on, oh my God. It's amazing.
Like I can't believe it. Um, yeah.
Bracelets are a great way to go.
You know what you do make a
bracelet that actually says a,
it'll make your dick bigger or give
you a flat tummy for the ladies.
You know, something like that. I
Dunno. I'm getting sleepy again.
I told you some good stories here,
haven't I?
You know the last time that
jet's won the Superbowl,
Jim Brown was the all time Russia leading
rusher and behind him was Joe Perry,
not from Smith.
Joe Perry from 1948 or so.
I don't even all the fuck he played
for the top three would Jim Brown,
Joe Perry and Jim Taylor.
Okay.
The guy from fucking Smith was
second behind Jim Brown in rushing.
That's how long it's been since
the jets have wanted. So yeah,
you can't wear a Tom Brady
Jersey down there by the way.
Thank God my patriots fucking one tonight.
Jesus Christ. And I'll tell you as
much as the score was, uh, you know,
lopsided there. Jeez,
there's a lot of water.
There's a lot of water leaking
into that ship. Jesus Christ,
I don't know what the
fuck is with our defense,
but so much of the game we look like we're
in a proven, it's fucking ridiculous.
So my big prediction this
week, now, my big prediction,
my big question this week is if
Ben Roethlisberger comes back,
doesn't miss a goddamn step and just
plays the way that guy can play and that
defense plays the way it's been
playing, uh, I put them on top,
the AFC, I would say that they, they are,
they are the team to beat the fact that
they went three and one with a third
string fucking quarterback
and basically all, I mean
we're what they lost in like the last
play of the game. They will, they will,
they were that close to going for and oh,
that's how good their fucking defenses.
And then not only that, that third string
quarterback got all that experience.
I'll tell you, big Ben comes in, right?
And just kicks ass.
And then they just stick them in an
armored car and they drive him past all
those Hooters and just get them home.
I think the Steelers might
be going for number seven.
How fucking Badass would that be? That
would be that. That would something.
Um, all right, here we go. I
remember a couple of years ago,
we will want Superbowl behind
them. I'm like, here we go,
Steelers and next we're going to catch
them. And then what happened? Nothing.
Then they want to more so we're
fucking in the dust again.
All right asshole friends.
I asked you guys for some stories about
asshole friends. Here's one for you. Uh,
just wanting to, so, uh, put
up the right off the bed. Okay.
Where do I start this?
Fuck you guys. I'm tired.
Why don't I just start at the beginning?
Just wanted to say I know exactly what
it's like to have a buddy who always
seems to have shit in his diaper and
just has that puppy dog look in his eye
that says, hey bro, can you deal
with my shit before I get a rash? Uh,
last night I was at a local bar just
relaxing and enjoying a couple of beers
with the girl I'd been talking to and
a buddy I hadn't seen in about a year.
Moseys on over. I'm excited. You know,
he's an old high school buddy and I'm
expecting to have a good couple of good
lasts with this guy right off the
bat. I asked him how he's doing, uh,
just expecting them to say, you know,
say something like, good, how about you?
Like any normal icebreaking human
being. Right? But he says, I say,
how are you doing? Uh, he just size
and looks at his beer and then do
his feet. And I'm just like, Gad,
damn it. Here we go. He
goes on about, I was,
mommy kicked him out of the House that
he's got something wrong with his neck,
that a heat pad won't get out.
Something about a Dui.
Then he has the nerve to complain
how he got turned down for government
assistant checks. It's like, if, have
you ever heard of AIDS in Africa,
motherfucker of Jesus. You went all
the way to the end with that one. Uh,
needless to say, I'm getting annoyed
at this point and I say, well shit man,
you know, we all got to grow
up. What a great fucking line.
Then I offered to talk to my boss to
try and get this guy a job so he can get
back on his feet.
He then looks offended,
pissed off that I didn't rub his belly
wipe is bubbling lips and tell him
everything was going to be just fine
and throw a couple of quarters into his
Little Tin Cup. Exactly,
exactly. How old are you?
Fucking move on and get a
Goddamn job, you bum. Um,
so anyways, the guy announces when
he, after the kids said, uh, you know,
we all got to grow up sometime he,
and he announces I wasn't
born to be a slave dude.
Fuck that noise. And
I'm just thinking, yeah,
maybe you shouldn't have been born at all.
As I turned back to my lady,
I know that's a harsh thought,
but when you're born with the fully
functioning brain in a nice area,
with a good educational system, with every
opportunity in the world to not suck,
and you still apply for
government assistance, it's like,
do us tax rape victims of favor and do
a triple Lindy Rodney Dangerfield style
down a flight of fucking
unforgiving. All right. Uh, yeah.
I have to go with you on that
one. Um, yeah, those guys,
they're the fucking worst. I love that
you said that to them too. While you know,
we all got to grow up sometime.
I wasn't put on this earth
to be his slave marriage.
What are you fucking King?
You're just going to sit around and
have other people bring wealth to ya.
I Dunno. I got no comeback for
him. I'm fucking exhausted.
I'm going to wrap this up then I shut it
off again. No, I did not know. All right.
Let's wrap it up. A little. Overrated,
underrated and some youtube
videos for the week. Um,
overrated. Uh, popular rap
and hip hop music since 1994.
Um, if a six month old song is considered
dated and dead than it wasn't good to
begin with. No one listens to jar
rule or Nelly or 50 cent anymore,
just like no one will listen to Kanye
West or little Wayne in five years.
If music we're a food than modern
mainstream rap would be Mcdonald's.
It's on every corner.
Easy to put together and it
gives grownups horrible diarrhea.
All right. I don't know much about hip
hop, but you know, think little Wayne
50 cent now, uh, since 1994.
What about Biggie?
You didn't like any of this shit.
There's a couple of guys I know wasn't
Nas illmatic wasn't around then.
I don't know about that album,
but everybody says that is unbelievable.
I know what you're saying though. All
these auto tune fucking songs out there.
I get it. I get it. All right. Underrated.
Not going out every weekend and
spending $100 at a bar or a club. Yeah,
I'm 21 and I'm supposed to get out there
and have fun, meet New People and Shit.
But like you said,
it's hard to meet girls when it sounds
like you've got a bass drum chilling in
your ear. Just not, just not
in a way, it's some broad,
you know, you won't sleep,
you know, won't sleep. What?
Just nodding away at some broad,
you know,
you won't sleep with and
you're just hoping to,
God she didn't just ask you a
question that requires an answer.
Call me lame,
but I'd rather hang out on a porch.
On a nice night with some good friends,
sweet girls.
Just fucking drinking a good beer.
You ran a country song here hanging
out on the front porch with some good
friends is a sweet girls drinking some
fucking good bear with the game on me and
a good conversation and rock
and roll in a CD player.
I'm not writing these lyrics.
Maybe you won't wake up with a hole
in your pocket and bleed nears.
Let's do it for America. Keep
it up, mother fucker. Yeah.
All right. Youtube videos. Yeah, I hear
what you're saying dude. Yo Chill at home.
Fucking try to bang the girl next
door. There you go. Save your money.
And with that I am with that.
I got a a underrated, uh,
not having a bunch of dumb dumb whores
with their tits and ass is hanging,
run out on a football
field during halftime.
I want the old fucking school
bands to come back out again.
Did you see that horse shit tonight?
You know Kelly Rowland up
in the stands said, oh,
it was the girl from Destiny's
child. We am I survive. Is
it
gives a fuck.
Who gives up and she's up on the stand,
like the desperately trying to make
music without a band. Interesting.
I'm sick of it. I want musicians
to come back, you know,
and I want them to play
in musical fucking, uh,
atmospheres. I don't want to
see it. A fucking football game.
Get a goddamn hundred men marching
band to come out there. Right.
Just play the old school songs. But I
have it up. Bam, Bam, Bam and Amsterdam.
Bam, Bam, Bam and eminent.
Yeah, but that's shit.
You fucking come out there with you God
damn shit. Talking about breast cancer.
I understand. I know. It's a problem.
You didn't write your fucking
song for breast cancer.
You're trying to use breast cancer now
to, to, to sell some more fucking cds.
Huh? Because that other one with the
awful voice is selling more than you.
Is that what you're doing?
How was that less offensive than Janet
Jackson's titty coming out is fucking
beyond me.
Tell you that right now.
You know all those fucking whores walking
around with their fucking asses and
titties, hanging out. You know, why
don't you fucking get a Goddamn job?
You'd dumb whores, Jesus. Fuck.
What would you be doing if he didn't
have half your goods hanging out of your
fucking shorts? You know? Do you
have any fucking talent whatsoever?
You can do a split. Great, fantastic.
Does that mean you got to put on some
cowboy boots and get stuck to the goddamn
astro turf turf in front of 80,000
fucking people on Monday night football?
I don't think it does.
I don't think it means that at all.
I think that's,
that's a sign that you suck as a musician.
If you sing at halftime
at a football game,
that pretty much means either you suck
your music socks or you've completely
sold out as a goddamn musician.
All right,
and that goes to those fucking
kids who play the Superbowl too.
I don't give a shit fucking Bruce
Springsteen screaming about dip and then
sliding around on his fucking knees
like he's not 60 Jesus Christ.
He got some good plastic surgery,
right? That guy was like 35,
(455) 055-0640 one he's 41 again,
I don't know how the fuck he did it.
He got his face yanked back and it
actually looks good. You know why?
Cause they practiced on all those real
housewives of fucking New Jersey in
Orange County and all that shit.
That's what they did.
They practiced on their faces and they
want to go look, let's not do that again.
All right, let's scratch that technique
of the list. Let's, let's try this.
That's a little bit better.
She only looks like half a lizard.
That's what you gotta do. Like I
said, it's like fucking hair plugs.
Hair plugs in the goddamn nineties looked
horrific. And now I've got to tell you,
these guys swimming around the pools,
you know,
aside from the psychotic look in
their eye, like, do I look okay?
Other than that they're their hairline.
I mean, I, I can't tell. All right.
Youtube videos for the week. I was
talking about those free videos, free,
uh, climbers or jumpers or whatever
the fuck it was. Free runners.
I wanted to see a chase
scene and somebody said, ah,
here's a video district be 13 chasing.
Um, I have, these are actually,
I have more, these are just
weird videos this week.
Okay, that's actually a cool
one. Here's a weird one,
a proper possum,
pedicure,
search that. Um, and then
this is one, I swear to God,
I didn't even think it was real,
but look up,
look up sweet home Alabama and
there's some lady singing it.
Just scroll down past all the Leonard
Skinner and just look for the fat woman
with one tooth.
And uh,
for some reason I don't think that she
realized that it got a million and a half
hits. Um, and here's another one.
Look up fake rapture prank.
This is all one word,
fake rapture, Ra, p. T. U.
R. E, prank, all one word.
It's basically,
do you guys know what the rapture is?
Oji Do you know what that is?
That's basically when Jesus, right
before Jesus comes back. Now,
correct me if I'm wrong.
People in Florida,
um,
I guess right before he comes back,
like people who are going
to come to go to heaven,
like they're going to be sitting
across from you, like fucking absent.
Mindedly like picking their nose,
thinking about,
you know what they're
going to do that evening,
and then all of a sudden they're
just not going to be there,
but their clothes will be there because
evidently you have to be naked to go to
heaven, right? So your clothes are
going to be there just left behind.
And then everybody who's not
going to have an gets left behind,
and then, uh, the whole
world turns into like the,
that island on survivor where I think
there's only one person's gonna win.
I don't know what you can
try to do to redeem yourself,
but basically Jesus is coming back and
this time he's not asking any questions.
There'll be no miracles,
no fucking seven o'clock show where he
does the fish trick with the basket.
No walking on water.
None that horse shit.
He's coming back like fucking Paul
Kurzy. Right? Is that the name?
Is that fuck Charles Bronson's
name and the death wish movies.
He's coming back to fucking kick the
shit out of all the centers make,
he's coming back to slap
me around a little bit and
then throw me into the fiery
pits of hell. So, uh,
they found this Jesus Freak girl and
these Jesus Freak people thought it would
be funny to fake the rapture and make
this fucking Jesus freak chick think that
she got left behind.
And uh,
the fact that this girl is an adult and
gets this freaked out is really the sad
state of,
uh,
of what organized religion does to
somebody that somebody this old could,
could get freaked out by something
like this is fucking beyond me. And um,
it's tragic. I would speak of that.
Somebody, I can't find where it was.
Somebody wanted me to ask me about
that story where those college kids,
uh,
these college kids taped this other kid
either having sex or fooling around this
other college kid and it turned
out he was with another dude.
So then the kid was so humiliated because
I guess he wasn't out that he went to
the George Washington bridge
and killed himself. And,
uh, I guess somebody wanted me to
comment on that. That's obviously a,
yeah, that's one of those
fucking things where it's like,
even though they're adults,
they're still kids. And, uh,
I don't think that they,
they don't think that people understand.
And even at that age,
I just don't think that a lot of people
understand the ramifications of what
they're doing sometimes.
Like how, first of all,
how fucked up it is to film somebody
the invasion of privacy that that is.
And then when you discover
this about this person,
just the level of humiliation that I
don't know why you would do that to
somebody. Uh, but
so for an unprecedented third time,
the fucking batteries die. I got,
I got a bootleg bag,
a fucking thing that Duracell's here.
So let me wrap it up here. Yeah.
Um, yeah, as a, as a
fucking free thinking adult,
I would never, I would never do something
like that to somebody but that age,
you know what? I had the courage to
be like, guys, this is fucking wrong.
Don't do that. Like I, I don't
think I would have to be on,
I hate to say that about myself,
but I wasn't a strong individual back
then as I think a lot of people aren't at
that age, which is tragically
how something like that unfolds.
But what's going to be fucked up is the
amount of people getting on their high
horse,
forgetting what you like at that age and
how so much of it is trying to keep the
uh,
humiliation off of you.
It's a lot of humiliation in
your teen years, actually.
Your childhood right up through those
years to you finally just accept who the
fuck you are, which is what that
kid never got a chance to do,
which is really sad thing and then freak
the fuck out and it made a really bad
decision. So, yeah, it's a
fucking tragic story obviously,
but, oh, I don't like how people,
once they are an adult and
they're comfortable in their
own fucking skin and who
they are,
we'll then turn around and they're going
to start yelling at these fucking kids
like, uh, like they, they
would have been, you know,
strong enough to go against
the, uh, the mob, you know,
it's fucked up. All right. You're dealing
with kids who are tactically adults,
but mentally they don't understand,
you know,
what are they thinking? Oh, this
is going to be funny, you know, uh,
then,
uh,
we'll have the most hits on our fucking
youtube page and then maybe everyone
will come to our house party and then
we'll get laid. Right? I mean, do they,
do you really think anywhere beyond
that? You don't really think that, okay,
this is a fucking huge secret.
We just unraveled on this kid.
His kid has family. This kid has
friends. This kid has a life.
You don't think that shit. You
just, I dunno. What's that residual?
A fucking playground shit.
So I don't know, man.
I know that's a fucking off.
What the fuck did I bring?
That story up in the end was already
a fucking brutal enough week.
Um, I don't know where the fuck did
I go that route. All right, let's,
let's fucking get off that subject. Um,
all right, that's the podcast this week.
My Yard DVD,
my DVD comes out,
um,
comes out tomorrow,
Tuesday the fifth in stores,
whatever stores still sell it. And a,
it makes a great stocking
stuffer as I said,
for someone that you have to buy a
gift for but don't particularly like,
or if somebody you do like,
and I gotta tell you this
is really totally different
than the special that you
saw on TV if you've already seen it.
They really took out two huge bits
and then I had other bits that uh,
we just have on there as extras and a,
I would really appreciate if you'd be,
if you check it out, if you buy it,
that would be a, that would be awesome.
And da and that's it. That's the
podcast for this week. Once again,
thanks to everybody who came out to see
me at the egg and Albany and everybody
who came out to see me out in
Buffalo. And uh, that is it.
Everybody have a good week at a,
yeah,
don't be fucking video tape and
people trying to humiliate a, alright.
And if you were the jealousy
where we got this weekend,
don't fucking wear the Jersey or the
hat of a team that kicks the shit out of
another team and going to their Goddamn
stadium and expect that you're going to
be treated even remotely
human. Okay. All right, ed.
Uh, and that's it. That's fucking it.
How you like dead fucking jets fans will
fucking patriots are slowly coming back
together. I still don't, I
don't still don't believe yet.
I still don't fucking believe you had
to still think that jets are going gonna
win the Goddamn Division as much as,
I hate to say it, but, uh, I still,
I think of Ben comes back there. My Hope,
because I think the culture reeling,
this is how much I fucking hate the jets.
I'm actually gonna root for the
fucking stealers. Those cons,
who always talk about bill Belichick
filming the other team and completely
ignore that the super Steelers of the
70s were fucking roided out of their
minds, out of their fucking
minds. You don't believe me?
Go ask Fran Tarkington.
All right.
That's it. Go fuck yourselves.
I'll talk to you next week.
[inaudible] [inaudible]
[inaudible].