B. Hey, what's going on?
What's going on to,
Oh
yeah,
it's Bill Burr. It's time for the
Monday morning podcast for Monday,
August 29th, 2080 oh, happy baseball
champion. Pappy baseball championship.
Why am I in such a good mood?
Why do I want to walk down the street
with a fucking bass drum kicking my
fucking feet up in the air?
Because your 2018 Boston Red Sox,
once again are world series champions.
Do you believe it?
Yeah.
I think I speak for all the New England.
When I say fucking okay.
Unbelievable.
I remember after 2003 thinking,
all I want to do is just see these
fucking assholes. Just one fucking time.
Have a clutch fucking
moment in your fucking life.
You Red Sox were in con
stats where I was at.
All right,
and the very next year they went in and
I was like, you know what? That's it. I,
you know,
I'm in such a good mood.
I don't give a fuck that my phone
is making noise in the background.
That's what's all,
what a great mood on mint.
All I wanted to see was
just some win at once.
Now only to get to see them when
it wants now, twice, three times,
four times the one buying the patriots.
So all you haters out there, just in
case you lost count in this century,
we won five super bowls for world series
titles and Nba Championship and his
Stanley Cup and one of those soccer
championships, mls, whatever, they,
but when did championships and stuff,
I don't even give a fuck about.
All right.
And for all you guys are doing,
does it get old after a while?
Don't you get tired of it?
No.
Fucking awesome.
It's fucking awesome.
You know?
And you know,
if it doesn't happen to us,
I hope it happens to you someday
unless you're in fucking New York or in
Montreal or a Laker Fan. Other than that,
I, I got no fucking problem with anybody.
Um, unbelievable. Uh,
I didn't know what to say.
You know, what's this? I know.
We don't know if Jackie
Bradley Jr or JD Martinez,
one of them said after game three that I
was at, can't believe I was at the game.
MMM.
He said,
I've never seen a take a team get,
just get punched in the face and then
just get up. Like nothing happened.
Like this team, something like
that. I know I'm butchering it,
but it was just perfect.
MMM.
They will just never out of it.
I have not seen a team score.
This many fucking runs with two outs be
down this much since the 1998 New York
Yankees, which is probably
the best team I've ever seen.
MMM.
The only other team in my lifetime,
and I vaguely remember them,
was maybe the big red machine.
Um, I mean, that team,
that team was fucking incredible. That
was just another team that was just like,
they would just stack. All right.
You know what I'm going to, I'm not,
I'm lying a little bit that,
that phone thing is gonna bug me here
if this continues to
happen here. All right. Uh,
oh fuck.
Am I supposed to talk about that shit too?
Um, anyways, um, congratulations
to the Dodgers, man. Jesus Christ.
See another great season.
You just came up short.
All I can tell you
having been through that.
MMM,
yeah. No, it just makes it all the more
sweeter when you finally went it. But uh,
you know, so we went to game three.
What a fucking great stadium by the way.
And not only is a great stating that
the Dodgers have like the stadium just
considering when it was built and
there was so many of those soldiers,
cookie cutter,
um,
baseball stadiums that they made.
They were multipurpose.
Basically all of them were asked to
design so he could play football and
baseball back there.
A very like forward thinking,
money saving environmentally
friendly thing that we did.
And then we all decided like, you know
what? Fuck these stadiums. They're old.
Why fix them up? I don't understand
why you just can't fix him up.
They're made out of metal and concrete.
They're not going anywhere.
That's like any,
any fucking car you have.
The fucking engine block is made out of
steel. As long as you take care of it.
It's gonna. It's gonna run forever.
Everybody just throws shit out.
So they knocked down all of these fucking
stadiums and then rebuild. Not One,
but two more stadiums.
We will,
I want my own stadium.
Yeah.
I don't want to share
it. Although, you know,
I did boomer Esiason show
boomer in and was it Gino?
And uh,
he was talking about what
it was like to play for
the Cincinnati Cincinnati Bengals
in the same in riverfront stadium.
He said down these to cover a home
plate with a piece of wood and then just
through astro turf on top of it.
So if you get tackled on it,
basically it's like you
laid it on somebody's tree
fort. So I guess, you know,
maybe that's a reason,
but I was what I thought they could've
come up with some sort of technology
where they didn't have to fuck it.
That was just basically cause it
was astro turf. Right. I don't know.
I don't pretend to understand,
but um, me and my buddies,
we went to game three and,
uh, I didn't wear any red sox.
Shit's still almost got into
a fight fucking west coast.
Stele almost got into a fight.
Unfucking believable. You know,
there was like what killed me was we
went to the game and there was so many
empty seats because stub hub just
gouged the shit out of every,
they were charging like 700 bucks.
I was at the top of the stadium.
Those tickets were over $700.
And you know,
I guess stubhub was can to
be like, well, you know,
we'll make it four times the fucking
face value of the ticket. What, what,
what do we give a shit if every,
you know,
three out of every four seats is empty
almost, you know, it wasn't that bad,
but they were big giant swaths of
fucking rows that were, were just,
nobody was there, um, from the
bottom all the way up to the top.
And you know, people got flat screen
TVs, they don't need that shit.
They would come home,
they'll see the fucking replay,
they'll know the pitch count, they'll,
you know, all that shit rather than,
than being like me trying to figure out
the scoreboard with my fucked up eyes at
this point. Um, so anyways, my buddy,
you know, he was having a few
beers and when he was finishing,
we just setting them up in the row behind.
He said it was like basically empty.
So there was a guy behind there and you
know, all you had to say was, hey guys,
do you mind just keeping your empties
on your, in your row? Just cause uh,
you know, me and the kid, my wife and
the kid won't try to get by here and wow,
sorry, I do it. No problem. That's how
would have gone down. But instead is,
he's a west coast guy, you know, they're
still fucking laid back out here.
He immediately just says to my buddy,
this is how we entered the conversation.
He goes, he's like, hey buddy,
is there something wrong with the
underneath your chair? I went,
Fred turns around, looks at him immediate
with that look on his face. Like, wow,
I'm about ready to get into a
fight. And he's like, what? He goes,
there's something wrong
with the underneath party
of chair. And he's like, no.
He goes, why don't you put, she
empties there? And he goes, oh,
there was nobody sit there.
And then it fucking in like literally
like fucking flash paper escalates to this
level. So I'm sitting there, so I just go,
you know, I've been out here long enough.
I'm a veteran.
Like I know this is going to happen.
Like you could literally go to the game
fucking eh dressed like Jesus or Santa
Claus, whatever the fuck you're into.
And still somebody is going to be like,
you know, a fuck it, Eh, a Whitey.
You think you cannot have your fucking
beard blowing over your shoulder block
and half the fucking feel like
something's going to happen.
A Santa why she sued red? What are
you a fucking cardinals fan? You know,
and all of a sudden you're into it.
So I just turned around and looked at
both of them. I just go, ladies, ladies,
ladies. Which usually diffuses it.
Somebody saying, ladies, all right,
then you realize I go, alright, I'm acting
like I got a fucking Tampon on, right?
I go, we're at the world series game for
how? Come on, let's have a good time,
right? So I got to shake the guy's hand
behind me and he leaves me hanging.
So now I'm fucking mad. I
don't say anything to the
guy. And then I just, he goes,
get just fucking sit us.
We sit down and then I fought for fucking
hitting and loudly talking about what
the level of fucking asshole fans,
fucking asshole fans that are out
here on the fucking west coast.
It's just like they go to the game
to get into a fight. It's just like,
so after eating half of
that, I'm like, dude,
do you really want to keep doing this?
And it's like, no, I don't. So I get up,
I go down and get a beer and I'm coming
back and I'm on some walking up the
aisle. This fucking guy is sitting
mean mugging me. Now this guy,
he's gotta be like fucking 50 pounds
over fucking weight. This four of us,
there's one of him not granted,
he's in the row behind us.
I guess maybe he could fall on
us and do some fucking damage,
but if we wanted to, we all probably could
have picked him up and thrown him up.
We were the second to last row,
literally just thrown him off the back
of the fucking stadium. All right.
And when you're dealing with people
from Boston, that is, uh, that is, uh,
there's a chance that there's that
level of fucking anger involved.
It wasn't us, but I'm just saying,
and this guy could give a fuck.
So he's fucking
Deron at me.
As I'm walking up,
he's with his wife and kid and
he's fucking staring at us like,
like fucking William Wallace staring
at me, I should say is I'm coming up,
so I'm lily, my eyes are fucking
bad at this point. So I'm like,
is this guy staring at me?
So when you're fucking old,
you got to eat this squint or you kind
of look away and then look at bet,
look back at something. So I had to
look away to focus on something else.
And then I looked back at him. I'm
like, yeah, he is staring at me.
And I just looked away. So he probably
thought that was a moment of weakness.
So now he's probably air. It is. He's
going extra hard with his face now
when it got, so it just got up there
and I don't know what happened.
All of the anger, all this shit, it
just went away. I was just like, buddy,
we really gonna do this man. Come on.
I respect the Dodgers ever respect you.
We were trying to, I apologize for
that stuff. So I've got a facility,
I see his face finally relaxed. I go to
fist bump. The Guy, he's so fucking macho,
he can't even like stick his
hand and he makes the fist,
but he has his hands still near his body.
It's like my daughter when I went to my
first bike was like teaching her how to
wave and she wouldn't like
lift her hand or her arm up.
She just like open and close her
hand while it just rested on a leg.
It was like adorable. But with this guy
it was just so, I don't know what it was.
It was just like, wow, this
guy has got a lot of pain.
I don't know what the fuck happened
to say. Fist bump. Long story short,
by the end of the game,
even though his Dodgers are losing,
we're like friends or friendly anyways,
diffused the whole fucking thing.
Am I anchor my angry fucking uh,
Italian Boston guy and what? He's like,
dude, how the fuck did you do that?
How to find, I just said to him,
I was just like, dude, I go,
I'm fucking done with it.
Um, I'm, I'm not, I'm not
fucking doing this anymore.
I'm not going to fucking go
to a fucking baseball game.
And then almost getting as a
50 year old bald fucking dude
almost get into a fight
over an empty fucking bud lite beer
can and where it was placed within this
concrete structure. I'm Jen, I'm just not,
I'm not fucking doing it anymore. Right.
I had already almost gotten into a fight
with my wife and I diffuse that because
we had pregame at my house and evidently
my wife didn't feel like she was
invited. I don't know why we were in
the house. She's always been invited.
But what Ha,
you know what happened?
I came off the road and I was under the
gun where I didn't have a lot of time
between getting back to the house,
given her a hug and a kiss,
checking in with my kid and then making
sure I had beer for people coming over
to go to the game because the game
starts at five and I didn't get back from
Phoenix until, uh, you know,
one o'clock didn't get home til
like two. Right. So, you know,
they're coming home, they're coming
back. I'm sorry. I got home at like one,
one o'clock and my friends
are coming over too. So I,
I barely hugged and kissed my wife
and then asked her to go out and uh,
and get some beer for the guys, you
know, which is something I never do.
I usually handle everything. You know,
she's always got the honey do list for me,
but I never have anything for her, so I
can get, can you walk and get some beers?
And she's looking at me like,
I just asked her if she could
fucking walk on water or something.
So a half hour goes by
and I'm looking at like,
are you going to go out and get the
beer? And she goes, are you serious?
I didn't know you were being serious.
And I was like, yeah, I'm being serious.
Like why, why would I say that is a
joke? And she goes, well cause you know,
I'm just sort of sitting here, you
know, hanging out and fuck it. You know,
it's one, it's one of those, you know,
it's just one of those things in our
relationship where it like one person is
going to ask somebody else to do something
that they never do themselves or, or,
or,
or vice versa or something like that.
So I don't know if she could
get her fucking head around it.
So then she goes and she gets the beer,
you know,
she pulls up and of course
when she pulls up she's like,
can you come out here and help me bring
the beer in? Cause that's what the fuck.
They can never just fucking do something
for, they still get a draggy in. Right.
And I missed that text and my friends
went out and helped her out and then she
was fucking pissed at me,
a whatever.
So we're driving to the game and she's
like texting me about what a jerk I am.
So I fucking diffuse that.
I go to the fucking game,
I diffuse the fat fuck behind us.
That's all I did the whole fucking day.
Diffuse and shit. As I watched the red sox
then go down, you know, four to nothing.
And after that crazy
fucking game and game three
where we used our starting,
you know, game for pitcher.
I mean what I mean, how great a game did
a, what's his face? Uh, Bueller pitch.
I feel like people forgot
about that with the Dodgers.
Winning was all about that guy
hitting the home run. And I apologize,
I got a kid now. I don't know
anybody's fucking names anymore.
I watch the games while I fucking switch
back and forth between the game in
puppy dog pals. Every time I switched
from puppy dog pals back to the game.
My daughter just points at
the TV goes, oh, oh dog, dog,
dog.
And I got
my just a second Mimi Mau,
Mimi Mau. So I was like,
she's speaking like Chinese or something.
She's saying Minnie Mouse, Mimi Mau,
maybe Mao, Mimi Mo. Um, anyways,
so I don't even know who
hit the fucking home run.
The whole thing was such a blur.
I've been so goddamn busy.
Somebody hit a fucking home run for the
red sox to make it treated. Nothing.
I mean four to three, then
we scored another run, then
we fucking loaded them up.
And then that whole analytics shit that
taking guys out that are doing a good
job of, Gee, I don't fucking understand.
I mean analytics when in those situations
sometimes I swear to God it's like,
it's like baseball's version of the
fucking prevent defense where like,
I am sure on paper this
fucking makes sense,
but why? You know, stop
watching the fucking pitch
count. What is this guy doing
to the opposite team right now? Oh, he's
key sees. She's fucking killing them.
Buddies.
Up to 27 pitches and,
and the juxtaposition for tis ball and
socket joint out fucking shoulder to his,
his,
his juggler.
We need to take them out during the 28th
and a half fucking pitch right there
doing that shit. So anyways,
we ended up coming back.
I think we won that.
We were winning the game like nine to
four and then Kimberly comes in, you know,
you know how he closes it gave me, lets
up a comb, run in a fucking double,
you know, I know he's coming off
injury. God bless the guy. Whatever.
We scared the fucking shit out of me.
And uh,
we won the game and then it was great.
I got to walk onto the stage.
I didn't have any problem. I shook
the guy's hand behind me and you know,
I know I saw a bunch of people
wearing red sox shit there. Um,
I guess what I'm saying,
I'm just too old to do it.
And my favorite fucking part about going
to an opposing team stadium rooting for
the other team is when I'm not wearing
my own gear and I go into the bathroom
and I don't have to worry that five guys
are going to push me in the back when I
go to take a fucking piss.
You know what I mean?
Cause their teams lose it and the the,
the,
the fucking bathroom with
all of that porcelain,
all of that tile and none of that,
none of the fucking security
in his urine on the floor.
It's just the fucking worst and that's,
that's where it goes down and to just be
able to walk in there and just not have
a fucking problem. I wasn't being a
dick when the red sox were scoring runs.
I was definitely cheering,
but I did it in a respectful way.
I didn't do that shit. I always see
that when I'm watching games, you know,
any game, any game I watch and
I'll see the opposing team's score.
When they cut to the crowd,
you'll always see one douchebag,
not only standing up wearing
fucking everything he could
possibly be wearing for
the other team.
He's turning around facing the crowd,
you know, like he's fucking, you know,
Steven Seagal and marked for death and
he's going to beat up a whole fucking
section though, is some fucking
fat, bloated drunk jackass.
And every time I see it,
I always just think like somebody
should beat the fuck out of that guy.
Somebody shouldn't.
But you know,
you never watch the discovery channel. You
don't know how nature works. Like what?
Yeah, just no fucking, I
don't know what, no. Uh,
no respect for like your own wellbeing.
Like the fuck,
why the fuck would you do that? So
anyways, that's just not how I did it.
So then I got home and it was late at
night and we would just sit in there like,
can you fucking believe this shit?
It was like we were down four to nothing.
I wasn't even nervous cause I was thinking
even if the Dodgers tied this series
up, we're still going to win it. Like
that's how much does the psychology,
and I'm talking about the
fucking Boston red sox.
I never thought I would
have this feeling about him.
I just knew these guys
were going to come back.
I didn't think it was going
to happen in that game.
And we won that game and I just
couldn't fucking believe it.
And I didn't talk one ounce
of fucking shit. None of
that stuff. I just, you know,
I wanted my team to win. They
won. That was good enough for me.
I don't need to fucking start walking
around being a cunt about it, but like,
that's really, um, it just really is
just sort of spot part of the, uh,
sports culture.
And what's funny is,
is how people don't see that their
own fans of their team do it too.
Like I know when the red
sox were playing New York,
New York for whatever stupid fucking
reason in the locker room after we won it,
it was all these Yankee fans.
No real clear to you. I could tell
you this with the Yankees win.
Last thing we'll be doing is thinking
about the red sox. It's like, yeah,
you will be.
Yes she will be because you took the time
to go on Twitter to fucking comment on
that.
You took the time to find out about it.
You obviously on the in in
the red sox threads to see it,
you know, and then they all real
classy Boston like and just like, hey,
you're really forgetting that your fan
base through a bear in the face of our
reliever is he came out of the bullpen.
You're going to forget you chanted 19,
18 at fucking old ladies.
If they had a red sox hat on for the
better part of a fucking century, man,
come on, grow the fuck up. It's
not something that I would do.
I think it's dumb to do that
cause it just, uh, you know,
gives the other team more
incentive or whatever. But, uh,
personally speaking,
um,
all I give a shit about is my
team. And like, now I'm out of,
the big thing is I'd love to
see the red sox winning again.
So then we would be in double digits in
Champions Championships in two different
professional sports,
basketball and um,
and a and baseball. And I think we would
be the first city that ever did that.
Um, not to mention, here's another
stat if you into fucking stats.
I also believe that the red sox,
other first professional sports franchise
to win a championship this same year
in two different centuries. Huh? Am I
going fucking Billy Ball on you here?
A little nerd enough
for you. Um, and lastly,
but not leastly I can't remember cause
I had to start this podcast again cause
my record recorded was filled up.
If I didn't, I don't give a shit.
I'll apologize to again,
my apologies to David Price.
Jesus Christ
not have been more wrong and there's
going to be a bunch of people out there
being like, dude, I fucking set in.
I know what never doubted that
guy about they are full of shit.
You're full. I'm, maybe
you're not. But I did.
I 100% thought I actually thought
we weren't going to win it in.
The problem was going to be
that David Price was a headcase,
couldn't beat the Yankees,
couldn't win the big game,
couldn't win fucking October. I 100%
thought that. Um, and I was like,
you know, you need the one
two punch. She need, you know,
you need to monster shut it down.
Pictures to win a seven game series.
Now that's how it is with all the free
agents seemingly piling on six different
teams. And I was 100%
wrong. I actually thought,
you know,
price should have been the MVP considering
all of that fucking chatter that was
in his ear and considering, you
know, he won both his starts,
he came in during the pitch relief
and eat up some meetings and he just,
he just crushed it and uh,
couldn't be more happy for that guy and
couldn't be more happy that I was 100%
wrong, 100% wrong. And I loved his,
when his press conference afterwards,
when he was going, you know,
you guys had that card on me and
you played it, you played it well,
but you don't have it anymore. He goes,
I have the Trump card and it feels great.
And I just pushed one of those
sports writers in there, you know,
they never fucking own up when they're
fucking wrong, you know, aren't released.
Not Enough. They should,
one of them should have been
like, Hey David, how feel,
how good does it feel to stare at all
of us who fucking doubted you and wrote
all that bad shit about you,
myself included. You know,
why don't they ever say that?
You know? So anyways, um,
I dunno, but getting back to that
stuff, I would not have played New York,
New York. I would not like,
why would you do that? You,
you fucking kicked the Yankees ass,
you know, you gotta be above that Shit.
But I guess there's always that stuff.
You go to a rangers game and the
range is still chant. Pod Van Sucks.
I go to an avalanche game, but
at, at, at, at that red wig suck,
you just have your fucking rival.
Um,
and I guess I understand it because
Yankee fans were such conc for so goddamn
long. Um, I guess I understand,
but, uh, I'm always,
I'm always,
I always think it's way better to score
the touchdown and just hand the ball to
the ref.
You do some stupid dance.
All it does is fucking make
the guy covering you. I Dunno.
Just want to fucking play that much
harder if you just do it like it wasn't
shit. I just feel like it's
just way more defeating.
But what do I know?
You know,
when was the last time bill you
played a game and fucking gym class?
I'm trying to think. The last
time I played, other than hockey,
I played hockey in three years, so I
hurt my back and then I had a kid, so I,
my hockey stuff has been sitting there
every time I walked by. I was like,
I have not. I remember September of 2015
I haven't skated in three fucking years.
Pathetic. Um, but anyways, uh, so
congratulations to the red sox.
Congratulations to the Dodgers, man.
I know with fucking brutal, but, uh,
it will be all the more sweeter when
you finally a pushed through and, um,
you know,
getting past all this fan shit like I
really do like all of those organizations
that we played, including
the fucking Yankees. I mean,
you can't get mad the most successful,
you know,
you can't be a fan of sports in that
respect. What the fuck they'd done a,
I know that. That's it. I'm done talking
about the Patriots. Got The bills tonight.
Hey, did Lewis Hamilton wrap it up
yesterday? Did He, I imagine he fucking,
he's always on the podium.
I think all he needed to do was just get
into like fourth and fifth place and he
would've had it wrapped up.
Let's see. Louis Hamilton. Oh,
by the way, thank you to
everybody that came out to, um,
why does it always go to f?
How come it always goes to Wikipedia?
Is that because I always go to Wikipedia?
What did I already be up there?
Wins 70 ones, Burns it, Duh, Duh,
Duh. Where's championships? Yep.
You just want it 2018 he wanted again.
Congratulations.
Congratulations. Um, so Lewis Hamilton,
when's the f one championship and
mock mock Perez one the moto GP race.
And I want to thank everybody that is
helped me along as I've gotten into both
of those sports and I'm absolutely
obsessed with them. Although I, you know,
like I said with the Kiddo,
I don't have as much time
mmm.
To watch them the way I want
to, but they are on my DVR. Um,
what was it was in Brazil.
I was Mexico.
That's one of my favorite races where
they drive to the old baseball stadium.
MMM.
I might go to that one next
year. Who knows? Who knows?
All I know is it's Halloween this weekend
I'm in town and I were having this
little kid Halloween party,
you know,
you know nightclubs that like, you know,
21 and older. I think this is like,
it's like 18 months and under.
So it was going to be a bunch
of little kids running around.
It's going to be hilarious.
My wife is like totally decked out the
house and everything. Oh, by the way,
when I came home after the game,
she was still upset with me and I
didn't know that she was still up.
So we were outside smoking cigars and
Shit, and she texts me. She's like,
where are you? I'm like, up
downstairs, the back porch.
And she got all fucking mad at me.
Like she wasn't invited.
So I went upstairs and I got tight.
She was so trying to have a fight with
me and I just wouldn't have a fight.
It was like, listen, I don't
want to fight with you.
Just tell me what the problem is. I
love you. You're awesome. I love you.
You love me. We're not going anywhere.
I want to go to bed angry at you.
What did I do that upset you? And like,
how can we, how can we work this out?
And just, you know, stop yelling at
each other. I don't want to yell at you.
She says, uh, okay. Uh, she had to
go through that, you know, for one,
she was being the baby,
you know,
so that's my new thing. I'm just, I,
I don't know what happened
somewhere in that dodger game.
I want to thank that guy who was
standing by me. The absurdity of it,
it just finally hit me. It's just
like, I'm not fucking doing it.
I'm just not doing this anymore.
Jesus Christ.
I just saw a fucking letter for this week.
I'm copying and pasting it right now.
It just said girlfriend
wants to bang my brother.
Now that that's just, I refuse to believe
that that's a true thing. Whatever.
I'll read that in a minute here.
I got to do the advertising was probably
not a good thing to tease right before
I'm going to read advertising.
Um, advertisements. Um,
all right, where the hell
is it? Oh, Indo Chino. Uh,
talk about stressful.
Talk about,
she'd say how stressful it is knowing
you have to go to an event in his suit
that doesn't fit. Oh yeah, that's
the worst I had to go to. Why?
The reason why I didn't see any,
a game clinching red sox game yet.
Cause I had to go to a wedding and we
had the after the after party for season
three of 'em efforts for family.
We had a great time.
We actually went bowling and a,
so I kind of do like
double duty last night.
So I was watching that whole thing
on my phone. Um, but anyways,
I love going to weddings now.
Now that I'm married and I have a kid,
it's like all the pressures over I did it.
Okay.
I committed to somebody I
procreated, you know, fuck off.
I imagine it's the same feeling
David Price has right now. Okay.
I did it. I got a ring. Go Fuck Yourself.
I am the David Price of wedding
wedding guests right now. Um,
anyways, what it was Indochino
right Indochino here's how it works.
Visitors,
stylists@ourshowroomandhavethemtakeyourmeasurementspersonallyormeasureathomeyourselfandshoponlineitindochino.com
choose your fabric inside and out.
Choose your design customization.
Submit your measurements
with your choices,
relaxed while your suit
gets professionally tailored
and mailed to you in a
couple of weeks. Call to action.
This is mandatory. All right.
This week my listeners can get any
premium Indochino suit for just 359
dollars@indochino.com when
entering burr at checkout,
that's 50% off the regular price for
a made to measure premium suit plus
shipping is free.
That's indochino.com Promo code borough
for any premium suit for just $359 and
free shipping. Incredible deal for
a premium made to measure suit.
Indochino are also expanding into
casual clothing you're made to measure.
Chinos will quickly become your goto pant
pairing as easily with suit jackets as
they do with the sweater and
there'll be good, oh my God,
they go with a fucking
suit jacket and a sweater.
That's totally my wheel house right
now. That's the age group. Ahmet
start wearing sport coats on
fucking a stage of at that age,
you know,
cover up my fucking the mistakes.
I've made it the fucking kitchen
counter. All right. Zip Recruiter.
That's actually not true. I'm actually
in good shape right now, but you know,
it's always good to have a big sport
coat hanging around for when you're,
you're going through your fat months, you
know, the holidays. Anyway, Ziprecruiter,
you know what's not smart job sites that
overwhelm you with tons of the wrong
resumes,
but you know what is smart zip
recruiter.com/burr. Unlike
other jobs sites, uh,
zip recruiter doesn't wait for
candidates to find you. All Zip
recruiter finds them for you.
It's powerful.
Matching technology scans
thousands of resumes,
identifies people with the right skills,
education and experience for your
job and activity actively. Sorry,
invites them to apply so you
get qualified candidates fast.
No more sorting through the wrong resumes.
No more waiting for the
right candidates to apply.
It's no wonder that Ziprecruiter isn't
is rated number one by employers in the
US.
Um,
this rating comes from hiring sites
on trust pilot with over 1000 reviews.
Okay, look at them. They're backing
it up. A little footnotes there.
Right now my listeners can try zip
for free at the exclusive web address.
ziprecruiter.com/bird that's
ziprecruiter.com/bar hey,
zip.com/burns the Ip,
r e c r u, I, t or.com.
The smartest way to hire. Oh, look
who's here. What are you got three more?
Let's break this up.
Let's read some fucking,
let's read some fucking questions here.
Let's read some questions here.
Then when I get off this thing,
I got to go do that. The honey, the
honey do list, right? And you know what?
I'm gonna do it with everybody.
I'm going to do it with the fucking
smile on my face and I'm not,
I'm not going to, uh, yeah, I'm
done dude. I am. I'm done fighting.
I've had, I'm just gonna keep saying it
out loud. So I make it a real thing. I'm,
I'm done with it. What is the fucking
problem? What I really need to say?
I'm sorry. What is the problem? But I, I,
the only place I've graduated to right
now is what is the fucking problem?
All right?
If I can take the fuck out of there,
get some of the angry tone out of my
voice, I think I'll be doing even better.
All right. Granted, I'll probably run
out of material that's beside the point.
Speaking of material, big guys here to
Patriot Patriot on announcement here.
Why? Uh, by popular demand,
people have been asking for more con
content where they can donate, et cetera.
Um, all right. The what, why, what, and
all of this shit. All right. I have a new,
I'm going to have a,
I'm launching a Patrion page.
It's going to go live on November 5th.
All right?
Um, and this is what you're going to
get all this extra content. All right.
Patrion spelled p. A. T. R. E. O. N.
You're going to get two episodes of the
uninformed podcast with me and old Joey
roses. I'm bringing it back.
You get extra video contents.
Citio Tor city tours, backstage
footage, helicopter rides,
whatever the fuck I'm doing. How
much is it? It's five bucks a month.
Jesus Christ. Lay off on a couple
of fucking cartons of eggs and you,
and you got yourself all this other
content. All right, November is content.
We'll go live November 5th. Uh,
I have, uh, I videoed a podcast,
it's a live podcast from Phoenix that
was a good podcast to full video of the
show as well as downloads to MP3,
two episodes of uninformed and um,
I'm going to be doing a bunch
of other fucking, you know,
bizarre behind the scenes shit at my
shows and all that type of stuff. Um,
you know,
it's funny they say that and you have a
patrion page and they don't even tell me.
I guess you go to Patrion and you
just try to look up my name, whatever.
I'll keep promoting, I'll promote
it. And again, speaking of which, uh,
please watch on a, what is
it this week, November 3rd,
Paul Versey standup special,
uh,
on comedy central is coming
out and it was done by my,
uh, my company that I started with
Al Madrigal, all things comedy.
This is our first special that is coming
out. We're very excited. And it would,
bu it would be huge this Thursday
night if you guys could, uh,
is that what it is? No, no, no,
no. It's not Thursday night.
Looking at the wrong thing.
Sunday night, Sunday, Sunday.
Wah Wah Wah Wah Wah Wah. No,
that's the wrong one too.
Why is it in, may I swear to God,
don't let, don't even listen to me.
Here we go. I'm sorry. This
Saturday night, November 3rd,
Paul [inaudible] standup
special on comedy central.
I think it comes on at midnight.
Um,
yeah,
I'm just really proud of them.
This is just one of these guys who should
have got a special a long time ago and
did not. And with the company that I
started with, Al Madrigal add matter,
Myalgia go being the
driving force behind it,
we're able to get ourselves in position.
We actually made a deal with comedy
central and we're producing, um,
for one hour specials for them for
the next year. This is the first one.
And we're gonna be picking
all these comics that we
love and I'm so please check
that out if you can. All
right, let's, let's read.
Let's read a little less
questionnaire. Corvette. Hey,
Billy Bean ball bag.
Uh,
needed advice on a car I would
love to purchase next year.
I'm looking to try at trying
to get a c seven corvette,
the latest model
Corvettes. A C seven. Okay.
Or is that the BOT? Is that the body type?
Oh, what did we do now? Look at that.
I can't fucking hear myself.
What just happened?
Gravity happened. I got to sit
there and literally hold this thing.
I literally have my thumb
down on the connection here.
Like one of those bad action movies
where the guy comes walking and going.
If I take my thumb off his pit,
we all go up.
I got to do that for the rest
of the podcast. Evidently. Um,
so anyways,
so I imagine that's fucking cut.
Jesus fucking Christ.
They'll go to a radio shack and just by
what the fucking IED set at dealing with
this every week. Fucking
moron. Hey, you know what?
I'm also done getting mad
inanimate objects. Jody, Rosetta,
great bit about that. And I remember
listening to it going, you know what?
I really should learn how to do that
and I haven't. And as far as I can tell,
he hasn't learned how to not do it either.
Anyways,
it's the latest model of Corvettes.
I'm currently 23 years old,
married to an absolute fucking gym,
have a house with her and pay for
everything we want. Slash half. Dude,
you're fucking killing it. Uh, not
trying to pat myself on the back,
but I'm happy with where
I am in life anyways.
Do you think it would be good or dumb
idea to get a corvette next year and I'm
going to be a little bitch
and get an automatic.
I want to be able to have my mom
drive it since that's her dream car.
Otherwise I would just
get a manual anyways.
Don't go fuck yourself and
keep on keeping on. Um, dude,
if you know you're married to a gem
and you're living within your means,
if you can afford to get a corvette, get
a corvette, you know, here's the deal.
I don't know if they
make it in a stick still.
It seems like everything is
just the paddle shifting. Um,
if you still can get it in a stick and
we'd be a great way to teach your mom how
to drive a stick. She grinds the
gears on your brand new corvette.
Probably a dumb idea. Sounded good in
my head until I fucking said that. Um,
although I tell you one of the big things
then in the future that I want to do
with my daughters,
I want to teach her how to drive my truck,
which is three on the column.
And um, I think that, yeah,
how bad ass will that be?
That she,
you know that someone born in 2017,
we'll know how to drive a 1968
Ford f 100 and she's a lady.
Yeah, my kid's going to be a bad ass.
She's going to know how to do shit.
She's not gonna be when these fucking
pretty girl sitting at the bar link.
I'm just going to pretend
I don't know things. Um,
anyways. Yeah, I think that's a great
idea. If you want to get it, you know,
if you know, she, she seems like he
kind of also doing it for your mom,
which is a great thing. Um, and cars,
you know, I don't know when
people are like car people,
it really means a lot when they, they get
the one that they've always wanted. Um,
you know, I dunno, I bought,
I bought a car, you know,
I bought the car and my wife wanted
and I saw the look on her face so I can
imagine, you know, and that's
the woman that I married,
so I know what that feeling's life.
I can't imagine if you
get it for your mom in,
you're able to pay her back like that.
Yeah, absolutely. I would fucking do that.
Um,
why don't you go buy a
shitbox in the meantime,
that's a stick and go teach
your mom how to drive, drive,
drive a standard transmission,
be great together time.
You'll laugh your asses off and uh,
you know,
and that's great for, you know, somebody
who's older to learn something new.
It's a lot of options here,
man. They're all good.
Glad you're life is in that place that
that email actually made made me happy.
Believe it or not, somebody killing it
like that. See that? I got it. Good.
All right, girlfriend wants
to bang my brother. Ah, we,
I tease this earlier in the podcast.
Girlfriend wants to Bang
my brother,
Jesus Christ.
I would love to hear Joel
Olsteen read this fucking thing.
I mean cheese wants your girlfriend
and bang your brother. Hey Bill,
I'm sure this happens.
This has happened to you before.
I said a long over a roundabout way of
saying that I'm not a good looking guy.
Uh,
but how should I handle my girlfriend
wanting to bang my brother more than me?
Thoughts?
She said it three times in one night.
What?
Why you still in this relationship?
Would you still be in the relationship
if you said that about our sin?
A listened Sweden. Not to say you
don't have a nice rack, but like,
I mean you, you got to
agree with me. I mean your,
your sister's tits are ridiculous.
D now bad.
I want to stick my dick between
the two of them. You know what,
what you told me?
Um, um, anyways,
she said it in one night,
three times in one night and that
he is better looking at Cetera.
So she's either going to fuck him or
she's just trying to get under my skin.
I told her after the third time to go
fuck him then and she tried to act like I
was an asshole. Yes, of
course. Of course she did.
I feel like this cross the line
and it's all I can think about.
Oh two I got to taste center right now.
Not only do you say
that you fucking dumper
too for her to fucking say
that to you is so out of line.
And that is just the tip of the
fucking iceberg of the mind.
Games of fucking asshole. Like this is
going to play with somebody. All right,
dump this person and this is the thing
she's gonna have actually fucking respect
you because she obviously doesn't respect
you enough that she's saying that shit
to you.
So if you fucking dumper,
you know what's going to actually
make her want to do is fuck you more.
And this is what you do. This is
the jet I level. You know what?
When she wants to fuck
you more after that,
you know what you do yet dumb fucker done.
Yeah. Done. It's over.
That's one of those things like,
I don't know what kind of a fucking
jerk off you think I am like that.
That's basically what she's saying to
you that she thinks you're a fucking jerk
off and you have to show
her that you're not.
I would dumper and then that is
fucking it. That is fucking it.
And when she fucking,
um,
does all of those women manipulating
things and fucking turns on the sex vibe
and all that dude, you fucking,
you like go you nothing.
You give her nothing.
That's it.
I don't need to read the rest
of this. I will though. Um,
if it was a friend of mine, she thought
was more attractive, I wouldn't care.
You should care. She shouldn't
be saying that, dude. This is,
this is why you don't fucking say that.
Let me ask you this.
Could you do any of this to her?
Could you say that one of her
girlfriends is more attractive than her?
Three times in one
night. Anyways, he said,
but I hate the fact it's my baldheaded
fuck of a brother. What should I do?
Anything I think about,
I get more angry. Uh,
thanks and wear a hat next.
I like how you're taking your
anger out on me. Um, yeah, dude.
You're dating somebody that has crossed
the line that you're not going to be
able to get past. Okay. Pass. Sorry.
I really going to save my voice, dude.
I've been screaming and yelling every
weekend doing my act and been watching the
red sox through the playoffs.
So I apologize for my son.
I'm going through puberty here. Um,
yeah, do that as a no fucking brainer,
you know, uh, just dump
her. And it's another thing.
Don't tell your older brother or younger
brother, whoever your brother is, don't,
don't tell your brother why you dumped it,
because one day he's going to get drunk
and he's going to bring it up and then,
you know, like an asshole and then you
guys are gonna get into a fight. Okay.
And it's all because of this.
This client who is trying is driving
a wedge into your family. This is,
this is the kind of person you're going
to bring this person in your family tree.
Huh? You're going to dump your fucking
seat into that. I don't think you are.
Walk away. Walk away.
And you know what, dude?
You got off fucking easy. If you
dumped this woman right now, you,
you got off fucking easy.
Jesus Christ.
God bless the poor fucking bastard
that she's going to fucking marry right
there. Um, anyways, uh,
deer hill, Billy Buck tooth.
Uh, I'm in a bit of a pickle.
I'm 23 lines, a lot of,
lot of emails from 23 year olds this week.
Evidently a 23 year olds.
I have have a, a little
difficult fuck dammit. Um,
deer hill, Billy Buck tooth. Uh, I'm
a bit of a m and a bit of a pickle.
I'm 23 and want to break up
with my girlfriend of two years.
We're long distance. I'm
a kiwi. She's a Yank.
Ah, what's a Kiwi again? Is that
fucking New Zealand? I can't even,
I can't even keep up. Um, anyways.
Uh, now I gotta look it up.
I don't want you guys to sound
ignorant like me. Here we go.
Key.
We pee.
So
Wikipedia,
once again,
Kiwis nickname used for international
internationally for people from New
Zealand as well as being
relatively common self reference.
Unlike many demograph Leyva, it's usually
is not considered offensive, rather,
it's generally viewed as a symbol
of pride and an endearment from,
for the people of New Zealand.
The name derives from the Kiwi,
a native flightless bird,
which is a national symbol of New Zealand.
It's a flightless bird.
Many you guys aren't leaving the island.
Is that what it is?
Until the first world war,
the Kiwi represented the country and
not the people. However, by 1917,
New Zealanders were being called
Kiwis supplanting other nicknames.
So that's cool. That's great. That
eventually it didn't become offensive.
Usually after a while it does.
Are you saying that my dreams
will never take flight?
Oh yeah.
Um, anyways, uh, I'm a
kiwi each. She's a Yank.
Uh,
sure. Blocker on Facebook. Okay.
I'm 23 and want to break up with
my girlfriend and two years. Okay,
well you just sit down. He just say,
listen, we have to talk. All right,
this is something I wish somebody
just told me. This is what you say.
You just sit down and say, honey,
listen, we have to talk something wrong.
And then you just say yes,
I'm just, I'm not happy.
Okay. I don't think you're a bad
person or anything, but I'm just,
this just doesn't feel right.
You know?
It feels right in that I like you,
but it doesn't feel like I like you to
the point that I'm going to marry you.
And then they just stopped talking and
then she'll start fucking crying and blah
, blah, blah, blah.
And she's crying because she's sad and
that is a normal emotion and you have to
be comfortable with that. And
just you, you just said it.
No, I did you say yeah, no.
And, and I, I, I think we need to, uh,
end this relationship now, I think,
and we need to end this relationship.
That's it. You said it, I'm not happy.
I'm not feeling like you're
the person I'm gonna marry.
We need to end this relationship,
bom, boom, boom. We need
to talk. I'm not happy.
Yeah, you just fucking, that's it.
And you just get it all out and it's
going to be another two fucking hours,
but you don't waver. You don't go
back and then, then you're out.
That's it.
And then you don't go back anyways.
He says,
sure. Blocker on blocker, on
Facebook and other social medias.
We used to correspond. The problem is
she has a lot of filthy nudes of mine.
I've sent her the past few years.
Needless to say,
I have my fair share of hers. All
right, well that's a stalemate then.
I'm worried she'll distribute them
maliciously in revenge for breaking it off
with her. She's that kind
of spiteful. Trust me.
Any advice other than hindsight,
thanks. And Go fuck yourself.
You're just going to have to man
up and do it, dude. You know?
And if the world's going to see a dick
for a couple of days, then so be it.
That's it.
All right. And, um,
I'm actually happy for you
because who wants to be,
who would want to marry a spiteful person
because she,
she would've done that to you if you
stayed with their in other areas.
You're not happy.
Get the fuck out of it.
And then your hindsight stopped
sending Dick pics to people,
you know,
I dunno.
That's, that's how I lead that way.
What do you fucking lay in there?
Like Burt Reynolds in playgirl because
if you weren't covering your junk,
I don't understand. Like I
understand women cause the beautiful,
I just don't understand. I don't, it's
under scan on a stand guys doing that. Uh,
you like these dick and
balls hanging off here.
Um,
a naked guy.
It's like literally it looks
like it's like a design flaw.
You know, women are all curvy. It's
smooth and aerodynamic, you know,
other went to the point, other women can
look at other naked women and be like,
oh my God, she's beautiful.
You know what I mean?
And they naked guy is Craig,
you're fucking this shit
hanging off. Cover it up.
Um, the lemme, uh, hey bill,
I'm writing in as another female
listener going on six years now.
Love your work and I'm hoping you can
help me decide something. All right.
I love when the ladies right in a
May 18 just turned 18. All right.
She's legal.
Uh,
and I've been working at an estate
firm for three years. Look at you.
Good for you. I don't know what that is,
but that sounds impressive to me. Um,
I'm a sophomore in college. How will you
only 18 years old doing all this stuff?
You're like advanced classes.
Most people who could play the cello
when you were three. Uh, I'm on a soft,
I'm a sophomore in college pursuing a
criminal degree then going on to law
school. I've always wanted to be
a criminal defense attorney. Well,
let's say you're gonna make that happen
by the time you're like 21. Anyways.
However,
the lady I work for who runs the estate
from once to pass the firm to me,
but I never intended to pursue a career
in a state law by dilemmas seems to be,
I can't decide whether I should accept
this overwhelmingly kind offer of the
estate from ready for me when I graduate
law school or start from scratch at the
bottom and criminal law.
The state firm would need some work.
But all in all is a successful business.
From listening to your story
of how you are a self made man,
I would assume you would say pick criminal
if that's what you've always wanted.
But who in their right mind turns down
a firm that's wrapped and ready with
their name on it? Looking
forward to your insight. Uh,
you make rush hour drives bearable.
Thanks and kindly go fuck
yourself from another broad.
All right. Jesus Christ. Is this like
the coolest person ever? She's 18.
She's crushing it. Um, listen,
you're an amazingly successful
person for 18 years of age.
And I would look at it like this,
the state firm, it's just, you know,
it's like when Columbus was sailing
across the ocean, before he saw land,
it was a couple of tree branches.
So that's what's coming here.
You seeing that your,
your big things come and you definitely
got do what the fuck you want to do.
Um,
I think you'll regret way more,
not trying to be in the part of law that
you wanted to be and then walking away
from some money because, uh, you know,
you know, the money, the
money makes money, makes you
like relaxed as far as like,
he can pay your bills and shit like that,
but it doesn't do anything for,
for like your soul or your heart,
you know what I mean? Your passions,
it just doesn't, unless your passion
is, you love fucking money, um,
you know, whenever the
fuck that is. Uh, so yeah,
I would definitely just stay
on the track that you're on
and you know, just tell the person,
I'm obviously ridiculously flattered,
but you know,
my dream since I've been little has
been to a criminal defense attorney.
That's the direction that's the
part of law I want to be in.
And I just know that I would have this
regret while I ran your state from and
your state from deserve somebody that
has the same level of passion for a state
law is I do for criminal law.
And there you set it and the
person's going to sit down.
They're going to start
crying. I'm kidding. You know,
it's like really like they should be a
course on how to break up with somebody
and then also how to have confrontations
like this anywhere from the fat guy at
yet you're behind you at a baseball game
to somebody offering you something that
nobody would say no to, but your, your
heart is saying, I can't do this. Um,
and that's it.
And the thing about it is,
is what you have to learn as
a young person is you have
to learn that the, this,
this is one of the biggest, biggest
skills in life is learning how to have,
um, productive confrontation. Alright.
Where you express what you
want and you get what you want.
Or at the very least you
stayed what you want.
If you're not getting what you
want, you walk, but you don't do it.
There's no name calling.
There's no raising of voices.
And even if the other person goes there,
you don't match their energy.
You just let them yell and stuff
like that and you just stay comp.
Um, they, they, they should, I don't know.
I'm sure somebody is doing that out there,
but they just don't do it enough.
And um,
you know, I turned the corner the other
night with my wife where, you know,
I didn't go to where energy was.
I understood why she was upset with
me and I told her she was right.
You are right. I didn't come home and
ask you how you were doing. You're right.
I apologize for that. I'll work on that.
But like, I don't want to yell at you.
I love you. That's it. I mean, what the
fuck is somebody gonna deal with that?
Okay. When she had to yell love me,
then they just, you just sound stupid.
And women fortunately enough or rational
enough that you can kind of talk them
down. You know, guys,
you know, were like, oh,
I don't want to deal with my emotions.
You don't,
you just go for a fucking by my new thing.
Then I go, I go for a walk. You know, I,
I go, go for a walk. I go out
to my garage, I played drums,
couple of pen terrorists songs,
and I've just lost myself in that.
And then I come back and I can just sit,
you know,
it's a little weird that someone in the
middle of a fucking discussion has to go
out and go play to some van Halen and
then come back before they can be. But,
you know, I, you know, I have some growing
up to do, but whatever. Um, so that, yeah,
that's what I would do. And you know, I
eat, if you're doing all of this already,
like this is not going to
be the last opportunity.
How much better would it be if
you built your own firm? You know,
I think that'd be pretty bad ass. All
right. But do whatever you want to do.
But that, that's my, that's
my feeling. Sorry withdrawals.
I've been listening to the
podcast since the first episode.
This is my third day off of opiates.
Congratulations. Congratulations.
Uh,
I've been on pain,
managed a pain management scheduled for
the last five years due to arthritis in
my spine.
Um,
eating painkiller after painkiller
for the last five years.
Eventually I got to the point where I was
starting to question if I was addicted
or not.
Every time took a painkiller.
You kind of skipped a few words there,
but you go through withdrawals.
The fact that be able to sit down and
fucking write an email is a victory in
itself. Asking myself if I
still have it under control.
I'm a single dad with the career.
I work long hours at night and I'm lucky
enough to still be there to get my son
from school every day. Uh, I've never
missed one of his games are racist,
but at the same time,
um,
I've been taking these
painkillers every day.
It felt like carrying a demon on my back.
I'm only three days into being cleaned,
still withdrawing,
still can't sleep.
Skin is crawling all
of the normal symptoms.
That hasn't stopped me from my
daily responsibilities out. Dude,
you're a fucking Troper. Nobody really
knows that I'm growing through this.
I don't open up about
things like this to people.
Well that's what you need
to do immediately. He said,
which is why I'm writing you.
I don't want anything in return.
Just wanted to vent to this,
to someone.
I've been relistening to the podcast to
pass the time until these withdraws are
over, there's absolutely no chance
that I'll ever go back to painkillers.
I feel miserable right now.
But it's the best feeling I've had
felt in a long time. Good for you.
No more demon on my back.
Well that's great. Well,
you need to reach out to people cause
it's okay to, uh, say that you need help.
And, um, you know, from
what I've heard, you know,
getting off opiates is, is, is, is
difficult, is trying to kick heroin,
which is also an opiate. Right. I'm glad,
I don't know a lot about drugs like that,
so, um, you know, I just, yeah,
definitely let people know what
you're going through. Uh, yeah,
I'll leave it at that. That's,
that's a heavy fucking subject.
So it's a tough fucking guy,
man.
Jesus skin crawl and he's still doing
everything you need to do for his family.
And he's, um, I'm not going back.
That's an old school fucking guy,
John Wayne Shit right there. Um,
anyways. Oh, it's the holiday season.
Doobie Doobie. Do. Um,
I'm going to be on Jimmy Kimmel tonight
promoting the front runner movie
starring Hugh Jackman. It's
the, uh, the Gary had story, uh,
directed by Jason Reitman. I'm so
psyched to be in this movie. A truly is,
you know,
one of the great things I've been able
to be a part of as far as being in an
ensemble. Ah. Um, so
check that out tonight.
And uh, other than that, I got to go buy
a shirt to wear on Kimmel cause you know,
God knows you can't wear the
same shirt on TV more than once.
Can't do that. You know, oh you fucking
assholes and make fun of me who have,
you know, 10 shirts that are in there,
you know, that ship your pitching staff,
that's you rotation 10 fucking shirts yet,
show Biz.
You not allowed to do that.
You got to wear it once.
So what you do is I always try
to pick something that, you know,
it doesn't really stand out,
just sort of a bland fucking color.
You're getting any sort of designs on it.
The people that God sets the shirt
you wore and fucking camel. Yeah,
it is now wearing it again once I spoke
to throw it out, you waste four count.
Um, anyway, so I have to do that and
I'm also going to be, uh, you know,
I always make pumpkin bread
during, uh, between um,
what is it, Halloween and
thanksgiving. Thanksgiving,
I start busting out the pies.
I make my fucking stuffing.
I'm throwing down this year cause
I'm gonna be in town. I can't wait.
I'm very excited and,
uh,
I think my daughter is still one year
away from maybe going trick or treating.
I don't know. I'll ask the AF. I'll have
to ask my wife about that. But that's it.
Go Patriots.
Congratulations to Lewis Hamilton.
Mock mock has the Boston red sox and um,
yeah, that's it. What a great fucking
week for me is a sports fan. All right.
And I'm not rubbing it in either.
All right.
I hope the Dodgers win it again
next year. If we don't, how's that?
That's the nicest thing I
could say. All right. Okay.
That's it. Go fuck yourselves.
Enjoy the next couple of days.
Please watch Paul Versey special,
uh, November 3rd on comedy central.
One of my best friends in the world and
I'm so proud of him. He's got a great,
great, great special that he did with
the all things comedy network. Uh,
I'll check in on you on Thursday.