Yeah.
Hey, what's going on? It's bill burn.
It's time for the Thursday afternoon.
Just before Friday.
Monday morning podcast in.
Ah Huh.
Just checking in on you.
I'm just checking out how the holiday
season is fucking go and for you.
Did you get some toys for
fucking girls and boys?
That sounded really creepy.
Um, hey, what's going on?
I uh, been running around all
day. Podcast is a little bit late.
I was actually doing Joe Rogan's
monster podcasts. Um, and uh,
we had a great time.
Talked a little bit about flying in the
helicopter earlier this week and uh,
and that he got me all sold on
buying a fucking sauna. Yeah. Joe,
Joe, Joe. Fuck. It tells you something.
Be like, all right, this guy, you know,
he's probably read up on
it, whatever. He was like,
people who do this four times
a fucking week, you know,
live a long time or some shit.
And I'm just thinking like,
well, I'm an old dad. Oh,
guys should get off. I
don't care. I'm an old dad.
Joe,
make me Camaya too far away.
Just give me me in five
years. Oh yeah, you can you,
oh.
[inaudible].
Um,
so I have to make sure I
take care of myself. So, uh,
Bill, he's got some growing
up to do. All right.
Abuse and alcohol for a while
now I take the bottle out,
I slept it around and let
them know who's boss. Um,
and I got to fucking grow up.
You need,
you need to take a little
Paris back to Philly.
Hey, fuck it. Say that all the
time. You know what you need.
You need a little bit of responsibility.
Uh,
I've never in my life
understood that expression.
You need a little bit of responsibility.
They'll pick like the most immature
fucking person ever and tell them you need
some responsibility and you're
like this fucking guy. No,
this guy does not need to be in charge
of anything. He's a fucking moron.
Because they have that
whole idea of, oh, well,
once you have a kid and then you have,
you know, you're, you're gonna have to,
you know, change your ways. Yeah.
Unless you're a fucking idiot.
And everything this person is doing is
demonstrating that there a fucking moron
and you're telling them to go out there,
procreate with somebody.
You know what you need
is no responsibility.
You need a fucking playpen
is what you need there.
Bucko my new year's resolution
is I'm going to, um,
I'm going to fix, I'm going to fix
this little phone, a headphone Jack.
I literally sit here with my thumb
on the button like a terrorist.
You know what I mean? Like I lift
it off. It's, you know, my mom,
my weight up fucking Evan
70 broads in my life.
I know it's a hacky joke, but the more
you're married, you're just like, oh God.
Um,
anyways,
um, all Bebo Oh, bill Burroughs
is fucking slowing down, man.
In a good way. You know, I'm off
the sauce. Who knows for how long,
but I'm off the fucking sauce
and I'm actually reading a book.
Swear to God. I mean, granted,
it's a sportsbook. Does
that even count? It's about,
uh, Bob Cousy and Bill Russell's
relationship. When I did the herb,
somebody over there gave it to me. I
believe that's where I got it. And um,
you know, one of the things that
always bothered me, you know,
something I always got meant to get
around to was to know all the Celtics
retired numbers. And now that
I've read the book, I finally,
I think I have them down. I swear to God
I'm not looking at anything. All right.
Number one is Walter Brown.
He was the original owner of the Celtics.
Number two is red are back. The great
coach, they consider a number two,
he got number two because he's the second
most important person in the Celtics
history I guess. Cause number one is the
original owner. Then it's Dennis Johnson.
Number three, Bill Russell, number six.
Why do I, why do I need to know this?
Jo Jo white on the great basketball names
number 10 and then it's Bob Cousy at
14.
Tommy Heinsohn is 15 some guys.
Tom Sanders is 60
70.
Yeah.
Eighteens Dave Cowens 19
is fucking Don Nelson.
21 is Bill Sharman.
22 is
Ed Mccauley 20 Three's Frank Ramsey,
24 Sam Jones,
25 Casey Jones.
All right now let's not eat now it's easy.
31 Cedric go and Brad
Maxwell, 30 twos. Mikael,
33 is bird 35. Reggie Lewis, double
zero is fucking Robert Parish.
Then there's another guy just as his name,
cause he also wore the number at
18 and didn't want to retire it.
And then Dave Collins got it. So I don't
know his fucking name. So that's not bad.
That's not bad. Um, so now I know
that. And what does that get me?
Next time I get into an argument with
my wife now, but watch Walter Brown now,
but two's red are back.
Can you do this?
No Dad,
I'm an old dad. I said, get off
of that now I need a nap. Um,
anyways, so after I did
Joe's podcast, he's like,
he's got like did that flotation salt
tank thing in there. And I'm like,
dude, I don't, I don't know.
Like if I went in that fucking
thing for like an hour,
like
I always wondered what those things were.
Like those isolation tanks.
I mean that looks fucking wild.
They just close that door and you're in
there floating in pitch black like you
floating through space like
Sandra Bullock in that movie,
right where the other guy was never going
to get married and then he did George
Clooney.
Right.
May just sort of floated off into space
that I could never get my shit together.
You go back to the bucket spacecraft,
I'm just going to float away that movie.
I feel like you'd feel like that,
you know,
if I ever get a role where I get
to play in astronauts, that that's,
that's going to be how I'm
going to prepare for the role.
But what did you do to prepare for
a role to play an astronaut? Well,
I kept my Boston accent and I just went
to an isolation tank and just laid there
in a bathing suit.
Do you think it helped you now?
But it gave me something to say
in this interview. Um, anyway,
so he had a sauna there, which I'm
totally sold on now. We went there,
we tried to be in there for like a fucking
half hour. He could do it. I couldn't,
I, I made like there was eight
minutes left, 10 minutes left.
I made 20 minutes and I was like
200 fucking degrees in there.
That's what he was saying. Like, how
the fuck is it? 200 degrees in here?
It doesn't water boil that
like 212 degrees or some shit,
hundred degrees Celsius.
Um,
I guess those Saunas can get harder
cause it's not like it because it's a dry
heat. I have no idea on all. I know. I
was just like, all right, 10 minutes left.
He goes, come on, tough it
out. I'm like, all right.
And then 10 minutes later I'm like,
how much time's left? And he's like,
eight minutes. I'm like, fuck.
And it at like five minutes I laid down
and he's like,
all right dude.
He knew I was too stubborn so he fucking
opened the door and then I was fine.
He goes, you almost made it. It's
like, I think I did all right.
I don't think I need to go any further
than that, but uh, I felt fucking great.
I felt peaceful.
I felt calm.
I didn't feel like yelling at anybody
or walking around being a fucking
emotional lunatic that's
just wears people out. Um,
so whatever. I'll see. They makes
little two person once I want,
if I get fitted my fucking
little ass garage, you know,
that would be great.
You know,
anytime you have a disagreement
with your spouse, right?
You just go into the sauna.
The rule is you go in there for half
hour and then when you come up then you
talk about it.
Hey Man,
like you left your shoes in the
hall, man. Oh, I'm sorry man.
It's okay. It's not, it doesn't really,
but I didn't know why it bothered me
31 minutes ago, but it did. But that's,
you know what, you can put your shoes
wherever you want. Ah, thank you.
I appreciate that.
I don't know what the fuck I'm
talking about. So anyways, um,
I get not only do I have all my
Christmas shopping done, I got them,
I got it all wrapped except for when I
bought my, my daughter, this book, uh,
the, how the Grinch stole Christmas,
I bought that on the road. And I just,
I forgot I had it,
I tucked it away in drawer because I know
if she saw it she'd be like, book, book,
read, read. Um, so I'm going to,
I just have to wrap that and then I
think I'm done. I'm think I'm done.
And I think for once my super smart wife
hasn't figured out what anything that
I'm going to get her,
you know,
I was really covert about this
shit's not going around. I just,
I brought everything into the
garage this year. Right. Sorry.
What the fuck was that?
You know that shit when you open your
mouth and you just make a fucking noise.
Did you just hear that? Sounded like
there was a ferret that was like some,
something in the back of my
throat while I continued to talk.
Sound like a little cat.
Did you hear that? You know,
do you realize like back if I did that
back in like the fucking 1700 state,
they'd be like drowning
me thinking I was a witch.
I was like possessed or I had a
fucking tape worm or something.
Jesus Christ.
Some of these fucking brides on,
on social media thinking they're not
being heard. How do you think it, the,
the fucking people felt back then?
Yeah.
Well, if you have to compare
ourselves to the Salem witch trial,
aren't you really proving our point?
[inaudible]
that was the hedge clippers
trim in the bush there. Um,
they broke.
Anyways,
I'm plowing ahead here. Uh,
by the way, I've keep, um,
promoted this on, on Joe Rogan to I
the Patrice O'Neal comedy benefit.
Still promoting that is February,
Tuesday,
February 19th, 2019 get your ass to the
fucking city. Alright, come on. Damn.
Great benefit. Big J. Oh, Chris.
Michelle Wealth Rich Vos.
Fucking SciFest sounds myself as going,
it's going to be a cavalcade,
a comedy for the best data of
comedian I ever saw in my life.
All proceeds go to benefit all the people
he was taking care of his family and
all that.
And it's been a very successful thing.
We keep his name alive and what not.
Um,
all right with that,
you know what?
I actually got to watch a Bruins game
the other night, uh, by getting watch.
Most of it. I watch most of it. And then,
uh, being a dad comes in, you know, I saw,
uh,
the first two periods of the Bruins,
Ford and nothing win over the Canadians.
You know,
we were up two to nothing and I missed
the fourth period. Third period. Sorry.
And uh,
you know,
one of my friends from Montreal
Comedy Festival texting me,
cause you watching this game, and I knew
it was the third period and I was like,
well, I go, I'm assuming you guys
tied it up if you fucking called me.
And to his credit, he didn't, he texted
me, he, to his credit, he didn't.
The man did not. He was letting me
know that we played fucking great.
And then I saw the highlights at last.
Fuck it,
Marshawn golden number for
that Little Bing Bang, boom.
All around the Oh and everybody,
it,
all those little Fred cheese with
the fucking crying into their little
handkerchiefs with this
silly socks. Oh, I love it.
Going into their building.
Okay.
Four to nothing. So they're probably
playing tonight. I have no idea.
But I gotta go, I gotta go on site for
fucking supper. I still call it supper.
Back in the day. That's what
we call sit down for September.
Your mother would bring the fucking dinner
bell and everybody would come running
in like cattle. Right? I'll fucking
filthy for being outside there.
It was chipped beef on
toast. Uh, chicken Alex King.
Yeah.
You know, I don't think a king
eats like this. Um, anyways,
let's plow ahead here.
Uh, Liverpool, my fucking,
my fucking adopted Goddamn team.
I almost fucking miss this game.
They're playing all my God. They're
playing the wolves. Jesus fucking Christ,
not the wolves. How the fuck is
that a professional franchise?
You've got some stupid Jersey with
like a w on it. We get it. You know,
you couldn't write the whole thing.
They can afford to have the
o l v e s on there, right?
Is that he spell wolfs
was it w o l f s wolf?
I don't know. They'd say
everything different over
there. Reagan, L or a gang? No.
You know, what else do
they say? Tomato or a Gyno?
Uh, all the spices they say
differently. What's mother Rose Marie?
No, that's not the one with the
flex time. They see the same way.
There's another one,
there's another one that is just the
ones Basel or Rogano Basel tomatoes.
And you just want to be like,
stop doing that.
Yeah,
you want to say that they're wrong. But
they did it first. So they were right.
Why the fuck did we switch?
We switched all the accents on everything
and I believe that was a fuck you
right to England after we kicked their
fucking red coated asses all the way back
to their island,
all the way back.
Right.
And I just think that our little rebellion
was not only are we kicking you out
in the country that you first
fucking occupied and took over.
Not only will we continue the
genocide that you started, right.
We're gonna, we're gonna change
the accent on the English language.
Right.
Do you say a automobile?
We're going to say automobile.
I don't know if we do that.
I have no idea. Um, anyways,
uh, the fuck was that. I am. Oh,
goddamn. Noise is now. I don't
know if I'm going crazy or what.
I will tell you what's driving me
fucking crazy is this year I, you know,
I thought it was being a smart guy.
Oh, who's this too was a tough guy.
He was a smart guy, right? I went
out and I bought a Christmas tree,
like when it was still November,
you know,
so now I'm water in this thing and I
got a missed it every goddamn morning to
make sure it's not all brown and dead.
By the time fucking Christmas comes along,
our wreath is on the, on the front
door is already dying, you know?
And my wife went all out. You know
what I mean? Like great mothers do.
She went all out, but I got more goddamn
shit. I'm running around, you know,
I'm the water boy. I got a water rate.
I missed it. I'm talking to it. No,
you look good. You look good. No,
you're going to be one of the
trees that lives after Christmas.
You don't just lie into them
like a fucking dirt bag. Right.
So I didn't have a lot of time the other
day and I'm running around the fucking
kitchen table and we got the stupid
fucking potted plant that literally has a
concrete plant plant or whatever the
fucking house that the roots are in,
whatever you call it.
Right.
And that was on the floor because of
the Christmas decorations on the table.
And I ran around the table
and just punted that thing,
concrete fucking block with my,
my pinky toe on my left foot
and Jesus fucking Christ.
It was like Barney the dinosaur
purple within two hours.
And it was like half of my foot by foot
looked like I got run over by a car.
Now, you know, obviously
I did some damage,
but most of it has to be my,
most of it is my complexion,
you know, being uh, a a fucking, you know,
redhead,
I'm borderline like transparent.
Like I'm always getting marks on
my body and like late at night,
like I go to bed and my wife be like, what
is that? What does that entail? What is,
you know,
fucking kilohm mark at my side.
Did you get to a fight with an
alley cat? Yeah, no, I took, I, uh,
think I leaned up against
the refrigerator. I don't
know what the fuck happened.
And then when,
you know what's weird is if you hurt
yourself and you don't remember what
happened, you press down on
it and then you're like, oh,
and he takes you right back
to that moment. Oh, that's
right. That's fucking right.
Yeah, it was, I was at the
fucking poster. Oh, by the way,
Jesus Christ,
I went to the post office.
I was trying to get all my
fucking gifts out and uh,
you can not fucking go there.
The only way you can fucking go
there is if you have everything done.
I went there,
I needed a box and I needed to,
and then I need the fucking, the
peanuts or whatever to put it in there.
So what I was,
whatever I was going to put in there was
going to slide around and break and I
need to tape the, close the box.
It should just like, it's just,
it's that last chopper out of Vietnam I
n and I was happy that I went down there.
I found somebody to help me
out. You know, I got the box,
I got the tape and then they said they
had nothing to put in there to make sure
my gifts to my nephews and nieces
wouldn't fucking slide around. And I,
I just, I just, I said, fuck it.
I said, all right, thank you.
I sent the tape down and put
the box where it belonged.
I walked out like a
gentlemen while I fucking,
I went a little Tourette's underneath.
Goddamn fucking, well fucking fuck.
Do you have fucking boxes and tape, but
you don't have the, the last ingredient,
most important ingredient
for the last piece of the puzzle,
I should say.
The box is probably the most important
ingredient. Well then you have to tape.
I mean, they work together like a
great comedy team, dare I say, right?
Like Bob hope and bing Crosby through the
guys who evidently created the fucking
the buddy movie,
you know,
which has now been hijacked by all these
females in all these movies acting like
they're breaking ground. It's like you're
just doing this shit. We already did.
There's nothing new here ladies.
You know,
why don't you reinvent the buddy fucking
movie before I get to listen to your
call on each other. A bunch of fucking
heroes. What do you think about that? Hey,
uh,
this is the thing that fascinated me
because I was reading the Celtics Book and
some of the fucking teams that
they were playing, like, you know,
playing Syracuse and Rochester
stuff I had heard about before.
But um, when they were
talking, what the fuck is this?
They were talking about playing like the,
uh,
what are now the Atlanta Hawks and I
knew that they were in Saint Louis,
but I didn't realize that they
were in Milwaukee before that.
All right, let's see here. Atlanta hawks,
yet they were at this, this is their,
their history.
They were the buffalo bisons then for
one season and then they moved or maybe a
half a season.
Then they moved to the tri cities in Iowa,
which are now the quad cities,
I believe.
And they became the tri city Blackhawks.
Then they may move to Milwaukee in
1951 and became the Milwaukee Hawks.
Then in 1955 they moved to St Louis
and became the Saint Louis Hawks.
And then in 1968 they moved to uh,
Atlanta and became the Atlanta Hawks.
And they'd been there for 50 years,
but they've moved five times.
And I always thought the Sacramento Kings,
which I can't remember if they were the
Cincinnati royals and then the Kansas
City kings and then the Sacramento Kings,
I couldn't remember. Hang on a second.
Let me get to this,
cause I got,
I got this fucking website here that
has all the franchises that moved.
If I can get it to work
here, please, please.
As people listening national hockey
league, what the fuck is the NBA?
Ah, Jesus Christ, come
on National Basketball
Association, the Tri City Hawks,
Blackhawks play their
home games in Moline.
And Rock Island, Illinois and
Davenport, Iowa moved to Milwaukee,
became the hawks. Then in 55
they moved to St Louis. Okay.
And then the Detroit Pistons where
Fort Wayne Pistons until 1957 Rochester
royals moved to Cincinnati. And then
where the fuck did they go from there?
Yeah,
cause this goes year by year, so I'll,
they became the Sacramento Kings. Yeah,
they were the rot Rochester's
Seagram's. What the fuck is that?
Yeah.
Anyways, Rob Chester pros and they
became the Rochester's royals.
Then they moved to Cincinnati royals,
Kansas City slash all Mohawk kings,
Kansas City Kings,
Sacramento Kings.
And then I think the Syracuse team moved
to San Diego and became the San Diego
Clippers.
Where the fuck is it?
The Syracuse nationals moved to
Philadelphia and became the 76 is, okay,
so who became the La Clippers?
The San Diego Clippers?
Yeah.
Oh, the buffalo Braves moved to
San Diego and became the clippers.
That's what it is. Oh No, it's
the Rochester was, I don't
know. I'm a fucking nerd.
I love that shit.
Then I go online and see if I can find
a tri cities black hawks tee shirt.
Like they ever fucking sold one of those.
I bet it's a minor league hockey team now.
Tri City.
Come on, come on bill. You can write it.
Black Hawks
tee shirt. Here we go. Somebody
makes it, you know somebody makes it.
Mitchell and ness. Chicago
Blackhawks, Tri city,
black hawks.
There it is.
Everyone would like myself would think,
oh,
is that where the Chicago Blackhawks first
played? And they'd be like, oh no, no,
no. That's not, that's
not the case. All dead.
Leave me alone.
MMM. Yeah. They've got
the, they've got the dude.
He's just see them all the fucking kid.
If they got it wearing,
it was like 21 fucking years old.
Similar designs. Look at this. They
got all the old ones here anyways.
Trust the process. Yeah. Boy,
I didn't want to know who the fuck said
that. Um Oh, there's a cool Lebron one.
Will they make his beard
like the State of California?
Do you realize if the Lakers don't win it
this year, this'll be the first decade.
They haven't won a fucking
championships since the fucking 1960s
seventies eighties nineties two
thousands they went for decades in a row.
Celtics won 50 60 seventies eighties no,
it went for decades, right? It
was seventies eighties nineties
2004 Oh yeah. No one's ever done five.
No one's ever done five. Can you see,
can you tell him? I'll fucking
talked out from Rogan's podcast.
We did like fucking two and a half hours.
I'm sitting here wondering
what the hell to talk about it.
Cause I can read some advertising. I
could read some advertising. By the way,
I'm not farting continually.
I'm just sitting in a leather
chair. I just realized
that. Yeah, that leather chair,
plush leather chair. One Chair, one chair,
my little fucking podcast area here
finally, cause now we have the kid.
I can't do it the way I used to
in the fucking bedroom and shit.
Screaming and yell and we can't
have that bill. We keep pill.
We can't have you be who you
are in your own home anymore.
Butcher box.
Everybody butcher box delivers.
That's a great name for like a
fucking female wrestler. Butcher box,
you know,
or finishing moves.
He jumps up in the air and fucking
puts her claim in your face.
Butcher box delivers healthy 100% grass
fed and grass finished beef free range,
organic chicken and the fucking mother
of them all the holy grail for all you
carnivores out their
heritage. Bread, pork,
the incredible, oh my
God, do I love that stuff?
The incredible quality of butcher
box means start with the co,
the commitment starting,
sorry.
With the commitment to raising animals
humanely and free of antibiotics and
hormones telling maybe look
beautiful before they murdered,
cooked with piece of mind knowing you're
eating healthy, high quality meat.
Each box comes with at least
eight to 11 pounds of meat,
which is enough for 24
individual sized meals.
Even for you size queens out there, you
can choose from five different box types.
All beef, beef and chicken,
beef and pork mixed. Yeah,
box,
custom box.
I feel like the mixed box is
to progressive liberal box.
We're custom box is more like, you
know, hardcore, right? You know,
I only want beef,
uh, in my neighborhood. Let's you,
let's you choose your own goddamn cuts.
It's delicious for $20 off your first
box and a package of free bacon in every
box for the life of your subscription.
Meaning whenever you order some food,
you're getting some free bacon. Never
pay for Bacon again. Go to butcher
box.com/burn enter borough checkout.
That's $20 off your first
box and a package of free
bacon in every box for life,
for the life of your subscription,
by going to butcher box.com/burr
and entering burr at checkout.
Um, I got a hats off to my wife. We had
some, uh, we had like this really mature,
like get together of like, you know,
four or five different couples.
And they came over and my
wife just did it up, you know,
hired these people to cater it. They
made all this great food, you know,
the booze was flowing, everyone was
having a good time. And I sat there,
she's like, come on man, it's a holiday
party. I have to have one drink,
have one day. I said I will, I will
start with the Ginger Ale. Right.
And I just kept putting it off and
putting it off and putting it off. Right.
And then all of a sudden it
was the end of the night,
we'd all sit in there smoking cigars
and a then all of a sudden the night was
over and I didn't drink.
Everybody had a time.
And I've almost done it.
I only have a,
yeah,
I got a couple more holiday
parties. Oh, I got a tough one.
I've got a tough one coming up with
a good friend of mine, comedian.
I'm not going to say who the fuck it is,
but he has a party coming up.
Oh this is going to be tough and no,
it's not that gutter dweller Joe to Rosa.
Oh Joe de Rosa loves it.
Gutter loves it.
Gutter.
I know he sees a Kirby
just east nuzzles up to it.
Like he's laying with his own
mother, his own mother. Um,
but anyways, I always get a little bit
sad this time of the holidays, you know,
cause I know that it's almost over.
I like this time of year, you know,
everybody just kind of sits
back cause like, you know what,
I fucking love you man. Fucking
PCH been in my life, man. You know,
you know they got the fucking lights.
It's just,
he just look around like why can't
it be like this all the time?
Why can't work be like,
all right, relax. You know?
And everybody just chills out and just
says how much they like each other.
Why can't we do,
you'd get bored of it,
I guess after a while they
can't have like, you know,
yeah.
It's sort of a summer, Christmas time
holiday, Hanukkah, Kwanza fucking thing.
Yeah.
You got to wait once a once a fucking
year that it starts all over again.
January 2nd or January 3rd or
this has got to be this company.
Yeah.
This quarter ever.
Where did you all a buckle down and
not go? You will not see your children
when you leave for work. Y'All
be sleeping. When you come home,
there will be a slave.
You'll be a stranger.
So this year we could sell the most where?
Jets we've ever Solera.
I'll tell you right now, if you've
got a problem, there's door.
The Internet has made this industry
more competitive than it's ever been.
Okay?
I did counter.
That's rob.
You're going to cry Maggie,
Huh?
Yeah.
Who else? What about you? Greg
hurt. You're all fucking sensitive.
Okay.
Did you fucking box of tampons
for the first fucking court?
What did you do less last quarter?
You didn't check.
You know,
can imagine if you had that fucking life,
just imagine that fucking life.
Get yelled at.
You know you liked that famous
scene in Glengarry Glen Ross.
Alec Baldwin comes in and starts yelling
at people. I can't fucking hear myself.
God Damn it. I've got
to get this fixed. Um,
this will be such a great stocking
stuffer. What did I tell fucking Santa?
I wanted this. Oh, here comes Santa Claus.
Here comes Santa Claus.
He's back from radio shack.
He got you the fucking
headphone Jack that you needed.
What does this even called? I'm gonna
you don't want me to do people in,
in fucking honor of the new year.
I mean, what I plan on doing,
which you wouldn't know from that last
little comedy skit that I did there.
And by the way, that was all written
out. I memorized all those lines. Um,
uh, you know, I'm going to try to fucking
chill out in the next fucking year,
you know what I mean? So anyways, in
honor of that and solving problems,
rather than complaining about them,
I'm a,
I'm going to let you
guys listen to me order.
This is the highlight of
your fucking week. I know it
is this self self involved.
I am.
You're gonna listen to me.
Order this fucking cock sucking
God damn thing that I need here.
What would you call this thing?
Uh, the rotisserie. Yeah.
This is basically like the
chick and you know, a porno.
She's getting bang from
behind it. A, you know,
she's put forward in the old fucking
a and how you been up front. Right?
And you know someone's going
to have a bigger Dick, right?
So one of them is bigger. The other one's
smaller. What do you call this thing?
The rotisserie.
A core Jack.
I don't fucking know a head phone.
I'm going to go with a head phone
adapter.
It's gonna take me to fucking Wikipedia.
Why the fuck would it do that?
It's in my default settings.
I get to figure out how to fucking do
headphone adapter. Oh No. Oh No, no, no,
no, no, no. That's not the
one I need. Let's see. Images.
Come on. You fucking bastard.
Uh, the do I need, it's not dual.
Oh my God.
There it is.
And it's at radio shack.
Yeah.
Three and a half millimeter.
Male to female. What do you
call this fucking thing?
Oh my God. I know the name.
Just like a cold case file.
3.5 millimeter male to female
headphone adapter. All right,
let me go,
let me go to fucking Amazon cause I don't
know how to do it with radio shack to
those guys deliver to do they have the
drones? I don't fucking know. All right.
Where the fuck is it?
A, where did it go? Oh,
you know what I did? I didn't
open a new window. Oh grandpa,
I don't understand the
Internet. Oh No, I did. Well,
where the fuck did it go? Oh, there it is.
Would you like 15% off? No
thanks. I'd like full price.
3.5 millimeter male to
female headphone adapter.
Let's see here.
3.5 millimeter male to female
headphone adapter. Come on man. One time.
One time. Make it happen. Make it
happen. That's what the fuck that is.
Oh, look at those ones. Those ones
look like they're made out of chrome.
That's, that's it right there. That's it.
$7.
Can you fucking believe that
all this Bitch Moan and complain and
I could've had this done. You know,
you know people a lot of times in life,
you know the things that
were the most afraid of.
A lot of times they seem like
mountains and they're really,
you're just stepping up onto a curb.
Wait,
what do you mean $125?
What the fuck is William get the gift?
I don't want to fucking gift card.
Proceed to checkout it away from me.
Can I just, can I just walk out of here
please? Can I just fucking do that?
Place your order,
fam.
Order place all this time.
Bitching all this time and said done.
I just fucking did it. I did all
this fucking screaming and yelling.
You know,
I just feel like that just to be
a performer isn't enough for me.
I feel like I should be this vessel.
Who is it? Come on in. Oh,
just when Christmas couldn't
get any better. Who Sat it?
Sat my little buddy. Hey, how you doing?
Come here. Oh yeah. Don't mess
up my notes on that. Scripted.
It doesn't work right now. Can
I get a hug please? Hi. Hey.
Hi. Hey. Hey football.
Can you say hockey?
Can you say basketball?
Can you say baseball? Uh,
yeah. Just don't have a knock.
All those cards over.
How you guys doing the two most
beautiful ladies in my life? How are you?
I've been bitching about this
3.5 millimeter male to female,
a headphone Jack and I finally got
it fixed. What did you guys do today?
Ingredients for Christmas dinner.
What are you going to make?
Um, am I plugged in? Yes. You were
plugged in. Ah, we're going to make lamb.
So I got a rack of lamb. Oh, nice.
And I had them cut it up and we're just
going to freeze it until it's ready
because it's going to be a mad
house when we go on Christmas Eve.
Or can you say strawberry?
Can you say football?
Trooper. Okay. And you say hi.
Can I say Merry Christmas?
[inaudible] I don't know.
She can say that. Wow. I'm here.
I know how to keep you occupied
while we're in here. All right,
well we're just doing something. I
didn't really, I had all these debts,
that script I'm writing, so I get a,
what's this? Oh, those are, those are Dad,
dad's keys. He said Daddy's
keys. Can you say dad does car
as car
is getting fixed.
I had an orange cone and my car and
all of a sudden the engine light. Yeah,
don't touch.
It was on the highway and this is random
orange cone and I couldn't swerve away
from it or I caused an accident.
So I just drove over and went underneath
the car and I was getting off the
highway and it was,
I just heard it under the
car was set Minnie mouse?
Yes. You want to go watch many moms? Huh?
What do you say here? She does a
football. Football. What do you say?
You say please? Now what he say,
Hey Danks please. And thanks.
That's why you gotta be a good
kid. Oh. Oh, I get a kiss.
Your Mama and Mama. Yeah,
she's the best. Hey, you're
the best. You're the best.
Oh my God.
Tell me about Minnie mouse.
Okay.
Just don't mess.
That's you. That's you. Yes
it is. Yes it is. All right,
we've got to wrap this thing up cause I
want to play with you Kiddo. All right.
And we're gonna Watch some football
ball. Football. Strawberry.
Yeah. Hey, what does the dog say? Oh look,
what's the duck say? What
does the cow say? Moo.
Moo. Is that she talks like
Trump the biggest, uh, brain.
Uh, what does the horse say? What is,
uh,
what is the rooster saying?
What's the cat saying?
Uh,
what does the sheep say?
What's the bear say?
Alright, you're a smarty. Oh, you just
shrug the shoulder like that was nothing.
That's like, give me something hard.
Should we go? Should we say bye bye. Bye.
Okay. All right. Say Bye Bye Dada.
You say I love you.
Yeah,
that's how we say I love you.
[inaudible] you could say it.
Say I love you.
There you go.
All right.
Eventually you're going to put that
together and melt my heart even more.
All right. Hello Paul t guys, but I
got to wrap this up. Hey you guys.
Thank you for listening. Have a great
week and I can't say what I usually say.
So Merry Christmas.
Enjoy the music and the next day,
half hour bonus of the uh,
Thursday afternoon just before Friday.
Thank you to Joe Rogan.
I haven't yet.
[inaudible] [inaudible] Magnolia blossom.
[inaudible] don't care.
[inaudible]
[inaudible] dot org get hang up your
socks cause just exactly at 12 o'clock.
Cam The camera down to
take it up. You fucking
laugh. I do fool. When
you're fucking cunt.
Christmas fucking trees will be Dolby.
See that's the fucking song I was trying
to remember from last week and I want
to thank all the podcasts
listeners letting me know
that that was Andy Williams
happy holiday slash the holiday season.
It's not until the second verse
already goes, Whoop de Doo
[inaudible] suck up a buck and crazy
twat and you don't see it exactly how I
said it. And then they had those
fucking women in the background.
[inaudible] Papa,
boom.
You're telling me you couldn't
write a fucking song back dead.
I mean Jesus Christ.
Maybe because it's so simple.
It sounds so simple that you think he
could do what? I don't know. So anyways,
it is. Oh fuck. Why did I play that?
And I want to be singing at the
whole God damn podcast again.
I don't like to repeat myself, at
least not on purpose. What's going on?
It's bill Burke. It is the Monday
morning podcast for Monday, uh,
December 20th.
Oh my God.
Only five more days till Christmas.
I only have half. Shut up.
You fucking all right.
I'm not even this angry week.
I'm just trying to figure out how I'm
going to situate myself on the bed.
I don't want to put my laptop in my lap.
You know what I mean? Why would you,
why won't you put it in your lap?
It's cool. The little dude. Um,
this is why, because it gives off
radiation and I like my balls.
I think the Illuminati came
up with the laptop, you know,
and they know we're too stupid to stick
at exactly where they want us to put it
so they can fin out the fucking
heard. So they go, you know,
with their evil voices. Why don't
we just, it the laptop, we call it,
they let up days, put it in their lap
and they fucking die. The infidels,
that was half Arab, half Italian. So
make sure I get notes from both of you.
Um,
yes it is December 20th.
I just came off of a
fabulous week out in Bray,
California and I want to
tell you guys something.
If you're ever in a situation where you
have a lot of vacation time and you're
just like, fuck, where the
hell can I go? You know,
you only go around once in this world,
where can I go to vacation to summer
does not what rich people say.
We live in the city and we
summer out in the Hamptons.
I'd love to summer somewhere when
that'd be awesome. Jesus Christ.
How much fucking money do you
have to have? They have two homes.
This is where I live during the year.
And then I summer,
we spooned no linters done and boom.
Bhutto's know doing what?
Visiting the fucking money that you're
not paying taxes, taxes on. You know,
I don't give a fuck.
I didn't know what I'm talking about here.
I was onto something there and then I
completely lost it because I thought I
wasn't recording here. Um, oh, I know.
I was out in Bray California this
weekend and I got to tell you,
I had a miserable experience the last
couple of times I went there and the only
reason why I was miserable is because
nobody showed up. And Lo and behold,
this time I came out there and the
fucking place was packed all weekend and I
had one of the best
weekends of, uh, of 2010.
So I want to thank everybody
who came out to my shows, uh,
out at the Improv in Bray California.
Actually had some people from La
came out and a, I had like 12,
uh,
Mexicans,
different Mexican fans coming up saying
you have some Latino fence. Okay,
hang in there.
We will spread the word out to Ontario.
So I want to thank you guys. Grassy
us. It's the only word I know. Mucho.
Grassiness Rosetta stone.
I'm a Rio.
Ah, thank you very much. And yellow.
That's my only Spanish words.
I caramba. Yeah, Shit like that, that I've
seen in like cartoons when I was a kid.
Um, so anyways, I don't know what the
fuck did talk about this week because a,
I am technically,
I'm on vacation.
Like Axel Foley had Beverly Hills Cop.
I'm not investigating anything.
I'm out here in La with my
Mumford fucking sweatshirt.
You know what I realized? I just
realized this podcast is going to suck.
You know why I have too much
other shit on my mind because a,
as much as I'm mocking people who
haven't started this shopping,
I'm one of those people. I
haven't started it yet. And uh,
it really fucked up because I
did like six weekends in a row.
So I just focused on the road work and
I did not deal with the fact that I
haven't done any sort of
Christmas shopping yet.
So now I have to go out there today.
It's fucking raining.
I bet in this weather since I went to
Seattle right after Thanksgiving and I'm
ready to blow my fucking brains out and
went to Seattle and I also went to San
Francisco and all those fucking
assholes. We're just like, oh, you bring,
you bring the bed where the with you?
You know, I don't, I don't know. It was,
it was great last week.
So you know what,
considering I bought the droid phone,
does anybody know how to shut that off?
Dry Aid every time you turn it on.
My phone says that I brought the droid
incredible and every time I turned it on,
first of all it takes 10 minutes for it
to turn on. And then about, you know,
eight minutes in it goes dried and I
don't think there's a way to shut it off.
That's one of those
fucking advertising things,
make it look nice and loud and obnoxious.
So everyone around we'll hear it and be
like, Ooh, I want my phone to do that.
All right.
I'm still waiting for that.
Like I hope that phone does not take
over as much as I love it cause uh,
I fly too much,
you know,
and at the end of the flights when it's
okay to turn your cell phones back on,
I don't want to hear like draw, draw,
draw, draw void on the fucking plane, put,
you know, I'm going to, um,
but anyways, yeah, I haven't,
I haven't started in my
Christmas shopping and uh,
I don't want to be that Douche just
goes out and gets the gift certificates.
You know that, you know that person, you
go out, you buy him something thoughtful.
What are they into?
A,
what did I hear a mentioned that
they wanted or something like that.
And you put a lot of thought and you
drive around now that isn't right.
Drive over here that isn't right. Bam.
And then you find it and they're like,
aw man, thanks a lot. Right.
And they give you like a fucking, yeah,
he waiting to see what they got you right.
Do you put some thought in?
Do you feel this way about me too?
And what do they do?
They hand you a gift certificate to
the fucking olive garden. You know,
it's like you fucking asshole.
You know,
I drove all over fucking
town and you just, you just,
and not even a good restaurant. That's
an, that's another thing too. Um,
if somebody gives you a gift certificate
to a restaurant, don't fucking go.
Don't even fucking go.
All right.
What sort of respectable restaurant
gives out gift certificates?
You know what I mean? That's, that's
just like one step above fast food.
You know what Douche bag of the week is?
Anybody who goes out and
does Christmas shopping,
it just gets a bunch of fucking
gift certificates. Hey, you go,
you fucking figure out what
you want is some money.
Why don't you just come in and take a
fucking handful of cash and throw it on
the floor,
like have some goddamn whore and watched
me crawl around on my hands and knees
picking it up. You know, like I
just gave you a bad lap dance,
but you got enough money to not bitch
to management a, you'll have the really,
that's what I get is you
have fucking hundred.
Don't spend it all in one place.
All right?
You fucking cheap bastards.
I'm talking to you and you and you just
gotta be at least three people on this
podcast that do that shit.
He fucking tight Fox.
Right?
And then what do you do?
You gather up all your nice gifts that
people put thought into and you just,
you know, walk out of the house. You
know, you don't give a fuck, right?
Fuck it. Right. It's
just the drinking water.
We can pour the shit in there.
Well that kept me the corner office.
I swear to God,
if somebody gets me a fucking
gift certificate this weekend,
I'm going to do some of the not, this is
Christmas this weekend. Five days away.
Yeah. Be Saturday. I'm going to take
that fucking thing. Oh, thanks a lot.
And I'm going to slice their
juggler like James Bond level,
fucking paper cut and just watch that
blood right off the side of their fucking
neck. All right, so you
learned something about me.
You already knew I was an angry son of
a bitch, but I hate give certificates.
I can't stand them.
I would rather get an ugly sweater
from an older relative than dent than a
fucking gift certificate.
That's just so you know he did.
That's just the fucking tap out.
You know shorty,
man, it'd be really busy. Oh really? Oh,
I've been laying in a hammock all year.
You Lazy. Fuck. Now you don't give a shit.
Why am I such a fucking Dick?
Somebody I knew every year would get me
a fucking gift certificate and you know,
I should have just gave it
right back to him. I never did.
I always gave him a nice gift thing. Can
I, you're gonna you're going to notice,
right? Nothing. Nothing.
Oh, we shit. All right. There you go.
This your first rent for the week.
Did that make you feel better? I'd
like to hit. Why? Why don't I have a,
why don't I have a podcast
where I give thanks.
I give thanks to everyone who came
out to my shows this year. You know,
I give thanks to the universe for allowing
me to fuck up enough in my personal
life to bless me with an
a new hour of material.
I've got to tell you, man, my fucking act
is right where I needed to be. And uh,
my next Gig is an until, uh, the
weekend, I believe of January 13th.
Um, I'm going to be in Atlantic
city with a, this is the show.
Jim Norton put this thing
together. It's Norton, myself,
Jim Breuer and David tell all on
one show. All right. The Miami Heat,
the Mount Rushmore, if you will,
of a stand of a standup comedy.
I can't see Mount Rushmore. That'd be all
time greats. Let's go with Miami Heat.
All right, let's go with
that. How about we say that?
So anyways,
that's my next show.
So they have this weird thing
where I'm off for like a month,
but I also have to stay sharp.
So my girls all excited that I have a
month off and I'm actually doing a show
tonight
and I was trying to tell her that
I, I have to stay sharp, you know,
I've got to stay on my toes.
I can't just sit around
fucking roasted chestnuts.
Does anybody do that anymore
than anybody ever had a chestnut?
Chestnuts roasting on an open fire.
Jack Frost nipping at your news.
There's no internet or
fucking cell phones,
so we have to talk to one
another. Um, all right.
What, you know, something,
something I mentioned,
they're actually tied into something that
somebody was talking about. Oh, they,
you're talking about die hard fans.
I'm talking about sports here.
Somebody said a bill,
just like the Yankees,
the Celtics purchased the last
championship with Kevin Garnett. I love,
and people do half ass research.
You know,
didn't you forget a couple of
other guys that we also bought? Um,
it's not, it's not even the purchasing
of Garnette that bothers me.
It's the delusion Boston's fans
have when they cheer for Garnette,
that mother fucker kissed the
Shamrock in the center of the court.
Like it was his homecoming,
like he was from Boston.
Like he yearned for playing for that
team at Boston's fans ate that shit up.
Totally bought into that shit.
Uh,
when in actuality it was just
another purchase for a championship.
How do you feel knowing your
fellow Bostonians got duped? Uh,
the bullshit fan base I see in Boston
makes me want to puke in my soup.
And it happens in a bunch of
other cities to, uh, sorry,
I, I can't read out loud and I'm
also reading this at a fucking angle.
Let's get some fucking stomach cancer
here. Put the laptop here. Uh, where was,
where was I? Uh, you have die
hard fans for all your teams,
but they're few and far in between few
and far between servers. How you say that?
Uh,
then you have just a bunch of stragglers
who suddenly come out of the woodwork
when their teams on top.
I live in New York and now in La,
in the past eight years I've
noticed an influx influx of pats,
fans and both of those cities.
All of a sudden everyone is
proud to be a patriots fan. Uh,
where were these fucks in the 90s?
Same goes for Laker fans.
Where will those assholes with
the flag on the car asked, uh,
with the flag and the car assholes
in the 90s. Explained this to me,
Bill and go ahead and shit on as
many front running New Yorkers,
Los Angelenos in Miami, schmucks
all you're like, yeah. Yeah. Dude.
You're basically explaining, uh, yeah,
that's how it works. Yeah. Where
were all the Yankee fans in the 80s?
Exactly. You can't say where were
all the patriots fans in the 90s.
Because once we got bill Parcells,
everybody jumped on board.
And then when Pete Carroll came in after
parcels fucked us that fat fuck that
fat fuck Egomaniac who never won a
championship without bill Belicheck is his
defensive coordinator who you will
need to cook to do, do groceries.
He says that right before our Superbowl
puts his fucking house up for sale.
What a cunt fucking were overrated
bill Parcells if you want your uniforms
changed and you want to make it
to the playoffs, he's your guy.
But if you want to win
the super bowl you got,
you better have bill Belicheck on
your staff. All right. Yeah, I, yeah,
Your Bandwagon Fence Bandwagon fans are,
are uh,
the majority of the fan base.
There's no reason to build
stadiums as big as they are.
If they're actually talking
about die hard fans,
you'd only need like a one level,
you know,
you could have those old school
like high school stadiums, you know,
with a wind whip through the
end zones. Uh, yeah, absolutely.
That everybody is guilty of
that. And, um, basketball,
I hate to say it has followed what the,
uh,
what baseball has been doing,
where you just sort of try to buy the,
buy the championship every year
and it's really a free agency.
I guess it's kind of the player's fault.
You know what it was,
it was an overcorrection.
It was before free agency,
you know, the owners were
like the owner in, um,
what does that call the perfect stallion?
What the fuck's that?
I can never mean Robert Redford movie,
the natural perfect stallion.
How the fuck did I get?
I can't remember. Shit.
I can never remember the names of
actors, a movie. So I just, whatever I,
first thing I think of, I just fucking
throw it out there. Uh, the natural, yeah,
the owners were like that. They
totally fucking owned you. And um,
that's why the fucking white sox
through the world series in 1919,
that's what opened the door to that is
they were getting so underpaid and they
were scumbag pieces of shit.
Those two fucking things. Um,
so then [inaudible] free agency came
around and now there's been like a total
overcorrection.
Um,
and the players are toe
seem to be completely in
control and they can just all
pile on one fucking team. I don't know.
I don't like it. I don't like it. Yeah.
The Celtics bought the championship
apps a Fuckin lutely uh, but you know,
it's one of those deals.
What are they supposed to do?
That's what the Lakers were
buying them too. You know,
what are we supposed to do?
Sit back and watch them by all these
fucking championships and we're not
supposed to go out and
purchase one. You know, Coby,
Brian's sitting out there can't win shit.
So they buy him Shaq and Phil Jackson.
Fucking Gary Payton,
Robert Henri fucking Karl Malone.
Who else? I don't watch hoop. Every time
I turn it on, there's another fucking guy,
the guy who beat up the
crowd, Ron Artest, that guy.
What a, what the fuck are the
Celtics supposed to do? You know,
it'd be nice if they all sat down and
just said, look, this is fucking stupid.
Let's go back to the way it was. But I
just think that that's the way it is.
So anyways, yeah, they just pile on.
I think Garnette kiss the floor because
he was sick of playing in Minnesota and
he knew he finally had a chance to,
uh,
to win a championship after being the
fucking guy for all those years out there
in Minnesota and, and always
coming up short. So I dunno,
I don't fucking, I don't know. I don't
know shit about basketball, but yeah,
you're basically, yeah. Diehard fans,
diehard fans hanging in there. But uh,
I even think die hard
fans are full of shit.
There's a couple that will
actually sit there. Come on man.
You gotta be honest with you. I'm a die
hard fan. Your team is going to, and 14,
you're actually sitting down
watching that shit. You know,
sometimes you're such a die hard
fan. You can't go, you can't watch,
you know, I didn't watch the Celtics. I
went to a Celtics game the year before.
We bought all those guys
to win a championship. We
played the Toronto Raptors.
I had like court side fucking seats and
I almost fell asleep and it was just sad
looking at the parquet floor and looking
at the shamrock and just seeing it was,
it was, you know, it was hard to watch.
That doesn't mean I don't love
the Celtics, but you know,
sometimes you got to look away and
you know what, you fucking cunt,
you do the same thing. Stop acting
like you're all high and mighty.
You just hate the Patriots and
you're sick of seeing them.
Be honest with yourself.
All you sports fans,
who the fuck ever saw anybody in a sports
bar with the New Orleans Saints Jersey
on ever 30 years of watching football?
I never fucking saw it.
And then last year there's like a whole
gang of them going, who dat? Who Dat?
Who Dat take? They gonna
beat them saints. It's like,
where the fuck did you guys come from?
The states were borderline.
They will like an expansion
franchise for like 40 years.
They couldn't even afford a
kicker with two whole feet.
They had a kicker with one and a
half fucking feet. That's, that's,
that's how fucking broke those guys were,
you know,
then they brought that football out there
with the helium in there so they could
have a feel good story. Oh by the way, um,
did you see how the jets,
when they got busted for cheating,
that fucking fag on the jets go?
Who to patriots are doing it to that
right there is known as a pulling a Cobie.
When you do that shit that's called
the shack fucks around on his wife too.
You know when you're down at the
police dude, you don't ever do that.
All right.
When you get busted for some shit,
you go into mister blonde mode,
you shut your fucking mouth
and you do your God damn time.
You don't start dragging other people.
And it was so passive aggressive.
I'm not trying to get anybody
in trouble. I'm just, you know,
if you just look at the tape,
I mean it's all there,
which was such a stupid, there's no
rule against lining up people there.
You can stand on the sideline,
you can all stand there
doing handstands if you want.
That's not what he got
busted for your green cunt.
He got busted for sticking
your fucking knee out
evidently on purpose.
How wrong was,
I tried to be nice last week and I
defended that Douche and it turns out, uh,
I dunno.
I like how they tried to act like that
was his decision and his decision alone.
That guy actually, he shut that guy.
The strength and conditioning coach.
That is a solid guy cause he just, he
took, he took the blame for that one.
The strength and conditioning coach.
He the only guy,
he's these the guy like
as far as moneymakers,
he's just above a fucking cheerleader and
he's saying like, he's on the sideline.
Hey listen guys, everybody fucking
line up the private over there.
They're blaming the private, you
know, give me a fucking break.
But I think sticking his knee
out was definitely his decision.
But as far as lining up on, on, on the
side, I don't give a fuck. So I love it.
So the jets cheated and this week the
panthers had somebody get up and drill,
drill, someone coming down the sidelines.
See this is what it's all coming out.
I love it. After all these years of
people saying the patriots are cheaters,
like no one else is doing it.
Like the Yankees weren't all taken
fucking roids [inaudible] along with the
fucking reds. Everybody
cheats. Do you guys watch that?
30 for 30 on Smu and how the entire
southwest conference football was played.
I hate to say it during the week of
Christmas, but there's no Santa Claus.
Everybody fucking cheats.
Everybody Cheats Booboo, booboo.
What song is that?
Remember that from fucking sesame street.
Everybody sleeps and they'd show like
turtles sleeping and you sit there almost
tearing up, not even knowing what the
fuck you were crying about. You know,
cause you're already knew it.
You could sense it even as a six year old
that the world was going to be full of
a bunch of selfish cons. Hey,
you know something? I have
a video for you this week.
How many fucking agonizing minutes am I
into this podcast? 22 fucking minutes.
Jesus Christ.
I gotta be honest with you
people sometimes this podcast
is easy and other times
I feel like I'm shoveling
what? Snow. And uh,
this is one of these times I feel
like I'm shoveling wet fucking snow.
Uh, I'm sick of talking about football. I
can't talk about it any fucking more. Uh,
thank you to Green Bay,
Wisconsin though I do want to say thank
you for that Christmas gift for allowing
us to win that game that we
shouldn't have one yesterday and a,
do you guys realize,
actually bet the Patriots after telling
you guys all if given 14 and a half
fucking points
I bought into the hype.
You know what a moron all year. I've been
saying, I hate our fucking difference.
Our defense lifts up 24 to
30 points every fucking game.
We have two good weeks in a row.
I even said last week on the podcast,
you think I'm buying into this shit.
Like we're going to win a super bowl.
You don't just play two good games in
a row and fucking wipe out 11 bad ones.
And after saying all of that,
what do I do?
I fucking bet the Patriots because
they're fucking quarterback was out.
And I'm a fan of Lsu. I don't ever
remember that guy fucking doing anything.
You know what it was that guy played
at Lsu right before it started watching
college football. But my experience of
watching Lsu is they have fucking, ah,
they always have two quarterbacks,
a white dude and a black dude.
And they cheered. They just Sorta, I
don't know what they'd do. They just a a,
they just switch them off and it's not
the same guys every, every fucking year.
They got a new white dude, new
black dude, and they just, uh,
put the white guy in there, Dan.
He's too fucking white. Look it up.
Take a net sec sick. The black
guy in there, Jesus Christ.
He won't stand in a pocket.
Get the white guy back in there.
I'll tell you if they could somehow
Amalga just stick those two guys together.
Add it probably wouldn't work.
I know it worked for Paul Mccartney
and Michael Jackson when they sang that
fucking song.
Was that one of the worst songs ever?
Wait a minute. Was that him?
Who Sang Ebony and ivory.
That was them.
Right.
I was thinking of Eddie Murphy and he
made it Stevie wonder and Frank Sinatra.
That was the sketch. Yeah. Was that
one of the worst fucking songs ever?
Ebony and a Boobie.
Somebody looked at the piano and
just came up with that corn bullshit.
You know what I mean? It's like, yeah,
we all want everybody to get along,
but do you have to try to make
us throw up in the process?
Okay.
Why is happy shit so nauseated?
Can anybody explain that to me during
the week of fucking Christmas, you know?
Yeah.
What is it about watching like a kid
trip and fall and start crying and then
looking for his mother? What is it about
that that's so fucking funny. Yeah.
You know when they get up and they're
crying so bad that they're not even making
any noise.
Okay.
Yeah. It just fucking
makes me laugh. You know,
watching my dog gets so excited
that it wants to go outside and it,
and it goes to make it quick,
you know,
fucking Barry Sanders cut and its legs
front legs go up from underneath them and
I hear him hit his jaw
off the floor. Yes. Okay.
Gets up and fucking does that
Little Harlem shake to try to,
it's just fucking funny.
I don't know what it is.
Maybe because I grew up watching the three
stooges. I Dunno why, but watching, uh,
watching people fuck up makes me smile.
What is wrong with me?
I really am destined to be alone.
Um, all right, speaking of Christmas,
um,
last week I made the mistake of,
I told you I bought a different kind of
Christmas tree for the holiday season.
Whoop de Doo be Doo. Um, I don't know,
the past couple of years just
to, just to, you know, for,
for new listeners this week, you know,
I don't know what happened. I just,
I had last couple of years,
I went there and I looked at these
Christmas trees and they would like,
they will like symmetrical and
there would be like, you know,
six inches of tree trunk and then
they'd have like these perfectly level
branches.
I just thought they look bad ass like
that Japanese garden sort of Zen look and
shit. And I loved it and I thought
that, you know, I thought, you know,
I knew I was going to get shit,
but I thought at least a couple of
people would come out of the woodwork and
dare to break free fucking tradition.
Let's read some of these uh,
these uplifting comments here.
A bill,
this guy tried to write day
Yom and he spelled damn yum.
D a m Y U M Damn Yum bill.
That is Charlie Brown's tree.
Looks more like an anorexic
low hand than Thurone.
All Right, Nice Tree Dick. You
see, this is what it's like.
You guys want to get into entertainment.
This is what you get all week.
This is pretty much the tone every once in
a while. Hey, great special. I loved it.
But other than that, that tree makes
the peanuts crew look like ballers.
I would rather decorate my coat
rack then that Skank Shrub,
Jesus Christ. Somebody wrote this
as the soundtrack to that tree.
I don't get Internet in this
fucking room for some reason,
so I can't click on that. Uh, it
looks like a used up toilet brush.
Uh, it looks like the tree, the tree,
the three stooges would have
thrown another picture up
when you throw the lights
on it. Oh, look at that. And I
liked that one. That's a twofer.
Made Fun of the fucking tree and
made fun of my bare walls. Um,
yeah. People, you've got a
glimpse of how I live my life.
This is why I'm debt free. I enjoy
in your credit card debt. You can't,
I know how to live.
I buy a Christmas tree. I can
actually afford. All right. Uh, yeah,
you probably should have got the other
tree. What are you a fag? I like it.
I wanted a Charlie Brown tree.
I was going to buy a real tree
and cut off half the branches.
So it was like Charlie Brown tree.
And my girl went out and bought one of
herself so she could say it's hers and I
can't cut it up. Okay. It's like I
was kind of like kind of on my side.
So what does that 20 against one for me?
Looks like a cell phone tower in disguise.
Jesus. I'm getting killed here. All
right. Uh, let me see something.
Everybody's just going, Charlie Brown
on me here. What do we to do? What?
I was genuinely excited to see your tree.
Where did you pick it out?
What'd you pick it out?
Champ. Fucking Afghanistan.
And actually looks like something that
would grow out of the soil in Hiroshima
now. Seriously, I'm Grad.
Glad you're going out of the ordinary with
the tree this year. Good. Good for you.
But I had no idea trees
could get hepatitis.
Merry Christmas. Oh look who's here. Nia.
Everybody is agreeing with you.
You want to come on the podcast?
Wait a second, let me, uh, let me
get your mic up here. Here you go.
Hi. Hang on, hang on, hang on. Let me
make sure you read. Go ahead, talk it.
Merry Christmas, everybody. There you
go. Talk a little more. All right.
Happy holidays. All right. Um, would
you like to hear some of these comments?
They all agree with you about the tree,
about the tree of the holiday season.
Boy, uh, maybe I should have known what
to expect when you scribed the tree,
but I didn't expect that. No offense,
but that just looks awful, man.
I have to admit that that one
hurts more than people who,
somebody said it looked
like a cell phone tower.
Like those ones are actually
funny. This guy that, that was,
that one came from the heart.
That will really was, uh, well
I'm a fucking termite and even I wouldn't
take a shit on that fucked up tree.
Jesus. Wow. Sweet tree.
Not Oh, lame. Yeah. No,
you know what that is?
That's like from a fucking anthrax fan
who's like fucking 48 now and has three
kids.
That's from like a Wayne's world.
Then they always used to say that not
the first time I saw not was anthrax.
That guy had it shaved into his
chest. The word, not an OT. Yeah.
The guy who then
eventually shaved his head.
You know those guys who go bald or always
like Harry, like apes, the guy, uh,
the guy who was on that VH one show
where they had the super group.
Oh, uh, yeah. And he had
the long beard. Yeah,
the long beard. Shaved head. But
just along the long beard. Yeah,
I know who you're talking about.
I forget what his name is.
I remember when I shaved my head because
I'm losing my hair and you love me.
Maybe you should fucking a
up that you love the shape.
Love it when you had the shaved
head. I say bring it back. Well,
I think nature is going to bring
it back for [inaudible], but well,
it's good to know that you still look
good. Well, you know, I can't do that.
Fuck it. Rogaine, Propecia shit.
I just can't, I, I just know it.
I know how it works in life.
You don't get your cake and eat it.
Nature's going to get you. Oh, you
want to keep your fucking hair. Okay.
Why don't we just fucking take
a shot to your goddamn liver.
Those people are going to
lose their livers. You know,
they're full heads of hair.
What did I walk into?
And I were talking about the tree.
The anorexic tree. Yes. So have
you done any Christmas shopping?
Let's do quick little interview. Uh,
get the people all caught up with you.
Have you, uh, look at that tree. I think
that tree looks fucking cool as hell.
It's not the Charlie Brown tree. You
have fucking asshole. Wait a minute.
You had to symmetrical Charlie Brown
tree was all brown. Call you guys. Well,
you have to take a picture of the tree.
Now that it's decorated though. What?
I think there's a debate.
It looks like a fucking fucking Broadway
singer with aids because it's all
glitter and skinny.
What a lot of them died of that.
They do. They do dress flashy. You need
to stop with, well, I'm not saying that.
I agree with that. I'm saying
that that's what they would write.
That's your out for everything offensive.
They, I'm not saying I agree with it.
It's just how it is.
Fucking dirt bag.
Oh, I saw that movie in the
band played on, right. I,
I don't want [inaudible] guys,
friends.
I don't mind any guys drive driving
garbage trucks holding their other garbage
truck boyfriend rocking them slowly.
It's not only gay people who can,
I know it's that. It's that and truck
drivers. That's not what it was.
Let's move on. It's Christmas.
Huh? I know it is now.
Let's talk about aids and let's
talk. Let's not play now. Come on.
This is fucking hilarious. I never saw
me. It was a long time ago. I don't know.
How did the song go? I don't
know. There was a song. Yeah,
I got in the bed.
Eat often happen.
Where are you asking me about Christmas
shopping? Wasn't it about San Francisco?
Isn't that where they basically don't
know Harvey milk came in and then that
other guy shot him in the head or is
that a different milk? It was milk. Oh,
you want to Sean Penn. Can I
show you the most? I can't even,
I won't even show this to you
because I love you too much.
Somebody sent me a youtube video. You
guys have to fuck never stopped you. Huh?
Showing me horrific. This is why you
don't get affection. I try to be,
I try to give it to you and you
slap it down. Look at that. What?
Let me, what do I got to replay?
What just happened there?
I said I'd love to show this to you
and, but it hurts you to, uh, you know,
I'd love you to whatever the fuck.
Nice thing I just said.
He don't even remember any of it's
two seconds ago, but I meant it.
All right.
There's a movie called Feast.
This is going to be on the Mlm podcast
where you guys feel free to go on there
and trashed my fucking Christmas
tree. I like it. I'm sticking by,
you know what this is like,
this is like the new kid who comes to
school and you guys all pick on him and I
prefer friend him cause I'm stronger. I
can step outside the group. Look at me.
I'm the hero.
It's just a tree and I'll fuck you.
All right. There's a movie, there's
a movie called a feast. Yeah.
Have you ever heard of that movie?
Okay. I don't know what's going on.
I can't, I don't want to, oh, that's my
phone. What is your cell phone sound like?
The tornado drill from the 50.
[inaudible]
cause you notice there's no, there's no
good ring tones. You know what I've got?
Go, go get the a, you know what? I'll
let my podcast listeners decide them.
Ringtone. Go grab my phone if you
don't mind. All right. All right.
Now I'm going to describe this fucking
thing where you're, okay, there's this,
this, this movie out there.
Feast that I, I have to rent.
I don't know what's going on,
but there is a woman tied down and this
beast that looks like a little person
that was a skinned alive
basically comes out of nowhere.
And
Fox,
this woman in the mouth and
finishes there. I set it,
I set it and it happened so fast.
I didn't even think that it was real.
And uh,
I don't know. That's when
I have to ask. It's like,
you're not really trying to scare me.
You're just trying to either gross
me out or make me fucking laugh,
but if you really want to get grossed out,
um,
here's another youtube video of the week.
Somebody sent one in.
I only got like two minutes into
this thing and I had to shut it off.
Human cryogenics. All right,
so if you guys, you know,
isn't that funny?
I told her to go pick up my phone.
She goes and answers it and now he's
talking to the person, you know,
what would you broads be doing if you
weren't running your fucking yaps?
You know, I, it's like I don't
understand it. They just,
it just have to be talking.
All right, whatever. So human
cryogenics, red sox fans,
we're all familiar with that.
You know what I mean?
Ted Williams head,
I believe is upside down sitting on a
tuna can and they accidentally broke his
nose.
I'm talking about Ted Williams.
They froze. Do you believe in a
pick up the microphone. Oh God.
You're going to be eating on the podcast.
You know,
I think this is good that you're on
the podcast. It's, it's, you know,
it's the holidays. It should. It should
be family April. I don't like it.
Then some people, some people
don't like my Christmas tree. Look,
first of all the Internet is like a,
you know like when you hang up those
lights to track bugs, Zap them.
That's what the Internet is for. Cuts,
you know what I mean? They, yeah,
they just gravitate towards it.
All these miserable fucks who have all
the power in the world to change their
life and live the wonderful life that
we're living on this fucking bed without a
headboard.
I've been trying,
you know somebody's trash
just because we don't have,
we don't have any pictures on the wall.
I'm trying to teach people how to live a
minimalist debt free life. First of all,
we don't need pictures on the wall.
We have our picture on
the wall that bill hates.
We have the live of pictures just getting
way too fucking intimate, but women.
But we have a picture above the
fucking bed of it. Looks like.
I thought you've talked about this
poetry. Have I talked about it? All right,
well I already brought it up. Yeah.
It's like every time I look up,
there's another deer, can't see it, and
it's staring right into the fucking Lens.
It's not black and white.
It's not in color. It's Sorta
in that Blair witch look.
It's kind of a Sepia tone. I fucking
hate it. And you know something.
I know you hate him yet. And I, whoa.
I almost fell in between the Tutsis.
We need a headboard. Homeless
just fell off the back of the bed.
But personally I'd like to point out the
fact that you went out and just bought
that fucking photo. Yep, I did.
And hung it. Right. Look at that.
And you just hung it right over the bed.
How can we didn't ask me about it?
I don't know. I just thought it would
be nice. Really. What if I get a poster?
A fucking Larry Bird.
He played for the Celtics and he used
to do this thing where he would always
wipe the sweat off the side of his feet.
So I'm going to get that.
So it looks like one of his fucking
blonde balls is going to fall out shorts.
And I'm going to hang that over the bed.
I don't want to see how
fucking long that lasts. Um,
I just want to say that we have a
mantle and there's pictures all over the
mantle of all of our annual something
that, those are the pictures we have.
You know what this is. This is hilarious
how innocent you are with the Internet.
What do you mean
you don't defend your position?
All you do doing now is
prolonging the arguments.
So now they'll do like really do,
why don't you put a picture
up of him if you have them?
Cause they just want more
material to trash you.
But they haven't even seen her apartment.
Who are they to say anything? Exactly.
I'm, I'm not, I'm just
saying what you're doing is,
it's like with someone trashes
you [inaudible] fucking
white. You're legs are,
I know. It's great. I just take them
out in a job interview when I get it.
So he know. You just agree. Absolutely.
Whatever. Yeah, I'm horrible.
I look like a puppet. Absolutely.
You're 100% and it kills it.
That's what Madonna's done.
You're a fucking whore.
I know you want to see my
[inaudible] check out my new book.
I got it all over there. I got a close
up. Didn't she take an in that book?
She took a close up of her fucking hoo
ha. I don't think so. Yeah, she did.
I think she was fully knew but then there
wasn't a closeout I that wasn't that
book. No. The sex book book
book was that, I don't know.
I don't think there is
with the little red wagon.
What was the last book that I read?
Actually that that book was, uh, my,
I think was my favorite work by Madonna
and I thought it was their most honest
work. You know who's standing out there
on the street looking like a fucking
prostitute. Exactly.
Exactly. She looked good.
She looked phenomenal. She looked really
good. I still bang that fucking cougar.
Huh?
You know what I hate?
You know what I love is that she's
gotten all their varicose veins.
Fucking that's what I was just going
to talk about that, cause she's,
everyone always talks about her
arms are so veiny. It's so gross.
But you know what?
Madonna works out everyday and that's
blood pumping through those veins.
You can see life. That's what those
veins are. Oh, it's very inspirational.
Yeah. Doesn't look aesthetic
though. She knows. She's
like, she's like somebody who,
you know, she's no, you
know what she's like,
she's like Clint Eastwood in that
movie. Gran Torino. Torino. Yeah.
I'd never been named that car.
The grant and that grant from Eda duty
year to your impression of that. Oh,
I forget to get off my lawn. Is that,
was it wanted? I can't remember.
I didn't like that. Yeah. But
then I would say all racist ship,
which people won't get that.
I'm making fun of the movie and I'll
think I believe it. Well that's what,
that's what he did in the movie. He was
racist in any way around. But anyway.
Oh yeah. Cause it's a Hollywood
wow. Because it's a holiday movie.
Listen. Yes. Grand Torino that, that's,
that's how she's treated like
the way he treated that car.
That's way she's treating her body. Her
body is like in fucking mint condition.
It is, you know, and all the
rest of us. What did we do?
We fucking back into a car at a
worry about it. Slammed into a tree.
That's how we treat our bodies. Damon
doesn't settle for second. Yeah,
she's out there waxing it.
She's the walking oil balls to the wall.
Not the whole fucking old
school shit this week.
So, uh, yes. I did go Christmas
shopping to answer your
dude. Go Christmas shopping.
I have a little bit.
What did you get me?
I'm not telling you what the surprise
you'll find out on me. A shirt.
You know what sucks about being a guy is
the last time you get a good gift is I
think when you're 11, the second you
turn 12, you start becoming an adult.
Maybe get some like electronic shit.
You know,
you just go into that, that
phase. We get shirts and uh,
uh, organizers. This is a place
to put your wallet and your keys.
I actually fucking love that.
That's really unnecessary.
Perfect casting, getting trashed. Here's
the perfect pushups. Merry Christmas.
I'm fucking with you. Got me great gifts.
You have first year I was with you.
You got me the drum sticks with my,
my initials and graved in him.
That was fucking adorable. Those were
great. That was cute. That was adorable.
This was when, obviously bill and I
were first day. What are we doing here?
Too much of our life.
Let's get back to the podcast here.
That was when we were talking about our
social security numbers that are seven,
nine, eight, four. I was just gonna
say that was what I thought. I,
you brought it up. I'm trying to get you
to stop talking about it. Fine. All right.
Let me see if I've got a question
here that you can actually answer
a where you can add to. I don't
think I have anything. You know what,
this fucking podcast, oh shit.
That I shut it off. I didn't,
did I please tell me I didn't. All
right, we're up to 42 minutes. Um,
so listen, yes, I, uh,
I got an offer for a corporate
gig on the day after Christmas
and,
uh,
Eagle Rock and I was wondering
if I can go do it. No,
please. First of all, I have to
fucking lie. All right, second of all.
No,
I'm just fucking with you.
You always get mad at me when I do
fucking work kid. You know what? This,
this whole fucking podcast and just,
I just forgot I was even doing the
podcast and I'm just sitting here watching
you eat oatmeal. Do you have
any closing comments? I got,
I got to bring this home with something
funny here. Do you got anything?
Anything you want to say? Oh, let's
talk about how I hurt my foot.
Making fun of you fucking ex. I mean, Oh
yeah, I made fun of her exercise tapes.
She,
she's in there like grunting and groaning
doing this fucking exercise tape.
And I walk in there and it's that dude
Bob from the biggest loser with is
shredded head.
He like has like,
he's, he works out too
much. Like he actually,
you know the cuts people
want when they get abs,
he has them on either
side of his forehead.
His head is shredded.
He's in great shape.
I'm pleased CVDS are no fucking jets.
So she sits there and she starts telling
me how his DVDs are hard and all that.
I was like, fuck that guy. I can do that
God damn DVD. I'll be fine. Typical man.
Right.
And then what happens?
I go to stretch before I do it because
I'm 42 years old and you're like, oh,
you don't need to stretch you
as this whole stretching thing.
And he fucking didn't and I ended
up screwing up my foot again.
They're stretching in the
beginning. Yeah, that's bullshit.
He didn't say he didn't do any
stretches for your back. Nothing.
Nothing to stretch out your feet.
And then the guy has the
fucking fucking jumping.
I got Bill Walton feed at this point. I
can't do that. God Damn Video Bill Walton.
Bill Walton was a big fucking redhead
who smoked weed and college and hung
around John Wooden and then all he
does is try to, like John Wooden was,
was this amazing coach who gave you all
this life advice and he's trying to be
John Wooden junior
always giving out advice,
always telling those stories and
he has his awful fucking voice.
That's like it comes from the center of
his head and goes out as fucking broken
nose.
[inaudible] we didn't do
good. Ugh, fucking red
headed Frankenstein. Well,
in the midst of that workout when there
was all that stuff going on with the
back,
I was like,
why don't you stop and just kind of
do an alternate version of it and you
wouldn't do it because you're a typical
man and you have to see like I can do
anything. You know what? I just love
the, you say a typical man. Yeah,
I lump us all in and then give me
shit when I talk about all the broads.
You've always done that.
I always have done that and I don't have
a problem with you saying that guys are
hardheaded and goes, we are. We're
fucking morons and you guys aside goes,
you guys are psychos. All
right. Where emotional.
That doesn't mean I don't like tea bars.
Fucking Bandana.
What do you think about that?
Oh t buys right from that fucking,
what's the name of that group that was
going to say like as long as they're
going to take you to get the name of
that bill. Never remembers the name.
Crazy sexy. Cool. Was the name
of their album. Don't go chase.
I thought they were saying
don't go Jason waterfalls.
And I didn't know what that meant. I was
like, is that some sort of hip hop slang?
Who's Jason?
Is that like a in why does
he like waterfall waterfall?
Can you fucking get the oatmeal? You
just spit out of your mouth. Oops. Um,
oh what was the name of
them? TLC. Yeah, you go
and uh oh left. Die Cause
I is right. Oh Shit.
What is this? Oh that's why she,
that's why she called herself left dot.
Cause what? Cause I is right. At
least that's how she explained it.
I know why they said why do you
have that thing under your, uh,
your left eye or it's she had something
on her fucking face and she said,
cause I use right. And I
was like, oh, what a cunt.
You know right there or cause she's dead.
I'm not supposed to say that.
When she was alive, she probably wasn't
difficult to be in a relationship with.
Wasn't she the one that burned down
that guy's fucking house? Yes she did.
I didn't go to jail because she has a
vagina. She went to jail. Are you done?
Went to jail for that? Yes.
How long? I don't know exactly.
Internet and look it up instead of just
one of those things where you end up
being wrong. Well you end up being
wrong and you're proven wrong.
So you just fucking gorilla your way
through it like you just said. Yeah,
that's what I'm saying. She did
go to jail bell. Look it up.
I'm not going to look at forest or
asked to go to Rehab because she was an
alcoholic on top of it. Anyway, with the,
why you saying it like she's some
sort of a victim. She burned out some.
He please keep the Mike
in front of your mouth.
He didn't say that she was a victim.
I did not say that. Yeah. The,
gave her the out cause she was an
alcoholic. No I didn't. Yeah, you guys,
you guys always see everything,
the whole, your whole fucking life.
You just given excuses.
That's why you guys,
that's why he can't do
as many pushups as a guy.
Has nothing to do with
your mothering hips.
It has to do with the fact
that you fucking get to tee
off 20 yards in front of
me and still get the gift.
The same fucking score.
What does the c stand
for and Tlc? Uh, let's,
I don't know what the,
the Tl stands for. Yes,
you do tender loving care.
So to stands for,
they're the names of the girls in the
group. All right. There was Chili.
I've got Chili, there's left die and
then this t boss. Hey Cow. Yeah. Got It.
There you go. Go ahead.
Quiz me on some more.
Pop culture can be a little pop coke
culture quiz here. I'll fucking,
I'll bury it. Go ahead. Do it. Ah,
can you name all the members of
now you can go ahead. New Edition.
Absolutely gone. Bobbi Brown, uh,
Jerome Robinson, the trail.
Spreewell. It's rough.
And uh, Nipsey Russell. I was, oh,
he was a manager. He was the manager.
I was done over the group.
No, but I know here it is.
Horrible. That's my, a little
ring. I'll give me a fucking break.
What the world would you want to hear my,
you want to hear my options?
Give me another group once you pick a
white group so I can actually get it.
New Kids on the block. New Kids on the,
although they had all those games. Joey,
Bobby, Stevie, Mikey in pooky.
Huh? Can you feel the
baby? I can feel it too.
It was Marky mark stealing the licking
the lips thing from ll cool j Marky mark
and who else? And the funky
button. I remember those guys.
See It, feel it. Feel it.
Okay. It's just that, that, that ratio.
Oh, it was horrible music. What was the
spinoff group from new edition? A bell.
Biv. Devoe. Wow. What did they say?
Okay,
I remember all that shit.
Go ahead.
Name a song by Bobby Brown when
he was solo. My prerogative.
These are a joke. Okay. Let's see. I'm
trying to get your money right, Joey.
We didn't look at my fucking shiny shoes.
What does SWV crack?
What does SWV stand for?
Sisters with voices.
You are all on your like
rnb 90. [inaudible] going.
All right. Let me ask you,
so, okay. What's the name
of the, the maniac and ACDC.
You can't sit still for two seconds.
He run around the schoolboy outfit.
I took you to see the ACDC.
What's his name? No. Well,
a great performers of all time.
He's like James Brown without rhythm.
Okay.
He never stops moving the
hardest whiteboard, uh,
working white boy and show business.
I forget. Okay. It's a kind of beef
Angus young. There you go. There you go.
See what she'd be on the fucking $10,000
pyramid. Ah, give me another one.
All right. Uh, namely
original lineup of Van Halen.
Name as many members as you can.
This is the white version.
Van Halen of new edition. Yeah. Eddie
van Halen. Bang. David Lee Roth. Good.
That's half the group. He's got a
brother. It's cool. It's one of the names.
A GSP always says Michael Van Halen.
Nope.
Alex video at x and x two,
three GS. George Saint Pierre,
do it.
Come on Lex.
Hey.
Okay.
Jonathan donor,
then sweep the leg down at 10.
Hey.
Yeah.
All right. Hang on a second. What else do
we got here? Where the fuck I don't care.
Oh, the ring tones has the ring tones
for the week. All right, I'll give you,
I'll give you another quiz. Uh,
okay. Oh, you'll get that one.
I can't even answer that one.
I was the same name.
Name the lead singer of Duran Duran.
You'll get that Simon Labon. Yeah, sure.
MMM. Everybody else? I don't
find the bond. All right.
We didn't get the guy from anthrax. No,
I wouldn't get that. Alright, quiz me.
Quiz me on five movies and I got to end
the podcast cause I have to go do my
fucking Christmas shopping. Five
movies. Yeah. You don't want,
I'm going to get you this year and we
want to see what I'm going to get you.
I'm going to get you
away. Uh, let me think.
I'm going to get you some
workout clothes, right? Uh,
maybe like, uh, uh, a positive CD.
A positive CD ones that made it on it
sounds like weather and it helps you sleep
better. Yeah. I'm going to get you that
and then I'm going to get you some new,
a toenail clippers. Stick that
right in your stocking. How's that?
Would that be a romantic?
All right. Go ahead.
Quiz me on some movies and then I'm out.
Um,
names talk into the mic name.
At least five actors in the movie casino.
Five actors in the movie casino. All
right. That should be, it should be easy,
but I'm not good with names. All
right. Robert Deniro. Joe Pesci,
Frank Vincent [inaudible].
Uh Oh.
Sharon Stone and fucking,
uh,
the guy went to MIT. What? Yeah,
I know about his personal life.
You had a fucking insane mullet.
Yeah. James Brolin. You've got James,
right? Is that his name?
James Dear Vanderburg.
James Vanderbeek. Yeah. What's that?
It's a picture I know of. What?
Deer in the woods. A cowards.
Oh, James Woods. That's
right. I knew them. All right.
This is just getting boring to you.
We'll just pouring the list.
Do you have anything that you want to
say before I dismiss you? Happy holidays,
everyone. There you go. Be
Good to each other. Okay,
now get your oatmeal and get out.
Get Out.
That's it near everybody.
The lovely near coming in on the
podcast once every fucking six weeks.
Get out of here
you go. And she's leaving.
All right, there you go.
So that's the podcast for this week.
People. I know, it kind of sucked.
I know some of it was Kinda
nice spot on that said, oh,
you know something of what I keep meaning
to fucking talk about on this God damn
podcast is I started,
somebody sent me something,
uh, about the fucking, what the
hell did I do to my damn computer?
Let it go.
Let go of my fucking cord.
Are you fucking kidding me?
Get up.
Hang on a second.
People fucking court is stuck in there.
Whatever.
People keep sending me this shit about.
A one person did send me
about the Liverpool soccer
club in the premier league
and evidently these American dudes bought
it and said that they were going to
buy a buy,
a brand new stadium.
They were going to do all this
type of shit and they didn't do it.
And somebody sent me this great video
of all these English people from their
heart's telling these American guys to
fucking sell the Goddamn team and to fuck
off.
And it was awesome.
And this is the same team that the owners
of the red sox then went in and bought.
And I started looking at the premiere
league and like three or four the teams
are owned by, uh, by Americans,
specifically people from the
United States. All right.
Because we're all from North
America up here. Uh, and I,
I can't believe how fucking
annoying that would be.
You don't have a bunch of English guys
came over and bought my team and said
that they were going to do a bunch
of stuff when they fucked it up.
I would be beyond pissed.
Um, so I, I don't know.
Sorry about that. England. I don't
know why the fuck we did that.
It's nice to know we're buying
something considered gyp.
Japan's come over here and they,
they fucking bought up everything
over the last 20 years. Didn't they?
Don't they own our roads? You know,
what are you gonna do with them?
Close them off. Do you have enough people
to do that? I don't think you do. Um,
so yes.
Send me some more information on it.
Cause I'd like to talk about the
premier league and also I'm wondering in
Ireland, is that a seven nation rugby
league or whatever the fuck it is?
Is that starting up again?
Cause I watched that last year in
March when I went over there and uh,
rugby is the shit and a
unlike professional football,
which they're just turning into
the biggest pussy sport ever.
Isn't it enough that we were,
that they have to wear pink for the
entire fucking month of October.
You know,
now you can't tackle people.
The amount of quarterbacks out there
that I get in like Joe Montana fucking
stats because they're drive was kept
alive because a defensive person had the
audacity to tackle someone as, as
just as fucking beyond me. And uh,
I got nothing left people.
I'm not going to lie to you.
This podcast was fucking
over before it started.
I have too much shit I have to do.
All right.
I remember the first year I did this
podcast, I actually took two weeks off.
I took two weeks off, so,
you know, whatever it was
dressed down fucking Monday.
I came in, I did what I
could. All right. That's it.
That's it for the, uh, for
the podcast for this year.
Everybody right now we've got one
more for this year and next weeks.
I promise you,
I promise you it will be just as bad
as this one if not fucking worse.
Cause I'm on vacation.
I'm not required to make you laugh,
but I want to thank everybody.
Seriously. Everybody who came out to see,
um, my shows this year, um,
I had a great time and I actually,
oh wait. Yeah, I know what I'm doing.
I'm missing an underrated overrated. How
the fuck could I do that? Underrated.
Overrated this week real
quick. Uh, overrated.
Both the jets and the Patriots being a
Dolphin Fan. Born and raised in Miami.
I'm six at sick and tired
of these two faggots.
Teams dominating the AFC
east for the past decade.
While it's really been the patriots,
it was very nice of you to
throw the jets in there.
I think the jets have one like one, one
division in the last fucking 10 years. Um,
so I get it. Were overrated
because your team sucks. Um,
80 you like how while the former Dolphin
won the game for the jets yesterday.
Have Bet you enjoyed that, huh? I
hope you get a sunburn on your ass.
You fucking cunt. All right. Underrated
the bills. Being a dolphin fan.
Born and raised in Miami,
like you already said,
I love the bills for always keeping the
dolphins in the hunt for the playoffs
every year for the past decade and a half.
All right.
That guy was just being a dick, so I have
to respect that. Alright. Underrated.
Michael Vick. He does sports announcer
voice, uh, Michael Vick, Michael Vick.
What are you,
one of the things you have to understand
about Michael Vick is Michael Vick,
the MVC P of this season.
Bob, because he's my MVP.
He's making fun of me talking about
how that's all they say. Michael via.
What can you say about Michael
Vick? Well, well, Jim, Michael
Vick, um, you know what?
I have to admit I was fucking
wrong about that guy. I was wrong,
but I was also right. Okay.
Because the same reason
I fucking fell for it by the Patriots
playing good defense for two weeks in a
row and then actually gave up 14 and a
half points ignoring the fact that they
only played well for two
fucking weeks in a row.
You can't say that a guy's the best dude,
the fucking lead.
Cause he lights up the Redskins and
fucking three weeks later John Chitana
lights up the fucking Redskins.
All right. But yesterday,
what happened in that game?
I mean that was unreal.
I think he went back to old school,
Michael Vick.
He just started fucking running down the
field like a God damn water bug. But uh,
I was wrong about that guy.
Um, it's where it's been a,
he can't say he's in,
he's in like a League of his own as
far as like what the fuck he's doing.
Cause I've never seen anybody
do that shit at his position.
And I'd say that he's going
to change the position,
but I don't know that they'll any be
ever be another person is talented.
Is that fucking guy at that
position? Um, I dunno. So anyways,
he says, uh, Bill, sorry,
you have to go through another week of
that shit of everybody saying Michael
Vick. But every time I hear them talk
about fiqh after a big wing, no matter,
no matter what I remember about
your rant against the announcers,
the announcers saying his
name over and over again. Um,
I say he's still underrated because he
broke two NFL records in the last two
weeks, but still can't
get any solid respect. Uh,
I think he's getting his solid respect.
The fact that there's,
they're saying that he might be the MVP
of the league and he's coming off an 18
month stint in Leavenworth
for torturing dogs to death.
You know what I mean?
I definitely fought when someone
plays the fucking race card.
I always listened to it because I,
you know,
I traveled the road and I know what
people are like having talked to them,
it's just people are fucking,
they're awful. The fucking awful.
But this is the one time where
it's like, dude, you know,
you're tortured dogs to death.
You drowned them, your shot him.
I mean straight up, straight
across the fucking board. You know,
you can't expect people to 100% Embracia
after you do some shit like that even
though you more than
paid the fucking price.
But I'd rather be you than one of
those fucking dogs. So anyways,
he said, I say underrated because he broke
two NFL records in the last two weeks,
but still can't get any solid respect.
Honestly.
As much as I hate Tom Brady,
he is the real MVP so far.
But people are still hesitant.
I don't know who the real MVP is,
but Tom Brady's having
his best fucking year. Um,
all right. This is a good one here.
Yukon women's team, 88 win streak,
overrated.
The audacity of these media prints to
compare the Yukon's woman's team to the
UCLA team, by the way, which
was cheating by the way,
with how they got all their prospects.
For all you people who trashed the
Patriots and act like all you're fucking
winning is because you're just such
smart fucking human beings. It,
I would,
I'm not going to get involved and I'm
not going to open that fucking can of
worms, but John Wooden, uh,
as my buddy said yesterday was the
king of looking the other way when the
boosters got involved. Okay, let's
leave it at that. All right. Of course,
it's a major accomplishment,
but as is typical with everything,
male versus female related,
people cannot put things into
perspective when it comes to females.
The woman's Yukon teams,
88 wins is in no way,
shape or form as impressive
as the UCLA teams.
88 whims wins.
I'll put it to you like this.
I used to play little league football
and got MVP three times in a row
and co MVP once,
however Tom Brady has won the NFL MVP I
think once or twice I have a longer MVP
streaked and Tom Brady, but who's MVPs
are more respectable and impressive.
That's right. Mine. Just
kidding. Of course his are, um,
all right, I get that. But
uh,
do,
but you're a guy and you could play in
the NFL but you weren't good enough.
So that's the difference I guess.
Um,
as far as that,
I would say that they're the Ucla,
the Ucla of women's basketball.
How about that?
You got to say that because they are going
up against the best females out there
and they have one 88 in a row.
So I would say it like that.
But to compare to put it up there
with Uclas. Yeah, the men's,
I definitely think that's bullshit.
That's just the classic, uh,
you know, it's like them wearing
pink in the NFL. It's just,
did you just appeasing them? That's
all the fuck you doing. You know?
And I really just compare breast
cancers to like appeasing somebody.
I really should just stop talking, but I'm
just going to keep going here. Um, yeah.
As far as sports accomplishments go,
I don't think females mean as much as
men's just because we're better at it than
you are.
You know,
we just have better hand eye coordination.
Just generally speaking,
we're just better at, you know, the
amount of guys that if you go, hey,
think quick catch and you just throw
them a stapler, they going to catch it.
And the amount of women who would just
take it off the face and have it landed
in their cleavage, it's, you
can't even compare it, you know,
let's debate that next week.
I don't think females are as good
athletes as guys are. I just don't,
I don't think they are. I don't think
that they have that killer instinct. Yup.
Unless they're there,
they're chemically wired like a guy
and they have as much testosterone.
I don't think it's going to be a problem.
I'm just saying this to Piss people off
so I don't have to work hard next week.
Uh, I think that's it. I do. I've
got some, uh, youtube videos,
you know, if ever I was going
to edit a fucking podcast,
it should be fucking this one.
This one is just Jesus, whatever.
Last week's was great. This is
what I am happy, you know, I mean,
this is a let down week for me. All
right, youtube, check this one out.
This is one of the creepiest ones I've
seen. And uh, it's called the liar card.
This is a card you can put in your phone
and for people, you know, so when you're,
you're,
if people are ducking your calls,
that will show up as
somebody else's phone call.
You can disguise your voice to sound
like a woman or a man. And uh, yeah,
I guess you could find out where they
are in case you know. I Dunno what,
there's another good one.
Our Danny Woodhead, you know,
the fucking all pro for the
fucking New England patriots.
Danny Woodhead as Modell's employee
selling his own Reebok Jersey.
He stands in a modal selling
his own Jersey in New
England and nobody recognizes
him. Uh, now the youtube,
would these all be up on the m
podcasts are the cliff lease signing?
Did Not make the boss happy.
This is actually a total ripoff video of
a video that a yes Canadiens fan made.
Um, or someone who hated the
Canadians a year ago. Uh,
they just took this footage of somebody
playing Hitler and a movie flipping out.
Um, just know that it is a rip
off, but it's funny, I guess. Uh,
what else do I have here? I think that's
it. Is that it? That is it. All right.
All those videos will be up there.
I apologize for the choppy podcast.
They can all be great hour and
five minutes. And by the way,
there's some maniac out.
They're transcribing my podcasts and
Mark Marin's and I think Adam Carolla's.
And uh,
how about a round of applause for that
fucking trooper actually sat down and was
reading,
I read like three minutes of my podcast.
The guy gets like every fucking word,
so, uh, God bless Ya. Okay. And uh,
that is, if that's the podcast for this
week, you guys all have a merry Christmas.
Happy Kwanzaa. Happy Hanukkah,
happy fuck the holidays.
If that's how you are up
is all, have a good week, don't take
any shit that's it and go fuck yourself.
[inaudible].