Hey, what's going on? It's Built burn.
It's time for the Monday morning
podcast for Monday, January 22nd,
2018 what's going on? How
are you? Hi. How's it going?
How's it going? All right. All right.
Let's just get right down to it.
The New England patriots are
going to the Superbowl again.
Super Bowl unfucking believable.
How many times can they win?
Games like that. It's incredible. I
thought the officiating was great.
Everything was great. Fantastic.
I liked how it all washed up.
I really enjoyed that referee laughing
his ass off after we scored a touchdown.
That was tremendous. I love everybody
who saw that rough cracking up laughing,
uh, which you are not supposed
to do by the way, as a referee.
And that guy will definitely
get disciplined because
what happens is that every
mouth breathing more and goes,
fuck the caves fixed.
He's laughing cause they
just, you know, like,
which I understand that
it's the knee jerk reaction.
But think about what you're saying.
All right.
Let's just say for the sake of argument
that referee was, was on the take.
All right. Which you know, God knows.
I always said that about the NBA.
And then they caught that fucking guy
and everybody said I was nuts. All right.
Put yourself in that guy's position. All
right, judge you by his age, you probably,
I'm going to assume you had a wife
and kids. He's got a mortgage,
she's got a house and he's risking
all of that and his freedom
to fix an NFL game.
Put yourself in that position.
Are you going to be laughing when the
team scores or are you going to be fucking
stone faced and you really going
to be sitting there going, yeah,
just like we fucking said.
You know,
so I'm hoping the NFL films will
come out just to hear what, what,
uh, whatever patriots said that made him
laugh cause he's going to get in trouble
for that because that opened this
floodgate. Everybody was just saying like,
oh look at all the penalties will
do solely boo boo boo boo boo boo.
I still don't like the ticky
tack pass in inference stuff. Um,
however, having said all
of that, uh, you know,
I think the Jaguars defense
was a little overrated.
Everybody kept talking about how fucking
great their defense was and completely
ignored that the week before they gave
up 42 fucking points to the Steelers in
the playoffs when it counted.
Everyone just kept talking about
how great their fucking thief.
But that defense is that the only reason
why nobody really fucking brought that
up
was because they fucking,
their offense scored 45 points.
So I dunno,
I dunno what the fuck to tell you
about that. Great Jaguar defense.
They also played in a week division.
They beat the cults twice.
That's why I don't, this is
what, this is my deal. Okay.
I'm not saying they don't ever have a,
they actually do have a great defense,
but they're young and they do dumb
things like take stupid penalties right
before they have,
when the home team whose favorite
is only scored three points,
that fucking helmet to
helmet hit by the way.
Stupid fucking penalty.
Big Chunk a yards.
And then you'd take a fucking bonehead
pass interference call on the next play.
And you basically give the Patriots a
touchdown. You give them fucking hope.
And then also your great defense gives
up two touchdowns in the final fucking
six minutes.
So I don't know what to tell you.
There was a brutal hold call on the final,
uh,
important offensive player of the
game. I will give you that, but okay,
let's say they call holding there.
We're going to run it the next play.
You guys are going to burn your last
time out. We're going to kick the ball.
You're going to be down on the 10 fucking
yard line and you're telling me what
the minute and Change Blake Bortles is
going to run the length of the fuck.
I mean, it could happen. It could
fucking happen, but I dunno.
I Dunno. But anyways, that's why
I don't give a shit about, uh,
you know, regular season stats, you know,
I mean, okay, here's a, here's a thing.
Pumping up the fucking Jag was defense.
Regular season. They'd beat the cults
without Andrew Luck. 27 nothing. Okay.
They beat the browns and only
gave up seven fucking points.
They beat the cults again,
30 to fucking 10 they beat the Texans.
45 to seven.
These are all fucking teams that
you're not going to see in January.
All right. But if you go
through their fucking season,
they played the titans twice a playoff
teams. They lost to him both times,
let up 37 fucking points and had a
close game at the end of the year.
They played the rams that were a
playoff team. They lost to them.
The only playoff team that I'm,
I'm looking here real quick that they
beat was the Pittsburgh Steelers beat him
30 to nine and then they met him in the
plant and they let up 42 fucking points.
So
I don't know.
I mean how much more advantage
could the defense have? I mean,
Edelman wasn't in the game are number one
receiver on next number one option was
rob Gronkowski and you're knocked him out,
you know,
on a helmet to helmet hit
that if a Patriot did,
it would have been viewed as like the
like, like you killed Christ or something.
MMM. But whatever it was a great game.
Jaguars should have won the game.
I just thought they were too young
and didn't know how to win the game.
Didn't know how to put the
Patriots away. And, um,
I dunno if it, Tom Brady's Tom Brady,
not to mention Tom Brady also had like,
I don't know what the fuck happened
guy cut his fucking hand.
Yeah.
We have an almost 41 old
quarterback with the,
with the fucking stitches
in his throwing hand.
Edelman is out and you knock out Gronk
Koski and I don't want to heal up.
Bronkowske wasn't doing shit ground.
Koski does something on every play.
He draws double coverage and you didn't
have to fucking deal with that anymore.
So I don't know what the fuck to tell you.
Uh,
I do feel bad for Jaguar
fans because you know,
that's a fucking football city that
nobody seems to give a shit about.
You know what I mean? I like
to Jackson, you know what,
I've actually come around
and those helmets too. So
it was a great fucking game.
Um, the Patriots are limping into the
Superbowl and should be underdogs,
but won't be cause every mouth breathing
moron who doesn't know shit about
football, we'll put money on the
Patriots for somehow we will be, I mean,
the eagles just look like fucking world
beaters. They have an amazing defense.
They have to fucking base,
nearly have pros and fucking
Malcolm Blunt. I mean, I don't know why
the fuck are we ever got rid of him. Um,
I'm sure there was a reason
for it, but uh, yeah,
I mean the eagles should be favorites,
but they won't be just historically
because it never fucking wanted and we've
won a lot. So, um, so then if we lose,
it's going to be like
an unbelievable upset.
What does it say about Brady's
legacy? Um, we shall see.
We shall see. And I feel bad for, um,
uh,
New England fans.
They're going to go to that game with
the behavior of eagles fans and all of
that shit. And uh, you know,
I saw some of the footage,
some of this shit was funny, but
like, I dunno, Philly fancy, you know,
what they act like. Do you remember when
you didn't know how to talk to women?
So you just fucking went out and did
crazy shit every weekend hoping that the
women would then hear this
story and be like, oh,
that's the guy I want to go out with
and it's, don't get it, man. I just don't,
you know, fucking vikings fans. Oh, hey,
oh, are you? Oh,
you're doing like the fucking Nice Midwest
people you throw in full beers at him
. I Dunno, but on the other
side it's just like, you know,
that's what you're going to get.
Why the fuck would you wear your,
your vikings gear to the Goddamn game?
Um,
but that's really getting played out,
showing that type of shit. And uh,
and they did the classic thing
too. You know, it's funny with,
with every like NFL city they have,
they have like the story,
like whenever there's a game in Boston,
they have to play that stupid
fucking departed music.
I'm shipping up to
Boston and I lost my leg.
And then they're going to show Paul revere
and fall this freedom trail shit that
nobody gives a fuck about.
Who lives in Boston.
I walk by that fucking statue a
million times. I never look at it.
Um,
and I don't eat clam chowder anytime
Philly in a major sporting event,
at some point some fucking Douche is
going to try to teach you how to order a
Philly cheese steak.
It's like we got it.
Gimme a Wiz with gimme one without,
don't say Philly cheese steak.
You're in Philly.
You could literally walk up there
to any fucking cheese steak place in
Philadelphia and be like,
I would like a cheese steak with onions
and peppers and provolone cheese and
you're going to get it
because at the end of the day,
they're a fucking business
and they need your money.
They always do that.
They show the fucking rocky statue and
then they bring up the fact that they
threw fucking batteries at Santa Claus
is if that is the only fucking thing
that has ever happened in Philadelphia,
why don't they ever reenact Ben Franklin
fly in that fucking stupid kite with
the key on it, right? Why
don't they bring up the 83.
Philadelphia 76 is the most underrated
fucking championship team of all time.
Who I've said forever that I would
put up against the 96 balls. Okay.
I would take doctor Jay
[inaudible] fucking Andrew, Tony
to fucking knocked down a lot
of what Jordan and fucking, uh,
what's his face are going to do.
Scottie Pippin.
And then underneath you got fucking Moses
Malone one on one against Luc Longley.
Um, I'm not saying they would have
won, but I'm saying, you know,
be a hell of a fucking series anyways.
Congratulations to the,
uh, to the fucking eagles.
What a game. Good Lord. They,
that was, they gave them the,
they gave the vikings
seal right there, Fred. I,
but there was a lot of biking fan wishing
that they just fucking lost to the
saints after that beat down.
They took them right across the
fucking lap. Spanked at fanny. Um,
is it weird that, I mean, as
much as I love the vikings,
I kinda was rooting for the
eagles just because, uh,
I dunno case Keenum I just
can't get past that name.
Case, keen him. It just makes
me still feel so fucking old.
Somebody named a kid case.
Yeah.
Couldn't just name Robert.
Yeah,
sorry, I'm being a cunt. Um, so anyways,
if you are a Patriot's fan, um,
yeah, just know that you know, it's,
it's going to be a terrible
fan experience, uh,
because nobody does anything about that
level of fucking ridiculous behavior.
And I think at this point they get so
much fucking hype out of how bad they
behave.
They like trying to outdo one another.
Like do remember a few years ago there
was like some off duty cop went to like a
Philly's game and this guy was swearing
and shit behind him and he goes, hey,
take it easy.
I got my kid here and the guy put his
fingers down his throat and threw up on
the guy's kid.
I mean,
at that point it's just like he
just doing that just to do it right.
I Dunno.
So anyways,
so now we're gonna have to sit through
fucking too goddamn weeks of them talking
about fucking throwing batteries at
Santa Claus and showing the fucking Paul
Revere Statue. And I'm shipping
up to Boston and I lost my leg.
MMM.
I Dunno.
I think the eagles are,
yeah.
An overwhelming favorite.
If people knew how to gamble on football,
I would think, but uh,
that's not how it works.
Yeah.
But I think it's definitely,
it's the eagles game to fucking lose.
Um, I might be crazy, but
that's, that's definitely what
I think. But, uh, all right,
so there you go. There's, there's my,
there's my football talk condolences
to the fucking Jaguars in Vikings fans.
MMM.
Hey. You know what I'm actually excited
to watch is that thing where they have,
uh,
some Thursday on CBS
about the NFL players.
Like who's like the most to like
basically whatever your hobby is,
they got guys in the NFL playing
drums, guitar, cooking and Shit.
I actually want to watch that
because I want to see how good the,
the football player drummers are. How
stupid is that, right? Oh, whatever.
You got a thousand fucking
channels. You've got to find
something to watch, right?
MMM.
Anyways, did you guys
see that fucking, um,
okay.
The fuck is that,
that that one year anniversary,
I forgot member that lady when Trump
got in and was just screaming. No,
I don't understand that,
that type of protest
to do something like that because I
think a lot of people were thinking that,
but to literally do what that woman did
makes anybody who doesn't like Trump
look like a fucking lunatic.
Hmm.
You know, just so much. Just weird
shit like that. Like I saw last night,
the Sag awards had all women presenters.
I just fucking for the fucking life
of me who comes up with this shit,
all of it just seems like
self preservation to me
and none of it seems like
you're actually going
to work on the problem.
Like that's all the sag awards have
to fucking do is just have all female
presenters and be like, yes, see that.
They're all good people over there.
They get it. It's a show of solidarity
as a show of strength. I Dunno.
I think it's a pretty weak fucking effort.
You know,
we're going to wear all black.
We're going to where we're going to
have all female presenters. There we go.
We've been vetted.
Yeah,
I hate that word by the way.
MMM.
Yeah, that's, that's the whole
fucking thing. It's just a,
I mean, who, who the fuck?
Who is pro sexual harassment?
Why would you need to go that much out
of your way to do something as silly as
that, which in a lot of ways is kind of
reverse sexist, isn't it? I don't know.
Here's one fucking thing about this.
This is the only business I know
about is this business that I'm in.
This business is fucking brutal and a,
it routinely picks people up and slams
him against the pavement emotionally
every fucking day. Regardless of
what's between you, between your legs.
I Dunno.
All right. I, I don't know.
I don't even know what I'm trying to say
here. I just look at it and I'm like,
well, if they just decided they were
going to have all male presenters,
that would be considered the
most sexist thing ever. And uh,
and then on the other side, if you
want all this fucking, all these
creeps,
well, islands speeds specific. Only the
male creeps in Hollywood if you want.
All of them out. I don't know that
that's the fucking way to do it.
If that's an effective way
to do it everywhere buddy.
Where's the same colored shirt?
And you have all women presenters.
You know, I don't have a, I don't
have a degree in fighting crime,
whatever that degree is.
Uh,
but I don't think same colored
shirts is going to do it.
We have to stop Isis. Okay. Everybody
wear blue shirts on Tuesday.
Okay.
He's not wearing a blue shirt.
Does that mean he's in Isis?
MMM,
it does not. What it is,
Bill, it says it's symbolism.
It's a sign of strength though. Jesus.
All right. Maybe that is what it is.
I have no fucking idea. Um, this,
this why, this is why I watch sports.
I watch fucking sports. So once
again, the New England patriots,
they're in their 10th fucking super bowl.
They have a chance to
win this six Superbowl.
Literally what
Tom Brady Belicheck and these guys are
doing as much as you guys fucking hate
him.
Every fucking time we win a game,
the sub giant Goddamn conspiracy
because nobody will give it up.
That there are fucking great team.
Uh,
what they've done at this point has
transcended the game of football.
All right? You gotta put them
up there with like the fucking,
I would say the Yankees from Dimaggio to,
uh,
Mickey Mantle that run there with the
amount of world series that they went to,
the amount that they want.
MMM.
The Canadians back in the day,
the Celtics in the 60s. I mean,
that's literally what you're watching.
And for them to be doing it now,
you know the reason why that never happens
anymore because now there's like 30
fucking teams and every,
basically every sport.
It's just too, it's too difficult
to do and somehow they are doing it.
So as much as you hate him,
can you at least give it up on
that or are you just going to say,
I don't know if we're going to start
weighing football's again and fucking,
I dunno. I Dunno. Um, all right.
Speaking of the Canadian say,
how are you guys doing up there?
Montreal. Okay. How are you?
Watch any Bruins Canadians Games lately.
We fucking,
we beat them three times
in the last eight days.
And the only reason why I know that
is cause Joe Barton from the, uh,
the great puck off podcast told
me I've been so goddamn busy. Uh,
I only watched the first
period of one of the Games.
I've missed so much Bruins hockey,
this and I know they're playing great
and they're on this amazing streak and a
pretty excited that they'd beat the
Canadians three times in the last eight
games.
I know I had all the games taped so I'm
gonna I'm going to have to watch them in
like one period segments now cause uh,
cause I got the Kiddo at home.
But uh, having said that, everybody knows
the regular season doesn't mean shit.
Um,
you know,
and Regulus I'm telling you,
regular season stats,
just go back to somebody's schedule and
look at what they did against playoff
teams.
And even then,
I think in football it gives you a
little bit more of a gauge. But like, uh,
in basketball,
baseball and hockey,
I don't think it means shit
because on any given night,
any they play so many games,
any team can beat another team.
But a wedding in the playoffs and
winning four out of seven is it's a whole
different ballgame. So, um, I just wish
more announcers would do that shit.
You know what I mean? Look at the
division, like even look like,
look at the Patriots for how many years
we've gotten all these double digit wins.
The fucking AFC east has been so goddamn
weeks, so many years, so many years.
Like the jets,
who by the way beat the Jag was in the
regular season that jet's fucking suck.
The dolphins have socked in. The
bills have such, so many of those.
You escaped Gibson, you
know, or at least mediocre.
And that has given us five to
six wins every fucking year.
MMM.
Anyway, all right. I'm done. I'm done
with, I'm done with the Goddamn sports.
Let's talk about, uh, it
was my dogs and my daughter.
It was my daughter's first birthday.
This, uh, this past weekend.
I can't believe it. She's already won.
She's no longer a baby. She's a toddler,
which is pretty amazing. And I gotta
be honest with you, it's a little sad,
you know what I mean? She's now motoring
around the house and uh, I dunno,
it's already going by way
too fast. And uh, so anyways,
it was her birthday, right?
So I decided that, you know,
every year for her birthday is a dad.
I'm going to make her a homemade cake.
And I did it. And uh, we had like the, uh,
invited all of these people. Like
it's weird, like all of our friends,
a bunch of our friends I should say,
um, had kids in like the last year,
I'd like the last three years.
So we had 16 little kids over here plus
their parents and a few of them brought
friends. Like we had like a, a,
yeah,
we had, we had a house party, but
it was just kids. It was awesome.
The kids were, uh, it was, it was amazing,
man. It just blew my mind
cause I was sitting out,
there was like 30 people
in my house at least.
And I remember standing
there thinking like, wow,
like literally like a year and a half ago,
this would have been a bunch of guys
sitting here smoking cigars on the back
porch,
drinking booze.
And now I've got all these kids
running around all of this stuff.
And I gotta tell you after
watching all the kids,
I'm kind of psyched I had a daughter,
two little girls, they're made, they're
like little adults. They just stay,
sit there if they're emotionally stable,
the little boys that they're,
they're fucking lunatics.
They're running all over the
place. That club, I got this,
this fountain out in my front yard
and I know that sounds wild bill. Wow.
You got a fountain in your front yard.
You know what I would say about our
farm to go back and watch that, uh,
Fred Armisen sketch on SNL
when he does that thing.
Marble columns when they would,
talking about putting marble columns
on the front of Split entry houses.
I hate this fucking fountain.
I've never liked it.
It's just a giant, it's,
it's like a fucking,
it's just a giant place for mosquitoes
to Fuckin and give us West Nile virus.
You know what I mean?
But they give you though,
then you got to buy these little fucking
donuts of poison that you throw in
there. And then a bird comes by and
drinks out of it and then the bird dies.
So I never have any water in there.
So these boys run out there that
climbing up on the fucking thing.
I'm having a panic attack that
one of them's gonna fall down.
You get them off of that,
then they're throwing rocks down
to the driveway hitting the cars.
I couldn't get, I, you know, a
little kid so I didn't get upset,
but I was just like, wow man, this is, uh,
having a girl is a lot easy
on the parenting thing.
I mean, they sit down, they're like
chill. They're thinking, you know,
the boys are just like hilarious.
I don't know if you turn your back,
one of them's going to be,
I get an idea.
What if I jumped through
the screen door? So, um,
I dunno. Made me feel lucky again.
So everybody gathers around, um,
to sing happy birthday.
And I got this cake that made and uh,
I've never made a cake before and
I didn't, I didn't try it out.
I didn't want to test a slice now of a
giant slice taken out. So I was basically,
uh,
going to have 30 people all taste the
cake in front of me and I was waiting for
this tastes like shit, the cake's
too dry or whatever. But uh,
fortunately everybody seemed
to like the cake and um,
after that, the whole Party was downhill.
That was, that was like the big thing.
I was just like,
I just have to get pat.
I got to get on the other
side of the cake here.
People eat the cake and they
actually like it. God knows.
If my wife didn't like it, she would've
let me know, you know? Well, in fact,
she did try the frosting the night before
and she let me know that she thought
it could have been a little more shocked.
It just tastes sweet.
I just wish there was more cocoa in it.
You know what I mean?
And I just went like, yeah. And then
had like a full on fucking panic attack,
you know?
It's like, why would you tell me that she,
you know, I'm stressing about this shit.
I don't know. That's what they do.
That's what they do. What, what, what,
what would they be doing if they
weren't fucking criticizing us?
Okay.
Why can't there be an award show
about that? Where they protest,
the lack of complements a man gets
the second he marries a woman.
I don't give a shit if my wife cooked
a shoe. How does it taste bill? Oh,
it's delicious though.
Can I have more than the laces?
It's almost like pasta except
their shoe laces, you know,
put on a fucking brave face.
Too many times I've made something.
Yeah,
okay. I've made my wife dinner and she's
been the first bite she bites into.
She goes,
[inaudible] [inaudible], [inaudible]
[inaudible] and then she runs over and
grabs some salt or something like that.
Or just like if I ever fucking,
a few times I've ever done that,
I did it for, I think for the first
time since I can ever remember.
I did it this year and it
was just one of those nights,
it was late night and she was tired
and she just went to the fridge and she
usually can look in there
and figure something out.
And this time she just didn't throw
it together and it wasn't good.
And she was like, how was
it? I didn't say anything.
I just kind of gave her a look like you.
And then she immediately,
she was just like,
yeah,
you think it's bad.
And then immediately it would
be like, no, no, no, no. It's
good. It's good. It's just,
you know, you've made better,
you know, and they need just
fallen down the fucking whole. You're
like, why did I, why was I honest?
She does it to me all the fucking time.
Okay.
I thought this was a little dry at that.
[inaudible] it's like a fuck.
I feel like I'm on the,
uh,
the iron chef whenever I put
something on the fucking table.
Yeah.
I mean, I'm literally talking
like oatmeal, like if I
put too much milk in there,
she'd be like, it's too soupy, it's
too soupy, and I want to be like,
you know what? If it wasn't as hot as it
was, what bill was that as hot as it is?
I would literally dump that over your
fucking head. All right. What do you,
what do you like a food critic?
This is actually making me
upset kind of a fucking person.
Another person makes them a meal
and all you do is criticize it.
How about you at least go,
hey,
I really appreciated that you took
the time out to make me a meal.
That's one of the most kindest,
loving things at one human being could
do for another meeting by a human being.
Having said that,
I like a little bit less milk.
There's no way to criticize it
without coming off like a jerk.
I'm just in the future just to let
you know, I like a little less milk,
by the way, making a homemade cake
not that hard. It's not that hard.
Don't be intimidated. It's easy
up making a pie. The Pie crust,
that's a fucking art. Making a
cake, not that fucking hard. Um,
I made a three layered cake and
what's going to happen is, um,
each layer is going to be a
little fucking little. Uh,
I know I was really hard
to try and make them level.
I don't know how to do that yet.
I'm sure there's something
I can watch them on youtube.
But when you go to make it, if you
know each layer cake, you know,
if one's leaning to the left,
the others lean to the right,
you just spin them around,
you put it together like Legos and know
that you're going to have frosting in
the middle. We can kind of level it
out and no one's gonna. Notice my, my,
my kid had a little lean
to it. Nothing crazy. Um,
probably the hardest thing
is frosting the cake. Um,
I started to watch videos on that,
but it was just, I was just too full.
I don't know.
It's just too fucking boring.
And there was all this playoff football
on. I wanted to watch that. So, um,
I probably could've done a better job at
that. I don't know. I'll ask my wife, God,
no, she'll fucking tell me. Right.
But enough with me complaining about her
complaining. Right. I sh I should be,
I should be secure enough
in my own baking skills.
Um,
[inaudible] [inaudible] [inaudible]
no, no. You did this one wrong.
You know, I was trying to,
cause I never a lot of shit to
talk about, uh, this week. Um,
other than,
than just being completely blown away
that my daughter's already a year old.
I can't believe it. And uh,
I got her up this morning,
you know, and I just couldn't
believe how big she wasn't.
It was already thinking like
she used to be able to fit,
like her head would go from my elbow,
not even to the tips of my fingers.
Like I could just hold it just like that.
Yeah.
Now she just, she's,
she's huge. What happened?
You know,
there's nothing I can now see why people
have a bunch of kids cause you keep to
hit reset.
There's nothing better than having a baby
around your house. It's the greatest.
It's like a puppy times a million.
Um,
but what is cool, she started to
talk, so I'm waiting for these,
uh, the conversation cause some of
the kids, my God, they were hilarious.
Um, there was this little boy,
right? And he was talking to this,
they wanted to see like outside my house,
like along the side. So I go, all right,
I'll take you over there.
Just be careful cause you know,
there's all these concrete steps and shit.
I don't want somebody's fallen down.
So, uh, he points to the side of
the house. He goes, what's this?
And uh, I go, oh, that's the back of the
chimney. It was a little kid. He goes,
what's that? And then the little
girl answers and she goes,
that's where Santa Claus comes down and
the smoke goes up when you have a fire.
Then I think the little kid like the girl,
and he goes, uh, he says to me, he goes,
does she live here? And I started
the answer, the girl wants again,
answered the question.
She goes, no. She goes,
I live out in the desert and
the boy goes in the sand.
She goes,
now what the heck?
Kid was bombing. I was pulling for
him. I was like, yeah, you know,
say something funny, make
a left. Um, whatever.
I just liked that he was working on
his game at like four years of age.
Um,
which reminded me when I was a little kid,
I liked this girl who
lived in my neighborhood.
So I just went over a house,
not even invited.
I just went over her house, knocked on
the door, take your name was Michelle.
I knocked on the door and a moments. I
was like, yeah, hey, it's Michelle ohm.
She goes, yeah, she's sitting
there watching TV. And I go, okay.
So I went in there and I sat
down and watched TV with the,
her, her mother, and I
think her younger sibling.
And I never said a word for like an hour.
I just sat there watching
t cause I didn't know,
I didn't know what to do.
And then I just got up and left.
I always wondered what
that woman was thinking.
Like this little red headed boy came over
to visit my, our, our daughter today.
Honey. He came, he didn't
say a word and then he left.
It's an odd little fellow.
Um, anyways. All right,
let me read a little bit of advertising
here for this week. All right.
Dollar Shave club doe.
I remember those.
Another girl I had a crush on,
there was these two twins when I was in
first grade and I had a crush on one of
them. And uh, the other
one had this giant pen,
which I thought was the coolest
thing ever. Even though it was pink,
it was just a giant pen,
which was amazing in the early seventies,
like were, there was no fucking
computers and shit. I guess they were,
but computers were gigantic.
So she dropped it on the floor and she
didn't realize it and I took it and then
I started writing with, it was funny
was the way they had the desk set up.
They had like us in like little groups
of four and we faced each other and she
was diagonal to me.
And I'm writing with this giant pink pen.
And she's going,
that's my pen.
And I was like, no, it isn't.
It's mind. So she's like an idiot.
Then she tells the teacher
and then she's going, Billy, is
that your pen? And I was like, yes.
And then the girls go, no, it was my pet.
Uh, I was going, no it isn't. It's my pen.
And then she did teach.
She's just like,
I don't think your mom
would buy you a pink pen.
And she took it and gave it back to the
girl. And you know, as a little kid,
like the embarrassment of that goes away.
Like eight seconds later,
you can't even remember. Like, you know,
you don't have like the
mental capacity to be like,
did I just really try to pull that off?
You know,
why the fuck would I do that? Right.
So then I remember I went out,
asked and I had to go to the bathroom.
So I went out to the bathroom and her twin
sister, the one I had the crush on, oh,
this is like the next day I went out to
go to the bathroom and her twin sister.
Yeah.
Who I had a crush on
k walking out at the same time.
And to me when she saw me, she really
put her eyebrows down. She goes,
I heard what you did, I heard you
tried to steal my sister's pen.
And I just looked at, I think I said,
no I didn't and I just walked away.
And that was the end of that romance.
Um Oh there's a lot of sad stories. All
right. Dollar Shave club, everybody.
Everyone knows. Dollar Shave club
ships. Amazing raises for a few bucks.
What you might not know is that dollar
shave club also has products for pretty
much everything else you need
in the bathroom. By the way.
I was in first grade when that happened.
I should think I'm some Weirdo and like
the fifth grade stealing pink pens.
All right. Body Wash, shampoo, Hair Gel,
lip balm, everything for a limited time.
Dollar Shave Club is basically
giving away their shit.
Shower shave status set to
new members for only $5.
This started set features,
their executive razor and three trial
size versions of their most popular
products that help you stay
fresh. So fresh and so clean. Uh,
in your first box,
you will receive their shave butter,
bodywash and one wipe challis but wipes,
um,
you will also receive their executive
razor, which includes their premium,
weighty handle and full
cassette of cartridges.
After the first box for placement
cartridges are sent for only a few bucks a
month.
This offers excuse exclusively
available@dollarshaveclub.com slash burr.
That's dollar shave club.com/burr dollar
shave club's high quality products.
We'll have you covered from
face cheeks to butt cheeks.
There is no better time to try the club.
You know what's funny?
The only time I notice I
have my Invisalign in at
this point is when I go to
read this copy.
Okay?
I already suck at reading out loud,
but I become this mush mouth jackass.
By the way, I'm on train
number seven of 16. Wednesday.
I go to trade number eight and I'll be
fucking halfway done all week from now.
Be Halfway done.
Um,
and I gotta tell you I'm
happy that I'm doing it.
They're happy that I'm doing it,
you know,
then all I gotta do for the
rest of my life is at night.
You throw in a little fucking mouth
guard to keep the teeth where they are,
where they are. And I'll have, I'll have
these love, nice teeth like fair faucet,
you know, I'll fucking white. You know, my
skin just gets older and older, you know,
people keep that teeth looking nice and
young so it looks like led lights coming
out of the year. Old fucking
pruned up face. All right.
Movement watches everybody.
Mvmt
uh,
and it's that time of
year when you could say,
I'd like a nice watch for no money.
All right?
And it's that time of year again.
Uh,
you thought gift giving was
all over after Christmas,
but Valentine's Day is coming
up and you know what that means?
That means that guy has to spend
money and the woman does not,
even though it's bolted your
relationships, right? It's
both of your relationship,
I should say. I mean, if we really
want to have everything equal,
how about every other year
the lady pays for it, right?
Takes you out for a steak dinner.
Okay?
Blows you in the back of the Uber on the
way home. Just, you know, make an effort.
Ladies. Just make an effort. But
Valentine's Day is coming up so you know,
you must find the perfect gift.
Okay?
You know what I love about the fact that
I'm already married is I don't have to
deal with the pressure, this fucking
horse shit anymore. You know what I mean?
That whole, where is this
relationship going? Oh Shit.
Shut the fuck up.
Talk about how you may have procrastinated
in the past or your own experience
with how hard finding the perfect
Valentine's Day gift can be.
Well, you know who the fuck
knows what a woman wants, right?
Jesus Christ that changed every five
seconds and God knows it's gonna be
expensive.
What if you don't have a lot of money
and the woman you with you just sort of
banging, then you're not sure
if you're going to marry her,
but you got to get her some nice so
she'll keep touching it right when it'd be
nice to be goodbye or nice watch,
but not break the bank.
Our friends at movement watches the ones
who reveleigh revolutionize the watch
game have put together the perfect
gift guide to make your life easy.
Whether you're shopping for him or her.
Yeah.
Like what women,
all they're worried about is what the
fuck they're wearing on this side.
You know, I really don't like this holiday
by the way. Don't go out on the 14th.
Go out on the 15th when prices come
back to what they should be. Uh,
whether you're shopping for
him or her, uh, want watches,
uh,
or their new fashion forward bracelets,
sunglasses or any combination in
their limited edition gift box,
MVMT movement,
watch movements in house stylists have
curated the most overly used fucking word
ever curated there trendiest
pieces for gift ideas.
Your special, someone will
love. Talk about how you expect.
Now what do I have to talk about?
Talk about how you experienced shopping
the site, looking for gifts for others,
movement new watch styles for
her sunglasses and bracelet.
I haven't gone to the website.
All right, I'm married, okay.
Which means I have to go for
something more than this high,
more high end than move
and fucking watches.
I wish movement watches was
around when I was single bic,
all would I be for their
fucker website right now.
A movement and their stylists
have curated, once again,
they used the word again and interactive
gift guide to make Valentine's shopping
painless.
Well,
someone should have vetted this copy to
make sure he didn't use that word twice.
You can find the perfect
gift for him or her watches,
bracelets and sunglasses
or any combination of these
gifts in a limited edition
gift box.
Get 15% off today with free shipping and
free returns by going to move and watch
this.com/bar go to
movement.com/burr joined the movement.
You know what's amazing by the way,
is evidently the government shutdown and
everything's still seems to be working.
Uh, legal zoom. Now that the
new year's madness is over,
it's time to work on your story
for 2018 work on your story.
Okay? Legal Zoom can help
you make this year, this,
the year you finally get serious about
launching and running your own business.
They can also help you rest
a little easier knowing
that your family's future is
squared away with the right,
the rightest state plan. I
finally did this shit, by the way.
I finally did this, so my family's
okay. They're going to be,
they're going to be okay. You got to do
it. You got to fucking do it. All right?
As a matter of fact,
legal zoom has been helping people just
like you take care of their dreams and
responsibilities for more than 16 years.
Legal Zoom is not a law firm,
but they had the resources and ladies,
don't be afraid to do this yourself too.
You know what I mean? It'd be nice
if when you guys kicked the bucket,
we've got a little doe,
Ray mate,
legal zoom is not a law firm and they had
the resources to keep you on the right
path,
including advice from their nationwide
network of independent attorneys all at
your fingertips.
Whether you want to take your business
to the next level or take control of your
family's future with an estate plan plan,
legal zoom plugs right into your life
without billing you by the hour because
legal zoom, legal zoom, all
pricing is given up front.
Start writing your 2018
story@legalzoom.now and
for a special savings.
Be sure to enter the Promo code borough
in the referral box at checkout legal
zoom where life meets legal.
That's legal zoom.com and finally,
lastly, but not leastly stamps.com
here's a new year's resolution.
You can actually keep add stamps.com your
business and save a shit ton of money
this year. Almost everything
you can do at the post office,
you could do right from your desk other
than expose yourself in public because
you won't be in public.
He'll be in the privacy around home.
So have you junk out while you do this.
Plus stamps.com is posts. It just counts.
You can get,
you can't get it to post office.
Not to mention it's a fraction of the
cost of those super expensive postage
meter is stamps.com send you a digital
scale that automatically calculates the
exact posts you will never overpay
or underpay for poachers. Again,
you got the hiccups here.
Create your stamps.com account in minutes
online with no equipment to lease and
no longterm commitments.
Key word descriptors. Oh,
this is stamps.com it's convenient.
It's easy, it's reliable and efficient.
I use stamps.com anytime I
send my posters, you know,
if I'm going to sell me posters up, you
know, at the end of the end of the, uh,
my shows, what am I trying
to, when a whore myself out,
I'm going to sell posters
at the end of the show.
I use stamps.com to get them there and
I'm a moron. So if I can figure it out,
so can you do not be intimidated
by this technology? And right now,
you too can enjoy the stamps.com service
with the special offer that includes a
four week trial plus postage and a digital
scale. Ready for a happier new year.
Go to stamps.com click on the microphone
at the top of the homepage and type in
Burger. That's stamps.com
enter bar, but a,
but a book is a story of a bald
headed freckled count. All right?
Okay.
All right. Let's read some questions here
for the week and let's get going. Billy,
you stupid La Cunt. All right, here we go.
You never mentioned why
exactly you move to La.
I didn't know I was required to.
Why did you move to la?
I just listened to you and
Jim Floren cunt. Slash.
Florentine. He said, uh,
and Florentine said he
didn't see a difference with
comedians in New York City.
I find it hard to imagine that La,
Oh God,
this guy, I find it hard to amount. I'm
just going to read exactly what I wrote.
I find it hard to imagine that La,
there are a lot less cons in the
audience that get offended too easily.
Uh,
you then agreed with Jim that maybe it's
because you now live there and are used
to it. But the way you said
it didn't seem believable.
So what's the deal?
All right.
Like
there wasn't one capital letter,
no punctuation whatsoever.
A couple of periods maybe.
Um,
I'm not required to tell you
why I fucking moved here,
but I will to eat up some time.
Um,
yeah,
I was living in New York, I was
just sick of being there. It just,
it just gets a point where you know, you
get to be told too old and you're like,
I can't live like an animal anymore,
which means you're either going to
move outside the city or in my business
you're going to go to la.
And I had nothing going on in my
career other than the OPN Anthony show.
But the writing was on the wall
with that show where, you know,
those guys, like they had a bunch
of comics on and I was one of them.
Jim Norton got us all in and you know,
there was no money in
the budget to pay us.
But the way that they paid
us opie and Anthony Show,
because they assaulted the fucking earth,
they used to run
advertisements of our gigs.
And um, Dan, our gigs would
sell out and it was great.
But then the corporate cons there
said that they couldn't do it anymore,
you know, so then he kind
of had the hype, you,
your show during the show, which
would get in the way of, you know,
whatever craziness was going on.
So that's kind of where my career was at.
I was on a radio show and
I wasn't getting paid.
I wasn't getting any acting work.
And the only way I was
getting paid on the OPN,
Anthony showed they no longer let them do
for whatever reason,
which is really short sighted
on Sirius XMS side because
opie and Anthony were this
launching pad for standup
careers. And they will make in like they,
they made us become like these draws.
MMM.
And then that would then feed back into
the show because then these people were
selling all these tickets were like,
hey, I'm going to be an EOP anti show.
So if you know, you know what way,
what is it? Totally fucking worked.
It was the perfect fucking
relationship for about three years.
And then like what always happens is
the money people come in and they fucked
the whole thing up.
So I mean that's not the
only reason I was, I was,
uh, leaving, but that's basically,
that was as it's high
up as I got in New York.
I was on a radio show not getting paid.
That's it.
That's the best I could do. I had
already done an episode of law and order,
so,
you know,
and I couldn't get on the soprano's
cause that was a bunch of Italians and I
look like fucking idea Billy
red face over here. So, uh, the,
there was like no opportunity left for me.
And I was going down to the comedy
cellar like every single night and it was
like, it was like groundhog
day and I just, uh, you know,
and I went out to la and I hated La
and I just came out here. I started,
each time I went out,
I was starting to like it and I
was fighting that feeling and uh,
I dunno, I just said, fuck it.
One day it's like, you know what,
I wouldn't mind living in an apartment,
paying a ton of money,
but I could actually have like
a couch that also wasn't my bed.
I wouldn't mind having a car.
Then I moved out here.
I had this apartment,
it was still a one bedroom,
but I had front and backstairs the
backstairs I did share with my neighbor,
but still,
that was amazing to me.
And I had a garage where I could park
my car and even though the traffic was
fucking horrific,
just the fact that I could live a
little more like a human being again.
Um,
okay.
Was appealing.
And then there was a ton of acting work
out here that I could potentially get.
Then I moved out here and
within the first year, um,
okay.
I got on breaking bad.
So that's why I came out here.
But I do have to tell you that the,
that I thought when it came out here
that the comedy scene was horrific.
So what I was trying to say on the
podcast is when I go back to the New York
now, it's just like, it's just,
I think it's just changed,
but because I'm not there every day,
I noticed the change.
Um, and out here last night, you know,
I was telling a couple of
jokes and there was silence.
So maybe that's what it was. I
don't know why you took it. So, uh,
so personally,
but that is a big fucking thing.
The whole east coast west
coast thing, um, I do, however,
I'm one of those weird people that
I do love both coasts, but, uh,
you know, I dunno, I'm
kind of out here right now.
I used to think like I'll always
move back when now I don't,
I don't know that I will. Who knows?
I don't fucking know. I have no idea.
I was kinda thinking about global warming.
Eventually I was going to,
I was going to have to move back there,
but now it seems like it's
going to be all crazy weathers.
So the fact that it was hot out here
now it's going to be extremely hot.
And the fact that it was cold back there,
now it's going to be extremely
fucking cold. And uh, I dunno,
I did like 40 something winners back east.
Okay.
I put my time and,
all right.
I'd rather shove a lot of
a mud slide in this snuff.
So there you go. Alright. Alright,
Bill. My problems with women,
this is funny. He wrote my problems
with woman. Oh my problems with woman.
Yeah,
dear bill's very dull boy. Oh,
I love that one. All right.
I'm a huge fan from,
yeah,
I don't even know how to say this.
Yeah.
F E R m a n a g h
Furman na Nog. I don't
know, Ireland, Ireland.
I'm years old and I've
always been a fat cunt.
Well, that's good, man. You're,
you're looking at yourself
on asleep. Now let's, what,
what can we do about this?
Recently,
I lost the weight and started getting
into the gym. They, you go, I'm now six,
one and 200 pounds.
So naturally have started getting
more female attention. All right,
this is all good.
I was never been,
I was never been successful with women,
but now I'm turning this franchise
around. They, you'd go, well, dude,
you're only 17. Give you just
getting out of the gate here.
My only problem is I'm a quiet guy
and don't know how to talk to them.
They seem to just want to talk about
bullshit or gossip and meaningless crap.
Oh God, dude, you can't
be this cynical at 17.
The sound like me right now
and I'm going to be 50. Um,
I try and be funny and make them laugh,
which can only get me so far.
I can't maintain a relationship because
they open their mouths and I contemplate
suicide. Jesus, he sounded like a writer.
You creative or something
or you think too much?
Uh, I consider myself as
straightforward, no bs kind of guy,
but I'm just a wanker. Uh, is
this a problem with me or them?
I don't hate women. I just don't
get along with them. If possible.
I would love to hear what Nia has to say.
Oh,
she wouldn't like how you worded
all of this. Uh, thanks bill.
And Go fuck yourself. Ps, if
you're getting into soccer,
I suggest you support either Tottenham
or Liverpool is they have young,
exciting teams and aren't
soulless corporate entities
like Chelsea, man city. Oh,
I didn't know that.
All right.
I'll support Liverpool then. That's
where the Beatles and from, right.
I don't fucking know why. Anyways. Um,
all right. What's your problem?
Uh, I don't know. I think
you're a little defensive.
I think you're a little insecure,
so you're kind of projecting on them.
I know that that's what I did.
Uh,
so I would say open yourself
up a little bit more and uh,
you know, realize how amazing they
are. But women are just like men.
The good one is hard to find.
Good woman, hard to find.
So, um, you're only 17 too.
And I think also trying to make them
laugh is always a good thing. And, uh,
what I've learned is a lot of times
they just want you to listen and, uh,
they don't want you to try to
solve their problems. So just,
you know, when they tell a story,
hold both their hands and be like,
oh my God, uh, I dunno.
Why would you ask me? Like, I know
anything about women? Jesus Christ,
they fucking hate me.
My fan base is a fucking sausage fest.
Um, I gotta give you more
advice than that. Uh,
yeah, dude, you, you see, this is a
weakness of mine, understanding women.
I have no idea.
You just basically a,
I dunno, it's like right in Charlie
Manson being like, hey, how do I, uh,
get along with people a little
more, a little more better? Um,
just probably better example, right?
Did he just die? What a fucking lifer.
What a fucking life.
I just can't imagine spending
that much time in jail.
Like he never getting out again.
You're in your thirties.
You're never getting out again. Okay.
You're not just sitting there like,
really?
Yeah.
You gotta be fucking kidding me.
Um,
fascinating guy and in all the wrong
reasons you like, you've really like,
I literally never come in as far as
we know. Never committed a murder,
but with such a fucking lunatic.
I remember seeing a horror movie.
We're all a guy to do was just whisper
in somebody's ear or something like that
and then they just fucking would
just do whatever the guy said.
Just had that like literally the
fucking devil he spent his whole life,
you know, just imagine
if he ever, you know,
he got Micky Dolenz as
part of the monkeys.
It's unreal.
Somebody like Hitler's drawings.
Yeah.
So you have to encourage
people. Alright. Westerns.
Everybody a dear Billy Sundance.
Billy the Sundance. Okay.
I've been just getting into Western.
I wasn't a huge fan as a kid.
I was more into space and
futuristic stuff. But as a,
around my mid twenties and then
living more of a loner life,
I'm starting to connect more.
I'm really looking forward to
the new Christian Bale movie.
Hostiles Oh,
I can't wait to see that.
I hope I said that correctly
because I loved three 10 to Yuma.
I loved the original to my other
favorites are tombstone and butch Cassidy.
I was hoping to hear which one your
favorites are and get some recommendations
to watch while I'm snowed
in for the next four days.
All the best to you and your family.
I would say a the Clint Eastwood's,
the Spaghetti Westerns fistful of
dollars, the good, the bad and the ugly.
Um, they had like a trilogy of those, um,
the outlaw Josey Wales, you
know, I hate to say this,
but I've never seen the unforgiven that
was right when I started doing stand up
and I just started missing out
on shit. Um, I liked those.
The wild bunch.
MMM.
Let's see, uh, the magnificent seven,
the original Westworld.
There's one that combines futurist future,
a rustic shit there. Um,
Psi Phi and Westerns.
Yule Brenner was incredible
in that you'll Brendan,
one of my favorites of all time.
Not because he's bald like me,
but I just thought it was a shit.
Um,
I never saw butch Cassidy
and the Sundance kid.
Yeah, I think that I would say that,
that that was all of them. I never,
never quite into the John Wayne ones.
Those ones were too far back in the day.
I like the ones from like the 60s. I liked
those and I liked all the war movies.
Kelly's heroes, dirty dozen bridge
over the river. Kwai Oh, that Shit.
Um, so those are my recommendations. I
would go with the Clint Eastwood, uh,
Spaghetti Westerns. Alright. My
life's flopped. My fucked life.
Sorry. My fucked life to
sounds like a Sitcom, right?
Oh fuck. The battery to the battery.
Just die. All the battery's gonna die.
Oh fuck. I gotta wrap this up.
All right, my fuck life. Hey,
if I don't get through all this, thank
you to everybody for listening. And uh,
once again,
congratulations to the Patriots and
the Eagles and congratulations to the
Jaguars and the vikings on
two great seasons. All right.
For grade seasons there,
right my fuck life.
Dear bill and Nia,
I'm 17 and still in high
school. I'm a bit of a, I mean,
a bit of a pickle. A, what the fuck is
war on with this thing? It keeps beeping.
I think I'm falling from my best friend.
I realized after we were
falling asleep at her house,
she had just taken off from makeup and
made a joke like, sorry, I look so bad.
But when I looked at her,
I thought she looked so beautiful
and cute and her sweatshirt,
that was just a little too big for her.
What does his flashdance however,
she's currently dating a cunt. Well,
what the fuck are you doing over at house?
All right, I'm back. I guess my,
my recorder was almost filled up.
Sorry about that sound. We had to fucking
attitude things together as always,
as always making my life
difficult. Um, anyways. Yeah.
So what are you doing over
at this person's house?
She's dating somebody else.
Anyway, she goes, he's a loser.
No Job's still gets an allowance and
expensive car that his mommy bought him.
Sits at home all day playing video games,
getting stoned and treats people like
he's above them. She knows I hate him.
And I openly mock him, um,
in front of our friends,
her and even him,
uh,
like he got are this really generic but
expensive looking hard shape necklace.
Um, when she showed it to everyone,
I looked at him and said loudly, wow,
must've cost your mom quite
a big whatever that means.
As you can imagine, he tries to avoid me.
Yeah, well you're being a fucking cunt.
Uh, we share the same friends
and they hate him and like me,
but mind you, I'm no prize
either. I'm trying to get a job.
Unlike him out Jesus,
you don't even have a fucking job.
And then saving up for a car.
So our choices are two guys who don't
have a job and she has a rich mom.
Well there you go. I tend
to be nice, a nice guy,
but can at times, cause people are put
my jokes and even be a deck with my joke.
She sounded like you're being a dick.
I'm not saying you are,
but you're being a dick to this guy.
He's at least three inches taller than me.
Enhanced. Some are
better looking, I guess.
He's got this great smile that
makes me want to fuck him up for,
well that makes me want
to fuck it up for him.
But recently I've started to turn my
life around, quit bare porn and drugs.
My grades are going up, applying
for college, working out a lot,
but all this in hopes of catching her eye.
Like I said,
she's my best friend and as a boyfriend,
so I really don't know how to handle this.
Any help from you and Neil would be
greatly appreciated. Ah, yeah dude. Um,
I would start fishing in
a different watering hole.
All right.
You know,
for you to sit there and stand there
and be a cunt to her boyfriend talking
about a boyfriend and you go on
over that for over a fucking house.
MMM.
It sounds to me like you're the,
you're like Chris Rock says you're
in the friend zone. So what you need,
what you need is you need some
time away from her. All right?
Move on with your fucking life. Keep
working out. Get you shit going.
And who knows?
You might just meet somebody else.
And then eventually when
she dumps his losers,
she comes around and sees you
should be, oh my God, look at you.
You're going to college. You look,
Greg, you've been working out, you know,
watch porn. Who knows? Maybe it'll happen,
but I could tell you it's
definitely not going to happen.
If you could just going to be your friend,
they making snide remarks about
her, her boyfriend. Come on.
Do you gotta be better than that?
That's just coming off like a, you know,
you're acting like a fucking,
you're acting like a Douche.
D and I don't know how else to put
it. Um, that's not a strong move.
All right?
Um,
then you should have more going on in
your life then the fucker be, you know,
you still have more self esteem
than that. All right? Okay.
She wants to date this fucking guy.
Guess what? It's her loss. All right?
So fuck it. Get on with your life. Keep
working out and work out for yourself.
Go to college for yourself.
Do all this shit for yourself.
Feel good about yourself.
You start putting out more of a positive
vibe and it's supposed to, you know,
hanging around her shitting on her current
boyfriend. I mean that's just like,
I don't know if that's not a good
look. Okay. I in you all right.
Do what I just said Dope. Cause I
don't have any professional training.
All right. Dumping my girlfriend
a Billy billboard brow.
I fucking asshole. That's
another good one. Recent fatty,
a podcast stand up and all that jazz.
Anyways,
I'm a 24 year old dude and I've been
dating and living with my girl for almost
four years now and I finally had enough.
She's a real Downer and talk shit
about people including a friend's,
like it's an Olympic sport now.
The problem is she lost a job a month
ago on account of a shit-talking.
It hasn't exactly been going
out and looking for a new
one because she's anxious
or whatever. Leaving me to
pick up her end of the bills.
She didn't have any savings because she
had picked up the habit of going out and
drinking every night. I honestly
wouldn't have a problem, uh,
just up and leaving.
But the apartment is a stone's throw from
the beach and my other roommate and I
really don't want to leave
the fucking decisions people
make right near the beach.
The other roommate is my best friend.
Okay.
She's got a lot of books and
shit and the bed is hers.
So when be a little,
so would be a little difficult to do.
The old put all this stuff in a box trick,
a deep down.
I do still have loved for her.
So the idea of kicking
her out hurts my heart,
but I just can't deal with the
endless drama and unhappiness.
We'd love to hear what your advice
on the podcast and as always go fuck
yourself.
Yeah.
The more the relationship has run its
course and you need to go your separate
ways. And sometimes when that happens, you
know somebody, yeah, somebody gets hurt.
All right?
But you're not doing her any favors if
you don't want or to be with you and you
just, you just wasting
her and your time. So,
uh,
yeah.
You know,
this is why you don't fucking live with
somebody unless you know you're going to
marry him. I don't, I don't
know. I don't know if, yeah, boy.
Um,
so what do you do?
Break up with her and then tell her
to move out all at the same time?
Or are those two separate conversations?
I just break up with her
and then let her bring up
where am I going to live?
Yeah.
Then I'd be like, well, I don't know.
I mean the coastline is pretty long,
so I'm sure there's another
beachfront apartment she could be.
And I'm assuming your name's on the lease.
Usually when there's a breakup,
the guy has to leave
and leave half his shit.
So it seems like you're in
a decent position here. Uh,
who wants a negative drunk without a job?
I don't think you want,
that doesn't sound like you want it.
Um,
and I think the love you have for her
was who she used to be or who you thought
she was. So neither. Yeah.
Those are happening right now.
So it's time for you to tell her to hit
the bricks. Happy new year, sweetheart.
Beat it.
You can't say it like that.
I just tell her, look, we need to
talk and sit down. She could deal.
What's the problem?
Me and you just to fight through
that fucking horrible feeling.
There's nothing worse.
The only worse than a woman crying is
when she's about to cry because you still
have hope that she's not going to cry.
So you're on pins and needles.
Once she's crying, you're
like, fuck, this sucks.
But you kind of know what's
going to happen. Um, yeah.
You just got to sit down and just
say, listen, um, I'm not happy.
This isn't working for me anymore and
we need to break up. All
right? Just like that. Boom,
boom, boom. And you got to get that
out. You got to get all of that out.
Don't sit there and be like, oh,
I don't know how to say this.
A Dah, Dah, Dah, Dah, Dah, Dah,
and turn it into a 45 minute thing.
Rip The bandaid odd. Just rip it
off. We need to talk. I'm not happy.
We need to break up.
Okay.
You go into the two minute offense.
Okay. You don't get out of
bounds. You keep the clock run it.
You want this game to
be over? No, I dunno.
Yeah. That's what I would
do. That's what I would do.
Just sit down and just say,
all right, in eight seconds,
this relationship is going to be
over. Okay. I'm on this side of,
of the eight seconds. All I do.
How long does it take to say that?
I'm going to time it right now.
All right. We need to talk.
I'm not happy.
We need to break up.
I just did that in like five seconds
and then she go, Whoa, what
have we, blah, blah, blah. No,
I've made the decision we need to break
up. It just, it's just not working for me.
I don't love you the way I used to love
you. That's what can I say about it?
They can get mad. They can
cry, they can do all that shit,
but the thing is you conveyed it and
you're out. Where am I going to live?
I don't know.
We'll figure that out.
I guess that's the next thing we need to
figure out. Yeah. Well it's your life.
Gonna suck after that,
but it's never going to suck more than
staying in a fucking relationship.
You don't want to be in. All right. And
that's one to grow on. Go fuck yourselves.
I'll talk to you on Thursday.
All right, I'm back. I guess my,
my recorder was almost filled up.
Sorry about that sound. We had to fucking
attitude things together as always,
as always making my life
difficult. Um, anyways. Yeah.
So what are you doing over
at this person's house?
She's dating somebody else.
Anyway, she, he goes, he's a loser.
No Job's still gets an allowance and
expensive car that his mommy bought him,
sits at home all day playing video games,
getting stone and treats people like
he's above them. She knows I hate him.
And I openly mock him, um,
in front of our friends,
her and even him,
uh,
like he got are this really generic but
expensive looking hard shape necklace.
Um, when she showed it to everyone,
I looked at him and said loudly, wow,
must've cost your mom quite
a big whatever that means.
As you can imagine, he tries to avoid me.
Yeah. Well, you're being a fucking cunt.
Uh, we share the same friends
and they hate him and like me,
but mind you, I'm no prize
either. I'm trying to get a job.
Unlike him out Jesus,
you don't even have a fucking job.
And then saving up for a car.
So our choices are two guys who don't
have a job and she has a rich mom. Well,
there you go. I tend
to be nice, a nice guy,
but can at times piss people off with my
jokes and even be a dick with my jokes.
You sound like you're being a dick.
I'm not saying you are,
but you're being a dick to this guy.
He's at least three inches taller than me.
Enhanced. Some are
better looking, I guess.
He's got this great smile that
makes me want to fuck them up. Push.
Oh,
that makes me want to fuck it up for them.
Okay.
But recently I've started to turn my
life around, quit bare porn and drugs.
My grades are going up, applying
for college, working out a lot,
but all this in hopes of catching her eye.
Like I said,
she's my best friend and as a boyfriend,
so I really don't know how to handle this.
Any help from you and Neil would be
greatly appreciated. Ah, yeah dude. Um,
I would start fishing in a
different watering hole. All right.
You know,
for you to sit there and stand there
and be a cunt to her boyfriend talking
about a boyfriend and you're going
over that for over a fucking house.
MMM.
It sounds to me like you're the yearlings.
Chris Rock says you're in the friend zone.
So what you need,
what you need is you need some
time away from her. All right?
Move on with you fucking life. Keep
working out. Get you shit going.
And who knows?
You might just meet somebody else and
then eventually when she dumps this loser,
she comes around and sees you.
She'll be, oh my God, look at you.
You're going to college. You look,
Greg, you've been working out, you know,
watch porn. Who knows? Maybe it'll happen,
but I can tell you it's
definitely not going to happen.
If you could just going to be your friend,
they making snide remarks about
her, her boyfriend. Come on.
Do you gotta be better than that?
That's just coming off like a, you know,
you're acting like a,
you're acting like a Douche and I
don't know how else to put it. Um,
that's not as strong move.
All right.
Um, and you should have more going on in
your life than the fucker be, you know,
used to have more self esteem
than that. All right? Okay.
She wants to date this fucking guy.
Guess what? It's her loss. Alright,
so fuck it. Get on with your life. Keep
working out and work out for yourself.
Go to college for yourself.
Do all this shit for yourself.
Feel good about yourself.
You start putting out more of a
positive vibe as opposed to, you know,
hanging around her, shitting
on her current boyfriend.
I mean, that's just like,
I don't know if that's not a good look.
Okay. I believe in you. All right.
Do what I just said or dope cause I
don't have any professional training.
All right. Dumping my girlfriend
a Billy billboard brow.
I fucking asshole. That's another
good one. Recent fanny of podcasts.
Stand up and all that jazz.
Anyways,
I'm a 24 year old dude and I've been
dating and living with my girl for almost
four years now and I finally had enough.
She's a real Downer and talk shit
about people including your friends,
like it's an Olympic sport now.
The problem is she lost a job a month
ago on account of a shit-talking.
It hasn't exactly been going
out and looking for a new
one because she's anxious
or whatever. Leaving me to
pick up her end of the bills.
She didn't have any savings because she
had picked up the habit of going out and
drinking every night. I honestly
wouldn't have a problem, uh,
just up and leaving.
But the apartment is a stone's throw from
the beach and my other roommate and I
really don't want to leave
the fucking decisions people make.
It's right near the beach.
The other roommate is my best friend.
Okay.
She's got a lot of books and
shit and the bed is hers.
So when be a little,
so would be a little difficult to do.
The old put all their
stuff in a box trick. Uh,
deep down I do still have love for her.
So the idea of kicking
her out hurts my heart,
but I just can't deal with the
endless drama and unhappiness.
We'd love to hear what your advice
on the podcast and as always go fuck
yourself.
Yeah.
The more the relationship has run its
course and you need to go your separate
ways. And sometimes when that happens, you
know somebody, yeah, somebody gets hurt.
All right?
But you're not doing her any favors if
you don't want to or to be with you and
you just, you just wasting
her and your time. So,
uh,
you know,
this is why you don't fucking live with
somebody unless you know you're gonna
marry him. I don't, I dunno.
I Dunno if you're, yeah. Boy.
Um,
so what do you do?
Break up with her and then tell her to
move out all at the same time or are
those two separate conversations?
I just break up with her
and then let her bring up
where am I going to live.
Yeah.
And I'd be like, well, I don't know.
I mean the coastline is pretty long,
so I'm sure there's another
beachfront apartment she could be.
And I'm assuming your name's on the lease.
Usually when there's a breakup,
the guy has to leave
and leave half his shit.
So it seems like you're in
a decent position here. Uh,
who wants a negative drunk without a job?
I don't think you want,
that doesn't sound like you want it.
Um,
I think the love you have for her was
who she used to be or who you thought she
was.
So,
okay.
Yeah.
Neither of those are happening right now.
So it's time for you to tell her to hit
the bricks. Happy new year, sweetheart.
Beat it.
You can't say it like that.
Okay.
I just tell her, look, we need to
talk and sit down. She could be a,
what's the problem? What's
the problem? Me and you,
you just got to fight through
that fucking horrible feeling.
There's nothing worse.
The only worse than a woman crying is
when she's about to cry because you still
have hope that she's not going to cry.
So you're on pins and needles.
Once she's crying, you're
like, fuck, this sucks.
But you kind of know what's
going to happen. Um, yeah.
You just got to sit her down and
just say, listen, um, I'm not happy.
This isn't working for me anymore and
we need to break up. All
right? Just like that. Boom,
boom, boom. And you got to get that
out. You got to get all of that out.
Don't sit there and be like, oh,
I don't know how to say this.
A Dah, Dah, Dah, Dah, Dah, Dah,
and turn it into a 45 minute thing.
Rip The bandaid odd. Just rip it
off. We need to talk. I'm not happy.
We need to break up.
Okay.
You go into the two minute offense.
Okay. Get, don't get out of
bounds. You keep the clock running.
You want this game to
be over. No, I dunno.
Yeah, that's what I would
do. That's what I would do.
Just sit down and just say,
all right, in eight seconds,
this relationship is going to be
over. Okay, I'm on this side of,
of the eight seconds.
All I do,
how long does it take to say that I'm
going to time it right now. All right,
we need to talk.
I'm not happy.
We need to break up.
I just did that in like five seconds
and then she goes, what
if we blah, blah, blah.
Now I've made the decision we
need to break up. It's just,
it's just not working for me. I don't
love you the way I used to love you.
That's what can I say about, they can mad.
They can cry, they can do all that shit,
but the thing is you conveyed it and
you're out. Where am I going to live?
I don't know.
We'll figure that.
I guess that's the next thing we need
to figure out and Whoa, it's your life.
Gonna suck after that,
but it's never going to suck more than
staying in a fucking relationship.
You don't want to be and all right, and
that's one to grow on. Go fuck yourselves.
I'll talk to you on Thursday.