It's like a boss. I um,
I watched on Netflix, I watched that
Ukraine documentary, uh, winter on fire.
[inaudible]
you know, it was just one of those
things where it's just like Jesus Christ.
I knew I wasn't politically active,
but watching what these people did,
what they turned around, I'll,
I'll try to give you a simple version
of what happened, which, you know,
with my brain,
that's all you're going
to get is basically what
happened I guess around 2003,
2004, uh,
there was some fucking
Russian dude pro Russian dude,
eight claim that he won the fucking
election. And they were like, no,
you didn't. Your piece
of shit. You rigged it.
And they proved it and he got bounced.
In 2004 pro Russian candidate, Viktor
Yanukovych wins the presidential vote.
The election was found
to be raped. As a result,
the people take to the streets in a
peaceful protest called the orange
revolution.
2009, the same dude comes
back and guess what?
He wins the election
like that wasn't corrupt.
2010 Yana Covich returns this time.
The election is confirmed
and he regains full control.
So anyways, you, the Ukraine is a
chance to join the European Union,
right? To start being more
like a European country.
And for once and for all get out from
underneath a, whatever you call, whatever.
Russia has a dictatorship.
Fall 2013,
a key milestone of coaches as Yanukovych
appears ready to sign an association
with the EU. Yet as the
people look to the west,
their leader turns to the east and
the future of the nation hangs in the
balance.
So the fucking Russian dude who
allegedly got elected legitimately,
you know, listens to the people and
they say that that's what we want to do.
We don't want to take
a step towards Russia.
We want to become part of the European
Union. We want to have a future here.
Like, um,
what we see going on in western Europe
and all of the fucking politicians go,
you got it. All right. The people have
spoken, we're gonna do what you said.
And what do you think happened? Right
in the midnight hour they gave him,
they all right there, Fred.
They're like, yeah, you know what?
We're not signed to that. And uh,
we're going go hang out with though.
Vladi daddy over there poop none.
Vladimir Putin and I were going to
fucking shoot 18 holes of golf with him,
but we're going to sell out
your country to the ruskies.
[inaudible]
so start it off this
whole fucking revolution.
I'm not going to say what the
fuck. I mean, you got to watch it.
It's unbelievable. But um, you know,
I mean it's totally, it's not in the
news. I mean, they ended up winning.
They somehow ended up winning and these,
these fucking people had no weapons.
They were just getting shot at
what I don't understand. I mean,
I do understand it, but I, I,
there's no place in the world where
you can protest. You can't do it.
You protest,
cops show up and they beat the fuck out
of you until you go home and they arrest
a few and then that's it. Everyone.
It happens in this country,
this country with all its on would
have free brave freedom of speech.
You know those fucking occupy
Wall Street people, right.
They come down there,
they beat the fuck out of them
and everybody knows the old trick,
the same shit that they was.
They would claim when they did it in the
Ukraine where basically when you have a
peaceful demonstration, it's like, well
fuck, we can't beat the fuck out them.
What should we do?
They hire a couple people to go down
there and pretend to be the protesters.
They throw a couple of fucking rocks and
then the, the, the, the cops go nuts.
No. So yeah, still
[inaudible] but then watch the
[inaudible]
and then on the newest,
they're like the protesters started
attacking the police. You know,
the police were just doing their job,
but Blahblahblahblah the police's job is
to go down there and beat the fuck out
of them. Alright, isn't it? Isn't that
what it is? Got Jesus Christ bills.
I Dunno what, what do you
know? I don't know. That's,
that's Kinda what I got out of
it. I got out of it that, um,
it was an amazing documentary that
these people actually with basically no
fucking weapons and just, you know, died,
lost their eyes, had all these horrific
fucking injuries, got kidnapped,
disappeared,
all of this horrific shit
and they were able to um,
hold them off for awhile.
Okay.
What is the [inaudible] [inaudible]
[inaudible] [inaudible]
[inaudible] what's the [inaudible]
so then the fucking Russian guy
ends up having to leave, right?
He fucking leaves and Da da Da.
He's a jolly good fellow.
It's all fucking over.
[inaudible]
and then all of a sudden,
out of nowhere, this,
this other revolution starts
with people who are pro Russia.
Since the, since the
document you've been made,
like 6,000 Ukrainian people died. But, um,
I'll try to say is if you get
a chance to check a Ukraine
winter on fire,
[inaudible]
our top story, this half hour,
dozens of activists are under arrest
after they've a demonstration and
Manhattans Union square got out of hand.
The protest is entering its second week.
The arrest were caught on tape and
uploaded to youtube as part of the occupy
Wall Street movement. Today,
activists are speaking out against the
NYP di claiming officers used excessive
force during yesterday's
crackdown last night,
a group march to a police precinct
demanding answers about their friends who
were taken into custody
earlier in the day.
More than 80 people were arrested when
the group marched from Zuccotti Park to
union square where police corralled the
demonstrators with orange netting and
arrested. Those who would not disperse.
Many of the activists say the police were
overly aggressive and arrested people
without cause.