My wife for whatever fucking reason,
absolutely loves that show
that American greed and um,
yeah,
she watches like three of those episodes
every fucking night before we go to
bed. And I,
and I and I always ended up falling
asleep cause it's the same fucking story
over and over again. You
know, it's the same thing.
The guy starts a for fucking
business. He dressing the parties,
faking it till you make it.
He gets a bunch of investors,
he hands out fake spreadsheets and you've
got these fucking innocent people just
go in like, you know, I'll,
I shot the recharge and I was getting
dirty, pretty it. And I was like woo,
you shove like a good Yale or me. Right.
And then they always go, you know, there's
always get some really bad metaphor.
They invested in an ice cream chain,
but this wasn't the flavor they were
looking for when we returned glass in the
ice cream.
Oh Wow. Oh Wow.
Fucking song for American greed. I'll
tell you. And I was going to edible.
I'm fucking American. Great. Is
that cunt? Who shot that lion?
Everybody's talking about this dentists
that went over to illegally poached this
lion that was friendly with
people. I love that shit. Oh,
is it a friendly with people until what?
It bites somebody fucking head off.
Fucking unreal. You know what I mean?
Everybody's fucking salient gas.
The pitbulls you shoot a fucking line.
Everything like, oh my wish. Nice.
He was a good line. I'm not
saying it was a bad line.
I'm not saying the guy
shouldn't have done it.
I think everybody's missing the
fucking story here. Alright.
Speaking of American greed,
this guy paid 50 grand.
All right. That's just for the fuck.
That's not even for his flight to go
over there and kill this fucking lion.
All right.
No trying to start anything up here.
But how the fuck can a dentist afford to
drop 50 grand to fly to Africa to shoot
a fucking lion
illegally?
Just think of all the,
how expensive the shoes he had to buy
that he had to sneak around and they had
to be some sort of Ninja wear.
Fucking, I'm gonna shoot it a, uh,
a protected lion wear
that he had on right?
I dropped 50 grand on that and
now he's gone under ground.
They go over his house,
he's got a match, right?
And all they talking
about is his fucking line.
And I'm watching an
episode of American greed.
Oh Wow. Wow.
How the fuck can you afford or fill in
fucking how many teeth are you fill it.
This guy's pulling teeth. He's,
I'm telling you right now,
I used to work in a dental
office, right? And I,
there was some good dentists just
like cops. There's some good cops.
There's some bad cops. And I'm
not talking about interrogation,
talking about brandishing a weapon. No,
I'm talking about fucking people pulling
teeth that didn't need to be pulled.
Fucking doing rooms,
doing fillings on teeth that did not
need to be fucking drilled into because
they bought a car beyond their
own fucking needs or whatever.
Their, their, their financial
responsibility. All right,
I think this guy should be fucking taken
back there just for the simple fact,
just for the simple
fact that, that he, uh,
he went to another country. It did
that. What do we got over here?
Does the MGM still have
a lion? What if he,
what if somebody from Zimbabwe came
over here? What about and the MGM lion,
right, right. As they were recording
that. You're watching an MGM film.
They fuck up. Please turn the air
conditioning back on back. Yeah.
The lovely knee. Everybody, she
came in. This is a studio man.
Dave Letterman had a
cold. I'm having a cold.
He lasted fucking 30 years on television.
I want to do 30 years of podcasting.
Huh? Well, what's good
is the air conditioning.
If you're going to fucking turn it
off. Listen, I'm talking about that.
Dentists that went out went
over to Zimbabwe. You got
to go grab a mic from the,
uh, from the closet there. Do
you know that story in here?
There's dentists from Minnesota.
He's a B. You know, like,
he's one of those big game
hunters, you know what I mean?
He's one of those fucking guys.
I'm going to shoot something that people
think is scary and that can be like,
God killed that Shit. You know,
like it went up and he fucking put it in
a chokehold. It's like you didn't you,
you went over and you shot
it. The fact that you can go,
you can walk up and kill an armed man,
a human being with a gun, you could
fucking kill. You could, you could do it.
Even if he knew you were coming,
you have a gun, he has a gun,
you could do that. So now
you're going up to a lion.
The thing doesn't have a gun. So I mean,
how fucking difficult is that actually
they shut out with a crossbow,
but then the reason why they shouted
with a crossbow was because they were
trying to disguise doesn't he have, he's
gone big game hunting before, right?
Like he's done a line. Well,
here's the thing that I thought I saw
some weirdly alarmists headline being
like, you know,
he's like a serial killer of animals and
it's like the way they were putting it
was like, you know, this is what
he does all the time. I don't know.
He's one of those guys.
He thought it doesn't seem like he
kills to eat it as this for sport. Yeah.
He's one of those guys to be like, Yay.
You ever hear of an alligator
fucking shot one in there? Hey,
where's does he put it up in his
study or something like that.
He's one of those guys. He's one of
those guys, so he won't want about him.
He fled, right? Like he
uh, he will goes over,
he went over to Zimbabwe like a crossbow
and he fucking went into some like
wildlife sanctuary. Allegedly.
This lion was friendly with people.
I love that shit. All the Lion
Cecil or whatever. It's, yeah,
it's friendly until it isn't to the one
day you do something that reminds us,
you know, shuffling from his childhood
and it fucking bite your head off.
But it, it's what it's supposed to too.
It's a line. Yeah. You Kill Shit. Yeah,
of course. So he went in and he fucking
killed it to capitated its skin.
The fucking thing. Yeah. He wants
the head. Yeah. First of all,
how do you get the head back? I Dunno.
I don't want to know that you
got to go gym bag. [inaudible]
they can get a drain it out. They
probably do it. They're like, oh no.
You know what he did?
He probably taxidermy.
Well he probably like takes the fucking,
just this, this skin from the head.
You bring that back and then you just,
you have somebody like make a like a
lion skull and then you put it over there
cause no one's going to know. Note
the skull isn't in there. Right.
This is the kind of shit this is like
Pat, no idea. Let me ask you this,
and yet, because you're into
American greed. This guy's a dentist.
He paid 50 grand to do that.
Now he's gone underground.
They'd gone by his house. He has
a mansion. This guy's a dentist,
he's a mansion. He's going all these
expensive fucking uh, you know,
going around killing all these,
how does it dentists have
all that fucking money?
Is he like a Hoity toity fancy dentist
that like doesn't take any insurance at
all? Like self pay and it's the,
I worked in a dental office.
Nobody was going on a safari. Even
just look at them. Forget about too.
I just want to safari how much
money that is. Forget about.
You're going to go over there and
then sneak back later. Kill a lion.
What's your the fucking thing and
sneak it back. Yeah. I don't know.
He sounds very sketchy though.
Oh Wow.
Well doing the theme to
American Green later.
Oh, by the way. So do you think,
do you hope that the United States extra
dates this dentist back to Zimbabwe?
Do you feel like you should do 10
years in prison and a hardcore prison?
Is he going to get a little, it's
going to get blood rigs I think.
I think he should be fine. Probably
a lot. Like a lot. No fuck that.
I think he should be
taken back at some point.
You got to put a value on animals lives.
I agree it the way you're saying he
should go to Jay. I think he should.
I don't think he should go
to the hardcore one. Right.
I think that he should go to the jail,
be in protective custody and through
his 10 years he should have to fix
everybody's teeth. I think for free.
He should work in an animal sanctuary
like cleaning up all like the shit and
everything. He can't ever, it's like
having a pedophile work at a kindergarten.
Eventually he's going to fucking kill
some. It's don't be able just, that's all.
I mean his, do you know
[inaudible] second.
There's not some law in place about him
going and killing that animal cause it
shouldn't. There already be some
other ways. But he left the country.
He left the country.
He's back here and now he's got to get
the United States to send one of their
own. Now the United States,
we're not going to send the guy
because that's one of our guys.
He's got the Barcode on the back of his
neck and he's not making us any fucking
money if he by us, I mean the
Illuminati guys, you know what I mean?
He's not paying any fucking a income
tax or any of that type of shit.
He's not walking around.
You know what he's supposed to be
saying cause he got it out of his TV.
You need that Zombie. You need that
guy. He's a big game hunter. That guy,
he's going to be on the side of
those. I gotta be honest with you.
I totally respect hunting. I think
it's the shit. I love animals too.
But I think if you go out and you hunt
and then you do it for food or whatever,
or you're doing it to learn
how to do it. I respect that.
Go shoot a fucking deer.
There's a zillion of them.
They're like mosquitoes but like to
go out there and, and uh, you know,
shoot a lion, a leopard to Jay,
these beautiful fucking animals
where they do deployments.
There was a bunch of fucking, it was
herds, a lions running along the prairies.
I mean, I, that's what we would have
on as a 4th of July, but we're not,
we fucking killed all of them. I think
there's really something, uh, like, uh,
I don't what this guy does, I don't
lump all hundred hunters into,
did he go out on his own? Was he
like this row we hired these guys.
I was going to say he hired people, right?
So he had people who knew that Saran.
Those guys are fostered.
Those guys are going to trial and
they're staring at 10 years. Oh they are?
Oh yeah. And being a
bottom. I was going to say,
I know he paid somebody like an exorbitant
amount of money in order to do that.
He didn't just go out
there on his own. Yeah.
It was incredibly stupid of the people
who lived there and this fucking guy,
I don't know,
he must've had the size of that duffle
bag that he must've put the fucking head
in. It's just, it's unbelievable
to me. That's what the whole,
how does the head travel
from man, what do you do?
I don't know. I don't know how you
take your hand. Put it up his ass.
Like those drugs, meals, you know,
have to fill out those little cards.
We travel, we travel internationally.
It's like, are you going,
are you bringing any fruit or any like
wildlife or anything like of plants?
I got an elephant's and my duffle bag.
Do you mind if I look in
your bag sir? Uh, yes I do.
Do you have any liquids in there? No.
It's all been drained and he's so sharp.
Optic. You can do any of that,
but the fucking with the,
I actually think there's something
fucking wrong with you if you have to go
around and killed the most
deadliest animals to human beings,
like walking around doing that shit.
I feel like that was an old
school like Teddy Roosevelt.
I'm an insecure guy and like you
shoot at, I can't kill the thing.
This like foreign land, like,
isn't that the whole thing?
It's like you sort of take over the
people and the neighborhoods and like the
countries and then like kill all their
wildlife, isn't it all about like,
I'm the big man and I can
just sort of, yeah, I don't,
I don't own nature as well as
man. I don't know what it's about,
but I can tell you only thing I'll give
him props was as he used to crossbow,
you know? That's, but of
course for, you know what,
he had to fucking laser pointer and
shit. But like I, I just am not,
America has bigger problems
than rich people shooting lions.