Okay.
Hey, what's going on?
It's Bill Burr and It's time for the
Monday morning podcast from my one day
Monday, May 29th,
2017 what's going on out? You
[inaudible] how are you guys doing?
Happy Memorial Day.
Happy Memorial Day when you're
supposed to be out there.
Remember the troops you're
going to be getting [inaudible]
the hammer [inaudible]
say bad shit to your wife that you laid
up to apologize for what's going on.
You fucking soon to be fat
fucks. Huh? You got the,
you got the grill going?
[inaudible]
hey Matt, about up right?
We got a little killed.
Bosh. What are you guys making today? Huh?
What fucking animal had to
get the old right there, Fred?
You know in an upper cut to another
one. You fucking sewed them together.
What God's name do you have on your grill
right now that you know you fucking,
what'd you put in there?
A bunch of cheese.
Who wants cheese on their burger on
and he sees a good fucking burn, right?
Um, oh. You know it's the best. So you
put the buns on. That's, that's the,
you know, you keep checking and keep
checking me. Looking at the meat.
Don't want to burn the bunt.
Uh, Christ they burn this one
with burns. Ah, I bet she
swallows up. Sorry. Sorry.
Why Bill? Why, why did you have to
take the Nice family day that this is,
you know, that the great
men of this country fought.
So you could go out there, you
know, work slowly, work your way,
take another step towards
a fucking massive coronary.
How many people are going to
face plant into their grill today
via too much alcohol?
Well, you know,
just eating that last thing that fucking
makes the ticker stop or you know,
the classic old fucking middle-aged man,
uh, injury, the fucking blown
out Achilles, you know. Oh,
did you say you want to pickles and you
just turn a little too fast and pallet
shit goes right up the back of your leg.
Then you face plant right to your fucking
grill. Full side of the face. Right.
You'd be surprised. I bet if I
could somehow get some sort of live,
you know, folders in here.
I bet my phone lines would be
lighting up right now with paramedics,
fire department people,
people that drive ambulances.
Hey is the driver the ambulance,
do you actually have to know how to
help people or you just like the guy,
the getaway driver, you know,
all you need to do is know how
to turn on the siren, you know,
be able to block it out.
Do you think ambulance drivers hear that
Siren at night as they lay there quiet
bedroom, you know, probably to put
fucking music on cause they don't,
they just laying there and all ears.
Woo.
Slowly going insane. Um, I dunno,
I'm in a great fucking mood. You know,
my lovely little lay is starting
to sleep through the night.
I'm starting to get some sleep
again. Dude, she's hilarious.
She just does this thing now she's
trying out a voice. You just guys got
[inaudible]
loudest shit laying in the bed in the
morning between me and the [inaudible].
It's like fucking a little mini
Jerry Lewis the entire time.
It's so I just put my hand
over her mouth and I just,
I just make it go like a
little out loud I think.
And then she kind of like looks
around like, what the fuck was that?
And that stops her for about four
seconds before she starts again.
And then she gets used to the
noise and then that's it. Um,
she starting to crawl. She's fucking
moving backwards. It's funny, like they,
I guess they moved backwards first.
So it's like the thing that they want,
it just keeps getting further
and further away like that.
A Alfred Hitchcock shot.
Um, but, uh, anyways,
I had family for Banky.
She out here this weekend,
which means plenty of booze,
plenty of fucking crazy foods.
So I've been doing the elliptical
every day doing what I can.
But uh, you know, this
is like, at this point,
everybody's going to come out here, has
come out here. They've all seen her.
They all love her. And what's
awesome is now I don't have to, uh,
I realize now when people visit
me, they're not coming to see me,
which is fucking awesome. That
coming to see her. Oh, hey bill,
how are you doing? Where is
she? Where is she? She over.
We all would you look at
her, look at her. It's great.
And you just peel off
in the back, you know,
all your family members come over and
then they all get to hold her and stuff,
you know? So then you get to sit
there. Boozing in the corner.
Yeah,
the holidays now. It's
been great. She's awesome.
Um, she's so awesome. I'm not getting
any fucking material out of it.
Everyone was telling me, Oh
my God, you haven't a kid.
I can't wait for you to
become a dad. Oh my God.
I want to see how your rack changes.
It hasn't. I'm still paranoid.
I'm still filthy and I'm,
my daughter's awesome.
So you know, that's not funny.
Hey Bro, it's like being a
dad. It's Gregg phenomenal.
I think most of my materials, just
about other fucking lunatic parents.
I'm telling you what I'm going to start
saying to people when they go, oh,
she's, Oh yeah, that's a great age.
I'll wait. Wait til three days from now,
then all well, you've
gone, she's going talk.
She'll fucking start stabbing
you in the night. I'm,
you want me to start saying those parents?
I'm just going to be like, you know,
you sound like a horrible father and
I think you married the wrong person.
Have a nice day.
Oh, you could look at this experience
in a negative way is fucking. Look,
if you're broke,
if you're a kid, if you're a fucking
high school student, right? And you know,
you started bagging your God Damn English
teacher [inaudible] you didn't know
enough to pull out as much as
they told you in sex education,
how much you know how a baby's made.
You couldn't fucking believe you are
banging your English teacher and the next
thing you know you're going to be a fun
yet then. Then it's brutal. You know,
you're married to this fucking old broad,
it's always correcting
your fucking sentences.
You know,
you're calling around for dressing like
a horror and she's fucking giving you
shit for a, for a dangling
participle, whatever the fuck.
I never knew what that meant.
The past part of supple
bill was a past participle.
This sentence, I don't know,
just send me to summer school,
just gimme gimme in that fucking
distilled version of this class.
That is nothing. That Dream Team of
class clowns that is summer school,
drug addicts and musicians. It was
just fucking tremendous summer school.
Underrated. I tell you,
I went, I did it twice.
I should've done it all four
years of high school, but a,
I blew off the last year cause
what was the fucking point?
My Sophomore Year my teacher
hooked me up, gave me the d minus,
um, d minus in geometry. Um,
I fucking had a great time. I had a
great time. I had to take one class.
You don't get me out
of bed in the morning.
In summer school was combined like three
towns where I lived and it was, uh,
it was all the class clowns. Just
like I said, creative people,
everybody had add in the level of
shit that they gave to the teacher.
I was like, wow, I got to up my game.
These people are on a whole nother level.
It's like when you go to jail,
you become like a better criminal.
I became a better class clown
just sitting there like, wow,
these guys are fucking,
these guys have no intention
of going to college.
I'm at least still lying to myself.
Yeah, I think I could, you know,
I think I could go in the later rounds
if you were a fucking draft
pick, be honest with yourself.
You're a high school student, what
round are you going in? You know,
and if you really think about
it, that's why Bill Belichick,
he doesn't like the first round draft
picks because the first round draft picks,
they like booksmart. Right. They're
the fucking nerds. You know,
you give them some information,
they'll memorize it and they'll
spit it right back at Ya. Right.
There's no passion. They, they, they,
they don't walk into a
room and light it up.
This is a bad analogy cause first
round draft picks do I guess, do they,
I don't know about college basketball
now with everybody one and done.
You'd bring this fucking kid
to a locker room full of men.
You can put the team on his
back, bony fucking legs.
Um, we'll bill, are they supposed
to do a lot of them? You know,
it's like their, their mothers, uh, you
know, they, they need a new kidney and,
and uh, the, the shack they live in
is falling up. Okay, fair enough.
Fair enough. Yeah. But
selfishly is a fan. You know,
you miss the days when somebody had
four years with fucking coach k or Dean
Smith, rest his soul, Bobby
Knight, flipping them in the chin.
Stop looking down on the
ground and fucking man,
that'd be, I've told them, but
we've got to be tell you much.
I fucking loved that Bobby Knight
speech where he says, you know,
I'm not going to, you're not gonna. I'm
not gonna walk around with a 14 to 20.
Okay.
I don't know what it is about.
That guy listened to that speech
and it makes me want to go fucking,
I don't know. I'll go to the gym.
I have to listen to that guy.
Something happened, you know, when
that guy got ran out of town, that was,
that was it, you know.
Then all of a sudden like,
okay
guys steered into just
literally being pussies,
like fucking wearing shirts with
cats on them and stuff. Yeah.
You know,
my wife was showing me that like there's
a men's onesy that's out there now.
The guys aware and I was like,
you gotta be fucking Kitty.
Like what is it going to stop? When is
it going to steer back to testosterone?
When is the guy's guy going
to make a comeback? I mean,
everything makes a comeback,
right? Classic Rock Disco Hair,
metals. Make it a little bit of a
comeback. I don't fucking, I, you know,
I just don't get it.
So then somebody show me what they've
like pulled Sean Connery wall one in one
of the James Bond movies
and it's like, all right,
but he wasn't wearing it like
he thought it looked good.
He wasn't wearing it cause
it was fucking stupid.
Okay.
You know, that's what
I can't fucking stand.
Everything's like mocking something
else. It's like, all right,
so what do you believe in? What are
you going to fucking sign your name to?
And these fucking millennial cons.
The deal. I can't say all of them.
That's not fair to whole generation,
but so the ones that at least
they're taking pictures of. Okay.
Which granted most of these
pictures of being taken care of,
taken by older people from my generation
who are jealous of younger people.
That's what a lot of it is. I bet.
I Bet I'm overreacting when
I really think about it.
I don't really see a lot of
people with cats on their shirts.
Although when they do,
people take pictures of them,
then they post them on social media and
then old fucks like me start going, oh,
look at these fucking millennials.
Barely fucking, um, all right,
so scratch all of that.
I mean really built up.
Have you seen anybody with the onesy?
Somebody just showed you
a picture and then you,
you literally started freaking out.
Like you watch CNN or
Fox News for two hours.
It's always a great thing to do.
Watch those for a couple, two,
three hours and they get y'all panicked.
What you want to do is you want to
switch between the two of them, right?
And then you out the lies and you
keep yourself levelheaded, you know,
fake news. Tell fake news.
Um,
so anyways, I don't want to be like
that. I want to be that guy. Okay.
God bless you millennials. I'm sure this,
there's plenty of guys guys on the way.
You're out there fucking
crushing ass and God bless you.
Enjoy your youth joy,
you fucking youth before it's memorial
day and suddenly you're that guy with the
dad bod standing in front of the grill,
filling that tightness in your Achilles.
You know,
you got to reach for that last burger
on the back of the fucking Griffith.
You just start feeling that tightness
in your ankle and you're like, God,
if it's going to happen, please
don't let it happen. Now,
not in front of my
family. Becky sched. Um,
nobody is guests the movie by
the way, that I am referring to.
We had problems with the family baggy east
a this, I was going to
say, I'd give you a hint,
but this isn't really a hint
in my opinion, that movie,
it's a car movie for me.
I just feel like that movies, a car movie.
Other people thought there was
some philosophical question.
Okay.
You know who's the fly?
Who's the windshield?
All I remember from that movie was I
loved the car cause I love the fucking
sleep.
Okay.
I remember the car that was a sleeper
and then I just remembered that there was
this one guy was Evan Bravo,
lived with the family Baggie East.
And that explained his
entire fucking backstory.
That's now if you guys can't guess
it now. I don't know what the fuck.
I don't know. I don't know
what to tell you. All right.
They had a fucking pizza. Wow.
Yeah. Can I get a, can I get
a sausage in a rubella? Eh,
we got no Rugola no, you don't have
any Rugola. Yeah, we had family.
We out with the family. Becky
still will give us a rubella.
Um, anyway, so what'd you guys do
this weekend? Other ones sit around.
You know what I did? I watched, um,
somebody tweeted me on the
old Twitter and told me,
you're watching the time trials for
Monaco and here's the thing. I, you know,
I'm new to F1.
She guys know I can barely
remember the fucking names.
Um,
so I'm like, I'm going to, I didn't,
I had no idea like how they qualify
for a race. I just thought you'd,
you know, you get like
five laps around the track.
Whoever has the best time gets the pole
position and then they just work their
way back. But that, that,
that is not how it works.
It's like a whole other day of
racing. Cause I always wonder why,
why the fuck did people show up
to watch these, these qualifying?
Okay.
I mean, just watch some guy
by himself out to he, yeah.
Eh, he's gotta be at
Eighth Place Tomorrow. Um,
that's not how it works.
It is the race before the race
and it's like this three race.
So there's three levels of the
qualifying. This is like, first of all,
there's practice laps to get you used
to the track and if you don't do the
practice laps, you're not allowed to race.
So obviously there's probably
some safety thing. Like, dude,
you're not just gonna fucking go out
there and start driving 200 miles an hour.
It's this next one, a right
or a left turn share. Um,
qualifying. Okay. So there's
this like three rounds of it.
So qualifying the first round one, it's
like match madness, but with, cause,
um, it lasts for 18 minutes.
Everybody gets on the fucking track.
I'm sure they, I don't know,
they let six out and another six.
I don't know how the fuck they do
it. I missed that part of it. Okay.
But it lasts for 18 minutes at the end
of which time can you tell I'm reading
this,
the six slowest drivers are eliminated
from qualifying and 16 advance to QT,
the qualifying two. So those six are
going to be, and I thought, oh my God,
are they out of the fucking race? Is
this like golf or you miss the cut?
And I found out later. No, they
just start way in the back.
Okay. So,
um,
so there's 22 fucking drivers.
I guess. So. Let's see.
So six of them are fucking
eliminated. They're not,
they're usually 20 drivers
to, to not kept to go home.
I have no idea if anybody
knows the information to that.
I don't know if anybody, if you don't
move to the next round of qualifying,
if anybody actually
doesn't get to race. Um,
cause I thought there was 20 cars in the
race and according to this mass there's
22 but whatever. So six are eliminated
in the first one, then the next 16,
you know,
after a short break the times are reset
and the 16 remaining cars run in a 15
minute session. It's
an hour down to 15. Uh,
and at the end of which the slowest six
cars are eliminated from qualifying,
leaving 10 to progress
to qualifying three.
Now the top 10 spots
after the race, those,
that's when you're in the points
from first all the way to 10th.
It's like something like 25
points for first 18 for second,
then it's like 15, then
12, 10, eight, six, four,
two one are the points.
Huh? You're in the,
you're in the fucking
lightning round at that point.
Um,
and then the, and whoever, yeah.
Obviously it has the best
run after that gets the, uh,
qualifying three after a further break,
times a reset and the final 12 minutes
session is held the decide pole position
in the standing order of
the top 10 grid places.
That's when you're in
the points. All right?
That's when you're going home with
least with a fucking year supply or
Rice-a-roni if you're in the top 10. So
I watched can somebody on Twitter
is like, dude, you gotta watch this.
This might be better
than the race. So, uh,
Lewis Hamilton from the ILM man,
it's an island with men,
nothing but men all walking around
like right way or the fucking A's,
the birds, whatever the fuck they
call them over there. Slags um,
anyways, he's out there,
he's got Mercedes,
he's got one of the fastest
fucking cars out there,
but for whatever fucking reason,
he's not getting enough downward force
or something on the front of his car.
And the front end is
sliding all over everywhere.
So he barely gets out of qualifying one.
He gets into qualifying too and it's,
there's a 15 minutes session and he's
outside of to qualifying to get to the
next level. His time is too slow,
so he's got time to do one more run.
Okay. Now he's in second
place overall for the, um,
for the uh, to become champ.
Just stay in to stay on
pace to be whatever the,
the fucking best drive of
the year. I'm sorry guys,
I'm new to this fucking thing. Um,
and his fucking front end starts sliding
all over the place and then some con
hits the wall so then the yellow flag
comes out and I guess that doesn't matter
if some asshole drives
into the fucking wall,
you're qualifying time is done.
This fucking idiot. Right?
Okay.
He's a professional driver. He hits the
wall. How did he hit the wall? I get it.
You caught enough. They said they
actually put some special steering,
they made custom steering just for that
fucking track and Monaco cause it just
driving through the streets and they have
such a hairpin turn that they actually
have to turn the wheel harder than
they do any other race. You know,
why would they just leave that in?
Did you want to have that option?
Okay. She had a drive a little all the
way around something at some point.
And the other races,
evidently not. Um, so anyways,
long story short,
this fucking guy I think from force
India with the few Checar just basically,
you know, he pulls the Greg Bay Brady,
you know gotta beat Marsha getting a
cold closer then a quarter of an inch.
He fucking slams right into
the wall and then that's it.
And Louis Hamilton was so
fucking dejected, he couldn't
even get out of his car,
you know. And a long story short,
the fucking Ferrari's.
What a fuck does my God damn
computer keep doing this to me.
Okay.
You want to get the screen
to come up? Can you stay up?
Do I got to sit there finger in the
fucking thing the whole time? Um,
yeah. So long story
short, the Ferrari's one,
the first and second
position and I think, uh,
that Butaro sky,
the finish dude started in third and
Lewis Hamilton was all the way back in
14th. So he's out of the points and a,
you're driving through the fucking
streets of Monaco, a sovereign state.
In other words, they're in France, but
they're not part of France. Like, yeah,
fuck off. We're doing
our own thing here. And
I guess it's really hard to
pass there. But despite that,
the fucking race starts and immediately
he went from 14th to 12th and I'm
watching the race and I'm
like, this motherfucker,
he's probably going to finish fourth.
He's somehow gonna figure somebody
is gonna fuck up in their pit stop.
Something's going to happen.
So I'm whining the whole time I'm watching
the race and I'm watching and he's
12th and he's 11th,
then he's 10th and the fucking announces
of blowing it off because they're too
busy looking at the, what the
Ferrari's are going to do,
what the red bold team's doing,
what the fuck a Bhutanese is going to
be doing in the Mercedes. It meanwhile,
is Lewis Hamilton just moving it?
This is the longest I've
ever talked about race and I,
they've got a film people like,
dude, I don't give a fuck.
Yo get driving around in a circle.
Um, no they're not. Then I try run
those left and right turns. All right.
Does a chicane
dude, you at least gotta Watch Monaco.
You should've watched Monica
with the fucking Illuminati.
People fucking back their yachts up.
Although I went online and I
find like you can actually,
there's a lot of them
are just like packages.
Like those aren't just rich people
with their yachts backed up.
It's just a lot of like booze cruises
and you can sit there on a fucking yacht
getting hammered, acting like you didn't
just light up your fucking credit card.
Whenever Stacy will deal with it.
When we get back, we get baggy aged.
So long story shorts, uh,
on a track that you could
not fucking pass on somehow.
Lewis past seven fucking people finish
seventh. So let's see, that's a one, two,
he got like six points or
something like that. And a,
the Ferrari's came in first
and second. All right. Uh,
Sebastian Vettel ended up winning
after a great fucking pit stop.
And what's his face? A Kimmy
riken in his, at his fucking name
raking in or whatever. Finish dude.
Sebastian's the Kraut, the German dude,
he fucking comes out of the pit
before him. Then he hit Kimmy
going like, God, what the fuck?
He sounded like Mick with
somebody cut me off for traffic.
But he's driving like 170 miles
an hour. Uh, and what's his face?
Daniel? Always a bridesmaid.
Never a fucking winner.
Ricardo came in fucking third.
The guy's always on the podium.
Never comes in first.
He's gotta be pissed. Like
guys, what the fuck can you
do some, do the car here so I can get
past these Ferrari's and Mercedes and man,
what a whoa. And I gotta do here.
Um, so long story short, Ferrari
as a team, as 196 points,
Mercedes has 179 and the Americans,
the Yanks, just to let you know,
we're pulling up the rear, we've got
our first points of the season. Uh,
what do we got? We got Romaine
like the lettuce, Grosse Gene,
he got nine points and then Kevin
Magnuson, like the condoms got five.
So we got 14 points. So I'll just
for those Ferrari's and Mercedes,
better mind that fucking
p's q's. Cause the yanks are
coming. All right. Thank you for fucking
sitting through all of that shit. Um,
let's talk about tiger woods.
Jesus fucking Christ.
Can you believe he got arrested
for drinking and driving?
It only happens to nine zillion
people every fucking day.
I'm so sick of people
talking about tiger woods,
like the way they disrespect
this guy. You know,
I love Stephen A. Smith,
but I started watching him talking
and he was saying that, you know,
that, you know,
this guy is just his fall from
basically his fall from grace and um,
and how his whole, you know,
he became a billionaire and his whole
fucking thing was based on the fact that
he presented himself as a family
man. And I'm thinking like,
what the fuck did that guy,
when the fuck did he ever
present himself as a family man,
I didn't get to where the fuck he was
because he was the best golfer anybody had
ever seen
because he was making like
PGA fucking links look like,
like he was playing
miniature golf. I know.
Pay attention to that fucking blondie
was why I don't even know her fucking
name.
Yeah.
And then [inaudible] he begs a bunch
of Hooters whores and then I'm spot.
Then I'm supposed to sit on the
couch going, you lie to me, tiger.
I thought after your golf,
you fucking went down to Applebee's
with your family and fucking your family
baggies and you shared a fucking bloomin'
onion. I have to be honest with you,
I never once thought about what the fuck
that guy did when he got off the golf
course and when I found out what
he was doing off the golf course.
I was like, yeah, I mean,
that kind of makes sense.
Yeah.
I am just going to say the steam out
of fucking men. Okay. When Steven A.
Smith walks out of his studio, you know,
he doesn't have a line of whores
just waiting to fucking blow them,
just so they could say,
I blew Steven A. Smith.
Tiger Woods had to deal with
that. And like most men,
he folded under the pressure
and the fucking reason why
he's not doing well right now,
it's not because of his fucking wife.
Who by the way took a bunch of his money,
bought a house, fucking knocked it
down and then rebuilt another one. Huh?
What about her?
I thought she wasn't
environmentalist. She liked to be
right. What about her? What
about all blondie? Right there?
I still a bit about this.
Do you think she would even give tiger
woods a second fucking glance if he
wasn't making all that money? If he
wasn't the greatest at what he did.
What? All blonde, blue eyed. Even
give that guy a fucking second.
I don't think she would've. All right.
Even when you're a bum like me,
when you fucking walked into the singles
bar back in the 90s what did women or
we say, what do you do?
They're not making small talk.
Okay. Women all fucking judge. Okay.
Their status and then they get a
number in their head. All right.
And then they find out
the jobs, okay, debt,
earn this and earn that. And then they
figured like who they can fuck. Okay.
And then it becomes a thing of like, okay,
you're underneath what I want for the
lifestyle that I'm looking for in the
future. But you're a good looking enough
guy that I'll fucking bang it tonight.
Maybe I'll have a little fling with you,
but that's getting the
end of the fucking day.
You know when you slid that piece of
paper across the table and you made your
off for say, my Dick and balls
bring home this each year,
they're like, yeah, keep it
moving. Keep it moving. That's,
that's 10 grand less than I want. And
you got that one snaggletooth fuck off.
Move on. Who's next? Go ahead. Put your
junk on the table. What's your number?
Okay. And he has it. And here's the thing,
I don't fault women for that.
Yeah.
Who would still live like a bumped if
you're good and if you're good looking
enough. Okay. And you can land somebody
that's making a ton of fucking money,
you can learn to love
that. Right? I Dunno.
So anyway,
so now he gets busted for drinking and
driving in that this is the bottom line.
This fucking guys fall from
grace. Okay. All right.
I'll give you the first fucking
couple of years after his divorce,
like maybe that got in his fucking
head, but at the end of that,
I mean either you got
divorced 10 fucking years ago.
What happened was was his marriage and
his body broke down at the same fucking
time, but guy just had major back
surgeries. Knees are fucked up.
And they always said,
they said back when everybody thought
he was a family band back east,
that um,
the way that the level of Torque and the
pressure that he's putting on his back,
they predicted his body was
going to break down and it did.
And then when it does, you know, now
they're going to blame, you know,
it's okay.
Classic Lady's just taking credit. That's
all it is. They always take it behind.
Yabby Greg man is a good
woman, you know, they, okay.
All right. Is it, I don't know, I
mean, what's your definition of great?
I mean,
but every great man is a great woman.
It's like the guy was already a
fucking champion when he met you.
Yeah.
So He's, if you're talking about his
mother, I'll, I'll give you that.
But this whole fucking thing.
Well now, I mean, Jesus,
I got to tell you his mugshot.
Oh, that's a classic one.
I'd like to have a couple
of pops with tiger.
Oh, lease. Yet. He needs,
this is what he needs to,
he needs to hit the fucking
treadmill. All right.
And he's got to shave his fucking
head already. You got to let that go.
You know. Oh God. He comes to Monday
morning. He comes to MMP Photoshop.
Can you please Photoshop
my fucking head underneath?
Hello.
Tiger Woods is fucking air. Uh, God.
You know what's funny is he
looks like he's fucking wasted.
But you know what he's saying? He's
looking into the camera going, well,
I know a billion people
are going to see this.
What the fuck are they going
to say about this one? Um,
I don't, I can't even to begin to
tell you guys. I, I can't, I can't,
I don't even,
I can't even begin to tell you guys how
bad I want to see this guy win a major
again. Uh,
look at this editor's pick the secret
history of tiger woods. Now how,
how much do you think they
actually talked to tiger woods?
So the death of his father set a battle
raging inside the world's greatest
golfer dish. Dish. How
the fuck do you know?
Why could you talk to his gardener? Is
that the closest you could get to them?
And now you gonna write 400 pages
of bullshit. Listen, do me a favor.
Don't listen to any of this stuff.
Okay? He's a man. He makes mistakes.
He's in the public eye. I hope his
back gets better. You know what?
I hope he goes out like fucking who's
that guy used to fucking just sit there
and the big dude, the blonde hair,
and he's fucking sit there.
I think he played Oliver on the
Brady Bunch way back in the date.
And then when he grew up, he became this
drunk. He was this alcoholic fucking,
he could get hit the ball of fucking Mya.
God dammit. This is going to kill me.
I got to look this up here.
Okay.
Alcoholic Golfer
driver long. That's how I search.
And John Daly. There we
go. Bam. Nailed it. Um,
John.
Okay.
You know, I hope he comes
back like a combination like
I dunno. Dot Terminator and
John Daly. That's what I want.
I want a fucking drunk cyborg going out
there and I hope he fucking passes Jack
Nicholas and just, you know,
I don't understand people that look at
people in the public eye to the point
that they, they disappoint them.
Yeah.
You know, get a fucking life.
Okay.
Jesus Christ. Oh,
what it was that fucking movie
called Captain Kirk when he did,
he did the sketch talking to the
trekkies on SNL, get a fucking life.
Okay.
You know, guys, I don't know.
I don't know if you noticed the last
couple of weeks I've been a little, uh,
I don't know. I've been a
little down, you know, and uh,
I know the podcast hasn't been as good
as it has been in the past and it's just
cause, uh, uh, you know, a tie
feel like tiger woods let me down.
You know, all those times I've never
met him or even remotely spoken to him.
Um, you know,
I just really thought we had something
there and for him to turn around and go
back on his word that he never gave
me because I've never spoken with the
matches. I was devastated. And, uh,
I'm not going to be able
to come into work today.
Oh Man. I hope that guy wins another
fucking major. I can't even tell you.
I can't even, I can't even fucking,
I just didn't tell you, didn't I,
I think I just did tell you, um, hey,
last week I was talking about
helicopters and, uh, you know,
I know some pilots listened to this
fucking thing, you know, mass bumping,
all that shit. You have to deal with low
g pushover with the fucking semi, uh,
articulated rotor system. Does anybody
know about these? Fucking these,
these new European helicopters that are
starting to be available over here and
it has a fully articulated rotor system
so you don't have to deal with any of
that shit and the fuel injected. So
there's no, do I need to pull carb heat?
Am I going to fucking die here? Um, it's
called, I don't know how to say a g U.
I M B a l gamble Cabri g two.
And I wrote next to it once the deal, um,
I talked to two of my instructors,
one of them said, hey,
that's pretty cool that they do
that. And the other one said, well,
it's kind of like,
remember when the first iPhone
came out cause they're brand new.
Then they had to work all
the bugs out. He said, uh,
they learned about aircraft through
people crashing. So I was like, all right,
fuck those things then. Um, anyway, so
you know, you don't, I was thinking,
I think one of these days when I'm going
to do is I'm just going to buy a used
Apache, you know, or
whatever the fuck they have.
Those Blackhawks is some shit.
I'm just going to learn how to fly that
and then I'm just going to join those
blackwater dudes. That's my apocalypse
thing. You know what I mean?
I'm not going to learn how to
kill people or anything like that.
I'll just be the shuttle guy.
I'll take you back from the front lines
back to base base camp and I'll just sit
there eating my soup. That's
my game plan. I'm all right.
Let's read some of the fucking
advertising here for this week,
which of course I didn't even deny even
look this shit up yet. No, I didn't. Uh,
I apologize for this. You know, I just,
it's just tiger woods let me down.
You know, I thought he was a
family member and, uh, I mean,
I haven't been this fucking,
I haven't been this
fucking distraught since,
uh,
Michael Jordan's acceptance speech at
the hall of fame when I found out who he
really was. I mean,
I was devastated and I just remember
all those times I had not hung out with
Michael Jordan or ever talked to him.
And I just feel like he really just,
you know, I just thought he was
better than that. I love that.
When he gave that speech and
everyone was like, wait a minute,
this guy's like fucking got ice
water in his veins and he's,
he's got a mean streak
him. It's like, yeah,
yeah. All those fucking people
who are never picked in gym class.
They were like, oh, this is why I sucked.
It wasn't just that I was uncoordinated.
I didn't have this killer
fucking instinct. He went
after his own Goddamn kids,
you know? And that's what it takes. All
right. Me On the better though though.
Mandy's beyond these Michael Jordan's
fucking long shorts dude too. To me,
Andy's me undies there that
long because it was dark.
He's fucking six six so it says Dick,
but his balls were rough until he got
me undies and then he made the hall of
fame.
He finally beat the fucking
Pistons because his pissed
inn was nice and fucking
soft with me on these. What
about Bill Walton? I'm all right.
Pride starts on the inside.
So celebrate yourself
with me on these Mondays.
Makes the ultimate feel good
undies with free shipping,
right to your door satisfaction.
Guaranteed. Oh my God,
I love designed in La,
Louisiana, Los Angeles.
Every pair of me undies is
made with micro modal, modal,
our fabric three times softer than cotton.
You know it's true because you have never
heard the cotton lobby ever debated.
There's soft, stretchy undies coming.
Every ever-changing array of colors and
patterns. No matter what your style,
they got something for you.
That's because me undies believes in
people feeling good and being themselves,
which is why me undies.
Why the oldies is putting their money
where their underwear is during pride
month for every pair of special addition.
Celebrate undies you buy during
pride me undies during pride.
Sorry.
Mandy's will donate $1 to
the Los Angeles LGBT center.
A you, you're pandering to your audience.
You got a bunch of colorful underwear,
right? I'd see what's going on.
You'd get did a little algorithm. Well,
more gay people than Straits a
by in these, you know we, oh,
maybe we got maybe gay people
by the gay people. Gay Guys.
I bet gay guys buy more underwear,
more underwear than straight guys too.
You know, because women are so fucking
forgiving, right? But guys are so visual,
so maybe gay guys are like,
I just feel a pressure that I always
have to have new underwear on because I
just feel such, I just feel like for me,
when somebody sees my Dick and ball first,
I want to have a brand new pair of
meundies. Good for them, good for them.
I bet if you looked that up, I bet
that's true. Generally speaking,
gay men have newer cleaner underwear
than a straight guy, right?
Anyways, as if you needed
another reason to try me undies,
they're offering 20% off your first
pair and a satisfaction guarantee that
you'll, you'll love them or your money
back. Just visit our URL, URL me,
undies.com/burr head to me on these
today and pick up a pair of special
additions. Celebrate undies.
You'll not only get a discount of awesome
these you'll be donating to an amazing
cause. Check out me undies.com/bird today.
I want to know when you're going to come
out with the Caitlin Janice. You know,
you guys ought to do it like a, uh,
like how basketball sneakers do.
They'll pick like, you know, they got
Jordans, they got the Colbys, you know,
and after that game seven, you know,
you know what's coming out next October.
The Olynyk ones,
every white guy with the dream's
going to be buying those.
They ought to do that
with me undies. You know,
you ought to have the tiger
woods, tiger woods, me undies,
the Caitlin Jenner's. Who else
has be a good person to fucking
money up with Rick flares? You
got to get the Rick flares townie.
It's a whole new market for you
guys. All right. Blue Apron.
Not only not okay, not all
ingredients are created equal. Well,
Jesus Christ like fucking Goenner's.
They're making America great again once.
Not all ingredients are
created equal, fresh,
high quality ingredients. Make
a real difference. Oh really?
Fresh, high quality ingredients make a
real difference when you're cooking. Oh,
I could just pull some out of
the trash. He's blue apron guys.
You're always learning something anyways.
It's important to know where your
food comes from. Really. I just,
I just thought I could keep eating
fucking cows that were fed other cows.
Talk about your personal experience
with Blue Apron. I've never used it.
Additional copy points feature
as desired. Okay. This is all,
this is all optional. Well, I'll go
right to the end then. Blue Apron.
A better way to cook now. I can't do
that. Alright. Additional cocaine.
Affordable. Okay.
Full for all you people are upside
down in your house out there. You know,
and nobody gives a shit and you still
want to eat well for less than $10 per
person per meal.
Blue Apron delivers seasonal recipes
along with pre-portioned ingredients to
make delicious home
cooked meals for rioty.
Choose from a vera, the
tiger woods, the tiger woods.
A option here for a variety.
If you don't want to come home to the
same fucking mashed potatoes and every
once in a while you want to have a
little fucking oven kettle. Okay?
For less than $10 per
person per meal. Sorry.
It's wrong with choose from a variety
of new recipes each week or let blue
aprons culinary team
surprise you. Holy Shit.
Recipes are not repeated within a
year, so you'll never get bored.
Guaranteed blue aprons
freshness guarantees,
promise that every ingredient in your
delivery arrives ready to cook or they'll
make it right.
Check out this week's menu and get the
first three meals for free with free
shipping by going to
blue apron.com/burr blue
apron.com/burger blue apron. A
better way to cook. And lastly,
but certainly not least,
[inaudible] dollar shave club.
Look at them with the Nice fucking
quick copy. They understand,
they understand my difficulties. Dollar
Shave Club is the smarter choice.
You'll get a great shave at a great price.
Conveniently delivered right to your
door. They have all the jerseys they had,
the steelies, the shacks, the
challenges, and more, sorry,
that was the voice I was just remembering
from MVP sports than read from way
back in the day when they didn't
want to hire somebody professional.
They just hired some fucking hot chick
that the owner was probably banging like
tiger woods. But he hasn't won a golf
tournaments and nobody knows, right?
Anyways, you no longer have
to Schlep to the store.
Buy a cheap disposable fucking
Raisa debt gives you a choice.
Okay. By educate what it,
you no longer have to Schlep to the store
to buy a cheap disposable razor that
gave you a cheap shave or spend a
fortune on razors with gimmickry shaving
technology so you didn't need and
when you use DOK Dollar Shave Clubs,
executive razor with the
doctor cabbies, easy shit.
[inaudible]
bled gently glides giving
you a smooth shave.
Dr Carver's shave butter is
transparent for a more precise shave,
helps prevent ingrown hairs
and fights. Razor bumps,
make the smarter choice by
dot. Joining Dollar Shave Club.
Do you know the people at Dollar Shave
Club at a custom Dr Covey's easy shave
butter tube that they framed?
Andrew finally was able to convince
me to take the thing. He goes,
they gave you something. I'm
like, I don't want any more shit.
I got too much shit. Then he goes,
now you got to see this thing.
And like fucking a year later I
finally got it from him and I'm like,
God dammit.
That's another thing I got to
put up on the wall in some day.
Explained to people, Oh,
I have mild dyslexia and I thought
Dr Carver's shave butter said,
Dr Carver's easy shave butter, and I
used to scream it and it's like cheap.
Bill. Do you have any more boring
stories framed on your wall?
Yes. Yes I do. Okay.
Make the smarter choice by joining
Dollar Shave Club for a limited time.
New members can get their first month of
the executive razor with a tube of the
toxic cabbies. Easy shape. Bought
it for only $5 with free shipping.
After that, razors are
just a few bucks a month.
That's a $15 value for only five bucks.
Then no hidden fees, no commitments.
Cancel anytime you like.
You can only get this offer
exclusively@dokdollarshaveclub.com slash
burger that's dollar shave club.com/.
Burn. All right, 44
minutes in. Just like that.
Okay. All right. Let's read these fucking,
let's read these fucking questions
here. All Right, Europe. Hi.
That's it. I like it. Short and sweet.
Been a huge fan of bill for many years.
Are there any plans for
touring Europe specifically?
The Netherlands would love to see him live
while I was there last year. Man,
if you will for a fan for many years
you should have checked my website. Um,
I think I'm going to go to Europe next
year and I'll probably build it around.
Um, a couple of F1 racist possibly.
I don't know when I'm
going to go over there,
but I'm definitely due to do a
run. I've got a bunch of new shit,
but you know,
I have to make sure it's at a
certain level before I go over there.
Cause Europe, he loves to just have
critic show up at shows without, you know,
the artist saying, Hey, can
you review this show? You know,
and they review it any way and they take
out their fucking goddamn steak knives
and they carve you up every fucking time.
So I always make sure I'm on my game here.
All right girl who stabbed boyfriend
isn't walking free. Okay, here we go.
This is the new, this is
new part of the podcast.
Everybody fucking correct
and old bill, you know.
[inaudible] that's why I made sure
to fucking like look up all my, uh,
my F1 shit. You know, cause
you caught damn cots, um,
girl who stabbed boyfriend. I have
a prediction about the red sox too,
by the way, which I will get to later
on, hopefully if I remember. All right,
that's a teaser and I might let
you down. I might disappoint you.
Like Michael Jordan, like
fucking tiger woods, you know,
all that entertainment that
they gave you when they watch,
when you get to watch them doing things
that had never been done before. Um,
all right girl who stabbed
boyfriend isn't walking free. Okay.
So this story was about a,
some lady at Oxford to fucking,
I don't know what the hell she did.
She stabbed her boyfriend in the leg
with a bread knife and blah, blah, blah,
blah, blah. And that, that guy
was like, well, I don't you have,
you know, yeah, I have all
this fucking, you know,
potential and all this type
of shit. So this person, um,
this person is writing back saying
she isn't going free. What's up?
I realize you like to make the excuse
that we shouldn't expect you to do any
actual research on stories you
talk about and that's fine.
Well then you should leave it at that,
sir. But in this particular story,
you ranted on Thursday's
pod. I didn't rant.
I'm joking around you
fucking overreacting.
Conc do you guys understand
what a rant is? Rant to me.
It's short for ranting and raving.
So you've got borderline have froth
coming out of your fucking mouth.
Joking around about a subject for
five minutes is not a fucking rant.
You stupid. Fuck God dammit.
All right. So even like right
there, to me, that's just,
I just fucking fucking wigged up for
a second there, but he re rant it.
Okay, I'm on Thursday. You didn't even,
you didn't even need to do research
to see how wrong you were. Again,
I'm not wrong. I'm being funny.
You fuck that Oxford girl isn't
getting off free because she's white.
Oh my God.
As the lovely Nia proposed and not
because she's a woman as the biliterate
birth suggested. She isn't
getting off at all. In fact,
it said right on the article you were
reading that she was going to be sentenced
in September and has been giving
a restraining order. Yeah,
I saw that and I also read
the fucking judge's quote.
I looked it up and I read
along with your pocket.
So sentencing was only postpone. She
isn't getting out of jail time yet.
Yeah, but don't you find it fucked
up? What are you going to address?
The fact that the judge
said you're so talented,
I don't want to derail your fucking
what you could possibly achieve.
You don't think that's
weird for him to say that.
Yeah,
and you don't think race and
gender affects your sentencing.
You don't think that? You don't think
that any day that there's all this racism,
there's all this sexism and all that,
but in the court of law there isn't.
There isn't status. There isn't.
You're at Oxford versus you did somebody
on the street and you stabbed somebody
with the fucking knife. You don't think
that any of that comes into play, sir.
So anyways, he says, if you
asked me which you didn't,
I think this is a good thing.
If she's is as bright as the
people at the school say she is,
she can definitely do a lot of good in
her career and sentencing her for a one
off would ruin that. So
you're agreeing with this guy.
Oh my God, this is fucking hilarious.
You're sitting there and saying
that I'm not paying this.
Basically what it is is
not that I was misinformed.
Okay? It's that you agreed with the
judge. He said, that being said,
she needs to be held responsible.
So what is it seeing as if
it was only a butter knife?
I think mandatory anger management
classes is in order at the very least.
Thanks. And Go fuck yourself. Come back
to Madison. You were great last time.
Go fuck yourself again, sir. She
stabbed somebody with a knife.
Okay,
let me let that sink in. She stabbed
someone with a fucking knife,
but because she goes to Oxford
and she could be a doctor.
Yeah, you're out of your fucking mind.
You're, you're just like the judge.
You're like, oh, look
at her. She's a girl.
She's doing so well in
school. She looks like me.
It was just a bread knife.
You're doing what they're doing.
In a perfect world, sir,
stabbing somebody with the knife and the
punishment is stabbing somebody with a
knife and the punishment
and that's fucking it.
Go Watch that fucking trap car thing
or whatever the fuck they call it,
where they park it down in the fucking
poor neighborhood and they arrest one
black eye after fuck another.
Yeah.
I mean it's, it's, they're
not trying to help anybody.
You don't think anybody
down there has potential.
You just going to say it's going
to fucking do that to them.
Why do they just do, why they don't,
don't they do that in a
fucking white neighborhood?
Okay.
Oh my God. I don't know. I don't, I
just don't see the world the way you do,
sir. And you see it the
way that judge does.
And I also think that you are like
what you're taking into consideration.
Okay.
Which is is the fact that she's at
Oxford and she could be a doctor.
You're completely in your,
you're now downplaying that she
stabbed someone and yes you are sir.
Yes you are.
Because you said she should take an anger
management classes at the very least.
Okay,
look, you might call me fucking overly
liberal, but if you stab someone,
you should go to jail regardless
of what your potential is.
Do you realize it's this woman,
if she becomes a surgeon will have a
knife in her hand every fucking day of a
goddamn career just about, and it
won't be a fucking butter knife.
Jesus fucking Christ.
And when she's goes to cut somebody open
and then finds out that they have state
insurance rather than private, what
the fuck is she going to do then?
Okay.
Just because you go to Oxford doesn't
mean you couldn't be a fucking lunatic.
You know what I mean?
And people in those schools commit
murders and they do commit crimes,
but they don't go to jail to wait.
Poor people with more of a tan do.
I don't know if you've noticed that.
So for us to bring up the fact that
she was a woman and that she was white.
I was not, we were not uninformed.
We were actually Morton. I actually,
you know, I'm going to
pat myself on the back.
I'm more fucking enlightened
than you are. Okay?
Because I'm not saying that because of
who she is, she should get punished more.
She should get the punishment.
I think once you stabbed somebody,
what the fuck you doing in the rest of
your life is out the goddamn window.
Okay.
And I know what you guys are
going to say. Well, they do that.
They do that all the time.
They fucking take into consideration
if people have children and Blah, blah,
blah, blah. Yeah, I know they
do. But the consideration is,
is a lot smaller by the level of Tan
you have and whether you have a dick
hanging between your legs and
not, and that's the fucking truth.
Going to a bar, a woman
can slap a guy in the face,
dump a drink over his fucking
head. She's not getting kicked out.
She's not. If she's, if she's hot,
she's a fucking Willdabeast. Yeah.
They'll throw her out in the fucking
dumpster. Come on people. This isn't,
this isn't new information. All right.
Stop acting like good Lord. All right.
Why Airlines lost their privilege
now. Hey Bill, big fan.
Love your podcast.
You recently asked why airlines are not
as prestigious as it was in the 70s as a
pilot. I have an answer for you. Oh,
I love when the pilots, right in sky
pilot. Why is, and it's still great.
In 1978 huh? I'm Jim McConnell.
Jimmy Carter signed the airline
declar deregulation act.
Ah,
leave it to a peanut farmer from Georgia
to ruin the fucking prestige of airline
travel. Prior to this law,
the government allowed equal usage of
federal airways among all the airlines.
All right. You already lost
me. Let me read this slower.
The government allowed equal usage of
federal airways among all airlines.
So the only way for airlines to compete
effectively was with good customer
service. Okay. After the
law went into effect,
airlines were able to bid for
exclusive usage of certain airways.
The Airways are basically the
streets in the sky. So different.
Okay. Oh, I see. So then, and everybody
had their territory. So it was like,
that's right. There was eastern
airlines, they just flew there. Okay.
All right. American and
United flew cross country.
So it was like wrestling back in the day
where everybody had their territories
and then rather than have one guy
dominate the whole thing like
Vince, it became a bidding war.
Okay. After the law went into effect,
airlines were able to bid
exclusive usage of certain airways.
So Airways essentially gained monopolies
on most of their routes with customers
having little or no say
in which airline to take.
The airlines were able to get us
by the balls. So now airlines,
business strategy has shifted from good
customer service to monopolizing their
airways and packing as many people
as possible into their plane planes.
Hope this helps. Ah, it started
to, what should I look up?
I should look up the airline deregulation
act now that all of a sudden in the
era of fake news,
I'm being suddenly being held
accountable for what the fuck. I said,
I can't believe this. I, you
guys are so disappointing me.
Can somebody please write in and mock
these fucking assholes. All right?
Not saying that the, the, um, the pilot
here, alright. Airline deregulation act,
airline D, Reg.
You Lation Act Jimmy Carter and affects,
let's see what we got
here. Oh my God. All right.
Wiki a law that changed the airline
industry. That's the one that looks like,
okay, this is the one I will read up on.
Are you guys going to try to make
me informed and then I'll join?
You know what happens when you
don't have to become you informed.
You become an arrogant ass. You
know, you start smoking a pipe.
You fucking eyebrows are always trying
to touch each other as your wrinkle up
your forehead. No one wants
to be around that. All right?
A law that changed the airline
industry beyond recognition. 1978.
All right?
Okay. Before deregulations
airlines competed on service alone,
as fairs were regulated by the
government, I didn't know that. I mean,
granted I was fucking 10 years old, 1978.
Many remember this era fondly
is the golden age of aviation.
When stewardesses as
flight attendants, uh,
were then known. Carved,
I can chateau Breon on rolling silver
carts and airlines put piano lounges and
upper decks of their Boeing seven 40
sevens passengers dressed up to board
flights and flying was glamorous and
exciting and mainly for the rich.
Ah, that's why the liberals
deregulations resulted in the
rise of a new kind of airline.
The low cost carrier LCC at
the time of deregulation,
southwest airline was a small regional
airline prevented by cab rules.
I don't know what that is from
flying outside of Texas today,
southwest is the largest domestic us
carrier in terms of passenger traffic.
Something no one could
have foreseen in 1978 yeah,
and that's back when
stewardesses were fucking hot.
So now it's a bunch of animals. They
pack us all in and then it's just like,
yeah, all the hotties
are like, well fuck this.
I'm going to go a sell Jello shots at
a goddamn one of those DJ shows. Wait,
Bay Bay. Bay Bay. Wow.
Wow, wow, wow. Wow. Right.
Southwest is a success story,
but deregulation aloud. Yeah.
I hate flying southwest. I
fucking hate it. You know why?
I hate how the stewardess is sit there
and making jokes and fucking around.
It's like, dude, my life
is in your hands here.
You're not making me more relaxed doing
your fucking Dean Martin impression.
Uh, but deregulation allowed airlines
to innovate new business models. People,
people express, I remember that.
Remember value jet, that one went down.
People Express may have come and
gone. It may someday be revived,
but it and others like it shook up the
white glove world of the U s airline
industry. And
Yeah,
democracies travel.
Hope I said that right.
We may peer through our rose colored
glasses and yearn for the days of Chateau.
Bring all in piano lounges.
But ultimately companies like southwest
and newer ones like spirit allowed more
people to fly more often. Yeah.
And now look at the result.
You've got people with no shoes on
walking into the bathroom. Oh my God,
it all fucking came full circle.
Okay.
Holy Shit. Do I like being informed?
Deregulation left the international
carriers like Pan Am and Braniff and to a
lesser extent, Twa,
Trans World Airlines without
robust domestic feeder networks.
I don't know what that means.
And it allowed domestic carriers like
Delta airlines to apply for international
routes. Pan-Am and Braniff scrambled
to create domestic networks,
but ultimately were unsuccessful,
although it took until 2000 for Twa
to be absorbed into American Airlines.
And some argue with it,
massive consolidation of the u s
airline industry in the last decade,
which has resulted in three large
carriers for when southwest is included is
deregulations final act. Then
network carriers that survive delta,
United and American learn to be tough
competitors and combined existing domestic
networks with the international networks
acquired in large part by carriers like
Pan Am that didn't make
it get the fuck out.
So now they have to drag people
off flights, barefooted, lunatics,
and then you've got
people fucking, you know,
you haven't seen those people that just
fly around the world all the time trying
to get in miles and shit just
created all these bottom feeders.
Wow. Do you think a VIP airline
would, would make it? I wonder,
you know, in this era of
Donald Trump, if they just,
if they didn't even try to
be nice, just be, I wish,
I wish I could do a Trump impression.
She'd be a lot of animals if flying
bear food, a lot of benefit and then,
you know,
liberals would be like, do you,
we use saying that beer footy
people shouldn't be allowed to
let it be your feet.
Let a pair of feet to,
can you, what if want,
if they had a fuck it,
you couldn't do it nowadays
if you had a fucking
topline airline, okay.
All first class seats,
all hot stewardesses, you know,
first of all, all the fucking,
you know, all the fucking
feminists would be up in arms,
would all be up in arms saying that
they, you're objectifying these women,
blah blah, blah, blah, blah. And
at the end of the F, I dunno,
I agree with some of that feminist shit,
but a lot of times I just feel like
it's women who aren't good looking,
hating on good looking women and just
being mad that could look and women don't
have to work as hard. You know,
it's like
that whole thing that you're going
to somehow get people to give,
not as good looking women, not as
good looking men, not as strong men,
like a chance. That's not how it works.
You gotta like you gotta look at it like
sports and realize that you're not the
Jordan. You're not Sidney Crosby.
All right? You're on the fourth line,
okay? So what you have to be is you have
to be a fucking, you gotta be a Gamer.
You know, this is coming from a bald,
redheaded male. So go fuck yourself.
If you think I'm being elitist
here, okay? You gotta be scrappy.
You got to go in the corners, all right?
You've got to drop the gloves every once
in a while you got to do that, okay?
You're not gonna get the calls.
You're going to have to work 10 times
fucking harder than other people to get,
you know, half as much or
however the expression goes.
But it's gonna make you stronger. You
know what's great is your fall from grace,
from your youth. Six as you slide
into a four is not that bad.
But at the end of
everybody's life, everybody
looks like a four or a two. Okay.
Yeah,
but you have a nice soft landing.
You do a little bit of a belly flop.
You get the wind knocked out of
you between 20 and 60 all right.
These fucking tents. I mean, they're
falling off the top of a goddamn building.
Okay? They in a lot of them, they
don't survive it. They don't.
If you look at their botox faces,
they look like they landed face first.
They fucking lips are all
swollen. I mean, Jesus Christ,
look at these fucking Mike Watches
this show and these women will not stop
taking fat from the back of their arms
and injected them in their ass and they
got these stupid look and fucking acids
now and their legs look like my legs
with this weird, like
they look like ostriches.
I don't know why they did that. I, I just,
I just don't fucking
understand why and what point.
It's like they're literally like Michael
Jackson where Michael Jackson couldn't
see what he's doing to his face.
These women cannot see what they're doing
to their asses. I don't understand it.
So anyways,
do you know what that was
actually fascinating and I
make fun of the fact that
I'm not a well read guy cause it gives
me license to be lazy and that's what I
like to do best. Okay. But if you fucking
assholes, they're going to meet me.
Keep reading. I did. I did enjoy
that. I do enjoy, I like drum shit.
I like aviation. I like that
type of shit. All right,
so if you're going to fucking really
start, hold my feet to the fire here,
could you please try to keep it a,
I don't know.
Well I guess I have the power, right?
I have the power where
I can actually decide,
um,
what the fuck it is that I want to
read or what I don't want to read. Um,
speaking of which,
for some reason I woke up this morning
thinking about Roy Haynes and the fact
that he's still alive and still doing
gigs and all the fucking people these
played with, like I saw a bunch of
great jazz dramas before they passed.
I saw a Max Roach. I saw Tony Williams,
I saw Louie Bellson and I saw Roy Haynes.
I saw Roy Haynes like 20 something
years ago when he was in his seventies.
He's now 92 and I looked it up
like, is this guy still on the road?
He's got a road gig coming up
and uh,
September, like the blue note in
New York City and he's from Roxbury,
Massachusetts. A fellow Boston guy.
I'm a suburb guy. He's
actually in Boston. But um,
yeah,
I don't know. I think
that's pretty fucking cool.
That guy's still gigging
out there. I mean,
you talk about a guy he
played with Charlie Parker,
Miles Davis, Sarah Vaughan,
all the way, all the way up. Right
up through like young people today.
The guy's been playing drums
professionally for 70 goddamn years,
so I dunno if you're into drums, you
got to go see that guy. All right,
let me go, uh, let me
read some more of the, uh,
all right, let me read these
last two. Cultural appropriation.
Dear Billy rationale,
a things are getting crazy these days
because of technology. It's definitely
a lot easier to be critical
of what everyone does.
I'm sure you've experienced this before
where people try and misrepresent what
you say for whatever self-serving
reason they may have. Yes,
of course. That would be
the Huffington Post. Uh,
one of the things going on today that
really bugs me is the accusation of
cultural appropriation. I hate picking
extreme sides to any arguments.
So I will say,
I do think that there are
cases of cultural disrespect.
Let's say someone wears a religious or
cultural garb and is overly disrespectful
for the purpose of
trolling. That could be,
that could be cultural appropriation.
You put that in quotes.
So do you not think it is a,
but almost everything anyone does is
derived from another culture in some
respect.
There is a youtube video where a young
black college girl borates a hippie for
his corn rolls and it seems a bit silly
because a kid is just doing what every
other wookies who listened to fish
do. I don't know what a wookie is.
Is that somebody in Indian Shabaka
now fucked up. I got to look this up.
What the fuck is a way
a white something.
Wookie meaning slang,
uh, a walkie urban dictionary. A what?
G. Oh, walkie
is a Harry yet modernized human being.
That commonly is seen in the western,
in the western most regions of Washington,
a gentle creature by nature but
tends to get a little erratic when it
overindulge itself with
its favorite foods.
Its diets consists mainly of
a blend of barley and hops.
If you see these creatures a bit cautious
as to whether you should provide him
with these items,
they will commonly respond to
the name of Richard Pulliam,
but be very worry of these
creatures. I have no idea there.
Usually I'm remembering a certain
brand of cookie that is very chewy.
Oh,
walkie is a lifeless idiot whose whole
existence consists of falling around jam
bands.
Here we go and not showering or shaving
when they're not panhandling or trying
to rip people off.
They're selling Veggie burritos or
grilled cheese to fund their useless
existence. They stand for nothing
and care about nobody else.
Not to be confused.
What the hippie AP as someone who lives
a certain lifestyle due to their belief.
If these often shower and have jobs a
used in a scented shows yo those wikis
over there trying to sell beat roles.
That's from fucking 2003 so I guess
they'd been around for awhile. Okay.
All right. Let me get back to the,
okay, so now I know what a wookie is.
I know what a Wiki is and I know about
airline deregulation and now I'm going to
be in suffer both.
The next fucking social event is I
try to work both of those into the,
um,
where the fuck is it?
I was an anthropology major,
which doesn't make me an expert,
but it definitely informs
my opinion of this.
I went to culinary school after college
and learned even more about cultures
through their food.
I came upon this article and wanting
to get your take upon it to take on a
couple of girls in Portland, Oregon
started a food truck selling Mexican food.
They traveled around and learn recipes.
The way every chef I've
ever known has has done,
they are accused of cultural
appropriation because they're not Mexican.
I'm not going to go on a tirade of
motherfucker motherfucks but my adrenaline
really starts going.
When I think about this.
I haven't heard you speak about cultural
appropriation yet and wanted to get
your take. Here's the link.
Oh, the Huffington Post.
What a fucking surprise.
Thanks for your podcast. Uh,
you're a great dad and husband. How do
you know that? You have no idea. Um,
I hate the fucking Huffington Post.
Um,
they're always trying to stir
up some shit. You know what? I,
I hate all these organizations that
try to act like they're their news
organization and you read two articles
and he know who everybody on the website
voted for. Essentially.
It's like back in the day,
like it was supposed to be in
and out. Fewer journalists.
She was supposed to just sort of
present what the fuck happened,
not making a Om. If you say this, um,
that's probably because
you're doing that, that site,
that whole fucking website. And
I shouldn't just single them off.
There's a bunch of them out there and,
but they're held in like this as steam.
I just don't understand it. Um,
anyways, cultural appropriation is,
uh, I don't fucking know why.
You know, look,
if you have an appreciation for Mexican
food and you still learn how to cook it
and then you sell it, I think at
that point, if you become successful,
that's when people get annoyed by it.
And a college kids are really
extreme in their thoughts as I do.
You know, you're fucking break
and free your parents, you know,
when you've got some anger issues probably
towards your parents. So you're very,
you're very open to a radical
fucking sort of ideas,
you know, going all the way over
here, all the way over there.
It's a very dangerous time in your life
because you make very extreme judgment.
Snap judgment calls with your
young brain, um, as I did.
And that can cause you to do
stupid shit. Like join cults,
uh, blow yourself up at a
fucking concert, you know,
for some stupid fucking
cause all the way to like,
I don't know what fucking
without a condom. You know,
you just let me pretty fucking wide thing.
This is why you don't
talk about shit like this.
I don't know what a cultural
appropriation is. I don't know what it is.
All I know is that my
culture is the matrix,
so everybody's allowed, you know,
I don't get upset when people get on
airplanes. Ba that's a white shit,
you know?
Yes.
Um, I would say that if the two white
girls being white and they're making great
fucking Mexican food, good for them,
but if they're sitting there wearing
a fucking sombrero and talking like
speeding and zealous when they do
it, yeah, then I would get upset.
But you know,
there's plenty of Asian in fuse days
and French and fuse that and um,
okay.
Cultures to me and all of
that shit. To me it's like,
it's like the MMA. How
was the, how was like,
how good were the martial arts when
it was, you were just one discipline,
you know, every way I am a
Kido, I am fucking taekwondo.
I do karate, I fucking box
or whatever. And then a guy,
Bruce Lee comes around, he's
like, I'll take a little this,
I'll take a little of that.
Wasn't he doing that? You know,
and then he was teaching it to fucking
the round dyed guys over here and
everybody over in Asia was
like, hey, that's our shit.
Don't be showing it to their
shit and now look at it.
Now look how great the
fucking fighters are.
Okay.
You know what I mean? I would
love to see Bruce Lee today,
if he him back then if he got into the
fucking ring, you know what I mean?
Did he ever have to deal with a double
leg take down what would happen to him?
Does he have a ground in pound
defense ground and pound didn't exist.
Could that man fight on his back?
That's how much it's progressed.
So I feel everything should
get all fucking mixed up
and then shit spins out of
that. And he just like, uh,
I think it's just when you start to act
like you're the thing that you're doing,
you know what I mean? Like, um,
and people do, but the thing is,
is that if you start getting into like,
like whatever Japanese cuisine, okay, Oh,
you get into anime, whatever. I'm
watching this animated show. But like,
I just watch it and I appreciate it.
I don't start walking around with a rising
sun fucking tee shirt and I get some
swords, you know, Chris crossed
on my walls. Do, you know,
start sitting on the floor and a
pillow with a little short table.
You know what I mean? I mean, W W I
dunno, I don't know where you, uh,
I think it's all how you do it.
I mean,
if I walk into an Asian person's house
and they got a bunch of shit from my Kia,
I don't go like, you know,
you're appropriating my culture.
What's what that l shaped couch.
But they're also not oppressing
me and I'm not oppressing anybody,
but over all the fucking, you know,
long tied concept, the top are.
So that's what it really
comes down to. It really,
I think it really comes down to a white
people get held to that standard of, of,
of cultural appropriation
because, uh, you know, we can,
the, the damage we can do and we
can be really ignorant with it.
And then other times people
are just being conti, like,
I'm not gonna read this fucking article,
but if it's just a couple of white
chicks making Mexican food and they're
crushing it, you know, and their dress
like white checks guy like, oh my God,
who wants the Berretta? I don't
think there's a problem with that.
If they're killing it.
Right. It's a fucking food truck. Fill
your pie hole up and shit. I don't know.
All right girlfriend.
I, Hey man. What's up? Um,
I just had a few questions.
Sorry for the lack of punctuation.
We'll use parenthesis when he said that
I flew this girl out all the way to
Japan's, you know something. Fuck
you. I'm not reading this shit.
You, I this, you know what?
You rewrite this fucking thing.
You rewrite this fucking thing. Okay.
And then I'll read it. Go Fuck Yourself.
Sorry for the lack of punctuation.
Yes. Sorry. And I fucking rignet.
There you go. I draw the
line at lack of punctuation.
I hate when people fucking
go. Sorry if you, sorry.
You would have taken the time
to, to put some shit in there.
You didn't, you're not sorry.
You fucking lazy. So fuck off.
Now I'm going to be lazy right back to
you. I'm not reading you Goddamn Shit.
However, if you want to fix it,
put some punctuation in it and I will
read it. God Damn it, Al read it.
All right. The Red Sox,
we're in second place in the evil
empire Yankees are in first place.
Those evil motherfuckers with all their
home grown talent. And here we are,
the young upstarts with a $215 million
team just doing anything we can
to try to keep up with
them. Um, I want to know,
I want to fucking know, cause I
heard he lost a bunch of weight.
I know he ended up getting
fucking hurt again.
I want to know when Pablo is
coming back. I don't know why.
I just feel like he's have gonna have
a great second half of the season.
Pablo Sandovall and he's going
to earn his goddamn money.
And I think the red sox I get,
they're going to catch fire here right
before the all star break and they,
and it's going to be Yankees,
red sox, Yankees, red sox,
and it's going to be great again.
It's going to be fucking hilarious.
Cause now we're the fucking
evil empire that could
spend 200 fucking million
dollars. Um, that's my prediction.
It's going to go down to them and, um,
ESPN will blow the Yankees because they
have homegrown talent and they will
fucking trash the red sox for
spending all this fucking money.
Like they never trashed the Yankees
when they did it back in the day because
that's how it works. Because when
the Yankees win the world series,
ESPN goes in, all is right in the
baseball universe. It's just like, oh,
so you guys are all Yankee fans there.
Why does it make it right?
I never understood that, that
they play favorites like that,
but I guess that's what they do. So
you know what? Fuck them. Fuck you too.
Have a great couple of days.
I'll check in on you on Thursday.
Be careful around those grills you have.