Here's a good one. Should I kick
my neighbor's ass? Uh, yes, yes.
Generally speaking, yes. Yes. Uh,
hey, bill loved the podcast. No. Yeah,
that's east coast. Oh, okay.
Uh, that's why people bitch.
Where the fuck is a podcast? I need
some advice on what to do about the gut.
This guy lives in a few
houses down from me.
I'm a third year college student and
I live at home. My parents moved, uh,
to go live in the state above mine.
I mean north and I currently reside, uh,
alone while they are
trying to sell the house.
A few months ago I was driving home,
coming back from a gym and while
I was driving in my neighborhood,
I saw this guy step in the middle of
the road, about 20 yards from my car.
He was yelling something at me, but
I couldn't hear what he was saying.
I slowed down and stopped my car right
in front of him and he came to my window
and told me to get out. I was totally
confused and thought I'd run over.
I thought I ran over his
cat or something. Also,
I think he just moved in because
I never seen the dude in my life.
So I rolled down the window and
ass. What did you say? He goes,
I'm going to kick your fucking
ass. Get out of the car.
This guy's probably in his forties and
asked to be around five 10 is that,
is this me? I'm 250 pounds. That's not me.
I'm 21 six three 200 I do crossfit and
I wrestle occasionally at another gym I
go to. So I get out of the car and I'm
standing there trying to figure it out.
What the Hell is going on? The
guy starts moving towards me,
so I take the initiative
and take a step towards him.
We ended up being an inch from each other
and he's trying to do some alpha male
shit by just staring at me. But
I have the height advantage,
so I'm looking down at him.
At least 10 seconds go
by before the guy goes.
How fast do you think you were
going back there? I say, I dunno,
probably around 30 the speed
limit. My neighborhood is 20,
and I know I wasn't going that
much over it. Then he goes,
I'm not going to have my children playing
in the yard if I know assholes like
you are driving like that in
the neighborhood after. Uh,
he said that I saw his wife and son were
a little off to the side of the road.
Once the word asshole left his
mouse, I was fucking pissed.
I wanted to just tackle the Dick and put
him to sleep in front of his wife and
kid to teach them a lesson,
but I pussied out and just apologize to
them and said that I was really Sally,
sorry. And it wouldn't happen again.
The guy then gives me a fucking little
smirk and turns around and says while
walking away with his back, turn it
better not or you know what will happen.
Ah, yeah, yeah.
You definitely should have kicked his
ass. You should have kicked his ass. Yeah.
What a fuck did you realize? What a
good do you realize what this kid did?
He's such a fucking gentleman.
He could have kicked the
fucking shit out of this guy.
He saw his wife and kid there. It
would've been a masculinity. Yeah.
His Dad is superman. He sits there. You
know what is? It's that little smirk.
Yeah, that fucking smart guy. But that
Khan steals from work. Yeah, I bet he,
sorry dude. That's the first time
I, I literally had to walk away.
You fucking cunt. Yeah.
He should have kicked that guy's
ass. But it's a good cause.
It's good that you didn't do it,
but because you weren't the
bigger person as they say.
But he definitely has it come in.
Then he writes snap to do that
shit. I wanted to explode.
I mean the guy totally disrespect me,
so I get in my car and drive
off end of the story wrong.
I couldn't get this fucking
guy out of my head. I t dude,
I can't get out of my head.
I'm going to actually fantasize
that I was there and he did that.
What I would want to do, I've already,
you know what I would fucking do?
I would wait till he was alone.
Don't do this shit. Don't do this,
but I know what you just want to get,
get the guy alone and be like, Hey,
what are you going to do now?
Huh? What are you going to do now?
Just get right in his fucking
grill and have him back down. Yeah.
Or I would almost just say
the guy say, hey listen man,
just call them over the
car and just say, listen,
I just wanted you to know the other day
that if I wanted to I could have fucking
stuffed you in my trunk.
Tied you up like a fucking pressel and
ass rates you in front of your fucking
wife. But I chose not to. Okay.
Cause I didn't want your son to know
what a little fucking f I can't say it.
Pussy. Yeah, he has for it. That
wouldn't have been homophobic either.
I wouldn't be me talking about gay
people. That's such a fucking pussy move.
Yeah. And if for some reason
but, but I'm putting up no,
then that's what you say. Maybe do
like Colombo to say. Listen man,
I got to ask you something cause I'm
six foot three, I crossfit. I wrestle.
Okay. And just looking at you. I
know I could tie into a pretzel.
I know I could do it if I want
to, but the confidence you had,
I just want to know what is
your background. You know,
cause you know I'm a real
competitive guy. You know,
if you've got some sort
of martial arts training,
you know I would love to
have you once we didn't.
You come down to the gym sometime
when your wife and kid aren't there.
So I don't have to feel guilty when I
fuck you up and close both of your eyes
with this one and his friend over here.
What does the rest of the thing
say? I don't even need to read it.
It's not a but it's not
over though. I know.
Because this is what's happening now.
This is what happens when you do
the right thing in life. Okay?
When you know you, it eats away
at you. You have to make peace.
You have to make peace and you've got to
tell yourself the lie that someday this
guy's going to get his. And you know
what? He doesn't guys like this.
Don't get theirs. Oh, that's
smart. I see this kid,
this kid really painted a fucking
picture. I can. This is driving me nuts.
He goes, I couldn't get
this guy out of my head.
A week went by and I was still
thinking about that asshole too.
I would think about this
guy. 20 years from now,
two weeks later I was driving home from
school and I see the guy rolling his
garbage can out to the curb.
I slow down to fucking under 20 and I
know this because I looked down at my
spit, Thomas pedometer. I
pretend to stare the guy down,
so I look at him and he looks
at me and yell, slowdown.
Wow. Now when he said
that I am fucking raging,
I wanted to stop my car and do some
ground and pound on his face. Yeah.
This kid knows what he's doing.
This isn't wrestling like
this kid's doing UFC shit,
but did I know I just drove off like a
fag the next day I talked to my friend
about it,
about what had happened and he said
that this guy said the same shit to him.
If he said it, he would have put
them on his ass. I know you do.
You know what I would've
done? He told me that, uh,
if he says he's going to kick your ass,
then that's a threat so
you can defend yourself.
Don't listen to your dumb friend.
He's saying you won't get arrested.
So a few months have passed and I'm still
thinking about this asshole every time
I drive by his house. Fast
forward, uh, two yesterday and,
um, I'm biking in my neighborhood.
Let's do an iHeart and I
hear a honk from behind me.
So I pull my bike over to the side of the
road and it's none other than the same
dude in his Ford F150 driving along and
he looks at me and gives me the middle
fucking finger. Wow.
Now granted I was in the middle of the
road and didn't hear the guy coming
because I was listening to music, but
still the middle finger. So I bike home,
take a shower and try to convince
myself to walk over to dude's house and
confront him. But after a
couple minutes of pacing,
I just decided to wait it out until the
asshole does one more thing. I mean,
I don't want to get arrested. So my
question is what the hell should I do?
I mean, every time I
drive by this guy's house,
now I want to fucking veer off the road
and ran my car into the middle of his
living room. Any advice would be good. A,
all of my friends think I should go over
there, but I want a second opinion. Um,
you can't do anything to this guy unless
he puts his hands on you unless he puts
his hands on you. This is
just one of these things,
but you can do to him what he's doing
to you. This guy has an insane temper.
So, uh, you know, I'm not advocating
legally, so you don't do this,
but like, um, I don't,
I don't what I would next time, you know,
if you see him out in the yard or
something, this is what you do.
I have a great idea. Do you have any
friends who are really good mechanically?
Um, why don't you take
your credit card out,
go down to the fucking
auto store or whatever.
I'll go online and buy like one of
those fucking train horns and have it
installed in your car and next
time you drive down the street,
just be sort of zigzagging down the
street just to get this guy to be fucking,
you know, getting all
like, Bro, what the fuck?
And the second he starts screaming,
you lay on that fucking horn as loud as
humanly possible and you blow out his
ear drums. That's what
I would, but then again,
then the no one do shit like this.
He would say that I have
permanent hearing damage.
You know what I think you should do?
Maybe because I'm a female and I'm
all about the cycle of revenge. Okay.
Psychological warfare. What
should you, what should he do?
I think when the husband is not
home, I don't know if how he,
if he knows his schedule,
whatever he needs to go over there when
the wife is at home and be like, listen,
you know, I'm so sorry about that time
that I was speeding. I really, you know,
but your, your husband seems really upset.
I'm really not trying to be like that.
I would never do anything like that.
And women are like, oh no, no, no.
Cause she knows her husband is a psycho.
Right. And like, I mean she could
turn around and be like, yeah,
you shouldn't do that either.
But I have a feeling she's not like that
and he can just go over and just make
nice and be like the sweet
kid that's helping out or oh,
do you need me to take the bowels
out? And then, but then the,
I feel like maybe that would fuck with
the husband and he's like sitting there
sipping tea with the wife
and Oh look who came over.
He just wanted to apologize in person.
And you know, I dunno. I Dunno.
There's there's, and then
fuck the wife. You No,
no, no. He should fuck his wife.
He should fucking play with
his kid in the backyard.
Like the toss the
football around with him.
Be More like rather he never had
nothing like just start keeping him in a
finger. Listen, this is the deal. All
you gotta do is just give him the finger,
give him the finger right back. Cause uh,
this guy thinks you're a bitch right
now. So all you got to do is, you know,
you can just yell back. Just say,
you know, just give them the finger,
yell back at him when he's in the
driveway. I would like swerve,
add him and then swerve back.
Just fuck with the guy. He's an,
I mean just do that once because the
next time you might have like a video
camera, but um, uh, I,
I just don't wanna get any, I
don't get any. You know what?
If I was in that situation, uh, dude,
you know what I would dope. Yeah.
Oh Monday morning quarterback.
Look while I was in that situation
with that other guy, right? Yeah.
At the last place we lived and I didn't
fuck with him cause he was an old guy.
I just didn't fuck with him.
And now we find out he has dementia
and all this shit. So I'm cite,
I never yelled at the guy, you know
what you do now. You know, what's,
what really diffuses angry guys like
that or it makes them even more angry.
It's just laugh at him. Just keep
laughing at him, laugh at him,
give him the finger and just keep
calling him tough guy. All right.
They're tough guy. Anything do
anything. You just keep calling them?
Anything that is remotely all
right there, Chuck Norris.
Anything you want to say to this guy
that will bait him into hitting you?
This is a really a fuck.
This is a great question and I don't
want to get in trouble if some shit goes
down so you shouldn't do
anything, sir. Wink, wink, wink.
Um, this guy's such a dick.
I, I, I always say, you know,
fucking with somebody
whose car is like a pussy.
Move with this guy is such a
dick and he has like such a, uh,
oh my God dude.
How many times you thought about throat
to choke slam and that guy ran into the
hood of your car repeatedly when
you said, I can step into my trunk.
Veggie like a Pretzel and ass
rape and your boy, nobody.
If you just said it really calmly,
if you set a comedy with
sort of a smile on your face,
you'll come off like a fucking
maniac. Yeah, that's true.
If you scream that at somebody,
you just sound like you're quoting,
like you know how Cogan or something.
Right? Let me tell you something, brother.
Come to Saturday. I'm going to
bet you in a pretzel asked for AP.