Hey, what's going on? It's Bill Burr and
It's time for the Monday morning. No,
it isn't. God dammit. It's a Thursday
afternoon just before Friday,
Monday morning podcast and
Ahhh,
just checking in on you and the volumes
too loud and the volumes to love what's
going on. Hey, hey. Hey, test has
two, two, check check two, two.
Oh Jesus Christ.
Happy Thanksgiving to you.
Happy thanksgiving,
United States of America.
Ah,
happy Thanksgiving to you.
What's going on?
Happy Thanksgiving to the United
States of America's citizens.
Each and every one of you.
I am thankful to be in America.
Sitting here with my gun,
eating the fucking doughnut,
getting fat and having fun.
My wife miles off to me going
to slap her in the face,
get my sales and pie,
and then make fun of another race.
Hey, all right. What's going on?
This is it for all you around the world
and you want to know what the fuck at
Thanksgiving is all about.
This is what it's about.
It's about sitting down and overreading
celebrating the fact that on this day,
thanksgiving,
1776,
the United States of America kicked
the shit out of the fucking bread.
It's British people at the
battle of thanksgiving.
You know, this black dude
Crispus addicts act, acts,
Attica, whatever his fucking name
was, he came walking up and he said,
he said, Yo, motherfuckers, what's,
what's your powdered wig pitch?
Right?
And then the English were like, Whoa,
why you can't talk to me like dad,
especially with dead skin complexion.
Then they tried to shoot him,
but he fucking Stab King Henry
the, uh, the eighth. Yeah,
right in the throat with the, uh, with
the Turkey bone, broke his larynx.
The guy survived. Really took
it out on his wife, you know,
beat her to death with a chastity belt.
This is all true and you can look it up,
but at the end of the day,
the end of the day,
that small act was what
created this country. And,
um,
I'm thankful for Crispus addicts where
his name was going back to my history
classes. You know, was that the
only black guy they talked about?
I think it was.
They sort of touched on slavery.
Um, all these white guys
did this amazing stuff.
Slavery and then they
built the White House.
Um, anyways, I don't know what the
fuck I'm talking about. Who Cares?
Hang on. Here we go. We're back.
We're back. Yeah. I don't give a shit.
This is one of these podcasts. I don't
care. I don't care from entertaining you.
I don't care if I'm confusing you.
I don't care if I'm ruining your fucking
meal because I am in a resentful moved.
A lot of people are thankful today.
I am not thankful and I'll tell you why.
Cause I'm working right now.
I'm doing a podcast because you can hear
my daughter screaming in the background.
She's already half in the bag.
Everybody's boozing. Evan,
a great time and old Billy.
No Fun little Billy.
No Fun is continuing with his streak.
Why is he continued with his streak?
Is it cause he's vain?
I don't know why I'm continuing.
I just don't want to be a fat
booze bag again. Can I just,
I'm just going to ride out the
rest of the year. I'll see what,
I'll see what the vibe is for 2018.
You know,
that first day when I roll out of bed,
I'll see how I feel.
Granted, I'll be at the rose
bowl, so I'll be very excited. Um,
which this year is going to be a,
as one of those semifinal playoffs.
I think the Miami hurricanes are going to
be there. Um, somebody was saying that,
I have no idea. All I know is I'm
going, I'm going right that, that,
that's what I did.
I bought some tickets for myself and my
friends for the Rose Bowl because I was
giving thanks to living in this wonderful
country that has the stadiums that you
can go to,
right.
It used to be able to get drunk and
have a good time. Can't do that anymore.
You can't do that anymore.
Somebody was jerking off vigorously with
the fucking shrimp cocktail and now to
everybody, shut it down. It's
going to be no fun anymore.
No Fun in the comedy clubs,
Dude.
Fucking the vibe and comedy clubs,
depending on what you talk about,
if you talk about absolutely nothing,
I'm sure nothing has changed,
but if you even remotely
touch on fucking anything,
there's so many subjects now and these
fucking millennials, they swear to God,
they just, they just sit there.
It's like doing a cruise ship Gig.
Yeah.
Can you imagine, sorry,
didn't mean to scream,
but can you imagine the fucking midlife
crisis that millennials are going to
have?
They're not having any fun.
This sitting around staring
at the goddamn screens,
they're afraid to say anything.
Everything's been judged and labeled.
It's like this, this fucking bizarre
like way back in the day, hey,
back in the day they, they used
to say that the government, right,
they're going to come down on you,
man.
They're going to take away free speech
man and Blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
Wasn't social media.
Social media has made
everything so fucking important.
Your quote,
everybody's on eggshells.
It's really different.
The amount of times I have to fucking
sit there is almost a 50 year old man and
tell young people to snap out of it.
And then they always applaud like, Yay, we
want to snap on it. But what did it say?
I'm calling this right now.
Yeah.
I don't know what's gonna come out of
this at the very least is going to be a
great wrestling character.
You know, if I were,
if I actually could take the beating,
the punishment of professional wrestling,
you know, and I was a younger fellow, my
character's name would be the millennial.
Right. And I would be
fucking sanctimonious my,
the word I learned this year,
self righteous, which is basically the
same thing. Set in a different way,
isn't it?
And I would act like how much I cared and
then I would go into the ring and be a
selfish fucking prick who just cheated
and fucked over everybody all the way to
my victory. Something like that. That's,
that's the loose or maybe maybe it's
not too late for me to be at wrestling
manager.
Yeah.
But I'm too old to be a millennial.
I'll be proud of my millennial children.
I don't fucking know.
This is why I don't rest.
I don't write for the fucking WWF or
whatever they're called now, the WWE,
um, Jesus Christ. Jesus' question.
How was your guys' Wednesday, just
before thanksgiving. How was it?
Did you go to the local bar here?
Did you see that lady?
Did you see that fella or maybe you
wanted to bang one of your teachers?
Did you hook up? Did it happen?
If I was a creepy teacher,
that's what I would do. You know
what I mean? To keep my job.
I wouldn't try to bang one of my students,
but I would hit every fucking Wednesday
before Thanksgiving at the local
watering hole, you know,
by then when the fucking,
whoever the hell I wanted to
bang was of age and I'd show up,
you know what I mean?
Just fucking chalk dust on my pants.
Do a little dance.
Mega little love bug.
[inaudible] um, hey ladies, have you ever
gone the Wednesday before thanksgiving?
Did you just check in on one
of your teachers? Have you
ever done that? You know,
not an old crusty guy, but
that new guy. All right.
The guy who was like in his
thirties seemed like he had
it all together at least
to you when you were sitting in your class
before you realize he's probably make
it only 18 grand a year with no benefits.
Course he has the whole summer off,
which would be great for the
kids and the above ground pool.
Yeah.
Underrated above ground pool under
fucking rated the above ground pool.
I mean,
how much into the water do you need to be?
As long as it goes up to your neck, you're
fine. Right? There isn't one at a time.
You let it freeze over
and you can skate on it.
Actually bill for above ground pool, a
little bottle of water. Shut the fuck up.
Nobody cares about your science.
So listen to this.
I told you last week I fucked up my ribs
or I fucking the Cartlidge around them.
I don't know what happened. So, uh,
I went to him with Seuss, you know,
which is what you wanna do.
You want to go to ah, fuck.
You want to go to an as suits, just
sitting up purse. If you want to go to,
you want to go to a fucking misuse
that knows what the fuck they're doing.
Cause basically all my muscles
were spasms in this guy.
Fucking fixed all of it. And I walked
out of there and they felt great.
And then like the German Irish asshole I
was, I'm like, well, you know about 60%.
I guess I can go play drums at 100% now
and see what happens that I came out of
there and I felt like I got
hit by a fucking car. Um,
you know why it is? Because they'll bill,
he's working on his double bass pedal.
He's got the double pedal now.
Huh. And you know what the deal is?
If you're a white guy and you're fun and
you're white drummer if you're a warmer,
right. What are the first couple of
songs you're going to learn? Huh?
Motley Crue live wire before
you move up to Pantera,
uh, cowboys from hell. That's what it is.
And I'm actually finding that fucking
triplet lick is easier than actually just
plain 16th 16th pass,
like fucking 95 a hundred bpms.
I just sound like a horse
gallop and down the street.
But what I didn't realize was how
much I was encouraging my obliques.
And the right side is all fucked
up. So whatever. I have a, uh,
I have another appointment
next fucking week. But dude,
I got to tell you something right now.
You guys out there,
all you old fucks like me.
If you have aches and pains in your
body before you go to a doctor,
I'm telling you, go see
him as Seuss. All right?
That actually I a top shelf misuse that
knows what that understands the body and
how it fucking works. Cause I'm telling
you right now, if you go to a doctor,
you know what they're gonna do. What
is it hard? This is my specialty.
I'm a knee doctor,
so I'm just looking at your fucking
knee and then they're going to give you
prescriptions. They're going to give
you some pain medications, you know,
next thing you know, you're, you're
fucking on heroin. You don't need,
Oh you just go to him with Seuss and
not play drums at the end of the day.
And I think you'll be fine. As always.
I have no idea what I'm talking about,
but it does warm my heart on thing.
I do give thanks right now thinking
that I'm possibly ignoring,
not ignoring,
unknowing somebody in the medical field.
That's not true on the new dog.
Do I take in consideration the hip joint,
the fucking theorics,
your larynx, pharynx, the
hypothalamus, pharynx.
I think I just invented a body
part. That's, yeah, that's,
it's your thyroid and your
lyrics where they connect.
It's like the taint
between the two of them
larynx is somewhere in your voicebox and
your thyroid. I don't know where that,
that isn't that in your neck?
Let a swollen thyroid Glenn.
Yeah. And you also got something
on the side of your mouth.
So if you don't pick up the conversation,
I'm walking away cause I don't give a
shit about you. Fucking can I say that?
Can I say that in the podcast?
Will I offend thyroid Americans?
Um, anyway, so I, uh,
I'd fucking made a sweet potato pie first
time this year. And what I learned was,
uh, there's no sweet potato and a sweet
potato pie. It's actually fucking yams.
I didn't know that I'm white. I
don't know. So I, it was the least,
the fucking sweet potatoes I got when I
fucking boiled them and got the skin off
them, they will, they will Hawaii.
So I was thinking, all right,
maybe the cinnamon and nutmeg and
that shit turns it Brown. It did not.
I basically made a sweet,
uh,
I made a potato pie that had a
little bit of sweetness to it,
so I had to fucking get rid of that
thing. Went back, got some yams. You know,
you've got to understand people that I'm
essentially going to be one of the few
white people at my Thanksgiving dinner.
And rather than making a Hawaii Pie,
I'm making a pie that is the staple of
the black communities as far as I've been
told. So there's all this
fucking pressure. Um,
I'm thinking I'm going to take a
pounding today as far as like, you know,
I should've put the,
he should put some vanilla in there.
You should have done this. You should've
done that. We'll see what happens.
We'll see how I survive.
You know what I mean?
Which is probably a good thing that I'm
not drinking today. You know what I mean?
Cause then, you know, I would
have all that alcohol in me,
everybody be criticizing my Pi and
then I'd start crying like a sad drunk.
Speaking of sad,
I realize I just fucking set back,
which is not what you want to do because
now I've got to make that noise again
when I fucking sit up.
Um, anyways, congrats.
You know what I'm thankful for something
else that I'm thankful for is the
Celtic 16 game winning streak.
What an absolute gift
to start off the season.
I'm thankful for Danny Ainge
or as I like to call him,
Bill Belicheck Jr Luke,
what this man is doing with draft picks,
look what this guy has done.
Anybody can be like the Lakers
and just sit around and go,
who's the best players in the league?
I will have them. Thank you very much.
Oh did you already developed them?
But to actually sit there and hold onto
your draft picks for years and then
exquisitely use them to trade,
to move up in the draft to pick
the guys to assemble the pieces.
Who's kidding?
Who were in the east?
So everybody in the east is
doing the exact same thing.
We're waiting for Lebron to get old.
You know?
It's like everybody in
the AFC east and football.
It's just how long is this motherfucker
Tom Brady going to be great for?
You know, you know what the
turning point in his career was,
was getting with Jazelle. All right,
so what she has him on is she eat,
he's like on that fucking wheat grass
yoga diet. He's all flexible and stuff.
You know what I mean?
He's eating like a stab
in model. Right? You.
So when he came into the league,
came right in out of the fucking dorms,
eating fucking Jalapeno poppers.
Do they even have those back then?
That's how old he is.
Like,
like a new appetizer has come around
since he started in the league.
That's when you know you're old.
You know what I mean?
When all you want is those little mini
fucking hot dogs with the mustard on them
and somebody go, we have Jalapeno
poppers. What? What? What are those?
I am not familiar with
those. Do you want some? Uh,
what are what set fucking weird one,
not smores. Let's say one. Every.
All those other weird families.
You know what the weird families are
that basically people that cook the shit
that you don't eat,
you know that's smores.
Not Charlie Brown's, what do they
call him? I said some chocolate thing.
It just sounds like a sweet
name for taking a dump.
I can't remember what the fuck it is.
They always hit. You want one of these?
It's like, no I don't, I don't,
I'm hoping the lovely Nia will come
in here and join me at some point on
Thanksgiving,
so I give thanks for having a lovely wife.
Yeah,
I was hoping that that was going
to happen at some point, you know,
you know what,
my wife is like,
she's like Louie Depalma on fucking taxi
as far as the way she always gives me a
fucking other jobs.
Sick.
She's like dispatch every time I'm out
driving around you gotta shut your phone
off. Cause if you don't, you're just
going to get all these assignments. Hey,
are you like 40 miles
away from the dry cleaner?
Could you go over there and
pick up some stuff, Neha?
Yeah.
Yes.
I'm in here trashing you.
Happy Thanksgiving to
you, but a boop, boop,
boop, boop. Who Do you guys
like today? You like the
lines? Do you like the cowboys?
Oh, here we go. Oh look
who's here. There she is.
Mrs Mrs Burb a Baba Baba Baba [inaudible]
triumphant return making a triumphant
return. Aw Man, I was just trashing you.
Can you, uh, can you pull up the, uh,
did your chair there? I was comparing
you to Louie Depalma on taxi member.
How he's in dispatch and it was always
telling the guys where to go and pick up
stuff.
You're 10 years older than man,
I don't does these references a lot of
times I don't get, well, it's classic.
Have you ever seen the Maltese Falcon
in college? But I don't remember it. Oh,
you don't? Oh, that's right. What's
your plan? What is my point? Oop.
I like how aggressive you're going into
this. This is very offensive. I like it.
But you just said to me, you're
trashing me, so why wouldn't I be I,
I wasn't saying that it was wrong.
What was your point?
Is it me or is there a lot of tension
for a holiday? Yes. Yes, there is.
I was just saying that I'm going to start
when I go out and about when I drive
around Hollywood,
checking out the scene,
I'm going to start shutting off my phone.
Okay.
Because you're always giving me jobs.
Ah.
Do you notice when you go out, I don't
call you up and be like, Hey Nia,
can you go by the two page
shop and pick up my, my rug?
[inaudible] [inaudible] [inaudible]
yeah. I mean, it's a real, that's a
real hard time for you. I understand.
It's difficult for you.
I get it.
Kind of just going to go with arrogance.
So beyond your capabilities.
So that's cool. I'll manage
my expectations. Thank you.
Thank you. Can you do that?
Can you stop giving me assignments?
It's really hot in here. Is it just me?
Is it really? It's really hot in
here. So take off your bath robe.
Um, come on, stop it. Be
Fun on the podcast. Okay.
Just cause I went in there and I trashed
you right out of the gate rather than
being thankful. Oh my God. Oh my God. Hey,
did you, um, where were you giving me
shit for coming in so late last night.
Cause I was wondering where that after
you were. I was upstairs first of all.
Okay.
Mom and I went to turn on the
fucking TV to watch the Bruins first.
The New Jersey devils and the fast forward
button worked and then I couldn't get
it to stop you. Always
worse. It was on one. Oh No.
I was actually trying to watch it
and I realized it needed to do batteries.
First.
World problems. Right. All right.
So tell me what happened with your
Thanksgiving dinner. Oh Wow. You know,
I don't like to trash people in the
podcast, but I will say that this,
you know,
particular company that I ordered from,
they promised you a peach cobbler and
you got there and it wasn't there. Well,
you know,
and so I made it known via a very short,
simple email that I was disappointed
in that fact. And you know,
I was waiting two and a half
hours to pick it up and you know,
nobody could have nobody came
out and said, hey, listen,
doesn't look like the peach
cobblers happening. I'm so sorry.
Because then I would've been like,
okay,
well let me maybe run out and try
to grab something. But you know,
I waited for two and a half hours in
the parking lot and got my food and came
home.
I was exhausted.
And now you're going to write those people
back as they responded to your email
with like a four page Gettysburg address.
I'm telling you,
she write him back and be like,
if you spend as much time making my
peach cobbler rather than giving me four
pages of excuses where you're the victim,
here's a good one for your
business in the future.
Don't promise what you can't deliver.
That's pretty much
what I, yeah, yeah. They said you ordered
really late then don't take the order.
Yeah, they should've said no. All right.
Um, hey, but they were doing me a favor.
Is is basically the tone that I got back
was that they were doing me a favor and
you know, um, it was difficult
to get my payments information,
but it's like I missed a couple phone
calls cause I was with the baby.
So now you have excuses.
Yes.
But then when the [inaudible]
pod here on a third time,
I gave them the information
and for the full amount,
not the half deposit that
they initially requested,
I was like go ahead and do the
full amount, but you know, um,
do you guys think that,
will there be a second date?
Do you guys think you're ever going
to, this is the second date. Recall.
So this is this, there will
not be a third date. You know,
life goes on and uh,
yeah,
but one thing is your own fucking
meal. I'm telling you, I see that.
So I have to deal with other people's
bullshit. You know, it's, it's,
it's fine though.
It's like I expected this response back
because I have dealt with this person
before. So, you know,
this isn't surprising that it would be
like a whole list of reasons of excuses,
I should say.
Not even reasons it's excused.
I love how she kept complimenting
you and telling you to have a happy
thanksgiving. Oh, all in Cadillac.
Just the air getting on an airplane and
we're jetting away to enjoy or the anger
as opposed to being like, I know you're
disappointed. Sorry about that. Sorry.
We promise something that we couldn't
deliver, but here's four pages of excuses.
Yeah. Here's a bunch of excuses
why. And then to like, you know,
bring my mother into it as well,
which is very classy. Very,
very classy on, on this person's part.
But you know, I feel like Andy Cohen,
right nose.
Like I wish the other person who didn't
make the sweet potato pie was here.
Sweet Potato Pie guy.
I don't, I'll come on.
So Nia, um, I have to, what? Have you
started Christmas shopping yet? No,
I have, I am fucking crushing
it. Nieces, nephews done. Okay.
You done what's I'm done with you.
I'm breaking up with, you know,
Christmas gift for you. No, I'm actually,
I'm going to wrap some shit and then
I'm going to wrap my presence. Sorry,
I'll look.
Can read a little bit.
Did you see the Christmas wrapping
paper that I got for you? For the kids?
Oh yeah. I thought it was cute. Like
peanuts and then like Rudolph or Mickey,
your gifts are also going
to be wrapped in that.
We have other wrapping paper. All right,
let me read this thing here. Yeah.
This frigging shied feel so much
better today after not moving.
I think the key, the key to letting your
rib cage heal is to not move. Right?
So I want to let you know today,
I'm not avoiding you and your relatives.
You're just not. I'm
nursing my side. Okay.
Are you just going to be able to handle
this sober? Me On the holidays. I mean,
having,
I've been it for the last
however long. You haven't
been drinking? No,
but on the holidays usually
get all drunk and belligerent.
Start telling everybody around the
room with their problems. It's anytime
I'm a happy drunk.
I like to think so silly and
goofy and you're very loving.
You're one of those drunks that calls
me up at four in the morning and telling
me how much you love me.
I do. That's so funny.
Yeah. That's why I don't need
weed, man. I don't need the we,
I'm done with that shit. You
say that all the time. Yeah,
but I don't smoke that much.
[inaudible] so every time I do,
I just always fucking burns my throat.
I don't get it.
I just don't know how to control your
inhale. Yeah. And I just don't get it.
You're just doing like these bong
rip type of things and like do shots.
What do you want? Because you're
trying to get that same effect.
It doesn't work like that.
You know,
I'm not just trying to fucking
inhale and fill it out. I don't know.
Yeah. I don't want to get good at
it. I don't want to get good at,
but whenever I don't drink then I'll
every once in a while I'll come around and
be all right. I got to,
I got to do something.
I've got to break up the monotony here.
Thank God you're not into heroin
or I'd be doing that. The heroin,
I made a sweet potato pie. I feel like
I'm down. I feel like I'm woke. Um,
all right.
Frame bridge everybody.
If you've previously
listened to this show,
you've heard me talk about frame bridge,
they make it super easy and affordable
to co two custom frame favorite things
from art prints and posters
to the photos on your phone.
I actually collected all the pictures
of our lovely daughter and put it on a
hard drive and there was so many of
them that I was like, you know what?
I think frame bridge could really help
me out with this one. There you go.
That's a personal story.
Men's health says frame
bridge has disrupted the
custom framing industry making
what has typically been a
frustrating and expensive process.
Easy and affordable shots
fired in the customer.
Big Frame. Yeah. Take that. Yeah.
Custom framers and with the
holiday around the quarter frame,
bridge is the perfect way to send truly
one of a kind gifts without that much
thought out. Right to everyone on your
list. This perfect. This is what you need.
The thing about it is there's so
many people that you don't like,
but you have to get him something right.
You know what I mean? That's perfect.
You don't have the fucking time. Just
scroll through your Goddamn cell phone.
Go past the Dick Pics. Go past that, that,
that picture of the directions.
Okay.
That you have saved on
there for whatever reason,
and find that picture of you in this
person you just required to get a stocking
stuffer for right and go in there and
just send it up and then it's done and
then it's done. There you
go. There you go. What's the,
where did you go during all of that?
You just fucking started staring a hole
through my giant head here. Sorry, I'm no,
I'm, what do you think you're
thinking about the meal,
right? You're a little off.
You're a little off on this
podcast. Sorry. I'm, yeah,
because I'm trying to figure out if I'm
going to respond to this email or not.
I don't think I'm going
to, oh, I would have to,
I would just real quickly I would just be,
I would just pay something along them
going back and forth and back and forth
about it. You know what I mean? Like
it's just going to be more of the same,
you know?
I said what I had to say and I was,
that they said would be right to say.
And you know,
you guys both said what you had to say.
Anything she's supposed to be thankful
that you, yeah. You know why I'm doing
this and highly favored, you know,
like the letters.
Do you want to keep doing this?
What I'm thankful for is I fucking hate.
That's the one thing about
Thanksgiving that I cannot stand.
What is listening to adults
toothbrush, like just eat.
Don't think that's nice.
I don't like listening to it because
I am so jaded that I'm just like,
I just feel like people try to top one
another about like what they're thankful
for and how much more they understand
what's really makes you happy in life.
Yeah.
Um,
it's like when people have a baby and
they tried to sit there and talk about
like how much they love their babies,
so then they have to top the other person.
Oh my God, my heart is just filled
to the brim with love. Oh yeah.
I feel like my heart is on the outside
of my body now and then they just keep
fucking going about their heart
and she's like to, to begin it.
You love your kids. You love your
kid. Yes. I get it. Oh my God.
Is it standing up like all babies
eventually do. That is incredible.
Actually. Some babies can't and that's
where we need to be thankful for.
That's right. All right. Just go
to frame bridge dot. Yeah. Calm.
Oh, blowed your photo from your computer
or directly from your Instagram feed.
Fucking ribs being messed up.
You can't sneeze and you can't laugh.
I mean that is basically, that's
my wheelhouse of emotion. I live,
I live between laughing and sneezing.
I'm going to be robotic today.
Do you we have ribs for as a,
as part of our uh, entrepreneur.
I hope he didn't get into the
peach cobbler fight before
they made those goddamn
things. No, I waited. So you
know, I just pictured him,
pictured him taking the ribs and running
itall right along the crack of his ass.
Now as you glaze for your
mother, fuck. Alright.
I don't think he would ever do that.
He is actually very classy I think.
Who wants sticky buns or if you have
a physical item they'll provide secure
prepaid package so you
can mail it in for free.
Preview your photo online
in any frame style.
Choose your favorite or get free
help from the talented designers.
He's a great idea.
Somebody you don't like,
you just take a selfie if you scowling
at them and then get it framed.
Yeah. And have a tee shirt on that
says, don't call me. No like that.
I like it.
The the expert team at frame bridge.
We'll custom your item in days,
not weeks or months,
and deliver your finished placed directly
to you or your loved ones along with
the handwritten gift or note.
Here's one to send to an ex.
You somehow just having great fun with
a maniacal smile waving and with the tee
shirts says, I'm moving on. You can have
a lot of fun with these. The best part,
instead of the hundreds you pay at framing
of framing store their prices start
at $39 in all shipping is free.
You know it isn't.
The best part is this
copy's going to keep going,
even though everybody already
gets the concept frame.
Bridge even offers a happiness guaranteed.
Unlike those peach cobbler people,
if for any reason you aren't
100% satisfied with the order,
they'll make it right. Go to [inaudible]
dot com and use Promo Code [inaudible].
You'll save an additional
15% off your first order.
Just go to frame bridge.com promocode bar
frame, bridge.com Promo Code Bar. Hey,
next year we're going to
go back to cooking our own
meal, right? Oh, absolutely.
This is just because we got
the little one this year.
I feel like I'm all over as I got a
little overwhelming. So, you know,
I thought I kinda like,
you have ever cheat on a test and then
you get it back and you have kind of that
feeling of guilt. Yeah. I never
did. Uh, me undies. Everybody.
Ah, but do, do, do beyond
these, beyond these,
where's my fucking pie?
Did you do to me and eat me undies?
Make it as someone's got to die.
I don't give a fuck about all your
excuses. Make the fucking thing.
Put it in the Khumbu, sir. And I'm
going to drive away nice and happy.
I guess we don't get to is there it
you fucking cunts. They're all right.
Every year millions of people receive
the least liked gift of all time
underwear. But I like, you know what's
funny is buying your wife sexy underwear.
I mean, is that really a gift?
Hey, put this on, dress it up.
Yeah. Who Does the flower? You
like lingerie? You like lingerie?
I love lingerie. You just liked the
word, makes you feel bilingual. Um,
lingerie on,
but we still give it to try it because
we still give it to our family.
That's what you do. You take a picture
of underwear, you get it framed,
and then you send it to
somebody. And that's two for
one. That's weird, isn't it?
Sounds like some weird like Jeffrey
Dahmer Shit. It's just the underwear.
I'm not saying you're in it with a stiffy,
but we still give it to our families and
our loved ones who just don't want it.
Uh, but maybe it's not, I
couldn't even just chuckle there,
but it's not that underwear to go.
Ha ha ha.
Oh, that wasn't a bad one. But maybe no,
because what happens is the muscle
spasms and they just fucking,
they start locking up. Okay. You know,
it's funny, he's trying to sneeze,
relaxed,
but I tried to do was just exhale as much
air out as I can and then you just go,
whew. He sneezed and it doesn't
get out. And then it just, yeah,
you need that Guy Barnes platoon
in your face going take the,
but maybe it's not that an underwear is
the problem. It's the kind of underwear.
Let, Oh, let, let me
tell you about me undies.
The only underwear that makes for
an amazing gift, soft, flexible,
like the whore up the street waistband
three times softer than cotton.
Naturally sustainable sourced fiber.
Mandy's maid underwear.
The perfect gift that
everyone is going to love.
He's going to love you for you know it's
funny. Did they break up with modal,
modal, cause they don't talk
about the fabric anymore.
Can they send me some underwear?
Underwear. Can I have some to there?
I don't want you walking around and
guys underwear. Oh wait a minute.
They also make them for the lady.
It's a Goddamn holiday miracle this year.
Don't give it, don't give underwear it.
Give me undies.
The holiday season dooby dooby do to
get your exclusive 20% off the softest
underwear and socks.
Fuel everwhere free shipping and
a 100% satisfaction guaranteed.
Go to me undies.com/. Bar. That's me.
undies.com/bar. Tell me two more.
Jesus Christ lift Nia. Can I come back?
Oh absolutely. I'll turn down
the volume I have to change.
Change into what did you buy?
Electric Turkey dress.
Do you have the little underneath
your chin? Peach Cobbler. That was,
that sounds like a wrestler.
Oh, maybe that'll be my
wrestling name. Peach Cobbler.
Peach Cobbler. I like it. I was
going to go as the millennial.
I just think it's a great
wrestling character.
You just get offended by everything
and then you go when you do some self
righteous con. Yeah. I'm going to be
peach cobbler. I like it. Okay. Okay.
There she goes. Everybody. All right.
I wonder if I use two microphones.
Will I be half is funny or twice as
funny? All right, lift everybody.
Lyft knows that drivers are what keeps
them moving so they do everything they
can to make sure their drivers
are happy on every trip.
Oh,
lift believes that being a ride
sharing drivers should be fun.
Oh, don't have too much fun. You
fucking drive in the car. Ramen.
That's like when you fly one of these
stupid airlines and the stewardesses as a
singing songs like on southwest,
it's like,
will you shut the fuck up and
try to be remotely professional?
My life is in your hands.
You know,
I hate more is the people that laugh and
applaud and just egg them on every got
a free show. I don't even know why we
have to get off the plate in Vegas. Uh,
lift believes that being a ride sharing
drivers should be fun if you have a good
time. So are the passengers. Um,
if you're choosing a Rogers
picturing everybody boozing it up,
we're having a great time,
right?
You're not going to be okay.
I said a God damn fucking Barts.
If you're choosing a ride sharing company
to drive for a go with the company
that treats you better. Lyft, Lyft
was the first to offer in APP tipping.
When you drive for Lyft,
you get 100% of the tips.
Drivers have been paid over 200 million
in tips since the feature was introduced.
Lyft has taken the guesswork out
of pickups. The new amp device,
is it supposed to be app amp device
uses color coding to help passages find
their drivers and lets
the light in the car.
You couldn't earn hundreds of
dollars a week plus tips. One,
earned money drive more. You want to
earn more money. Everybody worked more.
It's never been easier
to give yourself a raise.
It's a simple formula that's
not a res, uh, raises.
You make more an hour. A raise is not
you work more. Jesus fucking Christ.
I suck at math that even I saw through
that bullshit. It's a simple formula.
Happy drivers mean happy passengers make.
Maybe that's why nine out of 10 Lyft rides
get a perfect five star rating. Yeah,
and one out of 10 are good at math. Uh, s
of Jesus built. Don't burn this one down.
I love Lyft. I love Lyft.
Do you know what I mean?
Less people die from drinking and
driving because of Lyft. I love Lyft.
I love lamp.
I love Lyft.
So join the ride sharing company that
believes in treating its people betters.
Go to
lift.com/bird today and get
a $500 new bonus. That's
lyft.com/burr lyft.com/bar I want
to fuck a become a Lyft driver.
I would love to do that. Just fucking
cruise around the city. You know,
talking to people.
Everybody gets a free fucking DVD.
I don't have a DVD player.
It's free. I'm grateful. Fuck.
Simply safe. If you want to protect
your home this holiday season,
listen up. This is a
very, this is very cool.
My listeners now have early access to
simply safe's biggest black Friday sale,
ever $200 of simply safe's
holiday security system.
This is a true bestseller,
a 13 piece arsenal that
covers your whole home.
If you want to protect your family,
this should be how you do it.
Simply safe has made everything
about security effortless.
You're barely, you barely lift
a finger, just order it online.
It's delivered right to
your door for free shipping.
It takes less than an hour to set up.
A 10 year old can do this. No pressure.
So when you fuck this up, Christ, a
10 year old could do it and I can't.
Simply safe has no longterm contract,
no pushy sales guy,
no hidden fees. The prices are
honestly are honest and fair.
15 bucks a month for the best in industry
24 seven alarm monitoring and with
simply safe, you'll never,
you're never locked in.
Go right now to simply safe.com and
you get $200 off your security system.
Hurry, this offer ends soon and
these will fly off the shelf.
That's simply safe.
bird.com for $200 off simply safe
buffer.com. All right, where are
we in the podcast? Oh 38 minutes.
Are you guys thankful for the extra
eight minutes that I gave you?
Um, so I got my Christmas shopping
started. I'm very excited about that.
I think I'm actually going to do
a family Christmas card this year.
Every year we were like, we should do
that and we never did it well this year.
God dammit we're going to do it
cause we got a kid now. Right?
If you don't have a fucking kid, you know,
past a certain age is, if it's just you,
you, your significant other
other than your family pet,
don't you start feeling like
the other people judging you?
They haven't reproduced. What's
wrong with them? I don't know.
Maybe they're informed. They understand
how much you know, population.
Let's not get into the population problem.
Hey, hey, fair enough. Fair enough.
Speaking of, fair enough, the
throwback podcast for you,
for those of you who are new to my
podcast and you're listening for the first
time,
which I am so thankful for,
I just feel it for me. If
I have for listeners, um,
Andrew,
who I am also thankful for the wonderful
producer who picks out the music every
week. When we do the, the, uh,
after I, I babbled for a half hour,
we then had listened to some music,
a little interlude,
and then we go into a classic podcast
from a Thursday going by and another year
or possibly earlier this year.
Evidently last year,
one of these years I gave
the, uh, the now classic.
I like to call it a classic
because I would like to do
something classic in life.
So I'm going to say that what I did
was classic, uh, the fair enough,
like how to get through your Thanksgiving
dinner with the simple phrase.
Fair enough,
Huh?
You don't feel that a
boarding a child is murder.
Fair enough. It is. You
killed something. Right?
Cause if you didn't do it, I mean they're
dead based something. Fair enough.
I like doing that. I like arguing
the opposite side of political shit.
Like if I was in a conservative,
conservative fucking state,
I would argue pro pro choice.
When I'm in La,
I argue pro life and none of it,
none of it has to do with the
fetus or anything like that.
All it has to do with is me annoying
the person that I'm talking to him.
That's what I do. Anyways, that's,
that's the Thursday afternoon,
just before Friday. Monday morning
podcast. God bless all of you.
I am so thankful.
I'm so thankful to be able to go out and
tell jokes every night and I just feel
like for me,
all right,
have a great thanksgiving weekend you
cunt and I will talk to you on Monday.
I cannot to watch the football
game, but unfortunately my wife has gone
into that fucking Westminster dog show,
which I really enjoy except for the fact
that it comes on at the same time as
the football game there.
I said it by
[inaudible]
the Turkey day to you. Oh, you know,
stuffing and potatoes and pie and beer.
Cranberries in gravy and
your cousin who's gay.
Um, hey, what's going on? How
are you? Happy thanksgiving.
Happy not having to fucking
go to work today. Huh?
You around the table. Are
you sitting down yet? Well,
if you haven't gone downstairs yet,
I got, I got some advice for you.
Today is going to be a day. I think it's
going to be a lot of fucking arguments.
A lot of fucking arguments at the
table, right? The big fucking election.
Some people wanted the
guy with the eyebrows.
Some people wanted the fucking
lady with the pants suit.
Right? Um, this is what you gotta do.
So you're already gonna have a fight,
right?
There's already going to be your older
brother. There's going to be this person.
There's going to be another
person, somebody who's going
to say something, right?
And you're going to be begging to have
a couple of wild fucking turkeys as you
standing over there. You know,
eating a fucking appetizer or two.
Somebody's going to be
getting on your nerves.
Maybe somebody fucking wife who
won't shut the fuck up, right?
Why the fuck did he marry her? Maybe.
Maybe it's the husband, Jesus Christ.
What is she doing with this guy?
All he does is fucking talk about himself.
Something's going to drive you up
the fucking wall. If it's not this,
it's going to be that this is,
this is the phrase,
this is a phrase that's going to save your
day. Okay? Save the whole fucking day.
Cause you're not going to change anybody's
opinion. Oh, these fucking jerk off.
Still yelling. He hung blue.
Could you vote for Trump? Well,
what the Fuck About Hillary?
You're not changing.
You're just gonna fucking
yell at each other.
So here's the phrase you've got to
use to get through this fucking day.
All right? Along with the alcohol or
whatever drug you fucking want to use,
fair enough. You know, hey, fair enough.
It's like, that's all you gotta do. What'd
you say? Hey, hey guys, guys, guys, fair,
fair enough. Whatever. You don't
need to see him anymore right now,
if you're younger and you still live
there, that's kind of fucking tough.
I don't know what to tell you, but if
you've already moved out of the house,
why are you still arguing
with these people?
Why are you still trying to
change their fucking minds?
You're not can change their minds.
All right? I don't give a fuck.
If you majored in debating, it's just
stupid fucking school in the woods.
Whatever the fuck it is.
You did that.
Now you're coming back and now you think
you know something and you think that
you fucking siblings want to hear it.
You know what? They don't the same way.
You don't want to hear the way
they fucking eat. When they had,
they've had a couple, two, three,
right? And all of a sudden the man,
everything just sounds like they're
eating fucking mashed potatoes. You know,
you start hammering these murderers
fucking thoughts, you know?
Just fair enough. Hey, fair
enough. Whenever, whenever.
Was that what you think is that? Is
that how you look at the world? Hey,
God bless you. Pass the fucking
peas and carrots. Fair enough.
Fair enough.
You know,
and that's all you've got to do that
eventually the meal's going to be over.
All right?
And you're going to get in your fucking
car and you're going to drive away
unless you stay in there for the weekend.
Well then you've got to go out to,
I don't know, you've got
Uber. You gotta write,
you gotta get the fuck out of
there. Yeah. Thanksgiving is a, uh,
it's such a great day. There is no
pressure to get any gifts eaten,
a bunch of great food. All of
that is tremendous. Okay. Unless,
unless you go into her fucking
family's house or his family's house,
that's a weird one because you know,
you're used to all your
family's food and thanksgiving.
You know how it's supposed to taste it.
You're going to go somewhere else.
It's going to taste a little
bit different. You know,
this is like a classic standup bit,
like here's how it usually is,
but when you're fucking blah, blah,
blah, it's a whole different story,
right? And you just got to suck
it up and just be like, you know,
worst case scenario, this
absolutely fucking sucks, you know,
in which case, fair enough. You know,
you don't know how to cook. Okay,
you're supposed to cook
today. You know, it's,
it's like when it's somebody's birthday,
most people can't sing,
but God dammit, you got to sing the
song. So they do the best they can.
Happy Birthday, right? They
do what the fuck they can.
Well, sometimes you got to take the, the,
the same fucking theory of a tone deaf
person singing happy birthday to you
because they love you, right? You
get, you got to apply that to food,
which is a motherfucker,
which brings it to how do I make it
look like I ate the shit when I really
didn't? Well, oh Jesus.
I don't know how to do this one. Once
you got to do is you got to fucking, uh,
eager to engage in a lot of conversation
as you just sort of fucking hitting the
plate with your fork a little
bit is if you almost like,
you know that noise people make when
they want someone to make a speech,
that annoying fucking
thing, you know? Oh my God,
nothing fucking makes
my goddamn blood boil.
Like when I'm in the middle of a fucking
conversation at some con starts hitting
the glass with the fork and then for
whatever social fucking reason I have to
now shut up, you know? Oh
my God, that gets me gone.
But not today. Not Today. Everybody.
Hey, fair enough. Hey, someone's downs.
Somebody down the fucking street over
there with a little little fucking scone
knocking against some glass.
You know,
I guess we all have to stop as adults.
We have to shut the fuck up, right?
Yeah.
Like we're working for this asshole
bay. You know what? Hey, fair enough.
Fair enough. You know, he
just fucking sit there. Oh,
here we go. Oh good. Oh, here's a cliched
what? I'm thankful for speech. Oh,
is that what you're thankful for?
I'm thankful for lady.
Every fucking word that comes out
of your mouth is one less war.
It was one word closer to the end of
whatever the fuck it is you're saying.
You know,
that's when you know,
you know the passive aggressive movies
is when someone's in the middle of that
is you, you fucking as some just kind
of pointed, somebody pointed some plate,
you know,
little fucking give me that butter.
They'll still yammering on.
You know,
you know back in 1983 when we
first saw this house, right?
And you just sit there
butter in your fucking roll.
Oh is this mother fucker gonna go
every goddamn year from 1983 hey,
you know what? Fair enough. Fair enough.
Yeah. I didn't want to wear this sweater.
Right?
He's fucking have these potatoes,
instant these fucking potatoes and
hey, fair enough. Hey, you didn't,
you didn't have time to fucking cook real
ones. Maybe they ran out of up, down.
The quote is the last fucking time
they ever ran out of potatoes.
They never run out of
potatoes in this country.
It's why somebody fucking Irish people
over here, right? Fucking Irishmen,
they tapped out on their own country
one fucking time in their whole history.
They run out of potatoes and
everybody fucking jumped ship. Right?
But not the real Irishman,
the real Irish men and real
lady say fuck it stuck around.
I like these cowards that I'll
move to fucking New Jersey. Um,
but you know what a fair enough,
you know, they wanted some potatoes.
This is one of these days people,
you know, and if you're younger man,
you got to enjoy the holidays cause
cause they're never going to get,
it doesn't get better than you know,
cause you don't know any better.
So the food tastes the way the fucking
food is supposed to taste in your world,
right? Everyone who's
supposed to be there is there,
you know?
So when you get older and you start
expanding your fucking world and all of a
sudden you know Jesus Christ,
I mean you're sitting there with somebody
you might've given me up me and might
be sitting at that fucking table being,
I don't even know if I'm with
the right person right now.
What the fuck am I take? You know,
what hey say with be fair enough.
I'm with somebody that I probably was
never really in love with but didn't
realize what love was. You
know, and now here I am,
okay.
And all I gotta do is not get in
an argument for one fucking day.
I can do this right by Saturday I want
to be out of this fucking relationship
and you know what all I'm
going to be thankful then
you bet your sweet fucking
mmm
oh my God. If it starts going into
politics, that starts going into politics.
You almost need like a referee during
this period of us history to just
literally step in with
one of those footlocker,
fucking athlete's foot ref shirts,
blow of fucking whistle.
And just send the two people
to opposite fucking Lazy Boys.
Let it go.
Letter to Aa. It's all, it's all, she
went home. She went home solver. Okay.
She's not coming back.
I don't think she's got a third runner.
All right.
Sorry. Sit down. Sit down. Sit Down Buddy.
Nobody's building a wall today. Okay.
Just fucking relax.
Maybe it could be the peacemaker.
Who knows who the fuck knows.
Um, I'm actually very excited.
You wouldn't know it this
year for Thanksgiving because
I'm back at my house. Um,
yeah, there's going to be a
lot of arguments today and
it'll be a victory if I'm,
you know,
if you don't get in one,
maybe it could be that person that keeps
everybody out of it is everybody starts
screaming and yelling. You know, you
know, he's a fucking sex offender,
blah blah blah.
Well,
she's a fucking day and all that type of
shit and you can be in the back. I like
anybody tried this,
just walk right in the middle of it.
Oh Man.
I want to see a compilation of youtube
videos of the political fucking,
okay.
I've almost said discourse.
That's probably the wrong fucking word.
Okay.
Do you realize how many fucking words
I know that I don't even know what the
fuck they mean.
I just know what words they go with.
You know, discourse goes with
political, political discourse.
You know,
you used the word or Nate
when you're in a theater.
I Dunno what it means. I, you know, I
remember, you know, I got a computer.
I can look at any, fair
enough. I can look it up.
Why am I going to bore
you guys with the ship?
[inaudible]
Karen
[inaudible].
Hey,
what's going on?
It's bill burr and it is the
Monday morning podcast for Monday,
November 23rd. Listen to my
voice. Does it sound tired?
Does it sound sexy?
Um,
I just got back from the Improv in Tempe,
Arizona and uh,
you know,
what does that my 11th fucking week on
the road in the last couple of weeks.
That doesn't make sense. Mathematically.
I whatever, I been on the road a lot.
My fucking voice is tired. So, uh,
this is going to be my easy listening
vibe for you this Monday. And, uh,
I imagine some of you will complain.
I liked it better when you were angrier.
Go Fuck Yourself. How about that?
Is that angry enough for you? Okay.
I don't really have the fucking
energy to get as mad as I usually do,
but just know, you know that I'm
thinking hateful thoughts towards you.
All right? You fucking angry. Cons. See,
that's why you gotta Watch out who you
surround yourself with is because when
you actually make a positive step
in your life, for example, uh,
being less angry, they actually, they try
to make it seem like it's a bad thing.
Dude. You Change, man. You fucking change.
Look at you, you're smiling, you're happy.
You know, what are you doing? You
know what I'm doing right now?
I'm sitting here on my fucking couch
in the living room and it is my fucking
couch. If I was on the Sofa, I
just sales on the cell phone.
That's what I have in my living room.
I have a sofa and I have a fucking couch.
The fucking couch is fucking comfortable,
hence its name and I'm on it
because I'm fucking tired. Um,
let's try to hype my shit. Let's try
to be smart with this podcast, uh,
to begin with. Um, all right.
I'm doing a stand up special I next hour
long special of filth and silly faces,
which might be the name. It'd be a
good name, Huh? Filson silly faces. Um,
maybe this, I don't fucking know. Listen
to me. I'm exhausted. Fucking exhausted.
All right.
Uh,
I'm going to be taping it at the Fillmore
in San Francisco on December 17th.
I'm doing two shows,
one at one time and one at another time.
I don't have the information, but I
do have the link right on my website.
If you go onto a billboard.com
and you go down to a, you know,
scroll down on the lower left hand corner
and you will get to the link and it'll
take you to live nation.com
we'll see tickets for
Julio Iglesias,
um,
fucking men at work.
You know,
what's the name of that other group
is the name of that fucking group.
What was the name of the group?
It was the name of the song and it was
the name of the album in a lead singer
killed himself. There's a trivia
question. Do you remember it?
Early eighties big country.
There was a band called big country.
They had an album called big country
and the name of their hit song was big
country.
Needless to say,
with a well of talent
like that to pull from,
I dunno how they only had one hit song.
We're called cupcake is our
thong cupcake offer album cupcake
fucking cupcake to Lou and then that's it.
I mean what the fuck is wrong with you?
Don't think about switching
it up a little bit.
It's actually isn't funny cause the
lead singer ended up killing himself.
You know the song should've been called
continent I. What was I thinking?
Um, anyways, so if you go on,
you go on the live nation.com.
Let me see if I can even fucking do it.
If I even can find tickets to my special,
I'll go to bill burr.com I am blue. I'll
look at that. What a good looking guy.
All right, I'm going to click on the
link and it takes me to live nation.com.
Let me do this with you because so many
of you fucking idiots are going to,
I couldn't find it.
I did.
I clicked on the link and it
didn't do everything for me. A,
I don't know what to do.
You know what it's like.
That's like those Douche bags
you see on youtube. By the way,
you can learn how to play drums,
guitar,
a fucking Sitar or whatever you
want to learn, right on youtube.
Somebody is going to show you how
to play, uh, you know a Didgeridoo.
So these fucking guys get on there and
they show you. Exactly. They slow it down.
They show you how to play it. And
people still ask for tabs. Great video.
But do you have any tabs?
Why don't you just ask the guy to fucking
go over there and put your fingers on
the Fret Board for you? You're
lazy. Fuck. Oh, there's Lamponeli.
They got a nice picture of
Lisa Lampanelli on. Now.
Let's see if my picture comes up.
Now goes right to fucking you too.
Okay.
And some guy with a cowboy hat named Brad
Paisley on his American Saturday night
tour. All right, let's see if
there's some sort of search here.
All right, let's go to
the bees. Blue Rodeo.
Bob Dylan,
boys like girls brand new Brandi Carlile.
Brian Regan and know me
well, that's good. Well,
I'm glad I fucking did this.
Why don't we do this on sale now?
Top 10 tours. I know that's not going
to be me. Top 10 venues, the Fillmore.
Bam. That's what you do. All right,
so you get on the homepage, all right?
And then you, uh, scroll down,
you'll see top 10 venues.
You Click on the Fillmore and
then you wait for your slow computer.
All right. Live nation at the Fillmore.
And then you scroll down. Let's see.
He was going to be playing there.
The Black Crowes
Lo Los Lobos bill bar right there.
So that's what you do.
All right?
So I don't need any fucking emails from
you whiny bitches about how you can't
find fucking tickets, cause I just
did it in real time. All right?
So anyways,
as I said,
I'm sitting on my fucking couch here and
I'm actually watching a replay of the
Bruin sabers game. I don't know who
wins. Don't fucking tell me. Um,
that's what I do.
I tape all the hockey games and I come
back like a fucking scout and I watch
like seven games. I already watched
when the Bruins beat the, uh,
Atlanta thrashers and I
gotta tell you something.
They got a great fucking team and I
don't know why they have an NHL team in
Atlanta because you should,
you should have seen the amount of silica.
I got fucking AA meeting.
That's how many people were there for
the fucking thrashers game, you know?
And they got eagle yet Koval chuck and
a couple other fucking guys with names.
Like they should be
working the Russian border,
but they're fucking great players. But I
don't understand why did they put what,
what the fuck is wrong with the NHL?
Why did they put another team in Atlanta?
You know,
I don't understand cities that fail in a
sport and then get another opportunity.
You know,
I'm one of the few people that understands
why Los Angeles doesn't have an NFL
team. Well, let's say you had two
of them and you'll, they both left.
You know right there. I mean, granted,
I don't know why the fuck they left.
Typical me. I don't know what
the fuck I'm talking about,
but all I know is you don't put
fucking hockey in Atlanta. All right?
If the fact that the,
the original Atlanta
flames left 30 years ago,
if that wasn't enough of a tip,
why don't you listen to parliament
and they'll let you know that it's a
chocolate city.
You know who the fuck is
from Atlanta Little Wayne.
You've got everyone from like
little Wayne to like rem.
And I'm going to go out on a limb here
and I'm going to say, Michael Stipe isn't,
he doesn't strike me as a
fucking hockey fan. You know,
the fuck is wrong with you. So
anyways, I'm watching the game.
There's like 30 people in the crowd.
There's no fucking energy whatsoever.
But now I'm watching the
Bruin sabers and I always, uh,
never the Bruins play the Sabres.
I have to listen to the, uh,
the sabers announcer.
I Dunno what the fucking guy's name is,
but I swear to God he could make,
he can make watching somebody sit
waiting for a bus. Sound exciting.
He's one of the best guys in the leaks.
I always watch that fucking guy.
So that's what I'm doing. Was that boring?
I hope it was. Cause I'm fucking tired.
I'm really country this week. Um,
uh, why am I being an asshole?
It's thanksgiving. Thanksgiving is
come up is coming up. Let me, uh,
let me switch the tone
here. Um, you know people,
this is a week when everyone,
all Americans should sit
down, okay? When those fucking
Douche bags get on TV,
you know,
with their ear muffs and their
little fucking NBC gloves,
they're fucking overcoats with the
floats going by in the background,
they start telling you about why you
should be so fucking thankful for your
fucking miserable life.
You know,
we now maybe if I was on
network television, you know,
where the cashmere coat that I
didn't have to fucking pay for.
I could enjoy my Turkey a
little more this year. You know,
you know what all Americans
should be given. Thanks right now.
This should be sitting around going, what
the fuck happened? For whatever reason,
everything from the bankers to that
fucking twats dropped you out of nowhere.
He's supposed to sit there and happy and
you're catatonic state with cranberry
sauce dripping down your fucking chin.
You know I can't [inaudible].
You know, this is such a great fucking
holiday. If you don't listen to anybody,
you know you don't have to buy any gifts.
And by the way,
Wednesday of this week for
all you drunks out there,
I know you know this information,
but just bear with me for all you
amateur drinkers, drinkers out there.
This is the best.
The Wednesday before Thanksgiving is
the best night of drinking all year.
Hands down. All right? It's not new years.
You know when all his fucking idiots go
out with this silly hats and those noise
makers, why anyone goes out that
night, his fucking beyond me.
Unless you're out there telling jokes
trying to make money, which I understand.
All right
that night and Saint Patrick's day and
everyone's got their green plastic hats
and they're singing those stupid fucking
Saiad at green alligator and along net
goes, why are all eating corn beef
sandwiches? Let me ask you this.
During the course of the fucking year,
the amount of times you go out
to eat and grab a sandwich,
do you ever order a corned beef sandwich?
She had doubt caution down.
Does anybody even know what animal
that comes from? Cause I don't
corn beef is that Ah,
that's cattle, right? Beef.
Pork is a pig.
I fucking know.
You know,
you know as I was riffing about this week,
and I'll actually talk about it here in
the podcast because I don't give a fuck
about burning this joke just
cause it's a topical joke.
Why did they stop calling it the swine
flu and did all the farmers complain?
We ain't going to be able
sell no fucking pigs.
You keep calling it
the swine flu you want,
you want bacon up here fucking eyeballs
and every fucking pig warehouse out
there,
you know and don't even act like it.
Don't affect it because the government's
going to have to buy it back.
So why don't you come up
with a new fucking name for
h one n one is not the
name of a fucking plague,
the black death. That's the name of
a plague. All right. You know what?
Let me fucking look that up.
That's what's pissing me off
here is we finally got a plague.
You know something that I've been for
for a long fucking time.
Imagine if I ended up getting it.
They'd play this at my funeral.
Well, you know, we uh, he died
away wanting to die. I mean,
the guy was into the fucking
swine flu. Let me, let
me, let me search here.
Great plagues.
There's no way.
I'm not on some FBI fucking watch
list after this goddamn search.
How to fuck yourself spell plague.
I know it's not that way.
Pla gue great plagues did you mean I like
that after you should be fucking spell
it wrong and then Google's like, did
you mean this? You're fucking moron.
Of course I did.
Yeah.
All right. I guess there was
one called the great plague.
What do I need to search? Awesome plagues,
plagues. I want, I just search plagues.
All right.
This is a long fucking way to go.
Just tell you why that they should
still call it the fucking swine flu.
The 10 plagues of Egypt, Jesus
Christ, and one of the fluff.
So fucking skinny over there, Huh?
Time you turn around them. Mess.
A great way to lose weight. 10 plagues
in a row, even if you survive it, right?
There's no way you're going to be more
than a buck 40 are Egyptian skinny.
I don't even know what they are.
The only Egyptian I know is Anwar Sadat,
right? The 10 plagues. Ah,
who gives a fuck? All right.
Wait, the plague of lice,
the plague of flies.
What does it some biblical Shit I fucking
give up. You know what I'm saying?
They swine flu. That's a great
name. We'll think about it.
If you could just put yourself a
hundred years in the hit in history.
If you look back and they talk about,
you know,
when we're old we talk about it,
you know, every day was going great.
And then in 2009 the swine flu came.
Yeah.
G J GRANDPA. Where did the swine flu come
from? I'll tell you where I cam from.
Some foreign are fucked or fucking peg.
Have you guys noticed that?
All the new diseases,
there's never any sort of scientific
explanation of where they come from.
So all you can do is go get down to
your local bar and listen to people
hypothesize. I Dunno if you've
noticed, but anytime you go into a bar,
if you ask where a disease came from,
that's the answer you always get.
Somebody from another country had sex with
an animal and now we're all gonna die.
Ever since AIDS, remember that?
Do, I'll tell you what happened.
Somebody fucking blew a monkey and
then they fucked her store that's in,
there you go. You know, you always have
to have some sort of nationalism in it.
You know, don't, you don't see anybody
fucking pigs in this country. Right?
It's why we need to close the borders.
Ah, fuck. Yeah. I think the swine
flu would be great. You know,
it'd be a nice cleansing,
a nice cleansing,
get rid of, of punchy, you know,
you're not going to die of it.
Just take some vitamins, put
on a sweater, you'll be fine.
It's just going to kill the week.
And that's what needs to happen.
If you notice every other animal,
all the strong survive,
all the weak die the,
and that's why there's no,
there's no traffic in the
squirrel community. Have you ever,
have you ever just seen just a
fucking highways worth of squirrels,
you know,
peaking over each other's shoulders trying
to figure out what the fuck is going
on up front as are all waiting
to try to get some fucking
yeah.
Not or whatever the fuck they eat.
You know, you don't, you know why?
Because they did cause the weak
don't survive. And the problem is,
is we have medicine and
we keep saving people.
And that's why you can't get an empty row
on a plane anymore because seated next
to you or two fucking people who should
have died 30 fucking years ago, you know,
and if you don't believe me,
watch them.
Try to get their oversized
bag into the fucking, uh,
overhead compartment and
watch how their brain works.
As you're sitting there visually seeing
why doesn't he just turn it sideways?
If he has it going that way,
there's no way the door can close.
I can't believe he just tried
to close the door again.
Are you a fucking moron then? I like when
they're sitting there with a suitcase,
which I don't know if you've
noticed is a solid object. Okay.
And it's in the shape that it's in.
You can't push it in further.
Like it's a fucking beanbag and it's going
to take the shape of the compartment.
Like it's some sort of water based
thing. Alright. Jesus Christ,
Cleo. Oh my God, fucking
dog. Just farted really bad.
Really? You just got to lay there.
That's, you know, that's what kills me.
It's not that my dog farts, it's the
complete lack of guilt on her face.
She just doesn't give a shit.
Evidently that causes a lot of stress,
doesn't it? Holding farts in or
whatever. Some sort of methane gas.
I can tell you right now,
there's not a fucking ounce in my dog.
Cleo.
Why I bought you that nice big bed
about my dog. That's fucking insane.
Bed cost me like 200 bucks,
you know and I,
you know who spends 200 bucks in a bed?
I'll tell you I'd fucking dog on her
does cause that's how much you love your
dog. Right? And I swear to God, I've
gotten this thing there and it literally,
it loves this bed so much. You know
what it looks like when it's sleeves,
how hard this fucking dog sleeps on
the bed. You guys watch pro football.
You haven't noticed when somebody gets
knocked out for some reason when a wide
receiver gets knocked out,
this always ends up happening there.
Legs always end up crossed and then
they got that one arm like thing is like
stuck up in the air,
you know,
like they were right in the
middle of making a point.
Like they were pontificating.
If anybody at you haven't noticed
that that's how she fucking sleeps.
Her back legs get crossed and one of her
and she lays on her back and one of her
paws is up in the air. Like she
just got drilled by fucking ray. Um,
anyways, I what the fuck
I'm talking about here. Uh,
now I'm interested in
this 10 plagues of Egypt.
This has to be some sort of biblical Shit,
right?
That they're still fighting about today
that makes them want to kill Jews in
Egypt,
on Egypt and Israel as number three.
They always end up arguing about,
um,
I say you let them fight it out. That's
my solution to the Middle East. You know,
why don't we just pull up stakes
and let them have at it. You know,
you want to fucking kill each other. Go
ahead. It's great for the environment,
you know,
sort of a manmade plague. All right.
That's what I do the week of Thanksgiving,
I say, Oh, I'm pro war. Um, all right,
let's, let's talk about football.
I got a lot of shit last week
from people who are fans of, um,
Peyton manning for, uh, talking
about what a cry baby cry baby is.
And then a lot of points
that people brought up. Uh,
for some reason I can't fucking find them.
I don't know where the hell they are.
Maybe they're in junk,
but I'll basically paraphrase it.
Oh my God.
You're going to,
you're going to give Peyton manning
shitty and you can say Brady's not a cry
baby.
What about that time earlier this year
when he turned around and asked for a
flag and got the call?
What do you mean? Oh,
that's your example of Brady being a
crybaby because he got hit and he turned
around and asked for a fucking flag.
What you mean?
Like every wide receiver
when they don't catch a ball,
every fucking play in the NFL,
every fucking guy gets up
bitch and looking for a flag.
He got the flag.
The same way Michael Jordan is allowed
to push off people and doesn't get called
for a foul cause. He's one of the
stars in the fucking league. All right,
and other points somebody tried to make,
they're talking about all the roughing,
the passer,
the Tom Brady rule.
Tom Brady did not fucking
campaign for that rule. He didn't.
That was a fucking NFL rule where
they're like, wait a minute.
If our pretty boy
quarterbacks aren't playing,
the viewership goes down and we make
less money. That was a business decision.
Tom Brady didn't campaign
for that fucking rule,
which brings me back to the crybaby.
Peyton Manning,
who lost a playoff game to the Patriots
and fucking cried at the end of the
fucking game. And then he and his
coach, Tony Dungy made a fucking a tape,
a game tapes sent it to the league. They
cried some more at the fucking pro bowl.
Two weeks later, a week after
the Patriots won another title,
they're fucking crying again about it
and then he cried about it at the draft.
That's why he's a fucking baby.
And I forgot to bring up the fact when
he didn't win the Heisman trophy that's
on fucking youtube.
I believe Ricky Williams won it that year.
And when he didn't win it,
the look of entitlement would
you professional quarterback.
I always prayed for this. That fucking
look on his face. He's a fucking baby.
Tom Brady has never lost a game and
then thrown his teammates under the bus.
Peyton manning has.
How many fucking
more examples do you need?
All right.
You jackasses with your fucking
surrogate fucking team out there.
It's the Baltimore Colts, by the way.
All right. Or Colts. When I say Boston,
Baltimore Coats, I don't
fucking know. Fuck all you guys.
You just fucking hate the patriots because
we fucking went. And what did I say?
Did I not say that the Patriots
were going to fucking kill the jets,
which we did yesterday.
Other than that little brief hiccup,
31 14 all right.
And I called that Rex Ryan Shit too.
I've been saying it since the third
week. Rex Ryan, that poor bastard,
the guy's out of his fucking mind.
He's gonna make a halfhearted
attempt at his life this week. I did.
My prediction is he's going to break his,
he's gonna break his tailbone trying to
hang himself and yes, that is a fat joke.
All right.
I think I already did this on a podcast.
My psychological breakdown of Rex Ryan,
this is when I knew that guy
was out of his mind. Okay.
When he first said when the Patriots
were going to play him and he was like,
you know, I'm not here to kiss their
rings. I thought it was funny and like,
I like this guy, you know,
even though he's a coach of
the jets, he's talking shit.
But then there was that week when a
player from another team said something
derogatory about them and
he actually responded to it,
a hedge co head coach responding to some
player on another team and he's trying
to act all cocky and confident and
there was something about his smile.
I saw it in his face.
I'm like,
this guy fucking cries himself to sleep
every night with a pint of fucking ice
cream.
You know,
this is what I think happened.
All right? His Dad, Buddy Ryan,
one of the great defensive coaches
came up with the 40 60 fence, you know,
won a Superbowl. I'll tell
ya, doing something like that,
you don't have time to raise your kid
and you don't have time to be there for
them.
So all this shit talk and fucking Rex
Ryan does all the shitty saying is this
shit he wished his dad said to
him when he was, uh, killed kid.
So he could have built up some
sort of confidence, but he didn't.
He wasn't around.
So the combination is still looking for
his dad's fucking approval and living in
the shadow of a man who created the 46
fucking defense has caused this guy to be
an insecure shit-talking psychopath.
And I think in his head,
he knows that he can coach
at the professional level,
but the, the fucking deafening
voice of doubt that he goes,
that fucking is in that guy's head. I'm
telling you, that's why you overeat.
He's one of those guys, you know,
when that voice in his head's going,
rex, what are you doing coaching
at the professional level?
You're not as good as your dad that got
to find out you're going to get fired.
You'll never coach again.
You're going to have to move
home with your fucking parents.
They're going to kick you out.
You're going to be all bless. Yeah.
Not Heavy baguette. Oh yeah. That's
why he eats all that ice cream.
He gives himself that fucking ice cream
headache and that's all you can focus on,
you know?
And they,
it takes a couple of Tylenol pms and
then he goes to sleep and the next day
wakes up with all that dairy product
rolling around in his fucking intestines
and he's hung over from
all the Tylenol PM's.
And then he does a press conference.
He doesn't know what the fuck he's doing.
He's like one of those
wrestlers, you know, he's got
the sickness. He's like, Jake,
the snake. If he was fat, Hey,
you know what? Speaking of which,
somebody asked me a question,
um, this week they said, Bill,
you always drop references to
wrestling on your podcast. Um,
and during your appearances a,
the ric flair mentioned suplex seeing
a girl and you've said that during your
standup special.
So are you actually a fan or were you
a fan back when you were a kid? Um,
I don't think I know one adult in real
life who watches wrestling and I don't
blame him because a lot of a time it's
corny and it's Corny as hell, but a,
I'm still a fan and it's just one
of those things I never grew out of.
And if you're a fan, who is your
all time favorite? All right. I,
your first guest was correct.
I was a huge
fan when I was a kid and,
um,
but ric flair,
I have to admit,
I got into ric flair because of one of
the listeners here when he brought up the
flare chop and I started watching Rick
flair and I realized what a fucking
genius he was. So, um, I
watched the WWF when I grew up,
so ric flair was in something else.
I think with the von Erickson.
I kind of used to watch that,
but I,
I watch WWF and when I first started
watching Bob Backlund was the champion.
And I want to say Bruno Bruno Sammartino
might've been ted DBRC was the
intercontinental champion until Pat
Patterson took that foreign object out of
his trunks, smashed him in the face with
it, and somehow the ref didn't see it.
Then Pat Patterson became the
intercontinental champion.
And let's give me a sound like the
fucking rain man, as I always do.
When I tried to remember this shit,
uh,
the tag team champion was Tony,
Gloria and Larry's of Bisco and uh,
oh the fuck else. I haven't put
ski Polish power bulldog Brower.
Yeah.
Mr Fuji, Mr Sado, the Moondog,
you remember the fucking Moondogs,
those three fat hillbillies with their
overalls and then one wouldn't be laying
on the floor with the dog bone. And
I was, I was scared shitless of them.
You know,
it used to scare me was George the animal
Steele when he came out with the green
tongue and he'd be eating the belt buckle.
I thought it was fucking real.
Is fucking Harry back killer Khan the
way you used to scream that big Mongolian
son of a bitch used to scare
the shit out of me, you know.
Then I realized like George,
the animal Steele was like a fucking
substitute teacher ought to Detroit and
just kind of all fell
apart. So then I, you know,
I watched it right through Mr.
Wonderful Rowdy Roddy Piper.
MMM.
Oh Jesse the body Ventura when
he used to call a Tito Santana,
used to call him Chico Santana.
I don't care about no Chico Santana.
I used to watch back
then and then I briefly,
10 years ago I got back into it cause I
was roommates with Robert Kelly and he
started watching the Rock
and stone cold Steve Austin.
I got into it briefly during then,
but I used to mainly watch, uh,
just the shit talking on the mic,
but it hasn't been good for awhile.
So there you go.
There's my long drawn out,
a fucking answer to your
question there. Um, all right,
let's get on with the podcast here.
Um, oh wait a minute at the hype.
One other thing. I'm really all over
the place as opposed to the usual.
I'm even more so all over the place.
Um,
I have a new website out there.
It's called a uninformed radio.com and a,
that's the radio show. I deal with,
uh, Joe de Rosa and myself. Uninformed,
no reading, no research, just strong
opinions. It's our radio show.
Um, we are unable to get it onto iTunes
because we're not going through some big
conglomerate. Um, so we're just
going to be putting them up for free.
You can listen for free and eventually
you'll be able to download them for a
buck of whack. So there you go.
That'll be your options. You know,
if you don't want to pay,
you can just sit there and listen to
it at your computer. But if you know,
you want to take it on your iPod
and become the hit of the year,
the next party you go to,
you know,
just in case you go to a party and
they don't have a fucking computer,
you can download it, you can
download it for a buck. So, uh,
we're going to be trying to get that
up as quickly as possible. And uh,
and that's it. So anyways,
really been all over the place.
You know what I did last last week?
No, Bill, what the fuck did you do?
I went and I saw,
uh,
the best rock show I've seen in a
long time. I went to go see, uh,
uh, what does it them, Crick Crick.
Crooked vultures. So what the fuck?
I kept calling them crooked buzzards,
them crooked vultures. I went to go see,
which is, uh, uh, I guess
it's, that's super group.
It's got John Paul Jones
from led Zeppelin, uh,
David Grohl on drums.
And I don't know how to say the lead
singer's name cause I never heard anybody
say as a Josh Hommie from Queens of the
Stone Age and eagles of death metal.
I've been listening to all those bands
for years just because, uh, you know,
I've been a big fan of Dave girls drama
and so whenever he would go, you know,
do like killing joke or he'd
be in Queens of the Stone Age,
I got into those guys. So anyways,
I went to go see this show, um,
and I bought their new album.
They were actually selling it on vinyl,
so I had to get it so I could seem
cool and my next party and if you get a
chance, um, I mean their
whole album is up on youtube,
so listen to it. If you
like it, don't be a comment.
Go out and go buy it and then go see them
on tour. Man, they will fucking unreal.
And Dave Grohl might be the best live
rock drummer I've ever seen. The Guy,
he's just, he's fucking unreal.
The guy was the shit. And uh,
I dunno man. I felt like I was like a
fucking kid watching that were, you know,
even when you watch a great band and you
just wish you were up there doing it,
and then as you're driving home,
you start thinking of all the cool stuff
that happened and then you're actually
fantasizing
that it was you that did it. Like
that's how fucking good the, uh,
that's how I was just fucking
awesome. They're just a
fucking killer band. And, uh,
that's all I've been doing is listening
to this shit. So, uh, if you get a chance,
definitely go check those guys out.
Or if you want to see
the show that I went to,
what's already up on fucking youtube
because people record everything. Um,
just search, um, them crooked
vultures will turn w I l,
T, e, r, n and then Los Angeles,
and you'll get to see the fucking
show. I saw, you know, I haven't,
I've been fucking sitting here.
I've got the Goddamn game on mute here.
Who's winning?
Is it still one to one?
Okay.
Am I allowed to do that or am I on some
sort of copyright infringement here? Oh,
it's one to one.
The third period.
Buffalo's got a fucking great
goaltender, sons of bitches. You know,
something I wouldn't mind seeing
buffalo when it poor bastards. You know,
you got fucked in 99.
What else did you go to the finals?
Did you go to the finals in the 70s?
Was that Saint Louis?
Do you lose to the flyers? I don't
fucking know. No one gives a shit bill.
All right, let's plow ahead here. Uh,
last week I did the answer to the, uh,
the women thing.
Why is it never enough?
And that created an absolute shit storm
and a of basically misogynistic trashing
of women. So let's continue
it. No, I'm kidding.
We're going to try to balance it
out here. I actually, I took one,
two comments from women,
one supporting what was said last week,
and another one who just really brought
up the point that should have been made
from the beginning. So let me read the
first one. All right. Uh, first off,
bill loved the podcast,
especially this week's,
I've rarely heard someone so succinctly
describe what is wrong with the
predominant attitudes of
women. Even men today. Um,
you know what most women really
want from men? It's not material,
nor is it being spontaneous.
It runs deeper than that.
Women want sacrifice that I read this
last week. I can't fucking remember.
Maybe I did. I'm losing my
mind. Women, one sacrifice.
Most women will tell you, uh,
your dreams are selfish if
they don't revolve around them.
And that real love is
compromise and commitment. Uh,
they want you to drop. I'm just trying
to remember, did I had already read this?
Ah, fuck it. I'm going to plow ahead. They
want you to drop your hopes and dreams.
They want to see the moment you give up.
I emphasize that because once that moment
has passed and you have nothing left
to sacrifice,
you become that 30 to 40 year old loser
that they will leave to the guy who
asked,
why is it never enough?
It isn't until you've given up
everything that is important to you.
This is what love is for most women.
It's not even that they are selfish,
but proposed precisely the opposite.
It's the complete other lack of self.
I think I already read this,
didn't I?
The nature of love is not that of a host
and a parasite love is only possible
between two complete or independent
individuals who do not require sacrifice
from one another. Real selfish people do
not need approval or love from others.
They simply would not give a fuck.
I don't know if I agree with that.
What you're basically saying is you need
a significant part of your life that
you,
it's not two overlapping circles.
It's two intersecting circles
is basically what it is.
So where you intersect is your lives
together and where you're not is your own
fucking life that you're allowed to lead.
Um,
sign out. That was a bunch
of generalizations, but
that's what we do here.
But this, this lady here just basically
sums up the whole thing. She says,
Bill late,
you've been talking about men who have
been doing all these nice things for
women and the women have been complaining
about it like selfish [inaudible].
My response is this,
men need to stop allowing women to get
away with anything they fucking want.
Seriously as the pursuit of pussy turn
men into, um, all men into whiny bitches.
All these guys have been whining about
the way these girls react when they do
something they think is nice.
What these guys really need to do is
stand up for themselves and tell these
chicks they have two options. Say thank
you or I don't get number two. It says,
try to be nice and let them
and let him complain about it.
I don't know what that means.
Um,
these guys are writing to you instead
of confronting these women so the women
aren't even aware that their
behavior needs to change.
They are only making it worse.
Exactly.
That's really the truth
of all of this shit.
You know?
I mean, I actually ran into the guy when
I was in Tempe who wrote that, uh, that,
that letter of why isn't it enough?
I met his girl,
she was a sweetheart and everything.
It's just kind of a,
it just was a great question to ask.
That set off a lot of fucking
frustration and a, yeah,
what do the reality is, is what this
woman wrote here. Is that 100% true?
Is that you really shouldn't be
writing me bitching about it.
You should be talking to you woman.
But you know, some of it is, you know,
people just want to vent and then there's
other times people are there in fucked
up situations and by fucked up situations,
I mean they're married.
So,
um,
I think what a lot of guys learned quickly
is when they get married is now that
they are legally bound to someone
and if they break up with them,
they lose half their shit.
It becomes,
it's not a balanced situation,
you know,
if it, why should, I shouldn't
just just put that on guys,
but it's whoever has more,
whoever brought more into the relationship
when you get married you fucked
because you stand to lose more,
which weakens your arguing position,
which you have to do is get to that zen
place where you don't give a fuck about
materialistic goods.
And then you can really go off on whoever
the fuck you are with. But reality is,
you know, same thing, like when you
see like, you know, the big thing,
when I first started doing comedies,
I used,
so we see female comics would go on
stage and they'd be joking about how guys
don't know what they're doing in
bed. They'd be like, oh my God,
they have no idea where it is or what
to do. But Baba Baba Baba, you know,
which I understand the frustration
of that, but it's like, so, you know,
I'll wait. Sam Kinison did the bit,
just tell us, tell us what to do,
we'll fucking do it. Um, I think
that's what a lot of complaining is.
God knows a lot of my complaining is,
well,
why don't you just walk up to the person
or thing that you're bitching about and
tell him how you feel and just take
out all the fucks in the insulting the,
the insults. I Dunno, you know,
at this podcast fucking sucks.
I'm going to call it out before you guys.
This is podcast is just sucked this week.
All right.
I'm all over the fucking place.
I'm fucking exhausted.
It's a Goddamn holiday weekend.
You can you guys [inaudible] how
hard are you working this week?
You know,
has it?
Somebody's gonna come in and brought a
pie in and somebody is wearing an awful
brown and orange Thanksgiving sweater.
You know,
maybe it's your manager to show
that he has a human side. You know?
Isn't that the worst when
you hate your fucking boss?
And then around the holidays,
all of a sudden he just lets up a little
bit and tries to act nice, you know,
or it's a female. She gets a
little bit nicer, you know,
and the whole time she's sitting there
wishing you a happy thanksgiving,
you just want to fucking kick
her right in the box, you know?
But you can't,
you fucking can't.
Well, that was sad. What the fuck is it?
It's one to one 1515 minutes left
in the third period. You know,
one of the hardest things to do,
I think is to be announced or for hockey
now that they took and taken out the
red line,
the fucking game.
You break your neck sitting
there watching the fucking game.
That's why I like it and watching it on
TV is cause I don't have to keep turning
my head. The camera, the camera
moves for me. It does all the work.
What I'm literally out of
Shit to say they don't.
I feel like right now this how bad this
podcast is when you bomb is a comedian
is that works. When, when,
when shit is going great,
when everything you say is killing,
when you're on stage,
basically what happens is,
is you've done about 20
minutes of material and you
look down at your watch and
your watch says you've been
up there for 55 minutes.
That's when you know that you're
fucking killing. And conversely,
when you're bombing,
you will do an hour's worth of material
in 17 minutes and all you have left is
your closing bit.
And you look down at your watch and you
realize that you've been on stage for
just under 20 minutes and you're like,
wow, now what the fuck am I doing?
You know your mouth gets dry. That's
when you start going into the crowd.
Hey, you know, so what's there
to do around here in Raleigh,
North Carolina. Huh? Look
at this guy over here, Huh?
What do you do sir? Oh,
you're a plumber. Really? Uh,
a, I bet your butt crack is
always shut. Fucking kill me.
You know, you just, you just fucked. Hey,
how about a round of applause for the wait
staff, you know, keep it going for him.
You know, and I just want to thank
all you guys were showing up.
I know it's a recession. I
appreciate, uh, you know,
how about I am for the
tropes, you know, you know,
whether you support going to war or not,
you know,
these kids are out there that laying
down their lives and they're away from
their families in thanksgivings this week.
I think we should all sit back and give
thanks and be appreciative that I've
already done an hours worth of fucking
jokes and you cons haven't laughed in
anything.
So now I'm technically in overtime,
even though contractually I already,
I owe you like another 40 minutes
of fucking comedy, you know,
and let's not forget all the people who
have died in boating accidents this year.
You know,
a lot of people don't know that boating
accidents is one of the leading,
leading causes of death.
When human beings are out in the ocean
and you start remembering jokes from
the early part of your act and you start
telling him, you know, yeah, they
did a study the other day. They said,
you know, 90% of shark attacks
actually happen in shallow water.
No Shit. That's where the people are.
It's called the fucking beach. Oh,
what are their people swimming to Europe?
Let's go to France. You pussies. Ah,
you like that joke?
That's a joke for my act in 2001.
I'm too fucking old jokes on my act
on us than I used to fucking do.
All right? He didn't want to like my
original jokes. You guys see these uh,
rap group? Criss Cross one went up. Chris
warm it up. Chris. Hey, go to bed. Chris.
What do you like? Nine years old. Oh.
Oh my God.
I had horrible jokes.
He's do jokes about working in a dental
office. A people, I got news for you.
Six years. Neglect is not cured by
a tic tac in the waiting room. Hey.
Huh? You guys ready for
your next stack? Too Bad.
I still got another 30 minutes to do.
Yeah,
ladies back me up. Uh,
guys are crazy, right?
I mean, you know, where are we? We,
we don't give a shit that's gonna be
just searching for shit to say what,
but I mean it's, it's great to be
here in Raleigh. You know what I mean?
It's guy, you know, you come out
here to Raleigh, you know they got a,
they got a mall. All right folks, I'm
not gonna lie to you. I'm out of jokes.
I wish you could just do that and
just fucking become honest. I'm,
I'm out of fucking material. I don't
know what the fuck you guys want from me.
Come on. Tic, tic, tic, tic, tic,
tic, tic, tic. All right, 41 minutes.
Does that qualify as a podcast?
Oh, I actually, you know,
I forgot one story was
supposed to be here. I think
I got one other question. It's a
Phillips some time as I scroll down,
what's up with scrolling is a little,
when you're willing to do a fucking
piece of paper with some old Rodeo all.
Alright, unacceptable. Here you go.
Here's a classic example where somebody
should just have used the phrase
unacceptable and I really want to
go into this bar with this guy went,
this is a classic fuck over. Um, so bill,
I show up to this local sports bar at
11:00 PM the night before my birthday by
myself. While do, that's
your fucking fault, you know?
Yeah.
I don't know what your problem is.
Stop lashing out at the people
around you right now. Look at me.
I'm taking it out on you because I'm on
a material here and whatever the fuck it
is, I've lost my stream of consciousness.
Still one to one by the way,
with 12 minutes and 32 seconds to go.
Hey,
if anybody knows the name of the announcer
for the, uh, the Sabers, I'd love,
I'd love to know the guy's name.
I mean, I guess I could Google it,
but I know when I do, there's going
to be like fucking 58, you know,
buffalo sabers.net backslash org and
I don't want to go through that shit.
All right. So anyways, built, uh,
I show up to a local sports bar at
11:00 PM the night before my birthday by
myself. All right. He goes, the bartender
asked for my id, I give it to her,
she hands it back and
asked me what I would like.
Now I'm not looking for comments,
but you would,
you would think the bartender would be
aware of the date and time and have some
snide remark about hanging out by myself.
Um,
this close to my birthday.
Yeah.
Well,
I think she's just trying to see,
or he's trying to see if you're of age
and not, right. I don't fucking know.
Anyways. Uh, I'm not upset.
I'm just expecting a stupid
comment. So I ask her, uh,
what the specials are.
She tells me that the large
domestics are three bucks and well,
drinks are two bucks. I see they have
blue moon on tap. I'm not a huge fan,
but it's 22 ounces of beer for
three bucks. I'll suck it up.
I order. She says, okay, and serves
it. Fast forward to the bill,
it seems a tad high and I
see I was charged for 50
for each of the three beers.
I ask about the bill and she said,
oh,
only domestics are $3 my reply
was blue moon is a domestic beer.
It's made in America and she says,
no domestics or Bud Miller and cores.
Now wait a minute.
I thought Blue Moon wasn't
that made in fucking Belgium.
Now I've got to fucking look it up before
I take your side here because I really
want to be blue moon.
All right,
Blue Moon brewing company. All right,
here we go. Let's see what we got here.
Oh Jesus Christ. It's a whole
fucking website isn't blue moon.
It's not a Belgian beer date of birth.
Enter.
I have to give you a valid date
of birth to read about beer.
Are you fucking kidding me? All
right, let's go to Wikipedia.
God knows that's fucking accurate,
right?
A blue moon is a full moon. That's
not what I want. Blue Moon bear.
You're fucking, no one gives a
shit about space. Actually, I do.
My brother's really in this space
and I learned the other day I thought
something was the north star. He's
like, that's not in the north star.
That's Jupiter. How you'll get the fuck
out of here? He goes, yeah. First of all,
he goes, stars, twinkle
planets reflect light.
So ever since then I've been
looking up at the sky and go,
and that's a fucking planet.
I want to know what that is and
I want to go buy a telescope.
But there's no way to buy telescope
without looking like a fucking pervert.
You know what I mean?
That's yet another thing that perverts
who fucking ruin the same way gay guys
have ruined cowboy boots, cowboy hats,
and foo man shoes. You can't fucking,
you know,
you can't wear any of that shit unless
you're on a fucking ranch rustling of
fucking cow to the Goddamn ground or else
people think you're out there blowing
someone. Um, all right. Blue
Moon Beer. Let's see here.
Blue Moon beer is Molson
Coors brewing company.
All right, so the is fucking right. Good.
Now I can side with you because
I really want to go off on this.
So the fucking dude is ordering
a domestic beer and she goes,
no domestics or Bud Miller
and cores. Two things. First,
why couldn't she mentioned that Blue Moon
is not considered a domestic beer when
I ordered, but second, let's look at
the bigger picture. I'm sure bill,
you've run into this. You're told
domestics are on sale for happy hour.
So you order a Sam Adams.
At which point you told Sam Adams
isn't considered a domestic beer. Well,
actually, um, you may have thought, yes.
Sam Adams is a domestic beer.
It was made by the blood of the
American patriots. He had dumb cunt.
I like this guy. Uh,
who made the decision?
Who made the decision to call
Shitty Beers? Domestic beer.
What kind of a euphemism is that?
Whenever this happens in the future,
I'm going to ask for a manager and tell
them that not including all domestic
beers with their domestic
specials is unacceptable. Dude,
you should us fucking said that unless
this is actually made in a different
company. A country in Molson
Coors brewing just bought it.
You guys want to hear about it?
Blue Moon is a Belgian style wheat beer
brewed by the Molson brewing company in
Golden,
Colorado.
It's a fucking domestic beer was launched
in 1995 in Canada is marketed as a
similar beer called Rickard's white.
Why do they not have blue moon's up there
is blue moon offensive and it's brewed
in Montreal, Quebec. All right, so some
of it is brewed in another country.
Is that they're out? Well then it should
be called Rickard's white, right dude,
bottom line is you got fucked.
Yeah.
So they should say our are cheap ass beers
are a r three bucks and anything with
any sort of hops and flavor in it
is going to be for 50. There you go.
That's the big outrage of the week.
The student fucked. Um, all right.
That's the end of my lackluster one.
You know what I mean?
What the fuck do you guys want from me?
I do one of these every fucking week.
I'm running out of stories to tell you
I already did that gay guy joke before.
I've already done the fucking,
I think I need to take a break.
Just like the foo fighters, you know
when they sold out Wembley Stadium,
they sold it out twice and
they were sitting around going,
what the fuck else can we
do? Just like when, uh,
the Beatles sold out Shea stadium
or the police sold out Shea stadium,
that's when you just realize, well,
the only way to go now is to go down.
I think I've begun the backward slide.
I'm sliding down the backside of a,
of the podcast and I was
actually thinking about that.
How long am I going to do this
podcast? You know, Oprah's retiring.
She's calling it quits
after 25 fucking years.
I mean,
I've basically done one episode every
week for the past two and a half years,
or two years. Two months. So 52
weeks a year. That's 104 episodes.
Plus like another 20 maybe I'm
up to 125 episodes. All right.
Back in the day,
if you did a sitcom,
you needed a hundred episodes
to go into syndication.
I'm in syndication right now. So
think about that shit. I'm like,
if this was the drew Carey show,
I would be in like the seventh season,
you know when they've added the
fat chick with the crazy makeup,
cause we're on a story, ideas, you know?
So my question to you is how
much longer should I do this?
When do I bow out gracefully
and come out with a new,
a new form of a,
what do they call this
shit on the Internet? Huh?
Viral.
Yeah.
Do I, do I take it to the
next level? I do a video.
Maybe I'll do a video podcast next and
I'll do like, I'll, I'll have puppets.
All right, I'll have
the cont puppet, right.
What'd you just be sort of some twats
shape tortilla with a red lips on it,
you know, that can talk
and uh, whatever. I'm,
I'm just sort of brainstorming here
and a fucking no puppets.
A creepy,
you know,
you ever go back and watch
Mr. RogersRogers' and
just see how creepy those
fucking puppets are. You know why? Cause
their mouse didn't move king Friday.
Hello Lady Mclean.
My name is much.
Think I'm out of my fucking mind.
Actually did it in the living
room this week. You know,
that's why I had the Nice
Carnegie Hall sort of
Ah, Acoustics in here. Oh my
dog fucking walked out on me.
You don't really think my dog finds me
annoying. You know, I practice my guitar,
she has a habit of going,
gives me like a big fucking exhale and
if I'm practicing anything up high,
like I was trying to learn how to play
the beginning of for those about to rock,
we salute you,
which is way up on the neck of the guitar.
And I was trying to play it the way Angus
plays it, which is a combination of uh,
using a pick
and plucking with two other fingers.
So needless to say,
it sounded like somebody was choking
aspera and uh, my dog, you know,
she sort of got,
you know,
just lifted her head up and sort of looked
at me and I laughed because I knew I
was bugging her.
And then I was so focused on trying to
be able to play this for some stupid
fucking reason. And, uh,
when I came out of my fucking comatose
state, I looked and the dog had left.
So, uh, I don't know what the point of
that was. You know what the point was?
The point was to somehow get to 50
minutes because if I don't do it for 50
minutes, then I can't continue
to, to not get paid for this. Um,
what type my website? Uh,
Bill bird.com. Um, once again,
go there and a fucking,
I don't know,
go to my show in Cleveland or go to my
show at Sacramento. Those in, in a, in a,
the punchline is Sacramento.
There's the next two weeks I have coming
up and a or c'mon out and watch my live
taping. Oh, somebody asked me
a question and they're like,
which one of the two shows
are being taped that night?
Are both of them being taped?
And if you take both,
will you combine both and
make one special? Yes,
yes I will.
That's what happens.
You take both of them and if I just have
one set that's just fucking awesome and
I loved it. Wire to wire, which
I hope is going to happen,
I'll just take that cause I'm,
I'm really big into a,
you know, not creating a
performance that didn't happen. Um,
my CD is all one show. Why
do I do this? We only did,
we only taped one show, so that's
all one show. Um, my HBO special,
we did too.
And I forget which one joke is from the
first show and the rest was all from the
second show.
It's so it's basically
one performance and um,
yeah, so that's what I'm hoping for.
So yes, if you're wondering, yes,
both shows will be taped and um,
this is what you basically hope for.
What you do is you go out and you
fucking rock on the first one. See like,
all right,
I got a great special already and then
you can just totally relax and fuck
around on the second one. You
know, kind of the way you,
you get into like your head,
like you just in a club rather than,
than doing a special, that's
where you want to be. Um,
and that's what I want to try
to hope to do. So that said,
I need to rest my voice. I hope
everybody has a wonderful thanksgiving.
I would've played a Thanksgiving
song on my guitar, but, uh,
none of them exist.
There aren't any thanksgiving songs.
And I'd like saying Shit like
that cause there's always be,
actually there is one d Lawrence Welk
orchestra did and nobody gives a fuck.
There's none.
There's no
names. Is there a famous
one? You know what,
this is the last thing I'm
going to Google this week.
Let me see if I can find a
fucking thanksgiving song.
Do you know we used to do for
Thanksgiving, me and my family, we, uh,
or the family that I was part of,
it really wasn't my family. Um,
we used to fucking,
we used to,
we decided we were going to play
football one year and became a tradition.
We would play football and it was great.
It divided the family in half and it would
always be sleeting and raining and uh
, we would end up getting
into huge fights. Like, fuck
you, fuck you fist fights.
And uh, it was really bizarre.
And then we'd sit down,
we'd all be fucking soaking
wet, you know, grass stains and
uh,
but the food was great. You know,
still one of my favorite days.
Thanksgiving
music.
Get the fuck Outta here.
Yeah.
Thanksgiving songs.
They actually have thanksgiving music.
You fucking kidding me.
The Fuck Outta here? No, you
don't. You know what this
is. This is a classic thing.
When you go to search something and
it's just music. Shit just came up.
There's no thanks. Wait a minute, let me
go to fucking the evil that is iTunes.
This is the last thing I'm going
to do. This is over time. People.
You don't have to listen to this.
This is all for me right now.
Just checking this out for me. All right,
let's see. Itunes. Let's click on that.
Yeah,
you know, it really is time to end this
fucking show. When you guys listen to me.
You just fucking googling.
MMM.
All right, here we go. Here. Uh, thanks.
Giving music,
Susan Boyle that she
do Thanksgiving music,
the Thanksgiving walls,
the harvest home come ye thankful.
A Charlie Brown thanksgiving. Let's listen
to that. Let's have a listen to that.
[inaudible]
am I the only person who finds Charlie
Brown music? Unbelievably depressing.
[inaudible]
get off the black keys. You
can't. I'm trying to be happy.
Jesus Christ with the miners.
Is that minor chords in
their minors or sad? Right.
Majors are happy. Somebody is taking
guitar lessons. Actually I'm not
[inaudible]
what does that fucking
we're out of potatoes.
Hi. I wish I knew about classical
music. I could have made that funny.
This is where, uh, we're out of
potatoes. The fifth movement,
whatever the fuck they say.
This is the harvest home.
Is that the same? Ugh. I hate that.
Fucking inbred music at Bluegrass Shit.
Come be thankful.
[inaudible]
can you go? That's some, uh,
that's come ye thankful people
enjoy thanksgiving. Don't have sex.
You're all going to hell. That was the
name of that song. All right. Yeah,
I guess there is Thanksgiving music.
Who gives a fuck? Um, all right,
everybody have a great thanksgiving.
It's still one to one as far as I know.
Here you go. Brings it into
the zone. Craigy Wheela right.
Luke Cheech is back.
How about a score?
There we go for 41 left.
One to one and a stopped at your play
and a stoppage of the podcast. All right,
everybody. Happy Thanksgiving
and I'll talk to you next week.
[inaudible]
stop.
Stop.
[inaudible]
let star two
star. Just like in [inaudible].