Hey, what's going on it's Bill Burr.
It's time for the Thursday afternoon.
Just before Friday.
Monday morning podcast.
Uh,
just checking in on you,
just seeing how you weeks ago and how
things are shaking out. Jesus Christ.
If I get one more fucking tweak on pill,
what do you think is the carrier
Irving for fucking Isaiah Thomas Trade?
What do I think?
I think Danny Ainge is known what
the fuck he's doing up until now.
I think it's the trickle down effect to
the Kevin Duran trade where you for some
reason can just not have enough fucking
stars regardless of what your players
are doing.
Do you think they gave up too much?
Only time will tell. Only
time will tell. I will tell.
I would say that I
love, uh, Isaiah Thomas.
And what sucks about that trade was he
was on his way to being like the fucking
big Papi of, um, of the Celtics.
Like he was going to have a
fricking street named after
him the way he was going.
So it's a,
it's a real shame and a,
it was just a great dude.
And, uh, I, you know,
I, I dunno, I just thought he was a,
he fit in real well with our city.
You know, he was on his way to be
in a great Celtic I thought. And um,
we gave a bunch of fucking people to
get another guy who basically does the
exact same thing, has the same
amount of stuff. I don't know.
He's a little bit bigger.
I don't know who the fuck knows.
All I know is the team that Isaiah
succeeded with last year no longer exists
here. So, you know, I don't know
what the F I don't fucking know.
I hate all of this shit.
They gave up a first read
[inaudible] [inaudible] league.
Like how the fuck you get into the NBA
to that level or any sport you need to
get a fucking life when you start knowing
what people fucking make and all of
that shit. Like I, I don't, I, that's
where I tap out. It's just like, oh,
we traded that guy for that guy.
I will see what happens.
When does the season start
in a couple of months. Yeah.
I fucking think about it then either it's
going to work or it's not gonna work.
Um, there's a couple of
expensive fucking so stupid.
They burned their Isaiah Thomas Jerseys.
Like he left the Celtics, like he was
doing some sort of free agent. Fuck,
he got traded. You'd dumb fucks. Um,
then of course everybody on Twitter tweets
it to me and acts like this is every
Celtic fan and it isn't,
it isn't this always these fucking morons,
which is why I have been saying,
you know,
I would fucking,
I'm telling you right now,
this fucking Mayweather McGregor fight,
if he ever wanted to solve
the population problem,
the amount of mouth breathers
that are showing up, okay.
You send a fucking signal through the
fucking boss, whoever orders the fight,
that's it.
You're done.
Something happens.
You know when he needs to play in those
old spy movies where they would play
that really high pitch fucking noise and
people would just grab their ears like,
and then they would die.
Yeah. Do some star Trek Shit.
MMM.
That's going to go down is one of the
biggest fucking rip offs of all fucking
time. Mayweather. Mcgregor.
MMM.
That's my prediction.
And if it doesn't,
I'll just say I was wrong and
then I'll order the fight,
but there is no fucking way I'm going to
sit there on Saturday night and watch a
guy who used to fucking box 1520 fucking
years ago fight a guy who fucking
retired two years ago who's in his forties
and everybody's asking me acting like
it's going to be his first fucking law.
The guy's in his forties
he's been retired for two years.
You remember when Jordan came
back on the fucking wizards?
Okay.
Taking two, three fucking years
off. You know that was basketball.
Forget about boxing.
This is like the dumbest thing ever.
You know what it really is? It's a bunch
of fucking losers that want the know,
that are unhappy with their own lives,
that want to see a guy that's been
shooting his mouth off saying is life is
fucking great and they want to see him
getting knocked on his ass and I'm so
sick of people go there. Just
spectacle it. Just spectacle. I'm just,
I'm tuning in for this spectacle.
Why are you using that word spectacle?
You fucking moron.
Because everybody on in sports has been
saying this since the amount of fucking
mouth breathing dopes that I've
known, you know, and I'm one of them.
I've never heard him use the,
the,
the expression spectacle in my life
now it's like, yeah, just watch.
I'm watching it for the spectacle.
It's a spectacle. The sport.
What does that mean exactly?
A spectacle. You mean?
Is that like a fancy word for,
it's a fucking rip off.
These are the same people that would
have paid fucking $60 you know,
the equivalent of $60 30
fucking years ago, 40 years ago,
to watch Lyle Zeto fight
fucking Mohammed Ali,
which actually happened if he never
looked it up. Alright, spectacle.
Let's look up the definition of spectacle.
Spectacle number one.
Something to stare at. Number
two, a paper view. Rip Off. No.
A visually striking performance or display
and invent or seen.
Regarded in terms of its visual impact.
I Dunno,
I dunno what's going on with sports right
now or that fucking league where they
just take three people who used to be
superstars in played three other people
that used to be superstars and a,
what do you get out of watching that half
court basketball confirmation that yes,
we are all going to die a slow death.
I'm sorry, I'm really just being a
scrooge. Enjoy your fucking fight.
I will not be watching it.
I'm going to get out on the highway and
drive like 80 miles an out here in la,
you know,
and enjoy this city at the population
that should be during that fucking fight.
There's so many more constructive
things that I can fucking do. And um,
this,
you know what it is?
Is it just doing this clearly
for the fucking money and uh,
that's it. So, you know, in a way it's,
I'm actually happy for them because they
both get in their brains knocked out in
every fucking fight and God knows what's,
what their quality of life will be
in their fifties so good for them.
Go out and get your fucking money. But
I've given may, whether it at least,
I don't know, but his last
seven fights times 6,420 bucks,
that he should return at
least a portion of it.
He hasn't knocked anybody out since said,
was it Ricky Hatton?
He fights fucking packy out 10 years
after he should have the guy shows up with
the fucking injured shoulder. His singing
voice is gone and he just fucking edit.
It's just, I dunno. All right.
I've, I've said my piece.
You guys enjoy the fucking fight and uh,
you,
you texted me your oh shits
and whatnot. Um, afterwards,
first he was saying that bill, it's just
spectacle. It's a spectacle. It's fine.
It's like, dude, I've known you for
10 years. You've never said that word.
Um, like they're above it.
Like they're above it. I'm
just watching you. I, you know,
I know it's bullshit. I know. It's
like, no, dude, you can't look away.
That's what's your fucking problem is
people who are getting it just because,
oh we,
it's going to be so fucking ridiculous
are the same fucking cons in front of you
causing a traffic jam because somebody
changing their tire on the side of the
fucking road because they can't look
away and they will write behind all those
other cons screaming at him,
go on, go, go, go drive.
And then the second they come up to it,
they sit in their fucking rubber neck.
All right there,
I'm telling you,
you wrote the human population is like
the human population is like a fucking a,
you know, you know those fucking
movies that Hollywood always makes,
you know with a white person goes into
like the fucking inner city and then goes
in and turns everybody's fucking life
around and everybody become successful in
all of those. Nobody fucks it up, right?
That's what the world population is like.
It's like that teacher is running shit,
you know,
can't make the cuts that he needs to
make to get down to the fucking real NFL
roster.
Does it make any fucking sense?
I'm just saying it's just too big a heart.
I hate those fucking feels fucking
movies, by the way, you know,
with a white person goes into the area
with his no white people and then save
Shit. And they never addressed the fact
that white people caused the situation.
You know?
And then we turn ourselves into the hero
so that white people can go
see the movie and be like,
that's the white person Ip
in that scenario. Well Buddy,
you could go fucking do it.
There's plenty of schools that a fucking
hero white guy to go down to to try to
help out.
You know what it is right now.
I'm fucking on a rant right now
just because they fucking, you know,
Neil Neil loves those goddamn awards shows
and all of these fucking liberal cons
that go up on there. And they
talk about dolphins, you know,
and they blah blah blah.
And they use their celebrity is shine a
light on it before they go back to their
fucking gated community. It's like, why
don't you get your hands dirty? You know,
get your hands dirty or shut the fuck up.
And you're fucking Louis Vuitton Tuxedo,
whatever the hell it is you're doing.
Why am I in such a mood? You know what it
is. I didn't sleep well last night and,
uh,
these fucking,
I don't know why this army of bugs
beat the shit out of my left ankle.
Um, and it's on fire. I don't
know if it was a spider.
I don't know what the hell it was,
but my whole fucking foot turn red,
you know, and it's something back
in the day before I had a kid,
my wife would help me out with,
but now we have a kid. So you know,
I've gone down on the depth
chart it, I'm like, damn,
let's look at my fucking foot.
She's like, Jesus Christ, I've got,
do we have anything for that? And
she's like, yeah, I think we do.
Yeah,
that's it. I'm like, uh,
do you know what it is? Ah,
some aloe fucken Moose.
You put some Mousse on it.
I don't know.
So I've been dealing with, she
claims that, you know, as you know,
the doctor that she isn't claims
that it's getting better. I Dunno.
All I know is a,
you know,
I'm talking to you guys with
a really fucking itchy foot,
so maybe that's what it is. Um, oh man,
that's going to be fucking exciting.
I'm going to actually get to
experience what people experience.
You don't give a shit about
sports on the super bowl.
You get to fucking cruise around the city,
get a bunch of errands done, you know,
ride a bicycle right down the
middle of the street. Yeah,
this is a bad podcast, everybody, if
you're not really not really aware of it.
At this point, I started off negative
and I want even more negative. Um,
is anybody else sick of that fucking guy
in the Lakers, dad already? Jesus Christ.
It's like he made it to the NBA. You're
going to get your money. All right,
enough with the fucking carnival barking.
I would make Michael Jordan
cry if I played him one on one.
Was that the weirdest interview?
I just saw a clip of it and Jimmy Kimmel
is literally talking over the guy who
was actually going to go into the NBA
to talk to the guy who never made it to
the NBA,
who's sitting there is talking about how
he's going to beat Michael Jordan and
the other guys sitting there like a
scolded child that looks like a fucking
parents teacher meeting.
[inaudible] um,
tell me that isn't a 30 for 30.
When he goes to finally make his
break from his overbearing father. Um,
all right. There's another negative
thing. All right, where else?
Where else can we go with negativity? You
got anything positive to say? Ah, yes.
I finally have to not drinking
after false advertising of Billy.
No fun months ago. I can
only go three, four days.
I have now put together a run of
seven days of come back up from AAA.
I'm on a little bit of a heat
hitting streak right now and uh,
I've gone seven days and um,
I love it in the morning, not drinking
in the morning is the greatest at night.
It's been, uh, it's been a
little bit of a, uh, you know,
it's a fucking habit I have to
break, but I think, you know,
once I get it for like seven to 10 days,
then I'm like,
it literally go for a year. It's
weird. It's just getting to that,
you know, starting to drop some weight.
I've been jumping on the ellipticals,
uh, been fucking working
out my uh, rotate a cup,
feels a little bit better and a,
what I do at night is I just got to go
play drums and then I go do a stand up
set to a couple of sets last night.
Played some fucking drums and uh,
it's weird above playing drums are
an instrument is the more you learn,
the more you realize you suck and it's
just really frustrating. You know,
it's almost like he's just
learn everything you can
to learn, stop learning,
get all that shit down. Considering
I'm never going to play in a band.
I'm not going to pursue
this professionally.
Then I could actually sit
behind the kit and be like,
happy with what I'm fucking doing.
I have learned how to tune up a snare.
I can get it sound really good,
but my bass drum sounds like shit,
there's always something.
So he's fucking something.
Let's read some advertising here.
Maybe if I read advertising,
this will get me out of this negative
vortex and I fucking gone into
Jesus and 13 and a half minutes.
Okay.
Just negative. You know what's
funny is what I should really be,
I should really be rooting for this
McGregor Mayweather fight to be a great
thing. Cause then I can,
I can rent it and then,
and I'll get to watch
something interesting,
but I'm s I so want to be
right about this, you know,
you're not going to get me right.
I'm the Guy Walking, you know,
driving by who wants to look,
but I'm not going to look to prove some
sort of point that nobody in front of me
behind me or next to me.
He's going to give a shit about.
That's basically what I'm
doing with this. Um, anyways,
prediction on the fight. Yes. Uh, I
want to say Mcgregor's not going to be,
and you know, I dunno, it's two years ago,
if he's anything like he used to be
Mcgregor's not gonna be able to lay a
fucking hand on them.
Why anybody would think that McGregor
could lay a fucking glove on.
Mayweather is fucking beyond me
unless these,
unless he got really old
in the last two years,
unless it's Jordan from the Bulls to the
wizards. And if it's that type of leap,
yes, Mcgregor has a fucking
shot, but then who gives a shit?
He beats up a fucking guy, you
know, two years after he retired,
you know, imagine not going to the gym
for two years. Okay. Then fucking chick,
you know, racing somebody down the
street for a fucking mile. All right,
me undies are,
but it'll doe doe B and beyond these
old bill is a negative con Boudou too.
To me on the shut 'em up
if you want, I'm sorry. Ah,
you too can look good in your
underwear and be comfortable, right?
No, you want to look good in your
underwear and be comfortable. Right.
But that perfect balance is hard to find.
Don't sacrifice style of comfort.
Checkout [inaudible] dot com and find
the best pair of underwear in the world
world, world, world. Talk
about me undies and whites.
The best underwear you will
ever own. Well, first of all,
they sent it to me for free. Second
of all, it's fucking cottony soft,
but three times more so you know,
in late at night when my wife goes to bed,
my daughter's sleeping
and everybody's quiet.
My balls talk to me and
they say thank you bill.
Thank you for getting me undies beyond
these will be the most comfortable pair
of underwear you will ever own.
Made from a sustainably sourced natural
soft fabric fabric that is three times
softer than cotton for the fellows,
me undies,
diamond seen pouch cradles your jewels,
Lacoe Rod Stowe bowl bag
and gives you your stuff.
It gives you stuff to support it.
It needs without feeling too tight.
Ladies will love the soft
ecofriendly fabric for their twats.
They're so soft and touchable,
gross,
100% satisfaction guarantee that guarantee
you will love your undies or your
money back for whatever reason. There's
still another three paragraphs here.
Aren't you guys sold at this point?
Yeah.
[inaudible] is so sure you
will love their underwear.
They'll even offer a 100%
satisfaction guarantee.
You order a pair and if you don't like
your first pair of get a full refund and
fucking throw it out the window at
a homeless guy. I'm not the money,
the underwear, you keep the
money. All right. This no brainer.
This is a no brainer to try 20% off free
undies in 100% satisfaction guarantee.
What are you waiting for it to get
your 20% off and free shipping?
100% satisfaction guarantee and they get
the best soft underwear you'll ever own.
Go to [inaudible] dot com slash
bar this limited time offer.
This is a limited time offers.
So what are you waiting for?
Start wearing the best underwear of your
life. It changed my life evidently. Yeah,
it did. Cause I got to sing this song and
uh, I got more advertising from it. Um,
it's time to let me on these change.
Yours.
Go to [inaudible] dot
com slash bar right now.
Yeah.
Oh, we only have two reeds. Oh my
God. I love it. Legal Zoom, everybody.
It's national.
Make a will month at legal zoom and that
means it's time to take control of your
family and assets.
Preparing your family's future is the most
important thing you'll do this summer.
It's the most fucking important thing you
could ever do. All right? All the time.
People die in car accidents.
They drop a heart attacks a fucking piano,
falls in that Goddamn head.
All these young guys,
their wife fucking nags him to death
through an early fucking grave and they do
not have a will or a
trust or any of that shit.
And then all the fucking
evil people show up.
Yeah.
Start claiming that they were your best
friend and they tried to take all your
shit and the money away from your kids.
You have to fucking do it.
It's something that guys don't like to do.
Dealing with their own mortality,
which is probably why I'm not
going to watch Mayweather come in.
The fact that I could actually watch a
guy who does not box for a fucking living
possibly beat the best boxer of all time.
All that's going to mean is that yet bill,
everybody dies.
I don't need to watch that.
I don't need to watch the big three,
the big three coming out there and then
fucking walkers playing each other and
nobody can dunk anymore. I'm sure somebody
can dunk their fucking nine feet tall,
but I'm just saying, all right, man,
do not like to deal with that shit.
All right? But uh, this is, you've
got to fame. You got a family man.
You've got to fucking deal
with this stuff, right?
So go to legal zoom.com/ [inaudible]
prepare to get your free kit.
You'll get a ton of helpful
information plus legal zoom discounts,
all the things you need to
stop procrastinating and
start preparing for your
family's future.
Legal Zoom designed the kit to provide
the tools you need all in one place.
Whether a will or a trust is right for
you. What the fuck's wrong with my voice?
Not Drinking, I'm not smoking. Uh,
you'll get special legal zoom discounts
plus an estate plan checklist and ebook
and other information to help you
decide out of the buck them blue.
And if you have any more questions,
you can always get advice from their
network of attorneys available in all 50
states since legal zooms, not a law firm.
That's the guy I did all of this shit.
Okay.
And I didn't want to do it cause I didn't
want to deal with me dying and all of
this shit. What do you want to do when
you die? Do you want to be cremated?
Put in the ground and all this shit? I
gotta tell you, when I was done with it,
it was like a weight was off my
shoulders and my chest. I mean,
cause every time I'd get on a flight,
you know,
I always think of this fucking
thing goes down right now.
What's going to happen to my wife and kid?
You know what I mean?
Go to legalzoom.com/prepare today.
There's no obligation,
just great resources to help you protect
everything you you care about during
national. Make a will month. That's
legalzoom.com/prepare. All right,
now it's time to talk about
my real feelings about
the Mayweather McGregor fight. I
am curious. I do want to watch,
but I've just been burned
too many fucking times.
So what I'm doing is I'm letting
you guys take the beach. All right?
And if you tweet at me, Oh my God, that
was fucking amazing on [inaudible].
He is going to lie to me.
I'll,
I'll go on the internet and if everybody
said that was amazing and it was worth
the fucking money, I will then rent the
fight. That's what I'm doing from now on.
Cause I've just, I've just been
burned too many fucking times. Um,
I think it will be devastating
for boxing if Mayweather loses,
even though he's been retired
for two fucking years. Um,
basically it's all about
the first couple of rounds.
If Mcgregor's going to do it, if he
doesn't do within fucking three rounds,
he's fucked. That's it. Okay.
There's my brilliant insight.
I know what everybody else
knows. I've watched too many
of Mcgregor's fights. Any,
when he fought Nate, he get into the
fourth round and he would be winded.
So they fight five minutes round.
So I don't know. I don't know.
I think even though they only fight
one, how many I'm, how many minutes?
Or there's a three minute rounds,
right?
So
logically you'd be like,
well, five minutes in then,
then that's the equivalent to go in
five rounds. I mean, three rounds,
five minute rounds in the fucking UFC.
Jesus Christ belt. But here's the thing,
he's going to be using different muscles.
You know,
he's going to waste a lot of fucking
energy trying to hit somebody that nobody
could fucking hit.
And um,
I dunno.
I Dunno what it is,
but they're both brilliant fucking
fighters that both amazing. And uh,
they're also, you know, they're
as good at selling a fight,
which is why everybody showing up and
all of that shit cause two big shit.
Talkers,
you know,
there's nothing people like better than
seeing a shit talker lose and one of
them's going to lose. So I guess
that's why everybody's going to watch,
but I cannot fucking resist.
Okay.
D a the euphoria of not doing what
everybody else is doing and getting to do
other shit.
It's something I learned when I would
watch the super bowl and I would just take
the fucking thing and just do other shit
for the first 90 minutes of the game.
So I can fast forward through all of the
commercials and the absolutely fucking
horrific halftime show and the opening
ceremonies and all of that other bullshit.
I could just watch the Goddamn game. I
remember when I would drive around and go,
you know,
okay,
get something to eat or some shit and
they'd just be nobody on the fucking road.
And you just get to experience
what you city was like,
okay.
Back before there were automobiles,
except you're in a car and
there's paved roads. I don't know,
there's this sort of a,
uh, I kind of understand
a little bit
like why people don't watch sports.
I actually get it now.
Like the amount of free
time and if you to put it,
the thing is you've got to fill that
free time up with like some healthy shit.
Oh this is like a nice ying and Yang.
Total negative. Nominal go positive.
Just do some magic.
Yeah.
First of all,
a the food you wouldn't eat.
All right.
All the extra time you'd have to work out.
You know,
if you always wanted to learn how to
play guitar and learn how to speak a
language, the amount of
time you spend, you know,
I can't say wasting your time because
you enjoy it. I fucking enjoy it. Right.
If you're a sports fan, but just think
of everything that you could accomplish.
I remember like one of the first times
the NFL went on strike in my life
and then when it, when it
would come back, you know,
they showed a couple people on the news
and I don't know if they were lying or
whatever and they were just like,
yeah man, you know, I'm Kinda,
it was Kinda cool to have like Saturday
and Sunday in the fall to myself.
I can hang out with my kids.
I can go do some shit.
I just don't give a fuck anymore.
Um,
okay.
I don't,
there's this weird part of me.
I can't stop watching it then.
This is part of me that I wish,
I wish I could do it, but they need you
just fill it up with something else dumb.
Then I become one of those ones,
comic con people
that knows the actor's name that crushed
down in that r two d two fucking thing.
Little fucking trash compactor
that he was riding around in.
I Dunno. Do you know what all of
this shit, it's, it's bigger than me.
I have no idea what any of these fucking
shit means. Enjoy you God damn fight.
Don't, let's do a crappy freckled
bald like me telling you that.
It's a fucking rip off you go and joy you
goddamn spectacle. Yeah. You deserve it.
It's a spectacle. Donald Trump
isn't enough of a fucking spectacle.
That's not enough for you,
Jesus Christ.
Do you know I don't even, I don't even
fuck I that. That's something like,
I pay attention to that.
I don't pay attention to that.
The way somebody does who doesn't give a
fuck about sports pays attention to it.
Um, the fact that our president tweets
and reads is his Twitter account.
It's just, I don't, I don't even know.
Like it's like, dude, you're above that.
You go above it,
fucking respond. I don't, you don't meet
people shit on me. I don't even, I feel,
I don't even need to respond to people
shitting on me. I, first of all,
I feel it's par for the course.
Not Everybody's gonna like you fact
that this fucking guy's got to go on and
responsive.
What are you doing?
But then again, he did win it.
He Won. He won the whole fuck it.
I love people who think he's dumb.
It's like if he's that fucking stupid,
how did all those smart
people lose to him?
That was like back in the day when that,
that Woman Jessica Simpson,
when she would be like chicken of the sea.
Is that like chicken or is it tuna?
Which to be honest, looking back
was a legit question. I mean,
it is a food and he wrote chicken on it.
That's like chicken fried steak for years.
I'll say, is it chicken is at stake.
What the fuck is it? Hey,
take a ride in my truck car.
What the fuck is it? Why would you
call it something else? What is this?
Um, everybody thought she was
dumb. It's like, yeah. Yeah.
She's a fucking moron with hit
albums in our own TV shows. Like,
I would love to be that stupid.
You. No, she married Nicholas.
Shay's a good looking fella,
right guys? Guys in a boy band.
He plays golf on the fucking weekend.
She was crushing it.
Date and Tony Romo. Robo
Robo. Did she marry him?
Yeah,
I don't know. I felt bad for
one day. Like, I think it
was her. She, her little dog,
you know, like last seen in the
mouth of a coyote. It's like, yeah,
it's fucking dead.
MMM.
What do you think the coyotes have like
some sort of terrorist group and they're
going to fucking, you abduct your
dog and change it's fucking mindset.
It's going to be like the patty Hearst
to fucking chihuahuas. No, it's, it's,
it's dead.
Um,
that's why you got to
get a big dog out here.
You got to have a big dog that liked the
other Kyries are like, you know what,
it's not fucking worth it. You know
what I mean? Like for dogs out here,
this is like going to fucking
Rikers island. All right.
Will you need a big need to be a
big fucking muscular goddamn dog.
You need to be more of a fucking problem.
Then these little fellows out there,
these little dogs like,
I don't know what people do.
Like they fucking leave them in their
backyards and shit and they just,
they just did gone dead.
Gone.
Okay.
It's like lights, like literally like
one of those creepy fucking movies,
you know, where they would, you know,
the people would go to an island and
they were just living with some sort of
dragon or some sort of gorilla and they
would just sacrifice somebody like King
Kong and that type of shit. So this
fucking thing, but leave him alone.
That's such a weird beginning,
Huh?
To the King Kong movie that poor woman's
like tied up at those fucking vines and
I just don't get like,
okay,
you got a 60 foot God damn gorilla
he's going to eat that fucking won
one person and then be like filled up.
That's going to be like Doritos,
right by not Doritos because we're mostly
fucking, you know, protein and shit.
We're kind of a protein snack, Ali, right?
So that's like Kim,
you have on like a Clif bar.
Goddamn 60 foot gorilla is going to eat
one clif bar every couple of months and
then be fine. First of all,
I didn't think gorillas,
I thought they were vegetarians,
right?
I thought they sat around just fucking
eaten. I don't know what the hell eat.
There's always some fucking person got
to go try and live with them and get a
little closer and a little closer
and then eventually get
the shit kicked out of them
by the God damn gorilla.
I gotta tell you, man,
the amount of shit that a gorilla we'll
put up with it because it's as big as it
is.
I wonder if a gorilla has
ever fought like a tiger.
And for that we need to go to Asia.
You know,
you want to talk about spectacles where
you have a boxer against an MMA guy like
Asians. I'm telling you,
if you want to go see any,
anytime you start looking at like
this versus this, this versus that,
you will find black and white footage
where they put a fucking bear and a tiger
in the same cage to see what our alliance
against the tiger just to see what the
fuck would happen. Um, they did it.
That's their thing
where we experimented with human beings.
They experimented with animals, it seems,
I know, fuck. What am I even
talking about? You know,
this is one of these podcasts where it
just started off on the wrong foot head.
Now I'm just desperately trying fill the
last 18 seconds of this thing so I can
get up to fucking my contractually
obligated 30 minutes.
How about those red sox aren't taken.
Two out of three out of
Teray Terry Francona is fucking a
team there. The Cleveland Indians,
um, piling up the fucking numbers there.
I haven't been keeping up on what the, uh,
the Yankees are doing. So why don't I
try to end this thing on something plaza.
If you guys enjoy your fight, your
sports spectacle, this, this weekend,
I hope you don't get fucked over. And
I'm, I'm being honest. You know something.
I'm going to be a bigger man here rather
than being the guy that said I told you
so. I hope on Monday you guys can all come
back and I can read a bunch of fucking
letters of like bill,
you negative cont you've never been wrong.
More wrong in your freckled
pathetic life and a,
I really hope that you guys are able to
send those to me. I hope you make it.
I hope you get your money's
worth. Um, like I said,
I will not be watching the fucking
thing. Um, I'm too God damn stubborn.
All right. I, you know
something, I'm actually, this
is, this is actually from me.
This pay per view is about being able to
walk away because I have jumped on the
fucking, you know, the UFC has
done that to me. You have three.
I've ordered the fucking shit and then
find out somebody tested positive for
steroids. You know, UFC is
also doing that shit now.
Now that they got bought out by
other fucking people. You know,
Dana White's like the
figurehead now. However, the,
how the the fuck it works that doing that
shit now where like every three pounds
is a new way class. So now they
have all these air quote champions.
So then everything's a
fucking championship fight.
That's like what fucking killed boxing
aside from the fact that they had like 50
different goddamn leagues or whatever,
the WBA, WBC, the IBF, the,
it was like three heavyweight
champions all at the same time.
And then somebody had to try to
come in and unify the titles.
MMM.
Yeah. And like then, like every,
like eight pounds became like a
fucking weight class or whatever. I'll,
I know is everything was like a
title fight and they were, they did,
they weren't as good. So I hope to,
UFC doesn't go that route because, um,
what was great when they had the
monopoly was the best fought the best.
So I hope that continues.
Yeah.
I apologize for this podcast everybody.
I don't know why I'm shitting
on everything. That's just fun,
simple goddamn fun in this miserable
world. Why would I do that? All right.
Come on bill.
Pull it out of the mud.
This fight is going to be the
greatest spectacle of all time.
If you do not put $60 down on that,
you are going to miss out,
right?
There you go. That was positive. Ah,
what do you want from me? I tried.
I tried. I got an Itchy foot and my
fucking body is like reacting to the fact,
you know, you know what else is,
um, a couple of my friends, uh,
yeah,
became parents,
right?
So I always do my gift than I
do is I go out and I buy a nice,
cute, cool pair of fucking sneakers,
right? Little Jordans, all uptown's,
whatever the fuck you want, right?
That's what I get for the kid. Okay?
And then I get to sick bottles of
fucking booze for the parents. You know,
because here's the deal.
Everybody's,
I think I already told you
that everybody's going to
go out and go buy a stuffed
fucking animal,
this fucking thing.
And it's just going to be
this thing that the parents,
the kid can't fucking use it.
It's a baby to Goddamn blob that you
carry around for fucking three months.
All right? And then when we
finally can move around it,
it doesn't give a shit about toys.
All right?
It likes extension cords.
It likes pots and pans.
It likes, see if just any fucking
thing that it shouldn't be touching.
That's what it wants. And it could
give off. Fuck about the Goddamn toys.
Buying a toy for a baby is the biggest,
it's a bigger waste of money than buying
this Conor McGregor Mayweather fight
this weekend. I just can't
get out of it. People. Um,
I feel like the libertarian this weekend,
you know,
who is actually addressing the problem
where the Democrat and the Republican
would back one of the two candidates and
act like it's going to change your life
and that this was going to
be a good thing for you.
And I'm the fucking the fucking Green
party guy going, hey man, he's bankers
fucking you over man.
Everybody's button pay for me.
MMM.
You want a Brussel Sprout
nava account of sandwich man.
Um,
but the parents, everybody
fee immediately, immediately.
Now that you have a kid like you,
you go down on the depth chart,
nobody gives a shit about you.
Everybody cares about the kit. Right?
Which is great.
That's the way it should be.
But if you actually do
something for the parents, okay.
And actually acknowledged that they are
individuals with hopes and dreams that
have now been dashed because all of
their focus is now going on the baby,
which is the way it should be.
But every once in a while you got to
throw him a fucking little ginger snap
there. Right? So that's
what I do. I go out,
I buy a sick ass bottle of booze in a
nice bottle for the guy in a fucking nice
bottle of Rozay for the lady. And then
I just get the kid a pair of shoes,
sneakers,
cool sneakers for when the kids walk in
and they can actually use those things,
you know, and it's supposed to some
stupid fucking thing. You know,
that they're supposed to reach up
and grab whatever the fuck it is.
That's what I do. Okay, there you go. Um,
anyways, fucking, I got the hiccups.
My Foot itches and I'm off the sauce.
I'm after sauce and I'm going back to
Boston this week and I'm staying off the
sauce. I'd been working out and
I'm staying off the fucking sauce.
Um, I already, I already had
the conversations in my head.
I'm not fucking doing it.
I'm going to go on a nice nash run here.
I am a committed to it. I'm dropping
some fucking pounds. So that's it. Um,
enjoy your guys' fight this weekend.
I hope you get your money's worth.
I've said that 50 times trying to make
up for the fucking previous negative 30
minutes. Uh, that's the podcast for this
Thursday afternoon. Have a great weekend.
You constant joy,
this music and a,
and then we got to throw back
podcasts. Mothers' Thursday, I dunno,
from last year or the year before.
Maybe a couple of weeks ago. Who knows?
All right,
I'll see you later.
[inaudible] [inaudible] this mine,
we're watching the whites of your eyes to
the
wall.
You been reading some odor
is how much you change all the money
and buy back those days. Yep. Oh
[inaudible]
all right. Girlfriend in fantasy
league. Hey, bill loved the podcast.
Thank you. I've been in a fantasy
football league for 10 years.
It was started by one of my best friends
and it's been the same 12 guys for a
decade. I don't even
know how bands put, uh,
I don't even know bands that
have been together that long.
So this year my buddy who started the
league decided to boot out to lifelong
members in favor of his
girlfriend and the girlfriend
of a friend of ours.
Wait a minute. Wait a minute, wait a
minute, wait a minute, wait a minute.
Did those other two guys who got booted,
did they anything,
I mean if he was going to add the ladies,
why did those other
two guys have to leave?
Wow. All right. Okay, well I'm
sucked into this story. He said,
I immediately called bullshit and said
point blank to his face is she wasn't
sucking your Dick then she
wouldn't be in the league. Ah Dude.
That right there is a game change. You
can't say what if he marries this woman?
Always.
There's a rule for you guys.
Always be careful what you say
about the woman you're guy is with.
Cause you never fucking know.
You never know.
And I'm sure there's some listeners
that have stories and if you'd like to
contribute them to the podcast where,
uh,
you know it's even fucking worse is when
your body,
he says fucked up shit about the girl.
You know about what a whore she is in bed
and she's fucking brains out but blah,
blah blah, blah, Blah and tells
you all these these details.
And then the jackass ends up falling for
her and then he has to fucking break up
with you because he's not going to break
up with her because every time he looks
at you, he thinks out. You
know, he knows how this girl,
my future wife Sucks my Dick,
you know? Anyways, plowing ahead.
He's trying to defend this decision by
saying she at least knows a little about
sports,
so this is awful.
This guy wasn't raised right, man, this is
just, this is fucking terrible. He said,
the fact of the matter is that she is
from New York and knows who the jets are.
That's the extent of her football
knowledge. He thinks I'm overreacting.
You're not overreacting.
He didn't ask anybody else.
You've had 12 for the last 10 years and
he just removed two of the original band
members
do.
This isn't even funny. This is right.
This is really upsetting to me.
He thinks I'm overreacting, but I think
of it the same scenario. If you had,
if you have one night a year to have a
guy's night with your buddies and then
you get to the bar,
you see that your friends has invited
his girlfriend to guys night. Exactly.
Even told me that she,
she's the one who asked if she could join,
which obviously to me means he
had no intentions of inviting her,
but when he was backed into the corner,
his ball shot up into his throat
and he couldn't say no exactly.
It's not just the fantasy league,
but a clear indication that she's
going to slowly start chipping away at
everything else in the rest of
his life. Exactly. In summation,
his girlfriend wanted in and
he crumbled and said, yes.
Am I reading too much into this?
Am I overreacting?
I'd like to know because he's getting
pissed at me for being pissed at him.
Absolutely not, sir. Everything
that I was going to tell you,
you already know and you wrote in this
email. Okay? You ran down the mats.
You went off the little
fucking springy board.
Do you hit the fucking hobby horse?
You did your little fucking Mary Lou
Leighton. Flip and you stuck the landing,
you get a perfect 10 on that
one, sir. You are 100% right.
You know what you want. My move would
be, I would start my own fantasy league.
All right. And I would invite everybody
else in that fucking leak. Well,
I wouldn't do that because not that,
that's a chick move. Make people decide,
oh, this is what I, I wouldn't be as
harsh with them and just be like, no,
do what you did was absolute
bullshit and I guarantee you,
I would tell him that she's going to start
chipping away with you and your life.
Your balls are up in your throat.
Um,
but that's going to end your friendship
with them. But here's the deal, dude.
There are other fantasy
football leagues did join.
All right? And uh, that, that's
one of those ugly things about
that chapter of guys
lives after, um, college.
You know,
when you went to grade school together
or you met him and call up guys in
college or whatever,
but you guys have this unbelievable bond.
Like you went to fucking war together.
MMM.
If one of your friends is a pussy,
you know,
he has a,
he has a chance of meeting somebody who's
going to splinter the group. You know,
and this isn't an anti woman thing,
this is more like an anti pussy guy
kind of thing where uh, you know,
there are controlling, suffocating
people on both sides. Men and women.
And I know that this
women listening and Dave,
one of their best girlfriend started
dating some fucking over bearing
insecure Douche bag guy in.
The first thing they do is they cut them
off from their friends and then it's
the coworkers,
then the friends and then their family,
they stick them under a fucking
little glass or something.
So, uh, yeah, you know what
dude? You're the worst.
The sad thing is is you're going
to lose a couple of friends.
Sometimes that happens and a, you
just have to be content about it. And
you know,
when I think it's really important for
men and women to have men only and women
only social events that they can go to
once a week or a couple of times a month
and just hang out with the fellows a hang
out with the ladies and just whatever.
I think it's really, really healthy. It's
gives you something to look forward to.
It gives you a place where you
could just vent about your,
anything you fucking want in,
in a group of people.
That 100% is going to understand and
you don't have to worry about hurting
anybody's feelings or offending on
anybody. I think it's true. It's really,
really fucking healthy.
And this guy's fucking with that.
And uh, and he didn't put it to a vote.
What does he, the Grand Poobah this shit,
I dunno know. There's so many ways
you can go with that. Just spending,
depending on how much
you want to stir up the,
you guys should put it to the vault. This
would be great. Put it to a vote, dude.
Have this be like you're Arab spring,
but with a fantasy football league.
And just vote that content and then you
become the dictator and you move into
the palace. How about that?
Whatever, dude, you're 100% right.
I would just, I would choose my
words a little more carefully. Um,
don't say that you didn't have
the balls. Just say, listen,
this was something that we
did together for 12 years and
uh,
I'm really disappointed and shocked that
you made this big a move and remove two
other members and didn't
include anybody else in it.
I don't think that it was done right.
And I think we should put this to a vote.
That's what we should do.
And if he gets mad and he starts yelling,
don't lose your cool.
Just keep stating your opinion calmly.
And you know, if he's going to be a
bitch about it, let be a bitch about it.
And I would actually,
for your own health,
did she all they think she knows is the
jam. She's gonna be like, wait a minute.
Who's that? I have God, I
don't know. Dunno anything.
Had she still tried to do that?
You know that thing where women try to
act like they're dumb because they think
it's cute. Oh, you know
what I would do, sir?
I would just put you lost this
just fucking with, I don't know.
The more I think about it,
the more know what I'm getting at is
ruined my fucking day and I'm not even in
it.
I don't even like fantasy for that.
Well
[inaudible] [inaudible]
hey,
what's going on?
It's bill bird and this is the
Monday morning podcasts on Monday,
August 24th, 2009. How
the hell are you, uh,
another week going by? I got a big
week coming up here. Really excited.
I'm actually going to,
uh,
Sweden this week and um,
I really wanted to read
a lot about Sweden.
I want them to know a couple
of the phrases, you know,
the ones that you need to know.
Uh,
something about where can
I get something to eat,
how to say thank you and how
to say, dude, do me a favor.
Why don't you get the fuck away from me?
You know,
cause you kind of freaking me out.
I mean you need to know,
you need to know how to say that
in every language and your real,
that's the one that you really
need to memorize. Okay, so you can,
it was some feeling, you know what
I mean? You can't be like, ah Dude,
get the fuck me away.
You know you,
you gotta you gotta you just gotta
come out to get the fuck away from me.
I'm serious. I'm not kidding.
Get the fuck away from me.
You gotta you have to know how
to say that and I have no idea.
I'm not gonna lie to you.
All I know about Sweden is that
fucking puppet on the muppet show.
Remember that one?
Borghi Borg. The Borg.
Who RBD each mortgage.
Ebooks,
work, work, work.
Here we have it here. Dish, community
number that,
that's all I know you know is,
is Sweden the one where they cross
country ski to school? I know Hitler.
He still look at it across from
the waters. Start jerking off,
wishing he was blond and blue eyed.
You know,
if fucking poor bastard.
Not only did he not, well,
not only was he not blonde and blue eyed,
he couldn't even get a chance. He just,
he couldn't, his girlfriend
wasn't even blonde and blue eyed.
You know what I mean?
I'm going to put this out here at LACC.
I know there's been a ton of
shit out there on Hitler. Um,
I'm going to put this out here.
This is a theory that I have.
I think Hitler had no game with women.
You know,
women don't like angry guys. Psychos
do psychos, like hangry guys. You know,
I was actually talking to this broad
last night and she was saying how, uh,
I don't know what the fuck
her boyfriend does, but uh,
she was saying up until this point,
like the guy she's dating now,
this is the first time she's a not dated
someone who's a musician and she was
just, I and I just thought,
it's like musicians,
they know the passion they have onstage
and that crazy and a guy and I was
really sitting there listening to her.
She described dating musician.
I realized that for a female that's the,
that's the female equivalent of a dating
a stripper is if you date a musician,
it's the same fucking thing.
You know, they're on stage,
they're sweaty, they're on
drugs, they're bad with money.
And in the end you have
to take care of him.
You got ended up being a fucking parent.
Wow. That's really fucking came together,
didn't it? Jesus Christ. It's not
bad. It's not bad. Right? Cleo,
look at her. Jesus Christ. Um, anyways,
uh, let's plow ahead here. We got,
we got a lot of shit. So anyways,
I had this, this, this great week.
I did this benefit. How
funny is this? Cause uh,
if you guys listen to my podcast last
week I had that incident with that woman
from the humane society,
right?
So this week talk about irony.
I actually had a gig where
I was doing a benefit for a,
for rescue dogs and it was kind of the
usual thing where I'm sitting in my head
going, fuck, I hate doing benefits.
I can't stand to a benefits. My Act,
I don't ever, I don't have any jokes
that do well at benefits. I just don't,
there's always like,
they always put me on and there's a
bunch of Nice comics in front of me,
or even if they're not nice,
they're being nice.
And then I go up there and I try to be
nice and you guys all know I'm a cunt,
so, you know, you can't,
I can't get that cunty tone out of my
voice and I just always end up feeling
crass and ignorant. I just,
I hate doing them right.
But fortunately, this was
actually a great gig. And the, uh,
the dude hosts in the show, you know,
he was bringing up all these, uh,
these celebrity people. And, uh, I
dunno if I should tell this story,
but I'm gonna just cause I don't think
that many people listen to this podcast.
One of the people who went up there was a,
was Priscilla Presley, you
know, uh, Elvis's girlfriend,
wife or whatever and all
that type of stuff. So she's
up there talking about how,
uh, some ridiculous amount of
puppies every year get killed,
you know,
at shelters and get put down like over
a million puppies every year above.
There's really serious moment
and you know, she was dressed,
she looked beautiful and everything.
And uh,
I'm standing back there with
another couple of people and
ah, Jeez, I really shouldn't tell this
story because it involves at the pee pee.
Okay, fuck it. This is what comics do
in that situation as everyone else,
all you normal people who can get married
and fucking have emotions and shit.
You know when you're getting all welled
up is this icon is talking about dead
puppies. And we were
in the back going, ah,
a dude,
she sucked Elvis's dead.
Okay.
That started it.
And then what happens with comedians
and then everybody has to top it.
So I'm not going to say where it
went from there, but believe me,
20 seconds into that conversation,
I could barely stand up.
So we're crying. Laughing. Is everyone
else? I can't even say in the room.
It was outside in the parking lot.
It's a long fucking story
and uh, but whatever, and ended up
being this awesome fucking Gig. And, uh,
cause the guy who hosted the show, he
did a real solid, he went up there,
first of all,
he's the guy who's got to switch it over
from people talking about dead puppies
to a, you know, hey, you know
what's up with a, you know,
what's up with these fucking hybrids,
you know,
and you just feel like this asshole.
He had to do that. All right.
And not only does he do it,
he drops the f bomb in his first sentence,
which is just,
I can't even tell you what a classy thing
that is to do as a comedian because it
just totally, it just
breaks down. It just,
it just blows the thing wide open.
And He, and he really has to take the,
uh, just that reaction from people. I
can't, it's like a kick to the chest.
I can't explain it, but, and he totally
took it. And I remember standing,
I was standing offstage going,
you don't want a fucking great guy.
You know what I mean? It's like, that's
like a guy you at, you like that guy,
he wouldn't rat on you if the
cops will looking for you.
He wouldn't cock block you.
He wouldn't steal your joke just
to fucking total stand up dude.
You know what I mean? And I already
loved the guy, but as always,
I never name names on this fucking
thing. All right. So, uh, so anyway,
so that's what we're doing.
So I ended up going up last and um,
they just,
they were a great crowd and I made fun
of people who say I've rescued a dog and
they rolled with everything.
I did all my stuff about having a pit
bull and I just had a great time and I was
like,
isn't this great?
This really makes up for that fucking
Twat the week before being such a fucking
Twat. Right? So I get off stage and
people are coming out to, oh my God,
it's so funny.
We were dying laughing Bababababa bar
where you 17 years in your career and
you're still playing parking
lots. Who Cares? You're hilarious.
I'm having a great time.
Right?
And then all of a sudden this fucking
chick comes up, right? She's got her,
first of all, she's got a hair
in a ponytail in the front part,
look like Cameron Diaz, his
hair, when she put the ges,
Ben Stiller's Jizan her hair.
That's what she looked like.
And she comes up to me and I
was talking about, you know,
having a pit bull and how
everybody crosses the street
when I come up the street.
And she just goes like, yeah, you know,
I really thought you were finding,
but I have to admit I'm really, I'm really
scared. I'm really scared of pit bulls.
And we start having this conversation.
And I was just like, wow, you know,
I've had one now, you know, four months.
I really think it comes down to the owner,
you know, and basically the dog's
background. She goes, yeah, but you know,
you never really hear about a
poodle mauling somebody to death.
You never hear that on the news. It's
like, yeah, because they can't, okay.
That's the difference between owning a
pit bull and owning a poodle, you know,
is stick to capability of the
animals that you have. Therefore,
if you're a bad owner,
your fuck ups get magnified tenfold.
And rather than some mailman wrapping
some gauze around his ankle, you know,
they're trying to reattach his
fucking juggler. So, I mean, I'm real,
I really believe that. You know what I
mean? Like, I mean this, but granted,
I don't know shit. Okay. And I've only
on this thing for fucking four months,
so I have no idea. But that's
what my gut is telling me. Um,
but people have like this
thing. No, I think they just,
they just have this
thing and they just snap.
One day they just snap like they're
fucking crazy. And uh, I dunno.
Maybe I'm blinded by the love
I have for this fucking dog,
but I don't believe it. So we just keep
going back and forth and she goes, I go,
no, it's a pit pole has the
ability to mall somebody to death.
Okay. A poodle is thinking the
same shit. A pit bull is thinking,
I'm going to rip your fucking face off.
It just can't do it.
But when it's going at your ankle, it's
trained to mile you to death. It is.
It just can't. First of all, it's
fucking Afro gets in the way, you know?
You know like when you're fighting your
little brother and you just stick your
hand on your, on his forehead
and he's swinging and wind.
That's what happens to a portal.
You know,
if they come in with the crown of their
head, which if they played in the NFL,
they get fined for it. All right?
Nobody ever talks about that.
How fucking dirty those goddamn poodles
are always coming in leading with their
fucking heads, right? What happens?
That little poofy thing and and
and on the top gets in the way.
It's a little cushion. So you kind of feel
that first year, Ooh, is that a Koozie?
Oh no, that's a poodle
trying to maul me to death.
And then you just boot it right in.
It's little fucking pathetic excuse for
a chest and then it's over. You know?
Isn't that funny?
When you kick a little dog off you
when they're trying to bite Ya.
And then they do that shit where
they still want to be tough,
but they're sort of walking away
as they're still growing, you know?
But they don't totally
commit to walking away,
but they also don't totally
commit to attacking you again.
And then you just look at him like,
yeah, that's what I thought. You know?
That's what I thought. Couldn't
take a cooker. So anyways,
so we're going back and forth,
so I'm not agreeing with this woman.
She's not making any good points.
And then right in the middle of it,
she just goes, yeah, well
I'm actually, I'm an animal
expert. I'm an animal expert.
Like you know, I don't know
where she just says that. I go,
you're an animal expert. She goes,
yeah. And then she just goes, whatever.
And then she walks away.
This is that a benefit. Okay.
I just donated my time for fucking free.
Okay.
I had to figure out how to do
well standing in a parking lot.
Okay. I went through all
of that bullshit, you know,
me and all my friends had to
go on after people, you know,
talking about dead puppies and then this
fucking twat comes up and hits me with
that. And it was, uh, his
Sumpter for you guys. Okay.
Anytime anybody has to break out credits
to support their argument,
they, they lost the argument.
Okay. Who the fuck says that? First
of all, I'm, I'm uh, I'm actually,
I'm an expert on animals.
Really, really in,
you're afraid of dogs, you know,
as a fucking expert on animals.
Is that Goddamn Cesar Milan,
the dog whisperer.
He's not afraid of fucking dogs.
He'll walk into a whole bunch of them
that hit 42 of them that some old lady was
adopted and they turned themselves
into a fucking wild pack.
He walks into a middle of them and goes,
and everybody shuts the fuck up.
That guy is an expert and I have never
heard him once say, I am an expert.
He's never said that shit. Okay?
I got to tell you this right now.
If I was an expert on animals and I
was debating with a moron like me,
I would never have to
bring out that credit.
What I would be doing was just
throwing out all my expert knowledge.
First of all, what I do, I was,
I would feign stupidity and let me
Wade right into the fucking, you know,
you know let's shit where you think the
water is only two feet deep and all of a
sudden it just drops off a hundred feet.
That's what the fuck I would do.
I let you come walking in with all your,
Ooh,
I watch discovery channel for 15 minutes.
Bullshit,
and then I'd hit you over the head with
such fucking knowledge about pit bulls
and dogs that, that, that you would
come up with the conclusion of, Goddamn,
this person's a fucking expert.
But if you're standing with your fucking
just in hair and you don't make one
point and then you just go,
I'm an expert and animal expert,
and then you go whatever, like a
fucking seventh grade and you walk away.
You know what?
I'm a little biased here,
but I'm going to claim
victory on that one. Whatever.
Looking at how I did it. Who gives a fuck?
You know, what the fuck is it about me?
I don't understand. I really
don't understand you fucking Twat.
I did the exact fucking thing that
you guys are trying to do here.
Try to get people to fucking rescue dogs.
Okay.
And I did it and I got the biggest psycho
of them all. I went for the pit bull.
Okay?
Anybody can go down and rescue a fucking
Chihuahua and go take them down to Taco
Bell and laugh with your friends as your
dress him up in a little fucking midget
fur coat. You know? And you get
the same fucking credit I do.
Fucking animal expert. Go
Fuck Yourself. How about debt?
Go Fuck yourself and go rinse out
your hair. All right, so anyways,
let's plow ahead here. Um, Oh, before
we get going here, there's something,
I guess I remember last week when I
basically grovelled for you people to come
to Ontario, the Improv
in Ontario. I jinxed it.
Okay? I literally did that. That, you
know, begging you guys to come out.
Like I was doing a fucking
telethon and then what happens?
Like two days later my guy calls me, oh,
we got to move the day. Distinct came in,
you got to do this day. But bubba,
so now the Ontario Improv Gig is off.
It's not totally off. It
is being rescheduled. Um,
I'm actually doing a college gig.
It's a long,
long fucking story,
but I apologize because I got
probably a half a dozen dozen emails,
which is a lot for me
of people telling me.
I went out and I bought tickets
so psyched to see us a site.
You're going to be in California. I'm here
to support your bill. You know, you're,
you rang the bell and I answered
the call. Okay, and what do I get?
Four I get a fucking slap in the face.
I apologize to all you guys
went out and bought tickets.
I feel like an asshole and I'm a,
I don't know what to tell you because
I'm going to be ringing the bell again
when that fucking thing comes around
because I don't know, southern California,
this is like the fucking matrix out here.
I don't even know if that's the rain
analogy. I don't know what it is.
It's kind of,
you know,
I've got to get on one of those Latino
stations out here that'll get a white guy
on there,
learned some Spanish for some shit.
I gotta do something because it ain't
happening for me out here. Um, anyways,
let's plow ahead here. Uh, all right,
here's a story that somebody sent me.
Here's the story that somebody
sent me that I found interesting.
I really thought it interesting.
Um, there's, you know,
you've got these bloggers here on the,
uh, you know, bloggers. Sure. We all do.
Hell,
I even blog for a while till I found
out that my space owned them and can do
whatever the fuck they wanted to
with them. Um, but anyways, you know,
all these bloggers, they, they
make fun of what celebrities,
where they say a bunch of stuff,
they draw cum on their face,
they do all that hilarious
shit or whatever.
So evidently one of them at something
called I think skanks of New York and I
fucking know what it was. But, uh,
they basically trashed this supermodel.
I can't call her a supermodel cause
I never heard of her. Her name is
Liz Kula Cohen Cohen,
let's cool. Let's Schoola
to live quietly.
It's like me trying to say that rapper's
name and I already forgot how to say
quickly. I don't give a fuck what
I'm telling you that right now.
You guys send me all that hip hop
shit and uh, I'm really liking that,
that most deaf Alma from 1999 was
that the one black on both sides?
I Dunno. I've actually listened
to two of the tracks on it.
And at first it was
beyond me. Yeah, it was,
it was beyond what my
year's could fucking handle.
And now I have slowly caught up and
now I'm really starting to love it.
And I only downloaded two of the songs.
Now I'm going to go back and download the
rest of the fucking album, uh, legally,
by the way. So anyways, uh,
this list Cooler Cohen, who, uh,
does not look like a supermodel, I gotta
be honest with you. She looks like, um,
some hot mom who settled for less and is
now sitting there going, you know what?
I could've been a model,
but instead I married the Douche bag and
accounting and I have two kids and I'm
going to call the SAC.
And it's not exciting.
We have macaroni and cheese
with toast every Wednesday.
I just don't like my life. And you
know, you know where it goes from there.
Then she ends up,
you know,
she ends up blowing that guy who
hangs out in the fucking local borrow,
has the cool car, goes right back to
high school, you know what I mean?
She just looks for the biggest swinging
dick she can find within our area,
you know? And then, yeah, that's
what she looks like to me.
I wonder if she's gonna Fuck
Whoa. I, she can't fucking out me.
She knows who the fuck I am. The Monday
morning podcast. Conti. Alright. Uh,
so this is what happens is
a vogue cover girl has one,
a precedent setting court battle to unmask
an anonymous blogger who called her a
skank on the Internet. I mean,
they basically paraphrase what uh,
what the person said.
They both would have to say,
I want to have to say the first place
award for this Skanky iest in New York
City would have to go to lists.
Schoola Genteel Cohen,
the blogger anonymous wrote in one posting
the blog sense remove sense removed,
ridiculed the former Australian vogue
cover girl as a 40 something who may have
been hot 10 years ago when
she was actually a 36.
So evidently,
I guess they had been going off on her
for awhile and she got tired of it.
So she went to Google and
she sued to have the, uh,
she wanted to know who this person was.
Who was her.
So somebody sent me an email and was like,
can you believe this?
Fucking so-and-so does in
this come with being famous.
Why don't you go cry with all
your money and blah, blah,
the usual shit that they
say about celebrity.
And I have to be honest with you guys,
I can see both sides of this story.
Okay?
First and foremost,
the fact that she was able to
get Google to cave in and to uh,
give her the name of the blogger is kind
of a dangerous thing where once cases
like this happen, you know, it's
this little fucking whatever case,
a bunch of people, you
know, you open that door,
fucking run through the door and a piggy
back on that case and then all of a
sudden there'll be laws where you can
censor what people write and you can sue
people. Um, so,
cause I mean the Internet right now is
like the fucking wild west back in the
day. Do you ever think about
that shit? There was no banks,
there was no fucking credit cards.
You know, there was no mortgage.
You just chopped down some trees with
your friends and your built a square with
a roof on it. You know, shooting
Indians, there was, you know,
hang 'em, high fucking
frontier, Justice, rape,
pillage,
all that type of shit.
That's what the Internet is
basically like right now.
And they're essentially,
I think with stuff like this
will eventually whittle it down.
Um, and you know, it's
Kinda hard to, you know,
some of this stuff and obviously is
horrible pornography on it. You know,
I'm not really into that shit.
I wish I could stop fucking watching it.
I wish someone would actually helped
me to stop watching it by censoring it.
What a fucking pathetic
loser I am. But anyways, um,
but then you can go too far with this
shit cause I was saying you guys don't let
famous picture that iconic photo that,
that,
that guy who stood in front of
the tank in Tiananmen Square, uh,
back in 1990 or 89 or nine and it was
89 if you can believe it was 20 fucking
years ago that happened. Most Chinese
young people in their twenties,
if you show them that photo, they don't
even know what it is, what it refers to.
Cause they basically over there with their
fucking police state is they just oh,
race,
the whole existence,
like in a style and ask kind
of way where back in the day,
I don't know if George,
um,
George Yosef Stalin would, uh,
you know, he's a paranoid psycho.
And when he would offer you,
not only would he have you killed,
he would have some dude like a
ratio out of all photos, like your,
your existence.
You didn't even exist.
There was no like documentation
of it. And that's, you know,
that's the other end of this
little cases like this that uh,
that make them scary. But having said that
on the other side, just as a performer,
um, I actually love
that, that piece of Shit,
little fucking rat got dragged
out into the sunlight. Okay.
Because even at the
pathetic level that I'm on,
you can't believe how bad you
get fucking trash to the point.
I never read any reviews. I don't
read, I don't read anything.
I never watch any clips in mind on the
Internet. I never do any of that shit,
uh,
because people just,
they just write the most horrific
shit that they can about you.
And it would be hypocritical of me
because I'm a comedian and look at me,
I trashed people all the time, so I can't
get mad at it, but I got to admit, dude,
I don't want to read it. Um, so,
but this, she's just a fucking
model. You know what I mean? And,
um, I dunno this just like
a point where you, you know,
you're in the public eye and
someone can trash you, but you know,
they start writing shit that if
you actually had it in a newspaper,
you'd get sued for slander.
You know what I mean?
To suggest that she's 40 years old when
she's only 36 might not seem like a big
deal to me or anybody else.
But that's a huge fucking thing in the
modeling industry. And not only that,
I gotta tell you these
fucking industry people,
they don't know shit about the Internet.
They don't know how to control it,
to trying to figure it out.
And all it takes is one douchebag
with enough fucking people behind him.
And they're like, oh, this
is what everybody's thinking.
So does fucking Twat is writing this
stuff about her and she's actually
potentially fucking with
her ability to get gigs.
So I'm not saying that the person
shouldn't be able to do that,
but if you're going to do something
that at somebody, at least, you know,
have the balls to put your name out there,
you know?
And that's what I like,
because now this person's going to get
dragged out there and hopefully people
will know who the fuck she is and she'll
get to see what it feels like because
then people are going to be
going off on her. You know?
Cause actually it turned out that it
was, it was one of this, this, uh,
this model's friends, which I think
is fucking hilarious. You know,
how awful and awkward, you
know, does she feel right now?
You know what the worst thing is,
is I bet she cried.
I'm so sorry.
I just thought going through some things
and you're just so beautiful and I
don't know I, I'm sowing bears, you know,
they just fucking cry their
way out of that shit. Well,
I think that works with guys.
It doesn't work with women because they
that cause this fucking supermodel chick
, she probably does that
shit too. I'm sorry I do.
Colgate keeps me scary.
I didn't want to,
I look cut belly by the
fucking bikini shot, you know,
so that shit doesn't work on her.
You know what I mean?
That'd be like trying to
use the force against Yoda.
He knows what the fuck you do.
So I think it's great.
I hope she just fucking stares at him
when this blubbering fucking coward,
you know, cow or did I really
just use that fucking word?
Whatever. Fucking little,
you know what? This is the difference
between what I do, because look at me.
I'm going off on this girl right now,
but you know, I don't fucking know her.
All right. This, I'm going to justify
my boat. I am so full of Shit, right?
This is how I'm going to justify me.
I don't know her.
And also my name is on this podcast,
so no need to sue me.
You know who the fuck I am and then I
have shit on the Internet that she could
then go comment on, you
know. Right. All right.
I better than that fucking piece of shit.
I don't think I am.
I think get Jesus Christ. I think
I'm the same person. Um, all right.
So if that made any sense. I
think it's scary that, that,
that this case could actually start,
uh,
opening the door for some major
censorship in the future. And,
but then on the other
side, I love that, uh,
somebody who was talking
shit got caught for it.
I really liked that and I just wish I
could have had a video of that girl trying
to fight the injunction or whatever
the hell the legal term is,
realizing that Google was going to give
up her name and just her freaking the
fuck out, realizing, you know,
trying to get off that track when you
know it's headed right towards a brick
wall and she can't.
And then that fucking moment when she
realizes that our friend knows that she's
the fucking Twat who's been
writing all that shit about her.
And then she sits there going, what
do I do? What do I do? Do I call her?
What do I say? And as she's trying
to work all of that bullshit out,
her home phone rings and
who's on the caller id?
But this chick who she called a fucking
skank. You know what I bet our friend, uh,
this this fucking list Cooler Cohen was
actually talking to the girl looking for
some comfort. They're writing all
these horrible things about me.
Why do people write the thing? And that
fucking Twat kept a straight face going.
I Dunno.
And then like silently getting like
some joy out of the fact that she's
torturing her and she probably,
you know, as she comforted her,
tried to figure out what
part of it hurt her most.
I know it's just terrible
that she called you as skank.
I think that's way worse than questioning.
If you're 40 years old,
don't you? Or do you think the age thing
hurts more? They're, they're there,
you know, and basically figuring
out how to attack her even more.
I love that she got caught. I
love it. That's fucking great.
All right, let's move on. And
this is, this is basically,
and I went on a couple of
these, these bloggers sites.
Um, and I got to met. Dude, I,
I've gone on these, these, um,
some of these blogger things, uh,
actually has bullshit. I have on my,
uh, my girlfriend looks at some of them.
She's into that guy, uh, uh,
Perez Hilton and he's a due to drugs the
g has on people's face. And I got it.
That's just fucking funny.
Alright. It's childish.
It's, it's, it's not mature.
It's everything that makes
something fucking hilarious. And uh,
and you know who the guy is, you know
his name, you know he's out there.
There's pictures of him on the Internet,
so people trash and back.
I think it's a little tit for tat there,
but if you're going to write all
that bullshit and go under anonymous,
I don't know. I think
there's a, all right, well,
why don't you say the same thing 58
fucking times? We got it. All right.
So anyways, so I went on one
of these these blogger things,
and this is the type of
shit that people, right? Um,
they were going off on Ringo Starr.
There was basically,
why is Ringo Starr such a jerk? And
I just, I already love where this,
the jumping off point of this, you know,
none of these people I've ever met him.
I thought somebody would have met him
in an airport and they asked them,
they said, hey, uh, hey
Ringo, uh, can you sign, uh,
can you sign my fucking tee shirt and
can you also answer me why you've been
wearing the same earring
for the last 40 years?
That long one that's hanging down like
Kurt Russel in big trouble in little
China. Okay. That look was out in the 80s.
That fucking long dangling earring.
You like the bad guy in some
fucking a Mel Gibson movie,
or at least you have the jewelry of
the bad guy. All right. Uh, Sony was,
it says a Beatles member. Ringo Starr
posted a video to today to his fans,
telling them that he will no longer be
accepting any fan mail after October 20th
because he has too much to
do. Uh, and then it says what?
Like counting your piles of money,
sliding down a solid gold
waterslide making origami hunting.
What the fuck that is,
or a famous said that right.
Origami out of hundred dollar
bills. And then it says, Huh,
here's the video fucking Moron people,
right?
Like, because he's rich and famous, like
he's got nothing better to do. And just,
I mean,
the guy's like 70 years old.
Maybe his fucking wrist hurts
from writing back to people.
Okay.
Maybe you know,
he sick and he knows he's gonna die and
he wants to go fucking drive a Harley
Davidson across the [inaudible].
You have no fucking idea what's going on
in this guy's life. So somebody writes,
I've lost all respect for this man.
How rude and disrespectful
to all his fans.
He should be kissing the
fans ass since, uh, acids.
Since us fans are the ones who
made him who he is today. I,
there's nothing I fucking hate more than
when fans take credit for the fucking
unbelievable talent of a fucking,
of ring of,
of a star like that.
Really the fans made the Beatles
the greatest fucking band ever.
You know,
like,
like any of the fans could fucking
ignore what a juggernaut that bandwidth,
oh yeah, sergeant pepper's.
Yeah. Fuck that. That had
nothing to do with anything.
If it wasn't for those fans
screaming at their shows,
you know, that's, you don't
make them who they are.
They make who they are.
It's not like they're sitting there and
then you guys all walk up to them and go,
hey, you want to be
famous? Get up on stage,
play whatever you want and we're
going to scream and go nuts. No,
they have to fucking go into bars and
they have to get booed and they have to
have shit thrown at him.
That whole blues brothers scene with
a beer bottles get thrown at you or
whatever. You got to go through
fucking 20 years of that shit.
Actually those cuts they made
when they were like 25 whatever,
10 15 fucking years of that crap.
All right?
You have to have the balls to walk away
from the safe life of going to college
and getting a fucking job and no one,
you're going to have a paycheck.
You have to step off
into the fucking abyss.
Knowing that 99.9% a year never even
make enough to get out of that stinky,
sweaty fucking van that you're
driving around in you gotta,
you gotta you basically,
you take your life savings and you bet
on the fucking 90 to one dog, you know,
that's what the fuck you do, all
right? And then you have to come with,
you have to create something that's so
fucking great that that amount of people
will pay attention to it.
All right?
You fucking arrogant assholes.
This guy's probably, they say,
this guy's probably been answer in fan
mails and sign an og or autographs for
half a fucking century.
He wants to put the pen down.
Can he do that in his
seventies you're fucking twats
Jesus Christ.
And having said all that,
I will be signing my DVDs and
kissing babies after all of my shows.
Ah, you know what? I would love to get
to that level where I could just be like,
yeah, listen, yeah, I'm not interacting
with you motherfuckers anymore. You know,
and I'm so fucking, it's almost like
he can live off the interest. You know,
when you have so much money, you can
live off the interest of your money.
He can live off the interest of the fan
base that he has an amount of how much
it drops off because he's
not going to sell, you know,
sign eight by tens from that fucking
Bangladesh concert he did with George
Harrison. You know? That's another
reason why I wouldn't want to be him.
Sign a fucking autographs.
You know what I mean?
It's really depressing to look at
a headshot of myself 10 years ago.
Forget about one 40 fucking years
ago. You know what I mean? You know,
no one ever comes up with a head shot of
Ringo fucking 70 years old putting Ben
gay on his fucking Bass Drum foot.
You know,
they always got on when he's young and
in his prime and he probably sits today
like, what's the matter
mate? You know like me now.
How about when I'm all wrinkled up?
What a terrible fucking does that ring go?
Who the fuck was that? I don't know who
that was. All I know is that was horrible.
And if you had a fucking
shred of self esteem,
you'd fucking stop this podcast right now.
All right,
let's get onto some are videos here.
Um, this is in a funny youtube video.
This is a fucking amazing
video. Okay. And I go,
I want you guys right now to take out a
pen if you're in your cubicle slide over
your little yellow sticky things
because this is a long link.
And this is a guy who basically explains
the banking crisis and how we're moving
into like the little robot age where,
uh,
you know, some of the stuff that
they're coming up with like their,
they can like grow an ear in a petri dish.
Now they're talking about some lady who
had like an owl cancer of her esophagus
and they scraped off from
some cells from her esophagus,
put it in a dish and they grew
her a new fucking esophagus.
And then it goes all into like if you're
into the bionic man and hybrid cars and
Cyborgs, it's, they got a
fucking clip on this thing.
This is the trailer for it where this
showing this robot that basically looks
like a turtle with midget giraffe legs,
a turtle on stilts,
like deer legs and it is running sort of
trotting along and the scientists walks
up and just fucking gives it a front
kick as hard as you possibly could to the
side, which would have
tipped over any other robot.
And this thing just sort of does,
just goes with it like a living,
breathing thing. Like whoa.
Kind of like goes to the side.
Like you know like when a running back
is doing a sweep and that guy dies and he
hits him in his hip and it just
knocked some five feet sideways.
But he's able to regain his balance
and continue moving forward.
That's what the fuck
this robot thing does.
So this dude starts with the banks and
he ends with these robots and he starts
talking about how all the different
versions of man have overlapped each other
like uh, uh, like neanderthals,
Homo sapiens and that type
of whatever they, they,
they at one point we both exist existed
on the earth at the same time before
homo sapiens took over.
I know I'm using the wrong fucking cro
magnums Nariana falls or whatever they
overlapped and that type of shit.
So what this guy is trying to suggest is
that the half robot and person is going
to overlap the 100% human thing.
It is. It's the fucking shit.
And it's not boring either guys. Actually
he keeps it funny. So here is the link.
Okay. Would that really long
trailer, I wanted to do that.
So you guys have time to jot this
down cause you really should watch it.
It's fucking fascinating.
It's www dot ted.
Like the name Ted,
t e d.com/talks/one_and as e n r I Q,
u e z underscore shares,
s h a r e s underscores
underscore mind boggling,
underscore, knew half of you don't
even give a fuck at this point. I know,
but some of you do underscore
science. Dot. H T m L.
Alright. And if you got lost in all that,
just go to ted.com and just, you know,
go around the web sets.
What I gave you was a direct link,
but you can go around the website and
I'm sure you can find a cause. It's a,
you know,
as dumb as I sounded the other day.
Jesus Christ. Nia. Um, sorry.
What, what you're looking good.
You're looking really good.
All right, well I didn't know you
were in the room. Okay. Anyways, uh,
so anyways, um, what do you mean is
wrong with me? What's wrong with you?
I'm doing a podcast here.
Didn't you see the red light on outside
the fucking bedroom door that said on
air? I love what you just
laugh at me when I do these.
See, she is the advantage
of seeing how crazy I look.
I'm basically sitting here in my boxers,
my t shirt and my little headphones,
like I'm doing some sort of pirate
radio and she literally walks in as,
I'm like a ted underscore slash backspace.
What's going on with the
world underscore.com. Hotmail.
You're really dating a fucking loser.
How does that feel?
You were going to this way.
They wouldn't let him do this number.
Maybe upset. They think like that. Yeah.
Right. This is, this thing is for me
to trash people not to get trashed.
Why don't you fucking get Outta here?
Get outta here. All right. Thank you.
I want to sweetheart now beat
it. All right. All right,
let's, let's fucking get this. Uh,
let's get this back together here.
All right. She's stumbling out of the
room laughing at me. See, you hear that.
You're laughing.
All right.
Here's a, here's a really good email
that I got. Um, somebody said, Bill,
if you're looking for a
sport, a new sport, um,
I'm gradually getting back
into baseball by the way. Uh,
I've got to support my red sox because,
uh,
they're either going through the dog
days right now. All right. And, uh,
you know, be one thing at the red sox
were doing good. And I was just like,
all right, I, I need to take a
break from baseball, you know,
then I could actually do it. But the fact
that they're not doing well right now,
now, now, you know, this is when the real
fans show who the fuck they are. So I'm,
I'm coming back,
I'm gradually coming back,
but this guy was giving me a suggestion
on a sports that I should watch. It said,
Bill, if you're looking for a sport,
you really need to delve into MMA,
UFC and make an effort
to become a serious fan.
I really got into it for awhile and,
uh, um, I still really like it. I just,
I get busy and on the road
and I, I try to, um, I mean,
my favorite reality show is the
ultimate fighter. You know what I mean?
Every other fucking show
you make a bad sloppy Joe.
When you get kicked off the show and
this one you get your fucking ask.
He literally get beaten off the show.
So I really enjoy that. But anyways, um,
said I know you're a casual fan,
but the sport really is exciting,
highly technical in its,
satisfies a primal urge with men
to compete and beat on one another.
But in s and a somewhat state, uh,
safe and sanctioned environment,
I know that 50 to 75% of the
fans are meatheads and strippers
a while.
That's annoying.
You just have to block that out
and focus on the sport itself. It,
it,
uh,
it really is the future because it's so
natural and basic and doesn't require
any super fluid. I don't want to say it
supply. How do you say that? Nea Supply.
So peripherals,
there's no fucking I in that
he wrote super and then f you.
F L U O. U. S Super, Huh. Oh good.
You had dumped to,
let's have a dumb kid
and then we'll be those parents
who show up when they go. Yeah.
Basically your kids are more
annuity. Is it cute? Smart.
Um, all right. Anyways, it says a,
it really is the future because it's
so natural and basically and basic.
It doesn't require any.
All my God,
I thought I went past the sentence where
this word is and I'm back to it again.
And he superfluous rules and equipment.
It's just mad verse man with nothing
but physical fighting skills.
Strategic Acumen. Is this guy trying
to fuck me up and courage. Beautiful.
All right guys, you find a new
thing that you can do to me.
Send emails with big words that
I can't pronounce. Pronounce.
I'm just as just fucking unraveling.
All right,
let's get to the fucking youtube videos.
Um,
this is a great quick youtube video
that will give you a laugh, uh,
is called a girl gets answer very wrong.
Please watch this girl gets answer very
wrong. That's what you search on Youtube.
Um, this next one, somebody
sent me this and I,
I can't believe I forgot about this one
cause I stumbled upon this one before.
These ones are fucking hilarious.
Um,
there's one called Eddie van Halen
shreds and there's another one Santana
shreds. And basically what it is is,
you know, there's a bunch of, you know,
musicians go on,
you know,
up and coming guitarists and they watch
all these great guitar gods and they
watch their clips and then they
rate them. You know, that socks,
I give that five out of
10 stars or whatever.
But there's certain guys like Eddie
van Halen, he's just the shit.
You just can't fuck with them. So
what this guy does, he actually plays,
he plays guitar,
he gets rid of the audio,
he keeps the clip of Eddie
van Halen in concert.
And then he plays the worst
fucking guitar ever underneath it.
But he does it perfectly where if
Eddie's fingers are moving up the neck,
the guy moves up the neck
playing horrifically.
So it really sounds like Eddie
is playing the guitar horribly,
but he puts it under Eddie van Halen
shred. So all these guys, you know,
they want to see at a shred and then they
just get this horrific video that not
only is not Eddie shredding,
but it makes him look like an asshole.
And then people get all mad. Dude,
you should do is kill yourself,
would fucking loser. He's a god. Why
you do that? You know, it's usual shit.
You know, he's somebody. That's
funny. Um, here's another one.
Another one funny used car
ad ad is spelled a d not a d.
D. Um, now there's another good
one. Harrison Ford, my wife,
my family compilation.
MMM.
Then here's another one. This is an
Arnold Schwarzenegger one. That's great.
It's called [inaudible].
Arnold is funny. Um,
and here's the last one.
I saved the best one for last.
This guy has some sort of speech
impediment. He gets blocked.
I can't, I don't know. I've never even
heard of it. It's called Tono Tonow, t.
O N. O. T. O. N. O. And A.
I'm actually gonna call in
the EOP and Anthony Show,
or if you're an opiate Anthony Fan, can
you please tell them to watch this video?
Because this is just right
up there fucking alley. Um,
this is one of those
videos that I wish I could,
I could see Jim Norton Watch
for the first fucking time.
Just just to hear what the
fuck he would say. All right.
Tonio Tonio t o n o t o n o
and um,
yeah and if you are overseas, cause I
got a cup of people, England or whatever.
Sweden shit who listen to this thing.
Check out the opening
Anthony show on a online,
I think it's [inaudible] dot
com I don't eat well. You know,
wouldn't it be great if I had the
fucking thing? Just, just look for them.
They're fucking hilarious. And they got
clips. They have clips up on Youtube.
Opie and Anthony Show. They are hilarious.
Look for, look for the baby bird.
That's a nice simple one to get you in
on, into the show. All right, questions.
These are the questions that I'm
going to wrap this up. Question. Bill,
where was your first Gig?
My first stand up.
These are all gonna be stand up questions
where it was my first standup Gig.
I played Nick's comedy. Stop in Boston,
Massachusetts on Warrington Street.
I was in a competition called a fine
Boston's funniest college student
and a every night, each college had
a different night and I went on,
I went up on my night and I did okay.
I didn't do great,
but I did okay. And uh, and that's
it. That's basically the story.
Um, cause I know I've told
it a million fucking times,
but I was at Nick's comedy stop.
MMM.
Hang on, I just got a note. All right. Ah,
Jesus Christ. All right, let's move
on here. This is, I'm sorry guys.
I'm really killing the momentum here.
Bill,
did you have to play coffee shops
and bars before you could get up,
get to the comedy clubs?
Uh, yes, yes I did.
It's always been a grind
to become a comedian.
I know you comedians nowadays you have
it way worse where we didn't have bringer
shows. Some of these dudes, what they
have to do here in La, in New York,
God bless him man,
cause it was not that fucking difficult.
It just keeps getting harder. But uh,
the cream will rise to the top. Um,
did I have to play coffee shops?
Yes. Coffee, coffee shops, bars.
Um, I know I've told that story where I
played the second story Clia laid out,
Cleo,
lay down, lay down. Um,
I know I played that.
Uh,
I told that story where I
actually did a Gig at a,
a two story bar where I was performing
on the second floor of this bar that had
screens for windows and right across the
street was a carnival and you know that
ride with that Viking ship
just rocks back and forth.
It literally looked like a
cock going into, you know,
like didn't they do that horrific porno
shot where they do the underneath shot
of doggy style?
That's what it looked like.
And it was coming right to the window and
I was bombing so hard that all I could
hear was the people screaming on
that ride. All right, there you go.
There's one for you. And you know what
was great was the guy who hosted the show,
he actually had a lazy eye and you know,
he was really self conscious about it
and he went on stage first and he was
bombing and these two people are sitting
in the front row and they just didn't
give a fuck. This guy just goes, dude.
And he pointed right at his face. He goes,
the fuck is wrong with your eye.
And it literally just,
it was really painful to watch. I mean,
that guy's lazy. I was part of the,
probably part of the low self esteem
that made him become a comedian.
Okay. And then he's like, I'm
going to become a comedian.
I'm going to get on stage.
People are going to like me
and everything's going in
this guy just fucking Bam.
And a, and the dude had nothing.
He was just like, I can't,
I can't believe you just said that.
I think it was bad.
And then I went on after that
and I somehow had even a,
I had worst moments than that. Jesus
heals a lot of bad stories this week.
All right. Uh, Bill, when
did you first opened?
When did I first move up
to the opening spot? Um,
while I was getting through college.
So my first year was kind of a wash 92.
I started in March of [inaudible] 92
and Ireland probably only got on stage a
half dozen times,
maybe eight times 12 at the most.
And it probably was by mid,
mid 93.
WBCN used to have this to sing
called the comedy riot and I want it,
you know, it was for the up and
coming guy. And after I won that, um,
I remember that was the first time I got
a real spot on a Tuesday night show on
Jim will let us show. I got a spot. Um,
and I remember I was all fucking nervous.
Like, cause it wasn't an open mic show.
I was like, Oh fuck, you know, when
I'm gonna open up on an open mic show,
they know him and open miker but now
they're expecting a professional.
I was fucking unbelievably
nervous. And, uh, that was a huge,
huge fucking night for me
when I, you know, just doing
a spot on a Tuesday. It's,
it's like that incremental shit. That's
why I flipped out when I was saying,
you know, when they say, oh the fans
made Ringo Starr's you have no idea.
Like incrementally the baby steps that
you take to get to a higher fucking level
and how huge little things that like the
first time I got $5 gas money you have
to doing it for a year and a
half. I actually got, you know,
a piece of paper that used to represent
gold that really has no fucking value,
but I didn't know that then.
So I was like,
I can actually go out with this $5
and get the number three at subway.
This is fucking awesome. And, you know,
I love doing stand up so
much that I, I, you know,
I would drive to Maine from Boston for
free just to get stage time and we'd be
driving all the way back,
almost falling asleep at the wheel to go
to work at eight o'clock in the fucking
morning to go unload trucks.
And a was just loving life and a, it's one
of the greatest things about, you know,
doing this job as I fucking love
it. So anyways, um, next one, uh,
is the worth of your career starting.
Can you guys hear that fucking
weed wacker? I apologize. Um,
is the worth of your career starting
to weigh out the 20 years struggle of
making it to the top? Uh,
well dude, I haven't made it
to the top, but yeah, dude,
um, it was worth it. Uh,
the day I got five bucks,
the day I started doing it, it was with
the first fucking day when I drove home.
Excited that I actually got to,
had the balls to get onstage and I drove
home and I was listening to doctor,
not doctor fee.
I was listening to kickstart my heart,
what a child of the 80s,
screaming the song fucking ridiculously
pumped up in my little piece of shit
truck driving home.
I couldn't believe it.
I've failed at everything else and
I always thought I was, you know,
I always said I was going to do this
and I was going to do that and I never
followed through and I finally followed
through with something and actually went
great.
And uh,
from the second I went up on
stage and did it, you know,
it was worth it and it actually helped me,
you know,
in other areas like, um, like
last night, you know I was,
I went down to go do stand up and these
guys were playing afterwards you're like,
Oh I heard you play drums,
you want to sit in.
And I got all fucking
nervous cause you know,
I don't do that for a living.
And then I just, I do,
what I always do is I just think,
okay, what's going to feel worse?
I'm going up there and bombing and
sucking and making an ass out of yourself,
or going home, laying in bed,
not being able to go to sleep,
knowing that you are a pussy in that
moment when you could have gone up there.
So I said, fuck it. And I went up there
and it fucking went great. You know?
And plus when you get up
there, there's like, you know,
there's always other people
who are really good. In fact,
everybody else was really good,
so you can kind of hide behind that fact,
which is another thing that makes
stand up so scary is because everyone's
looking at you the entire time.
You can't blame it on
the stool. Um, all right,
here's the last question and then I'm
going to start packing to go to Sweden and
I'll tell you guys all about it.