Hey, what's going on is bill burn. Um,
before I start the Thursday afternoon,
just before Friday,
Monday morning podcast,
I'm going to do a little read here.
I know you're probably thinking,
dude, what the fuck is this?
This isn't how we normally stats it.
Well,
I didn't take a break during
the next interview, so I got,
I got to read this thing down now if I
can fucking find it, where the hell is it?
Yes, this is the most
unprofessional beginning of any
podcasts. Oh, here we go. Oh,
this is for all you fucking people
out there. Better help, help.
Is this something interfering with your
happiness or is preventing you from
achieving your goals besides
listening to this podcast?
Better help will assess your needs
and match you with your own licensed
professional therapists.
You can stat communicating
and under 20 hours.
It's not a crisis line.
It's, it's not self help.
It's a professional
counseling done online school,
St Louis Blues.
Uh,
there is a broad range of expertise and
better helps council councilor network,
which may not be locally available in
many areas to services available for
clients worldwide.
You could log into your account anytime
and send a message to your counselor.
Uh, you'll get timely
and thoughtful responses.
Plus you can schedule weekly
video or phone sessions,
so you won't ever have to sit in an
uncomfortable waiting room. Better help.
His commute is committed to,
why don't I buy glasses?
The facilitating great therapeutic matches
so they can make it easy and free to
Chariton change counselors if needed.
It's more affordable than traditional
offline counseling and financial aid is
available.
Visit better help.com/burr and join over
500,000 people who have taken Chad's of
their mental health with the help
of an ex variance professional.
For Bill Burton listeners,
get 20% off your first
month@betterhelp.com slash
bar. Um, and with that,
onto the interview on the Thursday
afternoon, just before Friday,
Monday morning podcast,
just chicken
Jack. I see it. I
can see on it's on. There
we go. Hey, what's going on?
It's Bill Burns time
for Thursday afternoon,
special edition of the Thursday afternoon,
just before Friday,
Monday morning podcast and a, I
have a guest, a very special guest.
One of, uh, one of my, uh, I dunno,
just the biggest fan of this guy and
all the bands that he's played in just
going to get right to it.
It's got a brand new album out.
Mr Duff Mckagan how are you sir? Bill,
how are you? I'm doing great. You know,
I uh, got the email saying that you
wanted to be on here. I said, you know,
the tough had made a new
album, a solo album, you know,
when he wants to come on and promote it.
And I got to tell you,
you just came off that giant tour.
You're like,
I'm all tangled up in
the fucking wires here.
I told you this was going to
be a bare bones operation here.
How did you get the time? You
know, cause I, I'm such a uh,
a pussy where I go on the road for like
a week and I'm like whining to my wife
Linda. Good. I miss my kid and everything.
And I know you guys had
breaks and everything,
but he did two and a
half years on the road.
How do you come out of that and
be like, you know what, I'm,
I'm ready to a sit down and write
an album. You're not like fried.
Well, um, I think, well that's
two questions and I do that a lot.
Yes. And so, so the, the being
able to tour, like, I mean,
I saw some tours when I was a kid.
I saw the clash before London
calling and I saw this like,
I mean they were as exotic
as led Zeppelin were,
but they were one of us.
Right.
And they made that known.
Like there's no difference
between the crowd and the band.
We're all in this together.
That was an early influence.
And then seeing Henry
Rollins like get prepared.
My first Gig ever was
opening for black flag books.
Ron raise of a singer to
singers before at Rollins. Okay.
So when Rawlins probably came into
black flag, there was a lot of talk.
You got to step up. That's a big
position to be the singer black flag.
And my band, again, there
was a different band,
but we opened for black flag when Henry
came in for like five shows. Right.
And seeing this guy, he was super
intense. He's still pretty intense guy,
but this is,
I mean I'm like 17 years old and he's
just has gym shorts on and you know,
and he,
he's pacing this is that sound check?
Yeah, I've seen him do standup
comedy and he just, he just like,
they introduced so many, just like 45
degree angle right out to the Mike.
Stan takes the mic out and wraps the
cord around. His arm was like, all right,
this guy's keys going in.
That's what,
so seeing that like preparation he
did for a show that kind of like,
that was at the state of my head.
And I though it was a couple of things
that made me decide to be a lifer.
Right. You don't have a choice
in this anymore. Like what,
how did you start playing music? I don't
know. I didn't have a choice. Right.
It's just, and then, you know,
so touring all these years now turning,
I'm 55,
you know, like you have to really like,
do you have to train like an athlete,
you have to like do all those things.
You have to pace your days and,
and uh, our shows are not
short in our shows. Yeah. Um,
so three and a half hours of, and you've
seen the size of our stage is this,
you know, so you're probably running five
miles a night with a base on, you know,
um, but to, to get to the, to
the writing of the songs thing.
I was in a position,
you know,
one that I didn't realize how much was
missing in my life until we kind of the
three of
excellent slash myself talked some
stuff out and we decided like,
let's, we were offered to Coachella,
let's, okay. I mean, we could do this,
you know, nobody else knows
about it except us three.
And we talked about all these kinds of
things that were hanging there in the air
for years. And, and we,
the way we approached it with our
kind of chess out and heads up and,
and with honesty and,
and a rigor, you know,
and it was so cleansing and going
out and touring and then like,
well we can go keep,
we can keep going,
we can do all of North America and
we can keep going. And I had this,
you know, right. I think at that time.
But when we're rehearsing for that,
that we rehearsed for three months for
that tour and we were like six hours a
day,
you know.
Um, how were you guys the first time you,
you, the first time you counted it off,
you hadn't played together in that long,
did it come right back?
Was the like riding a bike?
I didn't just go into rehearsal.
I'm going to spend a month in my,
my basement, you know, that's so cool.
So you actually went back and listened
to all your own stuff first time probably
ever like, okay. You know? Yeah. I
did the pre work and I know slack,
we all did the pre award. The young, you
stumped the older you will a few times.
Like what the hell was this?
No, I mean it's all in my bones.
It's all muscle memory of course.
Played a bunch of
these songs in other bands and whatever.
So it wasn't too far out.
But there was some stuff like a strange,
I hadn't, hadn't played coma, you know,
like, oh wow. Yeah. What will you know,
what kind of drugs were
we doing to the right?
Oh my. Yeah, I know. But also
that weird thing where you've,
I've played this song around the world
and I don't remember how it goes.
That's gotta be crazy. [inaudible]
and it is in your, you know,
you play and once you play you play.
Yeah.
But once you play on drums,
a song a few times, it's,
it's going to be there where,
you know, your, your body
remembers it. So, um,
but I had this,
I went during the rehearsals,
I got sucked into that things. I
think we all did. I was watching,
like it started very simply,
a friend of Susan Nights,
the guy who actually set us up on a blind
date, he used to write for Thrasher,
he got into politics,
became campaign managers for people.
Um,
and with John K six campaign
manager for that presidential bit.
And he, he like texted me, he goes,
Hey, watch my guy John Casick.
There was that first debate
of like 12 republican
nominees or wherever the guys who were
running and people were that were running.
And I watched John Kay sick.
Am I going to say real centrus
he's done a lot pro Ohio.
And cause I had a backstory.
So I'm watching him and I see this kind
of screaming and shouting and stuff
going down and because this is a mass,
but it got me into the news and I
started watching all news and it's fun.
You know, I started following
people on my Twitter, my Twitter.
I originally got to follow the Seattle
Seahawks. The mariners are awful.
They are. And like a few of
like people that I, you know,
respect comedians or rock guys.
Um,
but I started following all these
other things that just don't do it. Um,
and I went down a rabbit hole and I'm
smart enough. I read enough history. I,
it's all like done since I was sober
and sober for 25 years. It's just,
I read history.
I'm a total book nerd and some Watson,
this news are,
they,
they're Britain start bringing on panels
that are all yelling over each other.
I'm like,
this is an interesting way to keep
people that they know what they're doing.
They're polling like they're watchers,
you know,
this must be working because they're
in the business of selling ads.
I'm smart enough,
but I'm still down the rabbit hole and
I'm looking at my Twitter and wake up in
the morning and looking at,
go to the news first thing in the morning
and I get wrapped up in this whole
thing to divide. There's sort of
divide out there. Wow. I mean,
I've been traveling this
country for a long time, man.
I didn't know it was there where,
where if I bet isn't in a way.
Okay.
So,
so it isn't, it's, it's you watching it
on TV and it gets, that's why I stopped.
Nothing that was ever
the most informed guy,
but I stopped watching it when it just,
the way they were spinning it
and then it was just, he came up.
The same reason why I don't watch those
real housewives shows is I don't want to
watch or listen to a bunch of people
screaming and yelling at each other.
I grew up with that and you start,
it's if it affects like my mood and then
I also think it's all bullshit anyway,
so I, I don't watch it.
So you went to, I'm sorry,
you went down that
rabbit hole you started.
Yeah, I remember I went down the
rabbit hole. I mean, I, and I knew,
I knew I was going down a rabbit
hole and I, and uh, so the, uh,
one point in rehearsal,
like we would talk about rehearsal
one point I just right before,
right when we started playing Coachella
and then we went to Mexico City and then
we went, came back to the STA. I
turned off the news before all that.
I just stopped,
just stopped.
I stopped having Yahoo is my home screen
cause I used to be because you get to
sports pretty quick. That's
the only reason. Yeah. Y'All
who was just filling up,
you know, the important stuff,
the important stuff. Um,
I muted everything on my Twitter except
for the Seahawks and the mariners.
And I've done this for the last,
since again, since I've been sober,
I read about all this history and
I go to the places I read about.
So I'll plan and this is a stadium tour.
So we have kind of a day and a half off
and every city or you have travel days
in Boston. So I would plan my
travel and my bus like, okay,
DC to Atlanta.
What's in between Monticello,
let's go then get the
bus driver a room there.
I'm going to Mazzella a little big horn
that's between Minneapolis and Denver.
Uh,
world war one museum is a Kansas City.
I want to go on the air boat with the
guy in Louisiana and see alligators.
I do this stuff every day off.
And what happens when you do these things,
these activities,
you've talked to people.
And oftentimes I go to Monticello
between DC and Atlanta guns.
[inaudible] roses was playing nowhere
near there. So I can go in undetected,
I can go to a little big horn can.
People just are not expecting, you know,
a few people go, Whoa, duff, you know,
but it's not like I kind of tried to
not go to the places in the cities I'm
playing if I can help it sometimes.
Like when I saw you in Paris,
I just came from Normandy.
I did a whole thing.
Dda. How crazy is that? Yeah.
I went down there the, uh,
the next day,
uh,
in the morning I drove a van down because
that's all they've rented us as this
big stupid van. And I went down there and
I got lost. Oh, you did? But I didn't,
but I made it there. I made it. That
just couldn't get back to my hotel.
I couldn't find it because you
just walk the beaches of yourself.
I went and I smoked a cigar,
sat on the Bay beach in the morning and I,
I couldn't believe how moving it was.
Yeah.
And we took this incredible tour with
this piece with the creators. Yeah.
And that, and the guy, uh, um,
looks guy from Scotland and he took us
all into, but he did it all the papers.
Yeah.
And they had this bunker where I guess
Hitler had gotten gassed or something or
saw people get gassed in the, uh,
in World War One. Like when they,
when before they, that whole,
let's not try it, you know,
the poisonous gas shoot at people.
So he had showers installed in case,
you know,
any of the troops got,
you know, if they use gas.
So that was the weirdest
thing was just like, Oh wow,
that guy actually cared about something.
Right. I want to, I don't think I saw
that kind of rang a bell with you.
It was one of the German bunkers and
then was like, right as you walked in,
there was a little like a shower
thing that like, I guess if,
if whatever they spray you, if
you hosed it off you, I mean,
it's pretty ironic that he was
concerned about that. Consider, yeah,
no, I could see that, that, that, that
like, oh, oh yeah, actually, okay.
He was looking out for somebody other
than himself. Yeah, sorry. Anyways,
um, but I, I'm going to all these places
and I'm talking to people and, um,
you know, thinking there's
this big divide and you know,
red states and blue states and, you
know, make a joke out of this bite,
travel from state to state and I
don't notice a red one or a blue.
It's all the same.
And it was,
it's been the same since
I've been traveling since
the 80 [inaudible] punk rock
bands 82 and 83 throughout
all of this traveling,
I've traveled the whole
time and, um, raised,
we've raised our daughters who are now
1821 to be world citizens because that's
what we all fucking are.
You know, let's face it. Um,
I'm an American and proud American.
I make no bones about that.
I'm,
I'm super proud to be American. My
Dad fought world war two, you know,
my parents grew up in the depression,
but two of my brothers are in Vietnam.
We went to this amazing, uh,
I've got seven siblings. I mean,
the variety in our family is stunning,
you know,
and the things that I got to see because
I had this super cool mom, you know,
Martin Luther King March when he died
and all of these kind of epic things that
I wish I was older when I did.
Um,
but I'm traveling to America at first
and talking to people, I'm like, oh,
this to buy, oh, it's another selling
tool for the news. And it's politics.
Dude.
You read enough to know better,
like he fell down as stupid rat
like the guy and you know Louisiana,
you know once people you would
think where are the other, you know,
I mean he was alligators
like marshmallows. Who Knew?
Right then he, you know,
one thing he commented,
he's been doing it for 45 years and it
goes to the marshes are disappearing.
But what do you mean?
Because they are disappearing at an l
like I used to be able to go through this
channel right here. We can't, as you
see, we got to turn around and go in.
Our whole trip was this like
circumnavigating old paths.
He used to go and he goes,
it's like 900 cubic yards
per 30 minutes or something.
Like some, he gave me some stat. So
you find out more about your country.
And I what I found out that
the thing that being, you know,
getting back together with the band and
those guys and that's kind of talking
through things and getting on this back
to this place where we're friends and
we're able to go out like seriously
kick some ass and be like,
we never phone it in man.
It's back to that real thing and that
brotherhood and it gave me like this
intellectual sobriety or whatever
clarity to go out and just,
I was relaxed and able to talk to
people and put things together.
And I started writing while you out
on the road. Yeah, I started writing.
I thought maybe I was gonna write a book,
but I was reading hillbilly elegy
by JD bands where I was out there.
I read Sarah Canto whores
viewed from the fiber country,
read some book and I thought, is there
great books everybody should read them?
And I thought, well, should I put
another book out of like my observations?
Is that too much information?
Too many observations. And, uh,
I've wanted to do like a
really as a sidebar to this.
I've, for the last 20 something
years, I've wanted to do a record.
It's really toned down like Mark Atlantic
and Johnny thunders acoustic type of
record and I just didn't
really have the time or the,
the,
the intent to do as a
record like that I guess.
And I was writing all of these words
like chapter beginnings basically.
And uh, I carry acoustic guitar
on the road with me always.
And in a rare moment that I was in a
hotel room, I was looking at my computer,
it's just like, you have
yours out. I had my computer,
my guitar in my lap and I'm
strong strumming e major in, uh,
in a B minor seven chord.
And I was reading the words
too. Uh, it's not too light.
Will turn out the song. Everybody's
lying. Yeah, I need some truth.
Everybody is trying to push
you to the abuse. Um, and uh,
the whole idea of like,
maybe I'll make that that austere
record now and get these ideas across.
Well, I've got to tell you, you
said a lot of things that IB,
the like heard people that have respect
say like on this album, you know,
you've kind of talking about everything.
Uh, first of all, the sound of it, Kevin,
if I already said this to you
or if I said this down on the,
on the podcast or I sit in the driveway
as you came up, but like first of all,
the sound of it is, is complete
departure from anything that hurts,
heard you do in a great way.
It's a record that I kind of felt like
I wanted to go for a drive when I was
listening to it and it
reminded me of like, um,
it's Kinda got that timeless vibe to it,
which is what I like and
what you're talking about.
He talking about everything about
the drug epidemic, homelessness. Um,
there's that great line in there where
you say a go for a walk and find my
better man or something like that,
which is literally something I've been
doing just trying to deal with. Uh,
you know, the big demon in my family
tree is like rage issues, you know,
and just how that way yeah.
Wears on people. Yeah.
It just wears on people and Shit. So, um,
I I just threw one,
listen to this really connected.
Yeah.
With this stuff and it's,
it's kind of the stuff that I've
been kind of saying as far as like,
they're sitting there going after you
for Caitlyn Jenner joke and meanwhile
you're out there talking to some guy
who's trying to go through a marsh and
you're saying to 900 something yards,
square footage or whatever
is disappearing every day.
And every once in awhile you'll see some
anorexic looking polar bear and you're
like,
I think this is the priority.
And they got everybody screaming and
yelling at each other about just complete
nonsense. And then when you go on the
road, red state, blue state, this country,
that country, I just find everybody
who's just walking around, you know,
they're cool. They want to make sure
they have enough money for food,
they want to find love. It's
really basic. It's pretty basic.
But then you put it on TV, it's
like, ah, everybody's just screaming,
acting like the world is ending
because of these other fucking issues.
And it's like, no, this is the real shit
that's happening over here. And I don't,
I don't know.
It's that I,
I call it the support the
troops like Zombie mode.
They got everybody in, which I just love
that expression, support the troops.
Like why wouldn't you, you know, so
it's like, do you support the troops?
There's only one answer. Yes.
That's like, there you go.
But it's almost like a bill where there's
all this other shit attached to it.
And then that supporting
troops makes it like,
you can't question where you send them,
how long they're there, how they're,
when they come back, who's making
money, reasons why you go over there.
And the second I found once
that kind of took hold,
any sort of intelligence discussion went
from just support the troops America.
And if you said anything in the other
way, it's like, oh, you're a socialist.
Get the fuck Outta here.
His is a, is the truth of, of that, um,
presidents, kings, Queens,
warm makers have never made a
chase that's impacted our lives.
The people that make the
change to the good art are us.
Right.
Um,
my friend,
what do you think about cause World War
Two seems like there was definitely,
you know,
obviously that had to happen.
I mean if they were going
fucking what I'll be going down.
I mean it had to be stopped.
So it's at some point like I'm not
saying all war is bad. Do you feel,
do you feel that?
Well I, I was getting to a point
actually was like support our troops.
Like a friend of mine in US helping
each other instead of like the slogan
support your troops. You know that my
friend is a mountain climber who's a guys,
it was this biker guy got a really
bad accident back is in a cage.
Just put, they're going to chop it
up and he decides to climb Everest.
And he goes through this hell and,
and as personal Holly gets to Everest,
climbs it,
and he's coming back for whatever estate,
gets on a plane from India to Germany to
Manheim than any kid gets on the plane,
just came back from Afghanistan.
It got his leg blown off,
went to Walter Reed and in Madison,
you know,
and my buddy Tim says, this guy's
kids there at the airport together.
He's talking to the guy, he's got
a, uh, you know, kind of, uh, uh,
temporary prosthetic leg
and Tim's talking to him.
He's got a cage around his back.
My buddy Tim and his foots hanging on,
you know, by like just some clue and
stuff. And he's talking to this kid,
this pattern, marine kid,
this kid, 21 years old thing.
When you meet him there, kid,
he's like, what are you going
to do? Is like, I, I don't,
maybe I sit on my mom's couch and either
I don't know what to do. You know?
So Tim's like, you want to climb a
mountain? And he started one guy,
but one guy and he got a bunch of us
involved and we help train these guys.
You know what I'd done?
My friend Tim now has got better veterans
up all seven highest mountains in the
world.
Legless armless one guy missing two legs.
They did Kilimanjaro,
two legs missing.
So he had these little climbing
prosthetics for Tim's figured it all out.
Like how,
and it created this whole now network of
these guys who find those hopeless guys
who just gotten back right now
and they get them into this,
this climbing club.
I call it a gang.
Uh, but you know, that's
how you support your troops.
You follow the lead of a friend,
uh, like a guy like my friend Tim.
Oh, you mean you shouldn't just say that
on Twitter and on, you're done. Like,
so I hear all this. You hear on the
news a little American flag Emoji
and then you've done your part
of it puts perspective on the,
like the social media side of,
you know, help our or our trips.
Like Tim's just doing it like a ton
of people. This is in Hollywood,
you know,
people are jumping in and helping and
doing raising money and do these climbs
aren't cheap and, and come in and
help train these guys. And that's,
that's how you do it.
And that's the America I know,
not the one I see on the news,
not the one I see on social media.
You know.
What do you think I remember like
when I first like hung out with you,
hung out with you.
Uh,
two things that blew me away. One, you
tell a great street joke. Yeah, you too.
And uh, you already, you had me
laughing in the setup because they,
maybe it was something,
some joke when some guy went
to a hotel and then you just,
I could see off the top of you head and
you decided to pick a hotel and you said
it was this hotel and you described
the architecture is as an aside,
you already had me laughing.
And then secondly, we were
somehow talking about, um,
uh,
all that, the high end fashion that
women were into. Do you remember that?
And I was just like, I remember as a kid,
like I had never heard of Louis Vuitton.
If you wanted to get it,
you gotta be at a total fashion nerd and
you don't have to go to like New York
City, like, uh, fifth avenue, I would
think. Or maybe had to go to Paris.
I had no idea. Seattle, they
probably didn't have any of them. No.
And now it's like I was doing some,
tore through the deep south and I was
in somewhere Alabama and they had a
fucking mall and there was the same
bags that you saw like in Paris.
And I was like, I'm just, I know
you're smart with money and shit.
It's just like people,
just regular people going out and buying,
like spending money on bags like that.
It was sex in the city and made that
change, dude. Yeah, do a theory.
But when that came on and my
wife's watching all their friends,
they're talking about shoes like Manolo
Blahniks. I'm like, what is that?
Their shoes,
Jimmy child's shoes and bags and stuff.
And that's when that whole
culture changed for American,
like purchasing. Uh, yeah cause you think
you will kills me is I spent like,
I always joke, I spent like 15,
20 years in the back of the plane Sunday.
By the way,
I'm going to buy a fucking headphone
cord long enough that okay,
they got to chances for that. Bill Berg
got a guitar soon. Just get her Stacy.
I know. Probably Radio Shack other
than they don't have that anymore.
I know. I I they used to have one
right down the street and I didn't,
I didn't go but um,
okay.
Uh, I literally just fell out with
saying we were talking about the,
did I tell you what, when my friend
though I live down the street from me,
him and his wife,
they live in the apartment and he's
become really good friends with his next
door neighbor guy lists by himself.
[inaudible] guys. They'd been friends,
really good friends with the
past like year and a half.
And my friend with his wife,
he was watching TV last
night and it's living room,
gets a text from its next door neighbor.
Hey Man, I, um, I'm really sorry.
I got to be honest.
I've been,
I've been banging your wife for the
last few months, but it, but it's over.
I've stopped. So my friend put down
his phone, he went in the other room,
got a gun and shot his wife and it
came back and sat down and sofas. Like,
what did I just do? My God.
And there's phone buzzes again.
It's this his friend next door and like,
oh, sorry, I met Wifi. Got them autos
that was going to go, you can
cut that out if you want. No,
come on man.
You've listened to me play drums.
I can listen to you tell
a fucking joke. Um, but I,
that's what struck me when I met you.
I was like, this guy like that remind,
that's like something a comedian does,
like looks at something and just how you,
you put it together in like,
uh, like, uh, with music.
But like I even when you were saying that
to me, I was, I was actually thinking,
fuck, why didn't I think of that?
Because that would be a killer bit.
And because it always be,
like I was saying, oh, now
I remember, I thought I was,
I spent like 15 years in the back of the
plane. Yes. Working my way up, you know,
I always say the blast row then trying
to get the exit row poor man's first
class. Right. That's actually
sometimes can be better. Better. Yeah.
And then getting finally
getting up to the front. Um,
so now I get them to pass the front. It
was like, whoa. Yeah, these people are,
these people do. Yeah. And they'd be
on the phone or they'd be writing shit.
They own banks and stuff. Yeah. And, and
for Y'alls, you still riding in the back.
All they do in the front of the plane
is just treat you like a human being to
give you.
That's all it is.
They just give you a seat that
actually fits a human being.
They'll come by frequently and ask if
you want water or food as opposed to jam
and you in the back. So
what has struck me over, uh,
is the amount of people that I've
seen that will come on the plane,
you know, and you just, you know,
a comedian, I just, you know,
I'm always like looking at people and
stuff and I'll see something come up with
a Louis Vuitton bag. I'm like, oh this
person is probably sitting next to me.
And you'd watch them go into the back
of the plane and you just start thinking
of like priorities.
Like as far as like,
I guess the bag maybe that is worth more,
you could sell it.
I'm just thinking like why the fuck,
it's like the person who buys the flashy
car before they buy a house and they're
still like renting.
And I think that like beyond the sense
sex in the city that now the whole like
social media where everybody is,
is they're doing their own,
like almost like new cycles. Spin
that of, of the, I'm crushing it.
You hold the camera up,
see look like 30% better looking.
You got all this money and you just
live in and all you're doing is you're
taking snapshots of the coolest
parts of your month. Yeah.
Not the one where you're fucking
crying during a breakup or a,
you lost your job.
None of that shit is on there.
So it just kind of makes you
feel like everybody is leaving
you behind and that you need
all of this stuff. And um,
I think we're still learning how like,
it's funny because again,
back to my girls,
18 and 21 so we had to,
you're raising a kid, right? And I'm a
rookie here, two and a half years. Okay.
So our kids got to,
let's say seven and 10.
That's when social media was
just starting to like be a thing.
And so now you've got to raise your kids
through this social media thing too.
How did you do that by the way?
We had to figure it out and
crushing blows, you know,
just school kind of like bully,
like, uh, you know, social media,
bullying from school, like, okay girls,
you know, it's not real. It's just like,
they would never say that to your
face. So you've gotta and then, but,
but I lost you there.
So they would be getting bullied on
social media from somebody at school,
like a different group of girls or
something, you know? And so you have to,
you know, the girls are crying or
something will happen like that. Right.
And you have to talk to them. Like, would
they ever said that to your face? No.
Okay. So you've got to look at this as
like kind of, uh, uh, pussies, way out,
you know, so how does that work? The
next day at school? It's like they said,
I'll let shit, you don't
confront them. Like,
I don't know how it works with kids
today. Yeah, you'll, you'll figure it out.
But I think what's happened, like it
started off with the bowling and then,
and then these kids became smarter.
They're also aware of what's going
on outside as well. You know,
they know the school shootings
way more real to them than,
than us because it's happening and could
happen at school to that. Right, right.
Um, they're aware of things more
visceral. They're there, they're in it.
They're social media
geniuses more than us.
We follow dumb shit and like, you
know, you can't say that they're,
they, it's been part of them. So now
they're, there's weeding it out there,
weeding it out, and now they're starting
to take the pass way more than we can,
the way smarter on social
media than we are. And uh,
like the insta life, the Instagram
life, you know, pies seam,
that's more like 25 and above the
pupil that Instagram life is fabulous.
Right. You know, the kids younger,
this is my observation, right.
Take it for what you will.
Now I'm listening to this because it's
something that worries me because I think
now like my daughters and their friends,
boys and girls,
like we know all of their friends very
well. We were like the house sets.
It's cool to come hang out and let
some really astounding kids and,
and uh, they're taking the
pass right now and they're,
they're kind of sitting there silently.
She see Emma Gonzales ever speak up.
The parkland,
like those kids who spoke like through
this thing and then we're smarter than
you, you know, that is kind of this
new generation that's coming up.
It's just Imogen's Alice and the Parkland
kids who kind of stood up and said,
okay, hold on a second. Right. We do have
something to say and here it goes, right?
Uh, blown away by their
intellect in like, okay,
if everybody's as smart as that
18 we're in good hands and it,
the kids I observe or are just like that
and they're just kind of waiting like
they have now 18 they can vote.
[inaudible]
um, what are you guys going to do
with that we're going to take over?
No, that's the answer I get.
Every generation think that my,
my problem is I feel like there like a,
okay.
Like their hands are like bound,
you know what I mean?
By the time you get to a certain
level as a politician, like
th th th th the way the money is set
up. Like they are there already. All,
all of these people's favors and just the,
I don't want to get,
I also don't get why, where it's like,
Hey, do you want cleaner drinking water?
And everybody goes yes.
And then they,
they get to attach all of this other shit
to it. I don't know. I don't understand.
Well,
why can't,
the thing that we're saying yes to
just be the thing that you're doing,
because I think we have to do it, not
the politics. It's always been that way.
We have to do it like my friend Tim,
and it is mount climbing things. We have
to do it. Yeah, that makes sense
to me. But being able to let go,
so if they're saying they're gonna
take over by doing shit like that,
if there's anybody young listening,
that's the only way I
think to make change is,
uh, is you have to start it and
do it at a, at a small level.
But if you,
like I remember when Trump,
we became president and he
said something like, you know,
I'm going to come in here and
I'm going to drain the swamp.
And I just laughed when I heard that.
It's like,
and what do you think they're going to
do? Just sit there and be like, well,
I guess he got us.
It's like,
no one's going to work with you if you're
saying you're going to go in here and
you're, you're gonna, you're gonna expose
all, uh, like political corruption.
Um, like at that level,
it's just so walled off. Um,
I dunno,
I just Kinda got back from Europe and I
just felt a weird vibe when I was over
there and I, I forget what
country I was in. I was just like,
are you guys going to
start this shit up again?
And it kind of got a weird laugh and
then something in the back when, yeah,
like just the vibe over there was,
it's not the place I went to for the
first time 10 years ago or now it's just
becoming like, uh, like look at like
fucking Paris and mean Jesus Christ.
It's like, that's a fucking, it's like
a mosh pit over there every other day.
Like something crazy like a,
the yellow vest protestors.
Yeah,
that and then wage thing.
And when I went to Sweden there was these
other people protesting and I was just
like,
what's going on here?
And I talked to a couple people over
there who are Muslim and they just like,
yeah, racism is kind of like a, it's
not the way it is in the United States.
We have like such a long history of it.
So people really like overt with it over
here and just, and I don't know. Yeah, I,
I don't want to like tell you what,
what I saw cause your album I thought
is really positive and I don't want,
I want to put my awful world view into it,
but I kind of came away from it with
the positive of just like, look,
I'm just going to try
to be a better person.
Try to be cool with the people that are
in my life and just try not to be a dick
because other than that,
this stuff is so big and overwhelming.
I mean, I think what you just said
it, that's the answer. You know,
I too have traveled to European countries
that I've gone to says shit man,
before the wall went down,
you know,
many years before the wall and then the
wall going down. And then, you know,
opening up of a tech Czechoslovakia
became the Czech Republic. And,
and seeing like all of this that I
remember part Perestroika and you know,
the opening up of USSR and,
and after that glass nose and Perestroika
and then the wall going down and then
seeing those countries themselves,
chase Italy and republic and what's, Oh,
what's going on here now?
You guys were,
we're super stoked and now there's kind
of another vibe going on instead of the
five.
Talk to people.
Why does that always happen?
Um, there's, I think, you
know, I read so much history,
so there's cycles, man. Like,
and, and we've gone through,
we're going through a cycle right now.
There's
what I've learned from reading so much
history is, again, man, the politicians,
American politicians, European
politicians, they don't chase.
They run to get into the office.
And that you're right,
there's so many favors to be repaid
and that point and that, you know,
man of the people are a woman
of the people. That ship
has sailed by that point.
Um, and it's always been like the people
that made a change. There have been
just in really small than a ways.
There was a small little ways and that's
the positivity that we pick up from
other people.
They you,
you got to kind of bring it
local into your own neighborhood,
you know, if you go got and
try to solve huge problems.
I always wondered like I was sitting
there thinking like with Evan,
everybody stopped watching the news.
Then how would we behave?
And it's like, well before television
there was still all kinds of brutality.
What's then made me think like, well then
how did they get their view out there?
It seemed like back then what they would
do is they would send people out to get
slaughtered so then they could just
be like, do you see what happened?
Like sort of like what the native
Americans where they would just make these
treaties like, okay, we're
just going to go to here. And
then they tell, hey people,
there's free land beyond here. And
they, they, they tell them something,
then they would go out and get slaughtered
and then we had to go get her revenge,
which was really them just using people
to go fight the native Americans and
then just take more of the
land. Um, I don't know.
I have this odd sort of like I,
I dunno where I am now in a world
holistic, it's a little bit,
but I'm also like super positive locally.
Like I,
I'm just kinda like just person to person
is a real positive experience for me.
But it's why I don't like when you though
those school shootings and all that
type of stuff,
I stopped watching those because what
I hate about it is I don't want to know
that fucking person's name and I feel
like the same way somebody watches you
guys in a band makes them
want to be in a band.
I feel like school shootings are like,
that's like keeping up with
the Kardashians for psychos
and then they want to
watch it and all those women who young
girls who aspire to be like a car Dashi
in an all glamorous psychos,
watch that and go like, oh,
that's,
that's what I want to do.
I don't disagree with you
on anything you just said.
No, I don't hear that a lot.
Thank you. Yeah. I usually
get a lot of pushback. Yeah.
The Shit I say,
you know,
uh,
I mean I've got involved in a few
things because when I wrote these,
if it was going to be a book and there
was going to be a social action involved,
now that's a record. The song
social action involved, right?
It's small things.
Like I got involved homelessness
in Seattle's super gnarly.
It's super visible like in La because
street camping is legal, right?
RV camping is legal.
You can have four grams or under of
heroin and not get arrested. Seattle,
they tried this social experiment.
It's not really working.
It's makes homelessness
very visible there. And, um,
I had a brother in law that went through,
he was a,
it was my oldest brother in law.
He ended up homeless on the street and
when I was in punk rock bands and I would
see him down town when
they're all sketchy, you know,
punk rock clubs and stuff.
Um,
is my brother in law man.
And this guy is a guy helped raise me
when my dad left, like my brother in law,
Dexter buzz taught me how to run sprint
and do all this catch with football and
all this stuff.
And now I'm seeing him,
I'm 17 years old and his eyes
are yellow jaundice and you know,
alcoholism and 1983 82 and like
help try to help Dexter out.
Like,
uh,
and he helped somebody
out in that situation.
Like my friend had a punk rock club, like,
Hey, can my brother and I texted her,
like, make some money sweeping up or
whatever. That's how you help. Like,
but he, but he was, uh, receptive to it.
Text her. Yeah, yeah, yeah. And you know,
he helped me one time I was downtown
and I got surrounded by a group of these
dudes who are homeless,
you know,
street and suddenly like out of nowhere,
like leave that guy alone lungs,
my brother in law and there comes decks,
drop out of the stairs and
like he know night. And uh,
I thought I was going to get the shit
beat out of me or worse, you know. And,
and uh, so he looked out
after me too as well. Um,
we're brother-in-law's, you know, I was,
he was 20 something years
my senior. Right. Uh,
what is the age difference in your
20 20th, so yeah, you're the baby.
Yeah. So I'm 55. My oldest
brother, 75. Is that right?
Yeah. Wow. So he was burned.
My oldest brothers and sisters were
born during World War II at the army
cause I was, cause I was reading, you
know, Park next, our per view book.
It was saying how, uh, you know
when you were like in high school,
like two year brothers were in Vietnam.
And I was trying to like, wait a minute,
what, what is, what is, what is
this the spread on that yet? How,
how old were you when they,
like when your brothers went away and how
long went off to war and how long were
they away at war?
I wasn't born yet.
When my first one went off.
Oh, so he wasn't there right
after [inaudible] took over
from the France. Right,
right.
Okay.
Like 63 or 64 maybe. I was just born. Um,
so he went over for, you know,
so he went and right at 18.
Yeah, it could because there was
so many brothers in our family.
I think at the beginning of the Vietnam
war there was sort of like still this
kind of, well, I'll do my, do my bed,
there's told me brothers, we'll
get drafted anyhow. Right.
I'll be able to choose where I go if I,
if I sign up right.
Dad and signed up for World War II.
So there was,
our grandfather was a world war one, so
there was this kind of thing like, okay,
this is what you do. Uh,
my s second brother, uh,
the second oldest brother mark
did the same thing. Signed up,
thought he could get in, I'll get in
the navy or something. And they, they,
they put them in the army. He
was in, he was in the shit.
He never talked about ever in his life.
How does that work?
I thought if you enlisted,
you got to choose. Yeah.
Well I think he thought he was able
to choose and I think they needed more
people in the,
in the army and they kind of just put
them someplace and so he's building
forward, forward, uh, uh,
I know he was building those
forward arm positions, you know,
and then had to hold it down and
tells they could fill it. Um,
he did that for a couple of years.
He got his Gi bill used it.
But the school is a math genius in a
park at Hanford and then at Boeing.
It never talked about his
experience in the war.
He just died of cancer
a couple of years ago.
He did work a hamper for a couple of years
and he was in Vietnam for a couple of
years and that doctors, you know, kind
of put some things together, you know,
but Hanford also nuclear. Yeah.
I'm not that bright a guy.
He can produce a nuclear. So you need
to do that a lot during this pocket.
Hampers and nuclear.
This is a state and you know,
but uh, uh, what we was any out. So my,
my brother died downtown Seattle,
my brother in law, Dexter,
uh, Union Gospel mission was just placed
where that he used the services when my
sister that was married to him,
she also died just a couple of years ago.
Jesus. Yeah. Yeah.
So she all, she wanted all of
her, she died suddenly. Um,
so we see in her will like all every
like donations or whatever it goes to the
Union Gospel mission. Like, I
better check out this place.
My brother in law and then my sister and
I'm seeing homelessness and I do a trip
down there to Union Gospel mission.
I've seen it, you know, it's scary.
It's the things I talk about in the song,
like I'm not going near there. Right.
Um, but I went in and the
first time I went with,
with my wife and she just
had just done a news thing.
She was all dressed up and she's
like, I want to go. I'm like,
well, you're looking pretty, you
know, like, uh, you know, uh,
you look like you look really,
you live really indoors and it's like,
what are you doing here? Yeah, yeah.
But, but you know, we travel a lot,
so we do see a lot and we,
you know,
when we travel as much and see
the things we see, we grow at a
layer of empathy I guess.
Like you're not afraid to go some
places because you understand people are
pretty much cool everywhere you go. Even
that scary homeless guy that's yelling,
you know,
if you read Elyn,
Saks is the center cannot hold your
understand more about schizophrenia.
Like that guy's not screaming at you.
He's screaming at some
thing that he doesn't. Yeah,
no, they just went to Israel for the first
time and I thought it was going to be
everybody just shooting guns at each
other. He was just chilling, chilling.
It was cool. Yeah. So I'll
say the Palestinian people
protesting and they were,
they were civil, the whole thing.
I was like, oh, this is like,
and it was right on the Mediterranean
Sea. It's like, this is beautiful.
That's just not how I pictured it.
Because whenever they show it,
it's after something horrible
happen. Yeah. Or are they,
it's like they don't even talk about
it over here until something happens.
European people, if you've
noticed, you've traveled to Europe,
are terrified to come to us because what
they see as the guns and the shooting
and stuff, I'm not going
there, you know, so it's,
it's whatever you perceive something
else to be. Right. Um, right.
So, so we went to the Union Gospel
mission and they said, do you want to,
we're going to go on a run right
now I'm running, what's that? What?
We're going to go into the jungle,
which is
arguably the worst homeless
and cabinet in America.
If they called it the jungle,
it wasn't going to be something
that's been there for a long time.
These guys have an MTI,
Mti out part of it. Um,
cops won't go in there.
The city,
how are they going to go on
there but not the cops. The cops,
like we're not going in there,
you know, cause they, uh, so,
but these guys from the Union Gospel
mission who have lived in the jungle and I
went to Rehab and now run the Union
Gospel mission and we lived here and they
tell me my point to all of this. They,
they, we, I started asking him like,
how would people get here? How do
people get to that tent on the street?
How do people get to the jungle?
Like living in the bushes,
like underneath the freeway.
Like it's like, well, you know,
it's 85% drug and alcohol addiction.
Okay.
I kind of took it, but there's
a number. Okay, thanks.
But like I was, you know, I mean,
my fear of living on the street even drew
my whole, my addiction, I'll call you,
like kept me off the street.
I'd worked like nine times as hard to be
able to trace. You paid the rent, right?
Yeah. Nine Times. He's like, yeah,
but did you have like abuse as a kid?
No.
Yet did you could, you know,
go through foster care note?
Did you get abused multiple
times? No I didn't. None of that.
He goes that 85% number of drugs now
I'll call coincides almost directly with
the amount of child abuse that
these and the guy I'm talking to,
I won't say his name right. It
happened to me, it happened to,
my brother happened to this guy right
here sitting next to us bad and,
and we got stuck in this cycle that it
took me 50 years of my life to finally
get out of,
I didn't know how I'd know
means it goes to the t like the,
there's a ton
Linda Bennington,
Chester's wife since since his untimely
passing got hooked up to this thing,
the five signs,
the five signs to recognize something's
wrong and this starts very young,
these five signs and I think the five
signs should be putting in like school
like yes, right. Like, cause we
remember going to elementary school,
there was the guy that,
well that guy's a little rapey.
You knew it like in the fifth grade,
you know what I mean? Like I said,
she's going to grow up and not going to
be cool with checks because something's
going on the little rapey
that guy's a little, you know,
you could tell like at a young age like
we knew there was some guys weird like
weird. That's all you had. Was it weird?
He just killed his family's cat, you know,
staying away from that guy, you know.
Uh, there's, there's signs, you know,
as a young kid and if we had like,
and this one starts,
one person like to Linda started stinking,
I'm into it.
I'm have a propeller thing with my
record that you can get involved.
I'm going to make tee shirts from my tour.
They had the five signs on the back of it.
Oh that's great.
All I do is come on podcasts
and bitch about shit.
You actually doing something about it.
I need to to get fans involved and like
if we can just like one person at a time
, um, you know, it start
with the, you know, sure.
You hear about a guy getting radicalized
on Facebook and it goes and shoots up
is in place.
But sure.
What allowed that guy to
get radicalized on some,
the rest what you said there
about the jungle, right? Yeah.
I know everybody is going to give me
shit for not bringing up your song,
but I'm not going to do
well.
They had a sign that said no trespassing.
They have at Union Gospel mission is
great. It says no trespassing sign.
When somebody back in the day eighties
late eighties spray painted like gang
writing, welcome to the jungle and that
was assigned to get into the jungle. Wow.
And they have, I took
a picture of it. Yeah.
I'm saying like how that if I was to
drive by that not having not talked to you
[inaudible] my first thought
would be, you know, I want it.
I've got to get the fuck out here.
I'm not saying it still wouldn't be,
I would be afraid, but I'm now seeing
those people is like, that's some,
that's,
those are hurt kids grown up,
which humanizes them as
opposed to looking at it like,
cause I have to be honest with you,
like I see a lot of homeless people out
here in La and there's that thing where
you like, I definitely, you know,
as much of an asshole as I am,
I am empathetic and I,
and I do want to try to help out,
but it's just how to go in and
approach without getting fucked up.
Like I would just went by a drug
store the other day and this actually,
I almost said something to this kid.
There was a guy who clearly so many people
have just like, like mental problems.
Right. You know, and
this guy was just like,
he was still going on some,
you know,
schizophrenia fucking riff about,
uh,
something about hobbits or something and
the way he was moving it freaked me out
in this younger kid out. And at some point
we both kind heard what he was saying,
which was comical. On a base level if
he wasn't living the life he was living.
But then I saw the younger kids start
smiling and then he takes his phone out to
film them. And I'm just looking at like,
dude, this is like, cause they shut down.
Mental hospitals is now going to become
your content for your Instagram page.
And I almost said something to him.
Um,
but then there was just like, alright,
have an Iwatch, shit like that on you.
Now I'm kind of a hypocrite because I
remember when bumfights first came out,
I remember that these guys would pay
bumps to beat the shit out of each other.
And I was the age I was at,
I was way too old to find that funny.
But I was also still trying to
find my voice as a comedian.
And there was that whole thing
amongst comics where like, you know,
you gotta like you can't be softy,
everything's gotta be funny.
So I watched Saturn and entertainment
level, so I just, I quickly was just like,
all right, what? I'm going to be a
parent to this 20 something year old.
I'll feel like a fucking hypocrite.
And I didn't say anything, but my,
my problem is,
is I always go to anger and what it should
have went to was more like, hey man,
this guy's, he's, his life is hard
enough, man. You don't need a blow.
I should have gone like that.
And it's my default emotion
would be like, you know, hey,
fuck had you know this guy.
You know, I would, you know,
and who listens after hey fuck head.
Who listens to your true
Yo, my phrase, yes. Come on. Excuse
me. Fellow American. Yeah. Um,
yeah, I, I read this, you're talking about
the guy yelling at something. I mean,
we could go on forever bell.
I gotta tell you, I'm like,
there's levity in this and there's hope
like in the record that, that, that,
that's what I liked there.
There, there is. But I read,
I read a lot and there's this book,
I brought it up earlier.
The center cannot hold,
was written by this woman.
She's currently the head of school
psychology at USC. If you've heard,
we've heard of this school,
it's a big school.
I hear about them when
they win championships and
scan that stuff. But she,
she's a schizo frantic and she wrote
this book. She did admit it to,
she would live this like kind
of solo life until she was,
she has schizophrenia and wrote
a book. Was it, I mean she's,
the head of the joke there was, it was
an uneven, she's, she's brilliant but,
but to start her story,
you know, she's, she,
she gets scholarships to Cambridge
and yell law and all of this stuff.
Meanwhile going off on these
schizophrenia tirades of like,
I've killed a million people
and a million people killed me.
I've been killed a million times.
Her and her friend stopped and
then they would like, what are you,
what's going on? Oh, I was joking like,
but it still was able
to contain it like that.
We went into a hospital in England
for a year, the, but over there,
the professor recognize what was going
on. She's brilliant. No, she's brilliant.
He put her in this place.
They don't chain you down in the
mental hospitals and they use velcro.
They don't. They actually
done. Uh, but she got,
she had her stories.
You should just read the book,
but I wanted to tell you about the,
her beginnings of that. Like she,
when she was nine or 10,
she always thought there was a man outside
their door at night. And she's like,
well what,
what nine or 10 year old kid doesn't
kind of think that like the boogeyman and
she's like 1516 mark and home from high
school to houses would talk to her,
but everybody else seems to
be handling it well. Right.
The houses must be talking to everybody.
They're talking to me,
but I'm looking at other kids on the
street. They're not freaking out on it,
so I'll just, I won't
either. I'll just hold it in.
And it progressed and progressed and
progressed to where she was on the roof of
that.
They'll know about it.
But after doing a hundred
graduate screaming and you know,
blacked out like screaming map Kelda
million people had been killed a million
times and
I was going to ask, so she doesn't
remember saying that. Some of it she does,
she talks very real,
very real.
She would have these moments where
suddenly it all came to her like, ah,
I've killed.
But she would,
she also writes in that I
would never harmed anybody.
That's what's so misunderstood.
Like schizophrenia means a million
different things where they put a label on
sort of one thing just to
kind of get it in a group.
But I read this book all the way to its
end. She's now 60 maybe or something.
She was the head of school psychology
at USC and I drove past a guy on sunset
and vine. He's on the corner screaming,
chanting the top of his lungs,
like the guy you saw and several of
them parking lot of where it was right.
I suddenly had empathy for, I understood
it a lot more. And I think, um,
uh,
reading and educating yourself if you're
interested in your fellow man and it's
just interested in how we've gotten here
and what's in the future and cycles of
things.
I just read a lot and it's so interesting
and like even current administration's
don't bother me cause it just passes,
you know,
we go to Europe and stuff, we see how
administrations affect other countries,
how they think about
us. You know, there was,
I mean we've been traveling
through a few wars, you know,
I don't travel the way you like, I,
I've, I do a little quick little runs.
You guys would go and live
there. Yeah, we're there.
Um,
yeah,
we've been traveling there and staying
in Europe would go there and stay for it.
How did you like when when you
guys were always blows my mind.
I understand like when you
get to a certain level,
you can afford a business manager who
can handle your mail and your bills and
all of that shit when you will come up
and you just touring around in a van.
Yeah. Okay. And there's taxes to be
paid and there's the cable and yeah,
like money. So like you guys. Oh yeah.
It's just the sheer that see you basically
homeless in Flores and yeah. You,
you know,
like
I always, I had such as my parents
grew up in the end, the depression.
So I grew up with depression era values.
Like we'd hear these horror stories
of the depression. Like I'm never,
there was one time on, I was 18
years old, I was on a punk rock tour.
I was starving, literally
shaking, starving, and a guy said,
you can go down to the, I'd
had jobs as cooks. I paid tax,
I've done construction. I've done
every kind of job. There was this tour,
I had to stop for two weeks,
my construction job and go on tour.
I didn't have any money. I had
apartment paid this, you know,
the taxes, you pay pad of Europe, they
take it out of your paycheck, you know.
Um, but I was starving, penniless and
starving in San Francisco and they said,
you can go down to the
emergency food stamps. Oh.
But I was so hungry. I didn't
have a choice. I wasn't
going to fucking panhandle.
I wasn't, I didn't have it. I didn't,
there was no safety net in my family.
You know, like you can't, what
they mom, why aren't me some cash?
My mom didn't have any
money, you know. Um,
so I went to this line and I,
I'd maybe it happened for a reason and
went to the welfare line and you can get
$80 in emergency food stamps and
it was women with babies, but six,
you know, and there's me,
I'm an able bodied, you know,
18 year old bumps. Fucking
starving man. If I didn't eat,
I hadn't eaten for like three days, you
know, and I just needed something to eat.
So I waited there and I got,
and I went into a store and I bought,
yeah,
bunch of like a loaf of bread and
some Bologna and some cheese. I still,
so I still had like $70 of food stamps
and I gave, I gave him five bucks left.
Yeah. So I gave that, I get food stamps
to, to a woman that was in the store.
And you want these. And I never
had that experience. Like,
I'm never going to be homeless.
I'm never going to be homeless and
I don't want it. I paid that back,
that 10 bucks I got from the welfare a
million times. I Oprah paint, you know,
I met my taxes and everything,
but how do you know later on when I
started making money and stuff like a and
getting mail, so you have
to have an address for that.
The gas, right. So, you know,
uh,
I got a buddy of mine, a comedian, he
actually, he so living out in the woods,
he tried to legally see if
he could stop getting mail.
Oh. And just like he just,
that's the level that he
wants to just not be involved.
And they were like, no, you have to, you
have to have a mailing address, a SPEC.
We kind of have to know where you are
just in case you do some crazy shit.
We know where to start
looking for you, I guess. Um,
I went down that,
you know,
like 10 years ago I got totally into
like conspiracy theory and shit.
And I was buying like fucking
powdered food and all,
it's not how I ended up learning how
to fly a helicopter because I got so
fucking scared of living out here.
Like what happens when the dollar
collapses in the shit hits the fan.
How the fuck do you get out? It takes
like nine hours to get out of here.
Even when it works in up and out
was the only way I'd never took into
consideration how expensive
a fucking helicopter wasn't.
You can't land it in anymore. So
you know how to fly one. Yeah.
That's not an easy thing to do.
It's no flying. It's not hard.
It's all the shit you need to know so
you don't fuck up when you're up there.
That's, it's the, the ground school is,
is, is the hard part. But like, you know,
I mean if you could drive a stick shift,
you know,
I mean it's like four stick shifts
once, isn't it? No, no we're not. It's,
it's this, this is up and down. This here
is where you want it go movies. Yeah.
Yeah. So like the emergency
brake, if you want to go up,
you go like this, they're right now,
can't see this. What are you doing?
If you want to go down
and you go like that,
you just went down with his
hand and then the cyclic,
the stick between your legs.
He just Kinda, you know,
whichever way you want to go,
like a stairwell and then,
uh,
fly a helicopter.
Now you can show me how to do that.
Basically it,
well if you're ever in a helicopter
and then you just got your pedals,
that kind of keeps your ass and you
know, is where you wanted to be. I mean,
it's very,
it putting it all together is a little
about pat and you had rubbing your
stomach, but you know, I, when you know,
you play bass and can be
singing like in [inaudible],
what do they call that? Uh, like a
I'm poly rhythmic kind of thing. Yeah.
Where it's like,
I always wanted how the guys can play,
can play guitar and sing where it's
like the phrasing is different.
Just once things stuff. Yeah. Yeah.
You that takes a lot of practice.
Yes,
but that is way fucking harder.
That is way fucking harder
than the helicopter.
Helicopter is more the fear like
am I going to fucking kill myself?
That's indeed. Yeah. You don't think
that playing bass singing songs
when I was getting really hammered,
I want it.
I was the best idea was my
friend talking me out of it.
This is like 91 height of
my drink and I need to,
I'm going to learn how to try to get,
I'm going to get a helicopter in my
face like, yeah, not a good idea.
Oh Man. We can go up to lake
arrowhead. Big Bear. Yeah,
like 10 minutes man.
Fuck traffic it probably not a good idea.
What was your drink of choice?
You've got like 18 guns.
You think the mailman is gonna you
know, probably not a good idea. Yeah.
I was paranoid and like what was your
drink of choice? Oh, I had everything up.
Why do you got my drink of
choice was just straight vodka.
They fuck up. I was, I quit
drinking last November.
I still have some bottles of booze here,
Bruce,
cause they're high end shit
and I'm not throwing them out.
And I'm also not giving them away.
I just keep them with special friends
come by or whatever. I haven't, but I,
I uh,
I'm more of a,
I was a whiskey bourbon guy and yeah.
And I,
and I started buying the high end stuff.
So then you don't think you're,
you're kind of a drunk. You just think I'm
a connoisseur. Right. But I'm more of a,
I'm just a binge drinker because I went
to a couple of AA meetings and like this
fucking stories there. I was just like,
my jaw was on the ground and they like,
build, do you want to share? I was
like, I can't fucking follow this.
You're thinking of it as a bit like,
dude, I don't have any. Like, I mean,
I come home, my wife yells at
me, come to bed and I fall.
I fall asleep and wake
up in sports center's on.
I mean that's about as bad as the
gut. Um, I was just doing it too much.
Uh, I just, I kind of learned,
like I keep saying this on
my podcast because I hope,
you know, cause some people,
I think a like me and you can kind of,
I kind of like if,
if a doctor saw how much I was drinking
would say you are an alcoholic and it's
Kinda like a lot of people don't realize
that just 30 pounds overweight can see,
you know, your height is in there too. But
like if you're about my size, five, nine,
five, 10, if you're 30 pounds overweight,
you're obese. People think obese is like,
you know,
you fucking thighs are rubbing together
and you're wearing ray on slacks and
nobody wants to bang you, right?
It's just like, no, it's just,
it's just 30 pounds.
And I learned that from my buddy who was
about my size and he went up to a buck
95 and he went in for a physical
and the guy was like, look,
I'm not going to write you up but just
to let you know you're five pounds over.
And he was just like, write me up for
what? And he was like being obese.
And like it blew his mind who my mind too,
but not as much as him cause he was
actually being called obese. But um,
I just saw a thing on.
So I do watch this.
I watch local morning news in Seattle.
Right.
And here in La there was access. So it's
just like local stuff. Right, right.
You don't get the,
and I pick what news station I
watched it just as local stuff.
I want the weather, you know, like
maybe a little story about something.
Yeah, some old lady who jars around
on jam in the end makes you feel good.
You know,
rescued a dog.
I bet there was a story on the news this
morning talking about obesity and uh,
one of the rear admiral somebody
came out today and said,
uh,
majority of American kids wouldn't
qualify it for the military today cause of
obesity and mental
issue. I was like, whoa.
I rewound the story. I just hear that.
Right. Anyone who said they wouldn't,
wouldn't be able to do like
regular just jobs or our college.
It was a, it just reminded me the
thing you said about obesity obstacle,
look into that more.
I thought you was.
Yeah he was also talking like physical,
I saw a thing about like
some school between here and
San Diego like way back in
the day,
I can't remember if they came up with
the president's physical fitness thing
that did as a kid.
Yeah as a kid.
Like they probably don't do this now
because it makes kids feel bad about
themselves.
But they used to be this thing called
the the the president's physical fitness
test and you had to be able to do a
certain amount of pushups in a minute sit
ups.
And the one that blew my mind was a pull
up cause I had never done a pull up.
And if you've never done a pull up you
can barely do one because you'd never use
those muscles.
Like for some reason a chin up I guess
cause you're picking stuff up and you're
using your bicep.
It did not pass one of them.
And still be okay. Right.
So it was Paula was your weakness or
push up? I think you could not pass one.
Yeah.
I remember doing that every year as a kid.
30 30 sit ups in that in a minute.
I've been doing pull ups ever since,
since I have you til I
fucked up my shoulder and I,
I've been the last two years I have,
I had a bet with my buddy
200 bucks that when I'm 70,
I'll be able to do 10 of them.
And right after I made the bet I don't,
my wife showed me some,
one of her crossfit fucking exercises
and I was trying to do it and I just felt
this pinch and I had this rotator cuff
fish. Oh No, I know. So now I don't know.
I don't know what I gotta do here.
So I'm taking a few months off.
Yes. Those little, uh, so those
little stabbing, just a little pinch.
Like now I'm 55.
I'll get a little pinch where
when I was 30 something.
Just be a little page. Yep.
Shut off that little pinch.
I think I just bulged my
disc in my l four l five.
You Ready? Sure. You gotta
get like a Jedi misuse.
That's what I ended up finding
somebody to hook me up with somebody I,
a nerve issue and she,
I remember I was in my left leg that
was fucked up and she just sat there
listening to me for like a half hour
asking me questions and I was going like,
the fuck are we doing here? So
he goes, all right, let's go.
And then she took me in back in was
my left leg when I was feeling pain.
She started with my right shoulder
and I was thinking, all right,
either she doesn't know what she's
doing or she's at some jet eye level.
And it turned out, fortunately
it was the jet eye level. And uh,
I just, through all the years of playing
sports, it was fucked because the,
when the, the pain takes you back
to when like you ever say, hey guys,
I'm pasty as health sis, I'll get like
bruises on me. My wife would be like,
what happened? And I'll be, I dunno. And
what I do is I push on it and are Oh yeah,
yeah, I was walking through, I banged
into the door, it's fucking weird.
So she was doing that with my leg and
it was like the history of my life.
Like all my brother used to
give me charley horses. Oh,
I used to play pick up
hockey and not wear any gear.
I fell on my fucking leg
and she went all the way.
Like it took like three months
too. I was like, come on,
ray lived your life in that, the painful
moments. Yeah. That's great. No, no, no.
This was three months, three
months of slowly. She was like,
there's three levels of your
muscle were on the surface.
And then I was psyched
that we got to the moon,
but every time she would start a new
layer, like, dude, I'm telling you,
I was like coming up off the table.
And she was like, give me numbers,
give me numbers. And I was like, I'd
be like, all right. I was like six six.
And she goes, well, you're
Irish. So that's probably an
eight guys. Can't fucking,
you know, communicate like pain
or shit like that. So, um, do,
we've talked for almost
second hour and when,
I haven't even talked about like
the over an hour. Jesus Christ,
the how great the album, what's the
name of the APP was a tenderness,
it's called tenderness,
tenderness.
So I wrote the song, we did begin
with this, I wrote these songs on,
on the road, uh, during this
tour. I'll make observations,
we're going down again. I was at,
at, uh, at peace with like, uh,
my old bandmates and, and
proud there's really, and um,
I was able to observe and I, and I got
them to thank for it, for that being in,
being in that place and, and
my wife of course, and my,
my kids growing up into
like the strong young women,
I wasn't worrying so much about, ah,
your kid at school and this and that.
And I was just really observing and living
in life, being adults that you saw us.
I was traveling just like my
wife would come with me. Like,
we're tough and we're not worrying
about the kids at Humbard.
Like got this next level and um,
kids are on their own, they're cool. Uh,
we're going to go out and together
and see stuff and, and have some fun.
And, and I was able to go and talk
to just a ton of people. Not only, so
how did you, how did you put together?
Who's who singer? Who on this?
I did. That's your voice?
Yeah. What? Yeah, so I had, I,
I'm saying for a long time,
this is the first time I was saying
it like in a lower register. Um,
but so I wrote the songs. Um, Gotcha.
La showed, I got to see the,
I know I'm going to be, I'm,
I got an acting Gig in New York
this summer. I heard,
are you going to revive?
Told me because my wife had instructed
me to set up something with you guys.
And then the first thing your wife said,
are you guys coming in New York at
all this summer? When do you leave?
Can you say that on there? No, cause
there's too many Weirdos. Yeah. Uh,
we'll talk about later.
As soon as I said that,
I already said I probably shouldn't have
said that I'm going to be in New York,
but it's a, it's a big enough place. New
York state. Uh, yes. Albany. Yeah. I'll,
I'm going to be in a little couple
of John's town of Poughkeepsie.
Uh, Lake Ontario. I'll be up
there. Yeah. At the play her lakes.
Beautiful up there by the way.
Um,
have you ever looked at a
map and just started like,
I, I wish I did that from the beginning
of my career, all the little towns and,
and, and colored in all the
roads that I've been on. A,
I wish I would've done that because I
would think like as much the way musicians
travel and certainly, uh, I mean, I think
that's how I got the sciatic nerve thing.
I think it was all those years of
sitting in a fucking car and this leg not
moving and my knee got fucked up. Just
being in this stationary position. Yeah.
Will, will screw you up. Yeah. Not,
not a stretch or anything like that,
but I always wished, you know, it was
a big thing for me. When I finally did,
I got all 50 states. Wyoming was the
last one and I didn't have a good show.
Oh Wow. I think I weirded
him out. I came out,
I was excited to be there and
they would just, you know,
like the vibe of your, this album
that you have that's sorta like,
you know, uh, that was their vibe.
And I came out more like
whatever you guys close with,
with goods at Paradise City.
I came out on,
I came out with that and they were like,
the fucks with this guy.
And then I was thinking like,
what are these?
Just a bunch of country
hillbillies or whatever.
And then I went to their local club,
the dance club or whatever and slash
watering holes, like all in one area.
And I went there and there was like troops
there. They were gays couples there.
And it was just, yeah, it was like all
total mixed up. And I was just like,
that was that moment. Like, oh, I was the
asshole. I was the, I was thinking like,
what'd you call? Just get off your
fucking ranch. And it's just like, no man,
we came out here to laugh and you fucking
came out with like steam coming out of
your ears. It wasn't a really
bad show, but it was, uh, I, I,
I never stopped in addressed. It
was all I needed to say, like, wait,
can you guys out? You
know, I never did that.
We all prejudged alright. Don't
feel bad about it. All right. Uh,
the, the map, we were talking, oh, so
shooter, um, I wrote these songs. I,
I put them on, all my crappy demos
are on garage band, on my Mac.
Right.
Uh Huh.
And I back him up by sending
them a copy to my manager.
So that's my backup hard
drive. Right. So I have like,
and I might send it to my wife,
so I have like two backup hard
drives of my crappy. Yeah.
Demos.
How was she as far as like when you,
cause I bounce jokes off of
Nia and she's Kinda like,
she's so honest that like I, I kinda
use the risk like, all right, if I,
if I can make her laugh. Cause
she, her dad managed Comedians,
so she grew up around comics.
Is Does your wife like that
with music where she's from
Ohio. So she, she has this very
like, you know, if she's like,
I like that, you know,
that it's like, okay,
that kind of covers like a pretty big
area. She'll be, if she doesn't like,
like my band loaded superhard
my adult poke rock band. Right.
So you'd be like,
Whoa,
she wouldn't say super aggressive.
Ah,
ah, there's so much in
that. Whoa. Yeah. Hey,
I like this next to that guy.
He's a pill to like
just a very small group.
I'm pretty sure just by my wife's
reaction, um, this, this record, however,
like she,
her,
her reaction to these songs and she knew
she was with me experiencing all this
stuff so she knew where
the words are coming from.
She was just finishing her novel
at the time when we were traveling.
So she was writing a lot and,
and um,
my manager when I sit,
I don't think I just want to make that,
that austere record now.
And he said, I think, uh,
I'm going to look for somebody to uh,
to work with. And he said he goes,
what about shooter and shooter?
Jennings is a guy I've known since
he moved here in 2001 he was in a,
he was 21 he was in a band that
opened for my van loaded. Right.
They were called star gun and there,
you know,
like I think you could still to this
deck and it says 10 young musicians.
I can pick out that one
that's going to be a lifer
nine or just kind of like that back. Let's
plan to do that with Comedians, right?
The comic and an open mic can be like,
all right that person I get more be like
as far as potential like I can see like
the,
if that person,
it's just something about they have that
five and I'll meet people after shows
and they won't say I'm a comedian,
they'll just have this five. I'd be like,
are you a comic? It'd be
like, yeah. That's like, yeah,
you seem like you seem like one.
It always makes them stand up a little
bit cause I can see that awkwardness
sorta like looking down kind of that
can't even describe the community young,
the young comedian vibe though.
Dude,
I'm a shit and Dick joke
jackass, but they, they, they,
there's,
there's a social awkwardness,
a unique social awkwardness that a
comedian has gone back to that back bar at
the, at the comedy store that's
just for the or whatever. Yeah.
That's a weird room. Sometimes
that's a, it's a cause. It's a very,
the comedy store has always been a
very transient place where if you,
it was one of those places I
shouldn't, I, I'm not going to say it.
I'll say it because it's just
one of those people pass through.
Sometimes the sinks in your head built,
don't have to come out your mouth. I know.
Yeah,
I know you're right.
But I usually only do like an hour,
an hour and 15 and I just want
to make sure that we say all the
stuff, where can we, where can
we get the album and all that.
We haven't even said that yet.
Oh, I'm just hearing your manager.
Taryn is fucking hair out. Yeah. Work.
Where can they, they can download this.
Uh, yeah. I mean there's vinyl
records come in. Actual vinyl records.
I've got a stereo right over, there
you go. Uh, it comes up May 31st,
it's called tenderness.
It's on universal music. Uh,
they'd been wonderful about my
social action with this thing.
And um, yeah, we start touring
in Philly and on May 30th,
they, before the record comes
out. So hopefully like in
two days after they fill,
it would be like three people.
Like, yeah, what are you doing?
And then the next day. So hopefully
by the time we get to New York,
June 3rd and we're playing at Irving Plaza
there, some people know the song, Oh,
I get it. Um, Chicago, Nashville,
Austin, up up the west coast.
And then, uh, guns is doing some stuff.
That's my main priority. And this is,
this is, this is not an ego project.
This is not anything close to it.
It's
something like this is a legit album.
I love it.
It's the top topics are important.
What my daughters to know, like,
what did you do when,
you know,
and this is my little piece of what I
did when and that's getting active and
talking about stuff openly and, and kind
of like assuring people I beat, you know,
these things you might be worried about,
they're going to pass,
but we gotta be in this together
just like after nine 11, you know,
and just like when America's been great,
you know,
the hurricane two years ago in Houston,
the fires in California,
but come together,
we don't ask who the fuck you vote for
and come together and we help. You know,
and that's the America I choose to see.
And the,
they been acknowledged as opposed to the
crazy shit on t puck that turn it off.
Yes man. Yes. Thought I
did and I don't even know.
It's kind of fun walking around. It's
like a crazy old person. But um, anyways,
I absolutely love the album.
It's called tenderness.
It's on iTunes for a youngsters.
All of those areas where you can get it,
please pay for the album.
And if you don't, cause I
was joking with duff earlier,
I hate when people like they send
you the fucking emails being like,
I downloaded it illegally. Hahaha. But
just want to let you know I enjoyed it.
And it's just like, man, it doesn't
matter what standup up specials anymore.
It gets at this part because I'm not
selling my fucking DVDs. But anyways,
the great duff mckagan has got a
new album out called tenderness,
comes out May 31st he'll be on a Philly,
Philly, DC, Boston, New York,
Chicago, Nashville, Austin, Los Angeles,
San Francisco, Portland, Seattle.
Then you go check them out on the
road and check out his new album.
It's better day.
Leave it all behind you.
Nothing left to say.
It's all been shot through
living
other fool. Look up
Scott's blue.
Never
[inaudible] the truth.
[inaudible] scanning.
Tell soon the Nadis come through.
Never know.
[inaudible]
Hey, what's going on? It's
built burn. It's the Monday
morning podcast for Monday,
May 16th,
2011.
Another beautiful week in the month of
May. Has the nice weather hit you yet?
Go outside Cheryl. It's so
fucking nice out. Oh my God.
I was out there and my fucking
flip flops I had on a wife beater.
My fucking left titty was hanging
out right. And I went down,
I went down to the fucking post office.
I saw Kevin,
I saw mark.
Um,
I am beyond punchdrunk.
I uh,
I'm in the midst of a two week absolute
fucking terror of a travel schedule.
Um,
basically in 15 days I have six flights.
All right. I just pause there. So
all my travelers out there could,
could just go la dude, what the fuck? Yes.
Six flights, six flights. It was
seven, but then something worked out,
worked out where I uh,
stayed an extra day when I was
shooting an episode of Glee.
I really hope you guys like my
episodes ugly glee because a,
I was getting a little self conscious
with some of the shit that they were
sending, making me wear, by the
way. And this is just an acting gig.
This has nothing to do with
me as a comedian. All right,
so I don't want to hear,
dude, you're fucking sold out. Has
nothing to do with my acting. I mean Mike,
my like stand up comedy
that I'm on that show.
All I can say is I'm glad that
I stopped boozing because a,
I'm not going to say I
was wearing a half shirt,
but let's just say my shirt didn't
quite reach my genes. You know, the,
the sizes run a little bit
small over there. But anyways,
anyways,
yeah,
we were shooting out in fucking New Mexico
for this peewee Herman thing that we
were doing, the Mexican hat
dance, little little number there.
Suppose this so fucked right.
So I basically,
last week I went la to New Mexico,
New Mexico to a fucking Washington DC
and then back to lax and like an asshole.
Here's a little travel tip
for all you peoples out there.
For those of you who don't
follow me on Twitter, um,
when you fly into DC,
do yourself a favor.
Fly into Ronald Reagan airport.
Reagan,
that's the one you want to fly into.
Don't fly in to Washington Dulles.
Do not repeat.
Do not fly into Washington Dulles.
I don't give a fuck how much you save.
All right?
It's a fucking $60 cab ride. It's
like, it's, I don't know what to say.
It'd be like if you flying to New York
City and you flew into his slip instead
at five o'clock and hit fucking rush hour,
I forget it every goddamn time
I go to DC every fucking time.
And even as I'm landing, I'm going. Yeah,
it's kind of like a house isn't
only a half hour cab ride. No,
it's like a fucking 50 minute cab ride
and that's with no traffic whatsoever.
So do yourself a favor.
Do that. Fly into Reagan.
You come right in, goddamn buzzed.
The fucking White House, you know,
federal reserves right down
the street and a you land.
You're right fucking there and everything
is all good. But for the love of God,
do not. I repeat, do not go to
Washington, Dallas. It is a motherfucker.
All right.
Flying to Washington Dulles.
If you actually want to go
to Philadelphia, that, that
would be my suggestion.
But other than that, it
was, it's a nightmare.
So this week I got the
second half of that episode.
So this week I fly La to Mexico,
help Albuquerque, New Mexico.
And then I fly to Albuquerque,
New Mexico to New York City.
I do four days of Caroline's comedy club,
and then I fly all the way back across
the country on Monday. All right.
And then guess what?
I'm fucking out in La for a week
and then I'm on vacation vacation.
Just like Axl fucking Foley vacation.
I am on vacation.
I'm getting my fucking Mumford fucking
sweatshirt out and fuck everybody.
I've gone on vacation. All right.
I'm going up to a Goddamn Lake.
Uh, put my little touch,
sees in the fucking water,
hang in there with Nino and my
fucking dog and I'm not doing shit.
I'm going to go on youtube,
learn how to fish cause I grew up in the
goddamn suburbs and even know how to do
that. So feel free to
send me some emails, Dude.
Oh my God. You know the fish. No,
I doubt I don't.
That's like me saying to you will you
didn't know who was an express train.
You fucking moron.
Stay up the middle platform.
Your idiot. It's fucking easy. Right?
Is that a way to teach them my
peaking on my levels here? God dammit.
I swear to God.
In this upcoming year,
I am going to get somebody
to help me with my mixer. Um,
by the way, speaking of which, um, if you
want to send me any emails, all right?
You want some advice for me?
I don't know why you would,
I know why you would because you're not
going to take it, but you like the way I,
I give out advice. You're like, wow,
at least I'm not as dumb as
him and my own fucked up way.
I make you feel better about yourself.
Right?
If you want to send me a list
of underrated, overrated and uh,
Yada, Yada, Yada, all that bullshit,
you go to the men podcast.com and send
all the emails to that fucking thing.
Is that what it is?
We'll all the,
all the shad and all this shit's on
the [inaudible] podcast. My fucking,
yeah.
The gentleman who helps
you with this podcast,
he just must be tearing his fucking hair
out right now. Just like really bill,
how many fucking times have I told you
what the goddamn email is and you don't
even have the decency to get, can you
get it right one week? How about that?
Can you get it right one week? Well,
as I'm looking this up, people,
mmm.
I have a new donation button for those
of you who are new to the podcast. My,
my fucking numbers have been
going through the roof lately,
which is making me feel good. It
makes me feel good about myself. Uh,
I actually have a donation button. All
right. Whatever you want to donate.
If you go to the [inaudible] podcast.com,
it's on the right hand side.
There's a button right underneath the,
the Twitter and the Facebook button. And,
uh,
you just fucking click on that sum
bitch and you make it goddamn donation.
Whatever you want to donate. I don't
give a shit. Actually. I do give a shit.
Give me as much fucking money as you can.
How about that?
MMM.
Oh, you fucking bastard.
Where's this information?
I'm the worst. I really am. The worst.
Why do you guys listen to this shit? Is,
is this, is this the fucking entertaining
part where bill makes you feel smarter?
Huh? That go fuck yourself. Whatever.
Go to the Amen podcast.com I'm
show they have the link there.
See, and I wonder, I
have the balls to wonder.
I have the balls to sit there and watch
TV and be like, why aren't, why aren't,
why aren't I where that guy is?
You know,
because you're disorganized, Bill
and you stutter. Other than that,
you should be taking this
business by fucking storm. Um,
all right, so what are we
going to talk about this week?
Let's talk about my fucking
unbelievable weekend. I, um,
I got to work with Jim Norton Breuer
and Dave Attell at constitution hall.
I told you guys that Eddie Murphy,
speaking of Axel Foley and Mumford
sweatshirts a, he did delirious there.
Chris rock did bring the pain,
only two of the greatest
specials of all fucking time. Um,
I got to perform on that stage,
man. And I, I can't even tell you,
I can't even explain it. It'd be like,
you guys, do you ever do that shit?
You ever get to take a tour of like a
baseball stadium and they let you down on
the field for half a second.
You can't fucking believe you down there.
It was the same thing.
It was just stand up version of that.
As I was doing my set was kind of
looking around the stage and I'm like,
you know, oh right there. That's where
he dropped the microphone when he said,
it's hot up here. And so he
said, take your clothes off.
And he dropped the mic and laughed.
I remember that walking away,
I could barely concentrate on my act.
I had all I could do to not
say goonie Google. Huh? Gus,
your wife is a fucking big
foot. Gus. What a fucked.
And I think to say that
just out of nowhere,
just to see if anybody would've
got it. Um, but anyways,
I had a great time out there in DC.
As always popped into the Improv.
I did a quick little guest spot.
I saw my good friend from back in the day.
Bob fucking Molly.
Yeah.
Beast of a comic that I started
out with. And uh, I had a great,
I had just had a great time out there.
Everybody crushed as always. And a,
we actually went over to the
Pentagon, all four of us. And we, uh,
went in there, we met a wound,
the wounded warriors sick.
The men and women over went over to
Iraq and Afghanistan and got hurt.
We got to talk to them.
We gave him some tickets to come out to
the show and I got to tell you stuff to
meeting those soldiers. You
know, everybody over there,
just the way they look. You
in the eye. Yes sir. No Sir.
All though I don't think I've ever felt
like such a piece of shit as a human
being in my life. I was just like, I
have no discipline. I just, you know,
I don't sit up straight.
These guys just,
they would just kick in my ass straight
across the fucking board. And um,
I really realized what a,
a pathetically insignificant life.
I'm leading.
These people are down there, change
in the goddamn world. All right.
Live in by like codes of honor.
I don't have a code of honor.
You know what's my big thing?
Ah, don't fly in Reagan.
Don't fly in the Dulles
Salute to you America.
You know what a fucking button.
That's what I felt like a fucking bomb.
And I can't even explain those guys.
They all, all those, all those soldiers,
they all got that look in their
eye. You know, it's, it's, I can't,
I can't fucking explain it. They
look at me. They could see it.
Like this guy's soft looking at price
sleeps till 10 in the fucking morning.
Rolling around his bed, bitching,
oh, I go to a podcast. I honestly,
I never felt so fucking
pathetic in my life.
I remember reading rd Lang's book
too fat to fish and he had a caption
underneath when he was on a plane
with a bunch of soldiers. He said,
here's a picture of a bunch of guys
who are better than me. And I was like,
oh Jesus Christ already the fuck.
Now I know what he was talking about.
I'm a fucking loser. Everybody. So
feel better about yourself this week.
Everybody, um, I guess compared
to me. So anyways, yeah,
it was great. Yeah, we went there,
we had a great show and I want to
thank everybody for coming out. And uh,
once again, I went on the road,
every one and I, and I, and I'm, um,
I'm fighting the battle against you,
the bulge.
And I'm not talking about my stomach.
I'm talking about my fucking squash.
All right? That, that's the
big goddamn thing is a guy.
If you want to age gracefully.
All right,
you got to make sure the
poundage of your head,
you got to keep it level member last
week and I was telling you about Ebay
Malmsteen how big his fucking head is now
and he's still trying to get away with
wearing those leather goddamn
pants and his booties.
He looks ridiculous or he looks like,
oh he looks like a hoard up. Ah,
ah.
What the fuck is her name?
That chick big head from that
Shell fish way back in the day. Um,
best podcast sucks. You know
what? Normally I'd abandon it,
but I don't have the fucking time cause
I have to catch 19 flights this week.
So you know what? We're going to plow
through it. I'm going to see it through
like a fucking soldier going to
soldier my way through this one.
Another rock star.
I'm just going to pick on rockstars
and next week I'll pick on it.
You guys can give me some, give me some
actors that you've seen over the years.
Male actors whose heads just
got fucking gigantic val Kilmer.
Val Kilmer didn't do shit.
He just fucking eat.
You know was the last time he had a salad.
You seen that hunk of fucking roast
beef sitting on top of his goddamn head.
It's unbelievable. Here's one for
you, Brian Setzer. Sally saves.
Damn the guy from the stray cats.
I don't know what the fuck happened to
his head and I'll tell you who's halfway
there. Is that Billie Joe Guy from
the fucking green day? You know,
she's got the exact same build. Is that
dude? It's the fuck. It's the worst.
Both of them full heads of hair. I'm
jealous, but none of them. They're not.
They're not having salads.
They're out there on the road day.
They're eating the fucking,
they're eating the potato skins that had
just keeps getting bigger and bigger.
That's why they switch every once they
switched from playing like an SG or a Les
Paul, they go to that big, what
the the s three 30 you know,
I like the sound of the old
Chuck Berry Song. No yet don't.
You got a giant fucking head and now
it looks like you're playing a Ukulele,
so you got to go to a bigger guitar.
I see what you're doing,
Vince Neil,
there's another guy,
I saw them when they went out and they
opened for Aerosmith like five years ago.
I was just sitting there going,
when did his heads get as
big as fucking Nikki Sixx?
Nikki Sixx can have a big head that
guys like fucking six foot four.
You know what I mean?
The fuck am I talking about?
I'm talking about old people
with big heads people.
That's what I'm talking about and I'm
talking about how at some point you gotta
be man enough to eat a fucking salad
every once in awhile. That's the key.
Just once a day, just go out.
Just get a fucking chef salad.
If you've got to throw some Balsamic
vinegarette on it and for Christ's sake,
eat a goddamn salad before you walking
down the street scare and children with
that Goddamn Jacqueline and
sitting on your fucking head.
You know you want to win at paint ball.
You want to stop getting knocked out early
in the game? You eat a fucking salad,
private
Jay Joe's age. Christ. What the fuck
is that on top of your head? Oh Shit.
All right, Gina. Head that fucking bitch.
That right there is why I never joined
the military. There's no fuck away.
I could stand there and get
screamed at like that, you know?
Then they'd slap the shit out of
me. Then I get a concussion. Right.
And I'd be like one of the,
and then of course,
you know they make you come
back too soon in the military.
Forget about and fucking NFL football
over the years you've got to come right
back.
Put that Goddamn baret on [inaudible].
Geez a, where did they find a fucking
Marae for that fucking squash?
Pick it up.
Well, it's at a toilet seat
cover. You think it's funny?
You think it's fun and boy slap me
in the fucking head again backing up.
Okay,
dude, why do you keep knocking it off
my fucking head? If you want me to put,
there's no fucking way. There's no
way. You know, my ego would tell me,
look at this old motherfucker,
you know,
skinny little guy with
his fucking bird chest.
Huh?
You're white chest area.
Do you think you're gonna yell at me and
knocked my little hat off front of all
these fucking people that had just met.
Sorry.
Um, anyways, is
podcast for this week
and uh, you know, it's,
you know what's funny about having
all the fucking free time I do.
I have all these, I only, I
work every other week. People,
I'm one of the laziest mother fuckers
you ever gonna meet in your life? Okay.
I'm sitting here right now.
I'm doing this podcast at four 37 La
time in the afternoon and I'm still in my
pajamas and wearing pajama bottoms.
Yeah.
All right.
For people like me to paint a picture.
And I got my little Tribeca film festival
tee shirt on. That's what I'm doing.
Drinking a little coconut water,
which one of my listeners said that he
actually went out and listened to and uh,
he fell, I forget how he
put it. Something about,
he felt like he was drinking out
of Momar Qaddafi's ass, I believe.
Is that how he, that's how he
described pure coconut water.
I think it tastes delicious.
Hang on a second.
Ah, oh, that's good stuff.
Oh, that's good stuff.
Um, anyways, so despite the fact that
I only work every other goddamn week,
I swear to God,
anytime anything cool is
happening in La and in La, in La.
And I'm like,
I'm going to go to that shit.
I'm going to take a night off from this
fucking business and I'm going to go to
that shit every time.
It's always when I'm out of town and
this week is no different. All right.
Listen to this shit.
I'm down the club the other night,
minding my own fucking business. I want to
go down there, right? I want to go down,
I want to tell some jokes,
blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
And somebody comes up to me and he goes,
dude,
you're not going to believe what they
have at the fucking La sports arena.
I'm Mike. I'm like, what?
What's, what's coming up.
La Sports and me with a fucking
clippers used to play as like, yeah,
evidently they're doing some UFC fight.
I swear to God this isn't a movie.
All right, this is actually
real. You guys into MMA,
you under that type of shit
course. You are right. Who is it?
Who doesn't like to watch
two guys with shaved heads?
Just beat the living shit out
of each other. Um, don't want,
I set one time when I was talking about
that, like the UFC style of fighting.
What I love about it is a, I think
I might've said this on the podcast,
I can't remember.
I'm going to blame it on all the altitude.
My dried out skin from the
fucking pressurized air. But uh,
when I watched those UFC
fights and you see somebody,
you see those guys where they got the
cardio there in ridiculous fucking shape,
they can strike, they can take it down
to the ground, they can submit you,
they can knock you the fuck out.
And that's what I was, you know,
I always look at that
shit and just be like,
that dude right there on
fucking rape bubble, right?
Who's kitten heel that, that's
the big thing. That's why you,
you keep going in martial arts as a man.
Do you want to be on fucking rape bubble?
You know?
And why is that? Because my
generation, when we first got cable,
every other movie that was on cable,
especially Cinemax,
always involved some fucking regular
dude go into prison for a crime he didn't
commit.
And then let people try to fucking,
they strive to try to stick
that Dixon is ash, you know,
then he's got to fight back and blah,
blah blah.
And of course he always fucking
wins except Shawshank redemption,
which is why that was such a great movie,
you know,
is Tim Robbins. You know, sometimes
he won, sometimes he didn't. You know,
Jesus Christ, think about that. You
know the expression, hey, you win some,
you lose some.
Now we're going onto faded.
But uh, yeah, the, all those fucking
movies, you know, always are about that.
So I said that, I said that to somebody
one time a guy yells, fucking guys,
you know what? Those guys out of their
fucking on rape of will they go to prison?
I don't give a shit what you do. You come
out and stand it up. You come at him,
fuck. He try to shoot their legs,
they'll fuck that choke you out.
You'll end up getting raped.
You know,
it's like when the lions go after one of
those fucking one of those buffalo and
they're pouting on and all of a sudden
that thing just whips around and the th
the Goddamn Tiger takes a horn to his
side or the lion does and then the lion
dies and he's like,
wait a minute,
I thought I was killing you and then you
fucking shank me. We got it, Bill. Fuck,
we got to get on with it. So someone
told me the other day, I was saying,
those fucking guys unbreakable
and this dude was like, Nah man.
I like, what do you mean? No? How the
fuck are you going to take that guy out?
And he said, listen. And he goes
inside. If they want to get you,
they're going to get you that Mike.
Like what?
Why the fuck you going to get that guy?
I didn't give a shit.
If you've got three guys, Adam, he's
still, he's gonna fucking knock them out.
Superman punch a fucking knee to the head,
rear naked choke and it's over and the
guy goes, Nah. You know they, they're,
they put stuff in your food. They
drug you that I, I can't even say it.
Just like, uh, it just,
it killed me when somebody said that
they, they put drugs in your food.
It just didn't even seem fates. I
can't even explain it. It was like,
I looked at those guys like they were
fucking superheroes and it's like, really?
Those guys would get fucked too.
That's brutal.
So I had to adjust my worship
and just be like, you know what?
All it's just going to happen.
It only happens at present,
but as long as you don't break the laws
or get fucking blame for some shit you
didn't do, you are unfucking rape bubble.
Jesus Christ. Bill, where's this going?
I'll tell you where it's going.
So that MMA shit,
I've always wanted to go to something
like that, right? So this guy tells me,
he goes, this is what they have. And
not only are they having this MMA
fights down at the La Coliseum,
back with the old, uh,
the La Clippers used to play before
the staples center. I swear to God,
this is the matchup.
It's cops versus cons.
And once again, this is not a movie
starring snake plus plus skin.
This is an actual fucking event.
There have,
haven't police officers fight ex
convicts MMA style in an octagon.
Tell me you're not fucking going to
that if you're anywhere near Los Angeles
cops. Verse fucking cons.
This guy's telling me this
shit out. I'm like, are you,
are you fucking kidding me? I
got to go to this. He's like, oh,
it's fucking a,
it's May 21st of course,
I'm at Caroline's.
So we here at the mm podcasts where like,
you know something that sounds
like some shit that if I can't go,
my listeners would love to fucking go to.
So I'm going to give you the
fucking information on this shit.
It's May 21st La sports
arena. It's cops, verse cons.
Go to cops,
verse cons.com listen in.
It's an all day event to this.
I'm telling you,
I don't know why this isn't
being and put on Hbo it,
they're going to have a bunch
of bunch of music down there.
They got fucking tattoo
artists. I mean, it's just a,
it is a white trash.
This is like the white trash Olympics.
And then you get to fight the cop who
busted you for fucking not paying child
support. The hosts are Danny. Uh,
what did you say?
Danny Trejo did the star of machete
and a tiny lister who played Debo from
Fridays. It just keeps getting better.
So we actually contacted them, said, hey,
you know what? We want to hike this
fucking thing. So he said, fine.
Let them know where we're
at. Go to the, uh, cops,
verse [inaudible] Dot Com there's a bunch
of different tickets, 30 bucks and up.
You can watch cops fight convicts.
I can't believe I'm gonna
fucking miss this. This is,
I'm hoping this is going
to be such a huge, uh,
a huge fucking hit that,
uh,
that I don't fault that they got
to fucking do it again because
I don't know. But so basically the
tickets are 30 bucks on up and if you,
if you buy the hundred dollar tickets so
you can get right down there and listen
to them shit talk or whatever. Uh,
just mentioned the m m podcast,
the P,
and they'll give you a 25 bucks off it.
So all it will cost is,
uh,
just cost you 75 bucks. What the fuck is
this? Did I give out the wrong website?
I am really, I am the fucking worst
if I gave out the wrong websites.
[inaudible] dot com right.
Oh Jj,
hang on a second. Hang on, hang
on. Hang on. Don't do this to me.
Don't do this to me.
Live
on the fucking oh, with cage
first. You can't be caged for our,
it's gotta be cops first. Hang on a
second. This is critical information.
Oh, Jesus Christ. This is one of
the, no, it's cage verse cons.com.
All right, so I fucked it up. Go fuck
yourselves. Cage vars, cons, cage verse,
cause we'll have it all on the MLM
podcast. I am the fucking worst.
Whatever it's,
but it's cops.
It's cops fighting for convicts
that I can't believe I'm gonna Miss.
This shit's really bugging
the shit out of me.
There's gonna be a bunch of
rappers down there, too short.
All these guys and I'm gonna miss it.
You know,
they should've got down there to fucking
hosted in character would have been
fucking snake listing plus kid.
Who's that guy hosted?
I mean, who's the actor who played
that? She's married to Goldie Hawn.
Remember that chick private Benjamin.
She was on laughing.
I remember looking at it going, you
know, she's riding it out. Look at her,
she's riding it out.
She's keeping herself in shape.
She's not going to go out and
get some fucking a bad face lift.
And what did she do? She went out there,
she went out and she got a face lift.
And now the,
the nicest thing
I could say about a face is
it looks animated. You know,
I don't know if this is the right movie
cause I was get these movies wrong,
but she looks like she's in finding Nemo.
Nemo is that he say it.
Nimo I dunno guys. I watch
sports. Okay, go fuck yourself.
Cage versus cons. Please go
down there. Buy The tickets.
You could actually watch it live
if you can't make it for you.
MMA fans around the fucking world.
All right?
They got a pay per view right there on
the fucking website. Cage verse cons.
See a GE, the s c o n. S. All right,
I finally got a fucking right. You can
watch it right on that Goddamn Shit. Okay.
And there's rumor that there
might be an mn podcast. Yeah.
Banner hanging from the fucking raft.
You liked that shit. This is what
I'm going to do on this podcast.
The shit that I advertise, I'm going to
tell fucking stories, make you laugh,
slide in the fucking promo and it's
just going to be shit that I believe in.
I believe in cops fighting cards in the,
the uh,
the octagon. I think that that's
how they should settle it. You know,
on the side of the road when they
do that shit where they, you know,
they show the video from the
state troopers thing, you know,
the state trooper's car and
all of a sudden the, the,
the regular traffic stop turns into a
fucking eight year sentence for assaulting
a police officer there.
There ought to be like some sort of
signal that means not only do I disagree
with you pulling me over, um, I, I want
to fight you in an octagon. You know,
you make some sort of gesture and
then he gives you a police escort.
You follow them right over there
and then you guys go at it,
you fight in the octagon and if you win,
you get no ticket.
You get no ticket.
Hey look who just came walking in.
If it isn't my lovely girlfriend,
how the fuck are you?
What are you talking about?
What am I talking about? I'm
talking about that, that,
that MMA match that I'm going to miss.
Which one? It's called cage for his cons.
It's over at the La sports arena.
I smoked.
No. It's caught one of these
Monday, Monday, Monday. Yeah,
that's exactly what it is.
No, but it's, it's, it's cops,
verse cons. Real cops,
real calls. Oh yeah.
You've got to go away. You've got to go
that real, you know what you sound like.
Cause I'm actually doing advertising.
We sound like we're doing like,
like I'm selling some hunk of shit and
that knife can cut through a cad
knowing chance. No, I swear to God.
Uh, what do they got down there? This,
this is some of the matchups it's like
officers, somebody versus somebody else.
And it's,
this white dudes are not real.
Like they can't be real cops in real cons.
There's no way cause this is la.
They're actors think so. Yeah.
No awkward opposite Gonzalez
versus notorious brick. Slayton
well you know Google, Rick Slayton
is he not? I'm not doing that.
I already did this shit. I already,
I already fuck you want to see it?
You want to see this guy? This guy has
the, the, these a white guy, right?
Shaved head and he's got those classic,
I'm a racist tattoos. Like he's got like,
you know, go fuck yourself. Slash I
love Hitler on the top of his head.
I'll show you this guy. Cage
versus cons cage versus, yeah,
and then it's the exact Sunday, Sunday,
Sunday. Listen to this shit. Here we go.
Saturday May 21st couple of years.
The event of the year versus
10 pro job breaking MMA fights.
I'd be know a sports arena.
Main event versus cod fun performances
by 40 is that go room too short?
Yes. Short. Oh, dog bounds.
St. There's something there.
Fred was actually pretty cool.
You want to get a tattoo
that you're going to regret?
You know a little tramp stamp. Yeah,
they, they have tattoos, stuff going on.
What else? What other shifts at when
is it too? I'm telling you can be,
I'm not going to be here.
No,
that would actually be fun to go and
then we could review it for the Mike.
There you go. We can review it for your
listeners. Know I'm actually sending a
Lawhead and Sam Tripoli down
there. Hopefully am AAA. Yeah,
it was going to be Bart. Nick. I was
going to send my Rosebowl cruel down.
Grew down there. That
was a great idea. It is.
Sure. It is. No offense boys. I love
you. I'm going to start doing, uh,
they're going to start doing remotes
for me at that, some of these,
these things that we're going
to start pumped telling you.
I'm taking this podcast to the next level.
I love it.
So I have my funniest love it drinking
buddies who were also comedians and,
uh, Bart next just started
townies gigging, but I'm
going to have lie ahead and,
uh,
Sam Shipley's going to be the standing
and they're going to go down that they're
going to be drinking and they're going
to be, they're going to be, you know,
hopefully interviewing
some of the, uh, you know,
high Buckeye class people like myself
who it would be going down there.
I can't fucking believe I'm not going to
be in here for this, but, uh, but anyways,
um, Nia, you've stopped by here and
we're, we're gonna, we're gonna,
you're gonna do a little
passing promo here.
What are we going to be doing tonight?
Okay. What am I going to go see with you?
Cause I hadn't been in town
for the last couple of days.
So you guys are probably wondering
how do you keep it going? How do you,
how do you keep them magical, you know,
you know you had to keep the spark.
You fucking annoyed the shit out
of me today. What do you mean?
You know what I mean?
I was talking about earlier when you,
you kept putting off
that vibe that you would,
you were annoyed by my general.
I was not present. Yeah you
were. I was just busy, you know,
I want to say I wanted to get up
and do it on the road for like five,
six days and I'm thinking, oh
she's gonna. I thought you want to,
you want to kiss me?
Like that chick who kissed that dude
and Times Square when the war ended,
that's what I thought was going to happen.
You haven't been gone that long
though. Oh Jesus. It's over. It's over.
No,
I just,
I wanted to get up and go to the farmer's
market and I had to wash my hair.
I had a whole thing. The only time
that you should have been mad at me,
it was the was after I'd already annoyed
you'd like five times and at one point
you were in the shower.
Did you say annoyed me? How
many times? Like five. Okay.
I just want the record to show
that you, that you annoyed. Yeah.
Five times its full course of mourning
that you're supposedly fucking annoying.
I didn't think of this was about me.
I thought it was about, you know,
it's about you being
being a jerk this morning.
This is the only thing I will admit
that was wrong was when you were in the
middle of showering and I came walking
in with the cold cuts and I said,
hey smell this chicken. Does this
smell like it went back in the shower.
I love taking like baths and showers.
It's like my whole relaxation,
like being cleaned, get to the fucking
fancy soaps and I'm in there and you know,
enjoying myself and who fucking barges
in the bathroom opens up the shower,
stall, shower, stall, door thrust,
a package of old ass lunch meat
in my face practically is like,
does this smooth 40,
taking a shower. Okay.
What are you doing? I'm trying to shower.
I have a bad sense of smell. I know,
but you kind of have a really
bad sense of smell. Well,
I'm doing my episode of Glee in a
couple days and I don't want to get uh,
some Nella. I don't want to get
fucking a, yeah, well if you
see right here so he could really
tie, came out of the shower, whatever.
We're going to see bridesmaids tonight.
This is how,
and Kristen Wiig and Maya Rudolph,
this is how long I've been out
of town that I actually agreed.
She goes, do you want to see bridesmaid
tonight? Now of course my brain was like,
no, it's produced by Judd Apatow.
Okay. So nick is any of that.
He's never in it. He's the
director. All right. Well,
he didn't direct the movie
produced. All right, well,
any of those other guys in it,
I don't know.
That's Rogan and fucking
Paul Rudd and those guys.
It's just going to be a bunch of broad,
it's just like slap stick.
My Big Fat Greek wedding.
Is this what it's going to be?
Put it like this Judd
Apatow produced this movie.
So whatever you think that it's going
to be thinking about the fact that he
produced it. I think the idea. All right.
You take a sippy, a big, uh,
a big mug full of wine too.
You got a big mug full of something.
Have you had some questions from a no.
You want, you want it? You want to, do
you want to do what advice one? Yes, I do.
Okay, we'll do it. Advice one
and then, uh, then that'll be a,
that'll be the little Nini segment
here for the fucking week. Um,
let me see if I got one that actually
involves men and women, men and women.
Like I'm not going to see enough fucking
broad center and the goddamn movie.
If there's, if there's one period
joke, I'm walking out, I'm walking out,
does this make me look fat? If somebody
cries for no fucking reason and goes,
oh my God, I love your guys, you
know, that's happening in act three,
I'm walking out, all right, I'm letting
you know I'm getting up and I'm walking.
I'm storming out and you won't even hear
me drive away cause we have a hybrid of
the Saturday night live people
a hem. Him, I am supporting.
You think they want to do that fucking
movie? They need the money. Uh,
I haven't seen it. So actually somebody
told me it was fucking hilarious.
All right, where am I hair? Uh, but,
but papa, Papa. All right here. Go.
All right,
Bill.
One of my best friends has been going to
church for years and previously it has
never bothered me at all.
Low Gg. Um, I grew up,
I grew up Catholic and like
so many Catholics I got raped.
No kidding. I no longer,
I no longer attend church,
but it doesn't bother me in the least.
If someone else wants to go,
this guy is the exact mindset than I am
except by make fun of people who go to
church a little bit, a
little bit. A few months ago,
my friends started asking me if I would
like to go to church with him gay. Uh,
I plight. I politely declared that sets
a gay thing to do and I don't mean,
I don't mean the how is it gay to ask
the want to go to church with you because
you're both going to be wearing sweaters.
You're going to be singing songs.
You are the
[inaudible] au Lait Lou
[inaudible].
You don't get to sit there and sing with
you have your fucking friend wearing a
sweater and then the priest up there, God
knows what he did, is going to be like,
hey, add a beard and some
long, Aaron, he cured a leper.
None of you guys can do that.
So you better give us some money.
[inaudible]
yeah, who are not making fun of mass
right now. It's not great to you.
It's nothing. Yes. Granted there are
some things that I've seen. Like what?
Not None of that horse shit,
that overly Boob, ugly,
ugly, ugly to him. Well, it's like a
call and response. I'll tell you what,
I'll tell you what fucking sacred.
Meaning the request of question.
Now you're getting the answer today.
I'll tell you what sacred.
What's sacred is how you go out in the
playoffs. The Celtics went out with heart.
We still lost their fucking, we still got
our ass. We still got our asses kicked.
We still got our asses kicked. All right?
But there was no quit in that team.
All right? Okay. That's
fucking sacred. What?
Sac religious is what
the fucking Lakers did.
And I'm at disrespect in the franchise.
I'm saying what? The couple of those?
And it wasn't all of them. What a,
it was really what buying them did.
I don't even think about
autumn did was bad. All right?
Can you just finish reading the
question? Jesus Christ. Really,
all of a sudden you're dictating it.
You asked me why.
So he wants to go to church
with me. With him. I repeat gay.
I politely decline. Dude,
I'm not doing that shit. Um,
so filling in the blanks with
your own commentary or no,
that's not a part of the letter because
you're presenting and then a bias
fashion.
Just read it and then give your opinion.
You see the shit that is
a classic fucking broad.
It's like I've been doing this shit for
four years and you're telling me how to
run it yet you have no idea how many
more on guys are going to send him hate
mail because of that, because not because
you're a jerk. Because some other, well,
there are more options.
So I don't give a chaise.
This is fucking elitist attitude.
Um,
since then my friend has told me he feels
it's his mission to spread the word of
God.
Saying it like that
and continues to ask me to go. They
got up, he drank the fucking Koolaid.
Now he's a Zombie and as time passes,
he's getting more aggressive
with this sales pitch.
That means he's probably reaching
out and like touching his hand. Uh,
what started off with him just slipping
it into casual conversation as loud now
led me to receiving text
messages that say the following,
this means more to you.
This means more to me than you know,
God has poured out love to me and he is
reaching out to you also ignore a few
months, but there is a lot
at stake here. Wow. Yeah. No,
he has a little one. Yeah.
He's buying into that.
Jesus is coming back and this
time he's not fucking around.
It's personnel. Yeah, he, okay,
so he's buying into the rapture that
this hippie is going to come back on a
stegosaurus and just start killing
people, killing people. What they say,
what they say is fucking wrong.
He's going to come back RAF.
One of the deadly sins,
judge's judgment is mind set at the Lord.
He's the son.
He's the Donald Trump.
He's got the fuck he's got to call them
over at this point, coming out of heaven.
He didn't make that money.
He didn't make the fucking world.
He's just allowed Jack ass a
fucking fuck. You know, whatever.
Cast me into the the fucking pits.
I don't give a shit. You know,
you think I want to hang out with
you in heaven forever. Just go it.
Isn't this awesome? Yeah, it is awesome.
Can you please finish the
letter? All right. What started
off. Okay, so here we go.
Uh, to be to this. I replied,
honestly, it's it, if it's my choice,
I don't want to go,
please stop asking me about it.
I don't know how many more ways I
can request that. There you go. Okay.
He responded with, I'll
hold off, but know this,
God loves you and will not quit.
If I do.
Okay, well then there's no
reason to hit me two times.
Let's just let God do it. All right.
Anyways, here comes my question. Bill,
why does this fucking Piss me off so much?
Why do these,
why are these cults do? Uh, what
do these cults do to these people?
He's involved with the Church that people
do joke around with and call a cult.
What would you do if you
were me at this point?
I don't even want to talk to this guy
cause he's conversations are infuriating
me. Um, yeah, I would, I would cut
this guy out of your life. Yeah,
it's annoying. This is what I feel
that way. No, but this is his friend.
This is his friend, his
friend and he, and he won.
He wants to get them out of the cult.
So the thing is is if you go to him
and you try to get them out of it,
you just going to drive
them further into it.
So what you do is just say he just
stopped being friends with them, you know,
and hope that that'll help because they're
not going to go out of that then he's
not going to leave it if you ask them to
leave it. Yeah. You never, you never know.
But yeah, he needs to just kind of
mouth cause yeah, there's no, you can't,
unless he wants to spend the rest of his
time with this guy debating Catholicism
or whatever, which I'm sure he
doesn't want to do. And then yeah,
he should just cut them off. Personally,
I would still hang out with them.
You would just so you could
get into debates with him? No.
And I would just do unbelievably Shay
titanic and it can be a bit annoying shit.
I've good idea. I would, I
would, maybe you should do that.
I would always have like shout
at the devil playing, you know,
or maybe just that beginning cheesy thing.
She didn't invite you to call my women
to a restaurant and it turns out to be
like a strip club and see what he does.
Yeah,
but you're going to see the titties on
the outside gentleman's club. That's true.
No, I wouldn't do that shit. I would just,
I would hang out with
him and hang out with,
I would keep saying I want to get involved
in the church and I would keep going
to events and I say we're going,
you know,
I just feel so filled up with God's love.
I would then be a,
you want to talk about filled up.
I would fucking jerked off into this
chick's mouth less. I'm telling you,
William Burns,
she had a big bass miles and I don't know,
maybe it was a couple of days since
the last time I fucking, you know,
let them loose. But I right up to the
brim. She was a champion. She swallow.
I'm sorry, what were you saying?
This is why you're going now.
Oh, why don't you pray for me? I will.
These fucking people, these people. Yeah.
All, all those, all those things
are like, uh, they're just there.
I don't know. It's, it's, it's a
cult. It's a fucking cult. I mean,
if it works for you, you know, I think
they just like wearing those old clothes.
You know?
It must be nice to drive a bicycle.
Talls banging against the fucking seat.
When you were growing up, did you never,
I was an altar boy. I was an altar
girl. Yep. I was an altar boy. Yeah.
That's the name of Mike. My mind,
my new book. Second Schuster.
I was an altar board. Yeah. And,
uh, I remember I used to do,
I'd sit there and I would
ring the bells. Yup. You know,
I have to do the incense where you have
to take that ball that's on a string.
It looks like one of those
medieval torture devices,
you know? And it's so, yeah.
I wish I, you know what it was I did
that chick, I was so bored in mass,
you know, I wanted to be involved.
I wanted to get up on stage.
I wanted to say something.
That's engine. Hallway. Yeah.
Potentially fucking an altar
boy. Yeah. I have one priest.
He used to do the fucking homily.
Then he would ask,
he would give us a lecture about
some shit about the, the uh, uh,
I used to craniums or whatever the
Crista cranium, the woo do these,
you know,
these fucking people from a long time ago
and he'd be giving you this speech and
going out, God, he's going to ask me
questions on this. And he would be like,
he would just be doing the homily.
Then we,
he be doing the homily and he just be
like, and ms to what is it blow you?
Just start quizzing you on them.
Fucking crowd would be laughing when
I fucked up the jokes and I look,
I'm not the jokes that the
questions and I loved it.
Beat the shit out of sitting there,
standing, kneeling, doing all that.
And, um, and I really bought
into it when I was younger.
I really bought into and I thought it
was good at that it was the right fucking
thing to do.
And uh,
then I got older and I started reading
and I traveled and I realized this is
just a bunch of bullshit at a,
I read into the history of the
church and I was like, wow,
these guys aren't exactly what
they say that they are, you know,
it's kind of like a lot like Taco
bell who doesn't like Taco Bell.
Then I do my little shoot out
there in New Mexico and uh,
there was some big strike they had out
there because they're not paying any of
those fucking workers that
pick the goddamn tomatoes
that go into it. Okay. Okay.
Did you go to a Catholic school?
When did this become inside bill studio?
Did I go to Catholic Schools?
Had this whole thing
is inside bill studio.
I didn't know you run a Yap
for like 90 minutes. No,
I just went off on like a monologue for
five minutes. You just go and go and go.
Um, no, I was asking cause
I went to Catholic school.
So yeah, it's a whole thing.
It's too complicated again too, but
yeah. So what was that? That's it.
That's it. That's why you stopped the
whole point. You know, what is the,
you just like talking into a microphone.
That's what it is. Fun. Okay,
well listen, I have to get on with the
podcast here. Are you kicking me out?
I'm not kicking you out.
I'm asking you politely to leave so I
can go back to running my yet finished
dinner. Anyway. Good. Thank
you very much everybody.
Thank you for coming by.
That segment was brought
to you by my bowls.
All right. Uh, all right, so I read that
one. Here's another one. All right, Bill,
just to give you some background.
I'm a 36 year old
Asian woman. I read this one last week
with the fuck is wrong with me. Um,
I wanted her to send me a picture.
I no,
anyways,
built a first thank you for the labs
on your weekly podcasts. Beep adopted.
Dupo um, all right, I want to cut.
I want to comment on your drinking.
By the way, today marks the
seventh month. I have not boost.
You understand what that means? I am
closer to a year that I am to not a year.
All right. That was for those of you
out there are not good at math. Do you?
Don't realize that there's 12
months in a fucking year and a,
Ugh,
I don't know when it's gonna happen
that when it does,
when I was in the Pentagon,
I was thinking about drinking because
I went to the gift shop. Yeah,
they do have a gift shop at the Pentagon.
And you know what else was awesome?
No one there seemed to know
how many floors there were.
They said there's rumored to be
like another five below the ground,
but nobody really knows. You
know? I'm sure. I'm sure the, uh,
one of the big generals were there.
I'm sure he knows I,
and what happens when you get all
the way down to the bottom layer?
Like who the fuck is down there? You
know, but it's a bunch of bankers.
I bet there's like an underground subway
from the Fed reserve right over to that
lower level of the Pentagon
is a little office in there.
And uh, that's where the people
from the Federal Reserve Go, uh,
when they want to yell at the president
and the president comes over on his
little private subway because
it's also close together. Right.
He comes over and then he sits outside
their office. I'll fucking nervous,
like wringing his hands going, Oh God,
did I, did I not say it right? Um, anyway,
so let's plow ahead here.
Bill,
I want to comment on your drinking and
if anyone could stick with any kind of
schedule. Oh, when I asked if anyone
could stick to any sort of schedule,
because I've been thinking about going
back to drinking and just like one day
every month,
just getting absolutely hammered.
Having October fest every
month is basically what I'm
thinking about. Oh, I know.
I actually, I forgot. So it was,
I'm in the gift shop at the
Pentagon and they had these,
these drinking glasses and they had this
giant one that had the marine corps, um,
shield or insignia, family, crest,
whatever the fuck you call it.
And the second I saw it,
I was like,
I want to fill that up with some beer and
have like nine of those. Um, so anyways,
uh, I asked if it was possible to do
something like that. The Guy said,
I just turned 25 and I've
never had a sip of alcohol,
smoke cigarettes or taking any kind of
illegal drug, never, not even by accident.
And it's been Ben by choice and
nothing religion affiliated.
My friends slash coworkers
also poke fun of me for not,
I'm often saying that they'd be able to
get me to drink at least one. In general,
everyone has the same reaction.
Jesus Christ hardy, unwind,
you must be boring, et
cetera. Well, anyways,
I guess that what I'm saying is it
is possible to not drink with all the
opportunities out there that are in the
world and the stress of life in general.
It can be possible to get it to get at
least to at least get it down to drinking
only one day a week.
Um,
congrats on your streak and if not
drinking and thanks for the last. Um,
well that's different
because you've never drank.
I wanted to hear from a drinker.
See,
the thing about you is you've
never opened Pandora's box.
And I've said this before, but
it's, it's, it's very easy for me,
for me not to do heroin every day because
I never did it. So I don't know what,
I don't know what I'm missing.
You know,
I've never gone to Vegas and just actually
called one of those whores and hadn't
come to my room. So when I go out
there, I never think to do it.
And then I don't feel like I'm
missing anything. But the thing is,
is when you do shit like that, when you've
done it, when you've lived that life,
that's when it's fucking hard.
The other night I was
driving home from the fucking
fuck was I coming from the comedy store
and I was just sick of being sober.
I was just driving going,
I want to get fucked up. I
just want to do it. This is,
this is a,
this is getting ridiculous.
I'm s I'm actually sick of thinking
clearly I can't explain it.
It has to do with that shit though,
because I know how fun it is to get drunk,
you know?
And I haven't had any embarrassing
things happen in seven fucking months,
so I forget how stupid it is, but, um,
God dammit.
Okay.
The only reason why I'm not drinking
is because if I don't drink,
and then I try to beat this streak,
I got to start all over again and go
seven fucking months. Oh, Jesus Christ.
What the fuck am I talking about? I
don't even go. I don't even know. Um,
let's move along. Let's, let's go with
underrated overrated for this week.
Everybody, uh, bill
new fan of the podcast,
I'm going to skip all the ass kicking ass,
kissing a,
I've noticed you do a lot
of overrated, underrated. So
here's mine. Overrated bars.
Speak of the devil bars.
They just turned 21 and I'm
starting to check out the bar scene.
What a fucking joke.
A bunch of drunk tool bags and
filthy Ho was as you would say,
what happened to sit around
drinking with your friends.
I'd rather have a beer with some close
friends and go out to a crowded bar
filled with people.
I want nothing to do with spending all
my money on watered down drinks. Anyways.
Keep doing what you're doing. You're
the man. Thank you. Um, all right.
Did you go out to the bars?
If you want to try to get laid,
that's basically the only reason why
to go out and do it. Other than that,
you're absolutely right.
If you're of legal drinking age,
just buy some booze and go home.
Go to a house party,
watch a game with your friends, cook
out, have a great fucking time. Uh,
play the music at the level
you want to play it at.
But the reason you go out to
the bars is because of the,
who is this because of the lady?
That's why you go out to them.
Plus they have a larger selection of the
booze. But a dude, you're only 21. I mean,
I don't know,
maybe a really mature,
you'd be one of those people is like
married by 23 and has a kid, you know,
when a fucking wheel barrel. Do you
know I finally learned how to say that,
that it was wheel barrel,
like roll out the barrel.
It's Barrow and I don't even know why,
but that's what the fuck it is. Um,
I'll give you an underrated for
this week. I'm underrated. Would be,
uh, the kinks. I just downloaded
some of their music, their,
their fucking ridiculously underrated.
Um, I know that they get credit,
they sort of get like half credit.
They kind of get lost in the wash
between the Beatles and led Zeppelin.
And I don't know why. I don't know
why. Because as far as I can tell,
those guys can, right. Yeah. Any
type of song you want, great lyrics.
They can write about heavy shit.
They can write about light
shit that could fucking rock.
They can actually do a ballad that is in
fucking cheesy, actually downloaded, uh,
give the people what they want. I bought
that on on vinyl when it first came out.
And you know what,
it still holds up still fucking holds up
to me and with my guitar playing skills
that can figure out some of
the songs. Um, all right,
we're getting to the end
of the podcast here. Um,
what was the last fucking thing I wanted
to tell you guys? Oh, wait a minute.
I've got two big topics
to talk about. One, uh,
Bruins verse Tampa Bay lately.
Um, how the series went,
the first game we lost three
to fucking or whatever,
wasn't three to one of those like emptying
it bullshit at the end of the game.
But like, that's exactly what I
was afraid of. And I, you know,
sometimes I'm so sick of these fucking
non hockey towns having great hockey
teams, you know, it's a fucking waste
to get it off.
It's a fucking wait.
It's like Kevin a boat and you
live in the middle of Nebraska.
There's no reason to have a fucking
hockey team or then amazing hockey team.
They're fucking great team in easily
the best team we've played and come up
against so far.
They're just a great fucker team and I
easily think that those guys could win
the Stanley Cup. Our guys on the other
hand, I don't know, I think we got a shot,
but like Tampa Bay, I think Tampa,
I, if I had to put my money on it,
I picked her up a bay because
Vancouver and San Jose,
they're too fucking and
consistent. They'll play like
lights out fucking hockey,
three games in a row and
then just fucking, hey man,
let's make it interesting and they'll
lose like the next fucking two,
three in a row. I don't believe in those,
those teams, she can't fucking do that.
Eventually that kind of play in is
going to bite in the ass and considering
they're going to knock each other out.
Um,
everybody thinks the champions coming
from the West. I got news for you.
It's coming from the
east and I swear to God,
if Tampa Bay wins second fucking Stanley
Cup during the time of this Bruins
drought,
that white trash piece of
shit city that nobody goes to,
you know,
it's like one level above Jacksonville.
More people go to Orlando, then
go to Tampa, people go to Miami,
they go to Fort Lauderdale,
bunch of fucking rednecks go out today.
Toner for the Daytona 500 we start with
the fucking super bowl. Super Bowl,
Nascar driving baby, right?
Nobody goes to Tampa.
Mm.
I was, you know what I was
doing yesterday? I was,
I was tweeting twittering during the
fucking game and all I was doing was just
shitting on Tampa,
just shitting on the city trying to annoy
people and of course people are taking
it seriously, which makes
it fun. And I said Tampa,
that's the type of city you go to when
you like abandoned your family. You know,
we just got divorced. Just
the, there was, you know what?
There was a life altering moment in your
life where you just got kicked so hard
in the balls.
You've just decided to say fuck it.
That's when you moved to a city
like Tampa. If you've quit,
that's what Tampa's for
Tampa is for quitters and all
you people down there with
the a new lightning fucking
jerseys or even worse,
the free fucking tee shirt that you
got from the local radio station.
All right.
No wonder you finally fill in the arena.
You finally want to see what a winner
looks like. Isn't that what it is?
They're all those fucking years of losing.
Yeah.
The Tampa Bay Buccaneers.
Bunch of fucking losers.
The fucking devil rays.
Huh?
Devil rays just like your
lives. Tampa, Tampa Bay.
Odians just like your fucking lies. Oh
I think it's going to add. No, it is it.
Yeah. I had to put three balls through
the hoop to when the teddy bear, you lose
Virginia's for lovers.
Tampa is for losers.
There's no fucking way done. The hockey
gods are going to allow this to happen
even though you have way
more firepower than us.
You've got a great goaltender and you
play in your one three one that you didn't
even show us in the first fucking game.
Go Fuck Yourself.
Do you know the Strip mall
was invented in Tampa?
It was,
cause they were too fucking stupid to
know how to enclose a mall. You know,
they'd start to build an enclosed
mall and then you know what they do,
they fucking quit. Then they would just
left with this weird looking structure.
You know, like what kind of,
well it's sort of a mall,
what should we call it? Well,
in tribute to all the whores that live
here in Tampa, we'll call it a strip mall.
You know,
the,
all these fucking cracked out whores
walking around half of fake tits hanging
out some fucking eight year old kid
still breastfeeding on it. You know,
I know you guys think I'm being harsh,
but this is the shit you see down in
Tampa. They don't deserve the lightning.
I think that's when,
you know,
your city sucks is when one of
your teams is named after. Whether,
you know,
I really should say it because the thunder
just fucking advanced to the western
conference finals.
Huh?
Look who's watching Hoop Nika watch
hoop because the Lakers are out of it.
I love it. I fucking
love it. Truly enjoy it.
Truly fucking and enjoy that.
So anyways,
I flew virgin airlines in
the way back from Washington,
Dallas, everybody. And uh,
like a smart son of a bitch.
I got there like two hours early and I
show up in computers are down and this is
fucking gigantic fucking line and it was
an absolute nightmare trying to check
in for the flight.
And it was so bad when I got to the gate,
the captain was actually helping people
get seating assignments and at one point,
you know what he said? He
goes, well, you know, he goes,
this is how it was before
computers and nobody
blinked. And I, when he said that
this is not the way it
was before computers,
this is how it is now because
of computers. You fucking moron.
Jesus Christ. We used to go to
the airport, he just walked up.
You walked up to the stern line,
but you fucking walked up
and you just, you gave,
you gave me information,
he had your fucking ticket
and you went through,
didn't take two hours and then another
hour at the gate to get your seating a
salmon.
You fucking idiot.
I lost all confidence in that guide is
ability to fly a fucking airplane at that
point. And then I got on there, right?
Virgin Airlines is where they've got
like this, this club lighting, you know,
like this Jersey shore sort of
look on the plane, you know, like,
like there's going to become
stains on the seats or something,
but it was actually a very enjoyable
flight and they have new airplanes and uh,
I highly recommend that airline and the
guy gave nice, smooth fucking landing.
They had all kinds of video games
and movies and all that type of shit.
And you know what?
I realize,
I don't think I've said anything
funny in like fucking 20 minutes.
What happened to this podcast?
Everything was going great. Do it.
I'll tell you what it is. You not boozy
and drinking fucking coconut water, dude.
That's what it is.
Huh?
What are you going to do next to have
a jank cucumber and fucking swallow it
whole you fucking queer.
Um, all right. Is that it?
Is that it for the
podcast to my fucking dog.
Smells like a fucking dog.
I just gave it a Goddamn Beth. I don't
know what's going on. You know what it is.
I've been hiking a lot
lately and you know I have,
I lost enough edge for you. I
don't booze. I drink coconut water.
I'm recommending eating salads and I
go hiking every day and I have a beard.
Okay,
that's just write down the
checklist of complete fucking pussy.
What's The matter you Colin?
Doggin
oh cause cause it's all windy out.
Yeah.
We have a vicious pit bull that's
afraid of the wind. Cleo, C'mon in here.
Look a walking with their head down
low. Oh my God. What's going to happen?
Cleo? Come here. She's truly freaked out.
Look at her tail between her legs.
Clear?
Yeah. Okay. Now I can't
pet you in this moment.
This is something I learned from the
dog trainer. If I pet you right now,
when you're all freaked out, you're
being rewarded for being freaked out.
Jesus Christ. Look at the fucking thighs
on you. You've been hiking with me, Huh?
All right. You know what? Fuck this
podcast. This is the end of the podcast.
Everybody. My predictions, my predictions.
I like a, all right, we're going to,
we're going to go with my heart first bro.
And slot at the fucking
Tampa Bay lightning.
All right, we're going to win that in. Uh,
my fucking dog is standing
there shaking right now. I'm
clear. What are you doing?
All right. Fuck it. Alright.
The Bruins are gonna win in. Um, I
actually, for some reason I think,
I think six games, the Bruins are going
to win. This is my heart talking. Uh,
my brain says Tampa and seven.
Let's go across the fucking lake here.
I like, uh, all right. This is the deal.
What's weird in the sports world right
now is San Jose in Dallas and the Dallas
Mavericks are both not choking.
There's no fucking way.
Both of them are going to
win a championship this year.
One of them is going down
and I don't think it's going to be San
Jose. I say San Jose Beats Vancouver.
I think they finally fucking
pushed through this year.
Joe Thornton is finally acting like
a captain. I think it's gonna happen.
Both teams are very streaky. Roberta
Lovango. I don't know if he gets the Yips,
they're going to be in trouble.
I'm taking San Jose and the fucking
West San Jose in the fucking West is
probably going to be Tampa,
San and San Jose.
I hate to fucking say it in the Goddamn
finals. The Bruins make it to the finals.
We're going to win it. Ah. It gives a
shit bill. No one gives a fuck about you,
God damn predictions. Yeah. Will I
do? I do. He don't do I give a five.
I give a fuck up enough about you
that you're driving to work right now.
This is an hour in. You're almost at work,
aren't you? Thanks to me. You laughed.
You giggled. You had a good fucking
time. You spilled your coffee.
You dropped something in between the seat
and the console. You reach down for it.
You stop short.
You broke the bridge of your nose and
you're still sitting there laughing. Cleo,
you have to fucking relax. All right.
You're freaking me out. Clear. Hey,
not Jesus Christ, that dog.
I swear to God. Yeah, you,
you're retarded. All right.
Basketball real quick. Um,
as much as I love Oklahoma,
I got to go. Dallas.
Dallas is going to make the finals and uh,
all right,
Tampa is going to win the cup
and I hate to fucking say it.
No Mavericks will when
I get a bad feeling,
the heat is going to go to the finals.
I'm rooting for Chicago.
I Love Dallas and I love Oklahoma.
I got to go with Oklahoma cause fucking a,
I love Durant and I also
like a Kendrick Perkins
and uh, yeah. And that's it.
And that's the podcast and the whole
fucking thing just whittled down to a
goddamn halt. All right.
What are we going to do here?
How could I hit my dates and then we're
going to get the fuck out of here. Huh?
What'd you guys like to hear that?
If you shut this fucking thing off yet,
God knows I would have. Um,
here we go. Cage verse cons.
Everybody check out that fight.
And uh,
what do I got coming up this weekend? I
am at Caroline's comedy club. Everybody.
How about we go out with a little bit
of music and as I whore myself out,
like those fucking broad down
there at a in Tampa. All right,
here we go. We're going to, we're
going to read some dates here.
[inaudible] Bill Burke, check me
out of Caroline's comedy club.
May 19 May 20th May 21st
and make 20 seconds.
I'll be hanging out afterwards. Where
in sparklers shooting out of my titties.
I will be selling my new DVD.
Let it go.
I will sign your titties.
I will grab your wife's ass if you like.
I don't give a fuck. I got two
shows for Thursday, two shows.
Friday,
two shows Saturday and one show on Sunday.
That's how it's going down and after that
I got, I got one more antisocial
tour in June on the shit.
That doesn't mean the tour is over.
I just have one ship one day. Yap.
I'm going to be at the Chicago
theater anti social network.
Go to Wa antisocial comedy,
Dicom June 50 2011 it's just part
of the Chicago comedy festival.
We will be showing our
hitch short film sheet.
Oh yeah,
I'm going to be out there.
I'm going to lie to people and tell them
that I directed it and say that job Joe
to Rosa was difficult to work with and
that Bobby Kelly bought a hairpiece.
That's what I'm going to say.
Oh, very special. Very special.
Let me bring the music down.
Let me bring them music down here.
The final date on the, on
the, uh, on my June schedule,
I'm going to be doing a, the
Greg Geraldo benefit, uh,
rest in peace. Greg Geraldo, one
of the great comics I ever saw. Um,
you know,
he's got a wife and he's got kids and
we're going to raise some money for them
and it's going to be an UN
fucking believable lineup.
A testament of how much
we all love Greg. And, uh,
and what a great comedian,
what a great comedian he was.
And it's going to be June 29th
at the Wiltern theater. Uh,
that's on a with a fuck is that?
It's down on Wilshire and a corner
of Wilshire and Western in, um,
Los Angeles. So please come
out to that. All proceeds,
obviously going to his
wife and his kids and uh,
it's going to be a great thing
and I'm just come on down.
That's the podcast for this
week. I thought, I hope you
guys all had a good time.
I all, my dog stops shaking. She's sitting
here panting, freaking the fuck out.
So you guys probably wondered what do
you do with the dog right now when your
dog gets like that, don't pet it
cause you're rewarding it going. Yeah,
I want you to be freaking out.
You don't want to do that.
When I'm going to do is I'm going to get
up off my age and I'm going to take it
for a walk and just get that energy out
of her and then I'm going to bring a
fucking back in and act like nothing
happened when she's chilling out.
I'm going to spoon with my
dog for the rest of the night.
This stinky Goddamn pit bull that she
is. All right, that's the podcast.
God bless all of you. Thank you
for listening. Uh, if you're in La,
please for the love of God,
cause I want to know what it's like.
I want to hear your feedback.
Go to a cage first,
cons.com you gotta go down there.
Get yourself some fried dough.
Get a tattoo while you listen to too
short snoop Dogg and all these other
motherfuckers who are going to be down
there and then go in there and watch some
MMA.
MMA fights in the,
the headline fight is going
to be a real police officer.
First surreal ex-con.
It's going to be fucking awesome.
I can't believe I'm going to miss it.
And thanks to Jason Law had from
men are talking podcast and a,
I believe Sam Tripoli. They're going to
be down there. They're going to cover it,
cover it all for the mm podcasts that
said, you guys go fuck yourselves.
Have a great week.
I'll talk to you next month.
[inaudible]
[inaudible].