Hey, what's going on it's Bill Burr.
It's time for the Thursday afternoon,
just before Friday,
Monday morning podcast and
ahhh
just checking in on you see
now your week's going. I
know your week's going great.
And Philly right now.
She not a sports fan then you probably
all upset that everybody's all excited
running around tearing up
the street sides, you know
eaten horse shit. I felt bad for that
Philly fan that had to eat horse shit.
You know what I mean? It's just all
the shit that their fans have gotten,
you know,
attention for like the bar has just been
set so high that this poor bastard that
was due, he was like
out of ideas, you know,
you know where it is as far
as bad behavior, you know,
or Philly fans are right now.
It's kind of like,
remember when they did the dunking contest
every year in the all star game and
at first it was amazing.
You know,
somebody just like takes off in the
file and it's like, Holy Shit. You know,
the next thing you know,
you've got to have like some fucking
quivering fucking woman standing there and
you've got to jump and your balls have
to just scrape the top of her fucking
head while you covered your
eyes like Dee Brown. You know,
that's Kinda like where eagles
fans had flyers to fans.
All Philly fans are as far as like,
how the fuck are we going to get on
ESPN this time? What are we going to do?
Throw up on a kid. I already did
that. What are we going to do?
Punch an old lady in the content.
We've been doing that since the 70s.
What does fall, my God, there's
a pile of horse shit, uh,
turned on yet.
Fucking video camera.
That didn't even make sense.
I'm not going to put that on Eagle stance.
I'm not going to put that on Philly.
I'm in debt is an individual act.
That guy wanted to do that
shit for the longest time.
He just needed an excuse.
You know what I mean?
Flick. All of us, most of us have
never eaten another human being. Right.
But put in the right situation,
you'd fucking do it. Right.
What was that movie alive plane
crashes in the rocky mountains.
You know, they're right next
to aspen, but they're all rich,
so they're not going to help out.
They wouldn't give him a sandwich.
And next thing you know,
they're eating each other.
There's this have to do with eating or
why the fuck did this have to do with
Eaton Horse Shit? I was trying to think
where they actually landed. When was it?
They didn't land.
They crashed.
I would actually be upset if I survived
that. You know, like you're like,
Oh fuck, I'm gonna die. Right.
And then you fucking survive me on top
of that mountain freeze and you fucking
ass off then you wished you did.
Um,
anyways. Anyways, um,
I actually was finally able to look at
some of the highlights because I really
wanted to see eagles fan celebrating.
I just couldn't handle it cause
they beat my team. And, um,
I believe I said,
you know,
on the podcast and towards the end of
December that if the Patriots get bounced
out of the playoffs, I was going
to root for the fucking eagles.
Just cause you know, they
had one, one, like I said,
I really don't have
anything I wanted to say.
I forgot to say that on Conan because
so many people fucking reached out,
you know,
Twitter and all of this crap because of
my Philly rent thinking I really didn't
want the eagles to ever win one. And all
of this, it's just I got booed in Philly.
I made fun of Philly.
If I got booed in Texas,
that would've made fun of pickup trucks
and women who wear too much makeup,
you know, and you dumb fucking
boots are walking around. All right.
If you've got a flat screen TV
and not fucking cowboy, all right,
you look like you're on
your way to a gay bar.
I would've said something like that
in Texas. That's what I would've done.
Oh look who's here. The lovely knee. Uh,
the fuck are you eating?
What are those things called?
Panoramas take it down a bit. Hey, that's
when you know your wife's hair. Hey,
what are you having a good time? Take it
down a bit. I'm eating pomegranate theme.
I'm eating pomegranate seeds.
I heard they're good for my
ovaries and my lady parts. They do.
I heard, I read that they're supposed
to shine up your vege lifts over there.
Oh baby. You know, it's
weird. As a weird segue,
you know, a year ago or so
when I didn't have a kid, oh,
we'll go back a year and a half when he
didn't get yourself knocked up. Right. Um,
I would just be walking around the house.
I would be singing whatever contemporary
shit that you know you were listening
to,
you know,
does she is white gold and Michelle
flavor dad some plum, right.
I'd be singing that shit right then.
Now that we have a kid,
I'm down there at brushing my teeth going,
whoa.
Vampyr Rina and may be blue
with pointy teeth. Whoa.
They're the marina but are
not so dev arena daddy.
Yeah. What happened? What happened to me?
A puppy dog.
What's,
when they go and do,
when they go on the adventure.
How's the song go on a mission
going on a mission that's
going on, a mission. Go in on a mission
about, Ooh, what? Oh, I costs.
That's why I brought you on.
Those are me undies. Biondi
sent matching, matching.
Underwears I love it. Are So
cute. What's the, what's on that?
A taco with hot sauce.
You get it.
Do you need to be explained?
And they make him be fun in front of me
for being a red head and making me a fun.
Well, they make it be fun of me
for being out redhead head. What?
The what the hot sauce.
You see the text that I sent you that
now they're going to have red head emojis
in June. Uh, yeah. Which I just think
it's going to lead to more redheaded hate.
The thing about being a redhead is what
you want to do is not stand next to
another redhead. You want to sort,
sorta like fade into the background,
but you know what? You don't really,
you're not going to use those.
But they also have, um, bald, bald emojis.
Do they have a bald with a red beard?
I don't know if the baldy has facial hair.
When am I ever going to
fit in my whole life? Oh,
when are you ever be represented?
You realize how difficult it is to be a
redheaded white male is so close to the
brass ring, but those blue blood and
what? They won't let me in Jesus.
I am like the, I'm like the runt of the
litter. The one that the mother rejects.
Yeah. You're the real underdog. I
hit when you do you? Yeah. Yeah.
The rail under the, why don't
you just do it? You know,
giant fucking I roll with the,
there it is a meme level.
It looks beautiful outside.
So why don't you put on your underwear,
Nini? I want to see you in those.
I want to wear it on Valentine's Day. We
have to both were on Valentine's Day. No,
we don't. That's why
they go, because I'm an,
I'm an adult that I can make my own
choices despite the fact that, you know,
something was killing me.
Can you just wait your taco underwear?
Can you just have a little
fun and not be so uptight?
Could you just say uptight like we're in
a fucking black and white comedy movie
here. Hayes white and she's black.
She teaches them to loosen up. Huh?
You're really uptight. You're not
uptight. I'm a fucking control freak.
I don't like people telling me what to do.
You're uptight if you're a control freak
than means or uptight. No, it doesn't.
Yeah,
it does.
A black people up tight because a sick
of white people fucking running shit.
What does that have to do
with anything that control?
Didn't Janet Jackson do a
whole fucking album about that?
Why am I here? Because I want you
to see the matching underwear.
I thought you'd have fun with
it rather than put demands on.
Isn't it enough that I have
to pay for the whole evening?
We're celebrating our relationship.
Whereas your contribution.
Oh yeah,
but you're supposed to do that.
You're supposed to do that. You have.
Are you supposed to want to do it?
That's up to cost you no money
and you're burning calories.
Ridiculous burning
calories. What do you, what?
That's a rubric exercise
if done correctly. Oh,
whoa. Getting a blow. We were,
y'all are wearing matching underwear.
Don't fuse those two worlds to there.
I will. And I just did. Hmm.
It's because of that world that
you now have a new world. Okay.
There you go. Okay. By the
way, a a lovely little one. Um,
she uh, she took her first steps
this week. Oh, it was awesome.
Yeah, she did. It's funny
you're going to start crying.
I wanted to film it and then fucking
put Aerosmith's walk this way.
Underneath it. Every time
she falls that debt, boom.
Boom cat and we'll hit the stairs when
she falls down and arrest. So cute.
She's so proud of herself too.
I didn't realize babies get
like proud of themselves. Yeah.
Like when she learns how to do stuff, she
looks over and smiles like, Huh? Yeah.
Look at me seeing this. He
checking this out. So cute. Um,
anyway, so, well, let's get down
to what everybody's talking about.
The scandalous interview
by a Quincy Jones. Nia. Ah,
Jesus Christ. Iconic interview. I
didn't like it. Of course you then,
what do you like, Bill? What? Oh, what
is popular that you actually enjoy?
What do you mean? There's a bunch of shit
that I like to talk. A cupcake. Oh look,
a bath. Full puppies. I hate it.
None of that's true. I like cupcakes.
I actually know how to make them and
I've made you some and I love dogs.
You've never made me a cupcake. You
fucking whore. Put that microphone.
It's exactly what I just said.
Excuse me. There's no need for that.
I drove all over the fucking La base and
trying to find you a fucking Yellow Cup
cake with chocolate frosting and it
didn't exist and I went out and I fucking
made them for you.
You don't remember that you
have in network in your life.
Made me cupcakes.
And this is in Los Angeles or New York?
This is here like when the last,
within the last two years.
Yeah.
Give me that microphone. You're off the
podcast. No Way. You're up the podcast.
Remember the unbelievable you made it
and you went out and bought me cupcakes
like late at night when I'd
have my cupcake cravings.
But you've never made because that would
mean you'd make like a dozen cupcakes
because that's how many were in the pants
and you frosted them and everything.
Yeah.
I don't remember this.
Yes. Walking with me. I know. Go
into the cupboard and go, look,
there's a fucking cupcake tray.
Why would I have one of those?
Uh, that's right. There it is guys.
And whatever said for years that
you're only as good as the last act,
it doesn't mean shit to them.
You know the Patriots are always
just pushing fucking all pros out.
The door liners are in there too.
Yeah, yeah, that's right. Wow.
Well guess who's not making
cupcakes anymore? Come.
Maybe I should film it. Well you make
some for Valentine's Day. No know why.
Cause you're not going to remember.
And then you come on the podcast made
red velvet ones and meanwhile I'm wearing
matching underwear. I'm playing the
game, I'm playing the game. Right.
And then I make you cupcakes. You
don't even remember. How dare you.
You look gorgeous. So by the way, oh,
Naomi's been hitting the
gym and I've been noticing,
I'm trying to keep it together.
Keep it together. Keep together.
Do you know my issue is that was all
positive right there. I made you cupcakes.
I said you're looking good.
All of that was what I didn't
like about Quincy Jones.
He was talking shit about
people who are dead.
And then everybody took
everything he said is fact.
And it's like you didn't notice
halfway through his gold.
I know who killed Kennedy. Oh Shit.
You should have told Oliver Stone.
He wouldn't have wasted all that time
making that movie when he could've just
called you up. Um, I
just liked what he said.
When you go for the money,
God walks out the room.
That's where like as far as all
that gossip about everybody else,
it's like do it once you
grow up. Huh? Well, who?
Who goes around doing that will you just
got used to steal Shaun's you didn't
say that when you will make
an records with them. Yeah.
He's still fucking alive.
Tell all the stories.
This is what I'm telling you are not cool.
Not Cool people on the old people,
my family, they just,
they don't give a fuck.
They're just telling them
stories about everybody.
This person did this and this
person did this and back in the day.
Was that cause what do they add
to lose? They're not, you know,
fearful of being politically correct.
Let me get this straight.
You're not supposed to be,
yes, you're supposed shit.
You're not supposed to be a snitch.
He's supposed to keep your mouth shut
and all of that shit your whole fucking
life. He's not in the men in the end when
everybody, do you know what the fuck?
I mean,
well,
I don't know how I was brought up
when she didn't do that to people.
[inaudible] no,
not that street shit.
Yeah. Like I said, I don't
pop off. I'd flip out,
but even in the hard streets in
the suburbs, pretty classic line.
I think for the podcast when I lived
in that Culdesac you want to talk about
dead end streets, man, you
had to go out to my suburb
that suite edited and all it was was
beautiful words into a lovely pond.
Oh, a lunch yesterday with mom
and she like, did you hear her?
Like kind of chastised
me for not drinking water
cause all, but I wish I could have
enjoyed done your body. Oh Man.
And I drank a whole bunch of water like
the whole entire morning and then saves
automatically. They automatically
filled up my glass again for more.
All right. In ask where they
just automatically filled
it up. And my mom was like,
do you want some water? And
I was like, no, it's okay.
And she like hits me on the arm. It's
just, you should be drinking water.
And it's like, I drink water all God damn
day long. It was just a mother's love,
I guess. So I just annoyed me anyway. It
has nothing to do a little bit. Hey Nia,
you should drink more water.
Wow.
That's an eye. Literally drink water
all day long. Nobody notices. Right.
System and why in that moment
she had to like, I don't know.
It literally has been bothering me since
yesterday. Oh it doesn't? Yeah. Oh,
then I wouldn't have
slept you on the wrist.
So if I knew it was really bothering
you and it's just annoying.
You want to talk about Nia? No, I got it
off my chest. Oh, there you go. See that?
That's what I've learned about women.
You just, Oh, I didn't know that.
You just learned about women. Yes, I
have no nothing. You have no instincts.
You have no intuition.
I nailed that whole thing about how you
guys stopped giving compliments when you
get married and you even said,
fair enough. I don't remember that.
Of course you don't just like the
cupcakes. You know what's funny?
I'm going to stop doing shit for
you and just say that I did it.
Cause you're not going to remember either
way and you're going to be like, wow,
I must,
I can't believe I keep forgetting that
I have the greatest husband ever again.
He made me a chocolate cupcakes.
I keep forget
what else. I can't believe that fucking
sat there with that Goddamn kitchenaid.
I wore goddamn apron for you. When do I
get for that? Huh? Nuh Huh? I'm sorry.
I can't remember. Ah, look at you. A
little sunflower icon. Isn't that cute?
I've never noticed that.
Anything that comes with it.
So what's up? What's up? Why am I here?
Because I want you to see the underwear
and I want you to, uh, you know,
thank you, Mandy. There you go.
And that's, that's the, uh, that's,
that's the one advertise
that we have today. Oh, great
photo. Boop, boop, me, ids, me,
Ids, match and fucking Ondo.
Where's Doo Doo Doo Doo me,
ids me ideas.
Put them on if you'd owe cares if I
can trapped in your relationship or the
food. She don't give a shit. She's not
going to remember if you made a cupcakes.
So just if I can tell her that you're
dead because you're a loser, right?
You want to blog,
you want to look good knee up with your
significant others this Valentine's Day,
right? Uh, then check checkout
me undies, matching pairs. Oh,
I should have been trashed.
And he said, oh no,
I can't wait to wear these matching
underwear with you. A unique, fun gift.
But yeah,
and your Valentine.
They're the perfect balance of
comfortable fit and exciting prince.
Uh, don't spend another Valentine's
Day giving the same old gift.
Checkout me undies.com and find
the best match for your match.
Did you see how suddenly there was
saying that I was a redhead with the hot
sauce representing the Dick? No, you
didn't. I thought you'd find that funny.
Talk about why me undies matching pairs
of the best Valentine's gift ever. Uh,
feel free to improvise. These are
so cute. I can't even tell you.
Put them on. They're very thought
right now. Put them on right now.
I want to see what you look like.
All right,
me undies are the most comfortable and
fun undies that you're going to wear.
Geezes
um,
Mandy's are the most comfortable and
fun on whether you ever gonna wear
undies are the most comfortable
underwear that you ever going to.
I'm not looking at the coffee.
God Damn it.
You fill out a fucking pair onto
woo.
Say our 80 go over there and
I'll pick up something that I uh,
forgot William. Um, all right.
You know what? Just for that I am going
to where the other parent, God dammit Nia.
Alright me undies are the most
comfortable. This is the last time,
the most comfortable and fun and ease
you and your significant again will ever
own. They're made from the softest
materials on earth, wind and fire.
I did it.
Feel good up here,
up against you who we're talking
three times softer than cotton.
Soft this Valentine's Day.
Get Your partner and gift.
That's for the both of you ordered by
February 5th at 10:00 AM for free standard
shipping. So your gift arise
in time. 100% satisfaction,
guaranteed me undies guarantees you and
your significant other will love your
matching pairs or your money back.
That's the first time anybody has
gotten naked on the podcast right now.
Me undies has an exclusive Valentine's
Day offer that just from my listeners,
for any first time purchases when you
purchased me undies, matching pairs,
you get 20% off and free shipping me
under use is so sure you'll love their
underwear, their off offer. They offer a
hundred percent satisfaction guarantee.
If you don't love your first pair,
you'll get a full refund. Uh,
what are you waiting for?
Order by February 5th for free.
Standard Shipping to get 20% off
your matching pairs. Free Shipping,
a hundred percent satisfaction guarantee.
Well that part's over. I can go to uh,
well at least the February 5th thing.
Um, [inaudible] dot com slash bird,
that's manatees.com/bird does.
This will be the best Valentine's
Day gift you that you will ever give.
Start matching your bottom
half to your better half.
Go to [inaudible] dot com slash bar right
now. Um, that's cute. That's very clever.
Her road. It is your bottom half
to your better half. There you go.
Our anniversary is coming up. Yeah. And
we don't even officially know the date.
No we don't.
So, I mean, do we always
say it's Valentine's Day?
No, we don't. And we never go
out on Valentine's Day. No.
We usually go out a couple of days after
when the price has come back to some
sort of sensible yeah, you can
get a table, right balance.
I say you go to Wendy's at
night, they're like, we're sorry.
It's going to be like a 45 minute wait.
Um,
but we never came up with like,
I guess we just now our anniversary is
our wedding date as opposed to like the
first time we ever hung out. Right? Yeah.
Neither one of us are big on dates. No,
but one of us, it's a little
bigger on cupcakes than the other,
but it was February 14
years ago. Wow. Yeah.
That's so crazy.
14 years
still looking good.
Still looking great.
Now they'll tell you that and I already
knew that until that little little
fucking display you just put on.
I'll make you cupcakes and knew each
other and you look good too. All right,
let's stop this. This is annoying
people. All right. Thank you.
The Conan O'brien show
for get me on on Monday.
Even as much as it was
painful for me to sit there.
I think a Philly fans deserve that.
You know,
if they're all this shit they've
gotten because of that rant,
which I said once again, was not part,
it wasn't personal. It wasn't personal.
It just so long ago too. It was, that's
a funny thing is now people had gone to
[inaudible]. Well, he plugged in one one.
Yeah. It only took half a century. Fuck.
Are you bragging about?
That's like the guy who fucking
finishes a marathon in Lynn, like hours.
It's like,
yeah, dude, I could've walked it
in that, that amount of time. Also,
that audience deserved it.
Who did the audience and Villi?
They deserve your wrath.
Yeah, they did. They were assholes.
Yeah. You know, it's funny.
Most of them probably have kids now and
they're raising little asshole kids,
but you know something.
Not all Philly fans are like that.
I remember having Shay's a
nice guy. Uh, you know you,
I remember those guys always
sunny. Yeah, they're nice guys.
I didn't see them do it. Yeah. They
weren't tipping over any cars and stuff.
Oh my God.
Um,
I remember you called me after that
whole thing in Philly happen and you were
like, I have a massive headache.
And I said, what happened? He like,
I just got into a fight with like 10,000.
You didn't you call me right after
it happened. I'll never forget it.
And I was like, oh my God. Whoa.
And then it just blew up and I think
that's right.
You were at my apartment and I was,
I rode home with Bobby Kelly and he was
filling teenage way head tonight. You?
Yeah. I was like, Bobby,
I've got a headache.
You judge people to go back and shells.
You know what Bobby Kelly
had to follow that night?
Bobby Kelly had to go on after the
intermission where somebody with an ear
infection drained it. Somebody else drank
it. And somebody who watched it. Cute.
This is in Philly? Yeah. What is
going on with the P in that? That guy,
that horse shit. Like what is
going on? No, no, no, no. Well,
what is going on over there?
Seriously.
You know, what happened to Philly was
when they built night interstate 95,
they got bypassed.
Okay.
So I just think that
they're just stuck in time.
But back in a time when people
ate Horse Shit, I dunno. I Dunno.
I think there's something there you,
there's either some sacred burial ground
that they built the city on or there's
some sort of toxic waste,
like the Simpsons thing going on.
I don't know what their deal is,
but all I know is they don't care that
people don't like them and they're proud
of their behaviors. So
I say, God bless them.
That's some really amazing people
though, an affiliate, right?
If you had any horse shit,
it, uh, the roots, that's not
a person, Scott, it's a band.
Um,
all the black people
I know, you're like really racist.
Oh, Kevin Hart. Keith Robinson.
Kevin Hart. Yeah. I didn't
know that he sold out the Eagle's
stadium. Yeah. And he was,
he did stand up in a fucking
football state. Funny.
He was so happy after they won.
You saw him on TV drunk. It's like,
I know that sounded hilarious. So it
was pretty great. It was pretty great.
He was very happy. Yeah. So that's the
deal. And what am I going to get mad?
You know, my team can't win
it every year. Right, right.
I don't know. I think you're
very gracious about it. You like,
that's the one thing you've actually
mellowed out about as the years have gone
by. I mean that candid compliments.
Go ahead boards. That's the one thing
I could actually say.
I see improvement on the rest of it
is taken a fucking nose dive now.
You're very gracious when it comes
to other teams. Yeah. I don't,
I don't take it to the point of like,
like I said, I just, you know, what's his,
I retweeted that, that uh,
nick foals audio in the, uh,
in the huddle was great. Other than he
said, I love you guys and just like,
why does everything have
to be so fucking sweet now
I would love to teleport Nick your
responses in a huddle in an NFL game.
I mean,
I would've loved to have had teleported
him back to that fucking 1980 super bowl
team when they were playing the Raiders
and just be okay before we do this first
place. Want to say I love
you guys just said, well,
we'll put Montgomery look at him high
when they win the Superbowl and stuff.
You can say, I love you. It's now when I
was not, when I was a kid. They didn't.
They didn't think anybody actually had
emotions when you were a kid that all of
a sudden it's a new millennial thing
to have emotions and express them.
Men did not cry.
When I was a kid that I saw,
I saw the Celtics won three championships.
I saw the Lakers win five.
I saw the Pistons went to,
you know,
the first time I think I
saw a guide cry was Jordan.
It was because his dad died and he
wasn't there and that was understandable.
You know what I mean?
But he'd just cry because he won.
He said that angry look on his face,
go only open five fucking six
and you always seem to win it.
On the road and you know, he's looking
at some little kid who was crying.
He got off on it, he got off on BNB.
That's what a man was back then.
Okay. Um, first of all, I just
want to say I love you guys.
I want to just take time to just,
everybody knows
how much way to offensive line is lost.
You guys, you know, you were really,
you know,
I dare you coming out of your football
pants the beginning of the year and now
you're just looking so shapely,
dare you and your next show was.
So when you think at night, I dare
you to say love you guys. Goodnight.
I dare you to say it. Oh, you kidding me?
I have a fucking do that per 10
minutes until everybody just got so
uncomfortable and left.
Huh? I want you to do it shows over,
but uh, I just want to take some time.
You'd just speak from the heart.
You know,
my life has changed a lot in the
last year letter and in a great way.
I became a father and I look at the
world at different time, different way,
and I've noticed the whole thing. You can
just be like, all right, goodnight. No,
it has to be a big thing because then
they're going to expect that there's going
to be this punchline that never comes
and gets you going on and on about how
much love you have in your heart.
Don't forget to look at this.
Don't forget to look at the
sky today. Everybody, you know,
it's those little things
that we take for granted.
If you get some of that fucking
pomegranate. Oh, my jacket. Oh, right.
You said my jacket is a table.
Yeah. I'm telling you now.
The second this podcast
is over,
we're going to do a dry run for two little
fucking booty shorts on just to make
sure we're in. We're in sync run. Oh. Oh.
Was that within six? No, that
light. I was, uh, the new kids.
I almost said the right boys.
I can now keep this Darryl's.
Oh, Joseph McIntyre.
Mm. The right stuff. You got
the red stuff. That's right,
baby. Okay, well I think that
might be the way you answer me.
Yeah.
Sorry,
I didn't mean to keep going.
If you were of that age, those
boy bands, they caught you, right?
[inaudible]
new edition and then you know the white
new edition also known as new kids on
the block. And wait a
minute, wait a minute.
Are we talking about the
Osmonds came before new edition.
Well that's no
new edition.
Had the same manager. Okay. As new
kids on the block and their manager,
Maurice Starr said he wanted to make
a white pop crossover version of new
edition that don't get mad,
don't get mad at white people.
And it was a black guy's ideas who said,
I'm mad at white people and we're
doing that fucking Elvis shit.
New Kids on the block have always given
props and respect to new edition their
whole entire careers.
That's good because I would hate to
know that those two bands are fighting.
I'm just saying it's, it's a nice thing.
All right, well you have a new addition.
Got Screwed. They really,
really did big time.
So it's just nice that new kids on the
block as I was giving them their other
crops. Okay. And why know why?
Why get all weird? Not Weird?
It feels weird.
Well that's because you live in a
place of fucking awkwardness and anger.
Can I ask you a question?
Do you really know what to tell you about?
I asked you questions sincerely.
Is it ever you?
Is it always me and my world of
awkwardness and anger and negativity?
As you say? [inaudible]
fucking unbelievable. If
you guys caught it for me,
I woke up this morning,
but I do want to do,
I fucking change my daughter's diaper.
Right?
The hanging out with her,
I'm watching cartoons is all the
great shit that had done today.
And this is what we,
all,
she all she talks about how
she just just dials into is my,
is my fucking anger. Right? And I haven't
even lost my shit yet today. So what?
I burned my hand in the kitchen, which
is not why I yelled. Fuck. That was why.
Because I was putting the fucking
keynote into my thermos and you know,
and always falls down in between the two
stupid burners you said that's why you
screaming obscenities?
Yeah,
cause I want before he fell off the spoon
and it went all the way down anyway to
clean it up and I just went, fuck. Then
you will the other and be like, what?
I was like a burned my hand.
No, you're a sweetheart because you've
just given me a bunch of compliments and I
love you and you're fantastic. Yeah. Yeah.
That's really doesn't hold any water.
You've been trashing me like you've been
in the last three times you've been on
the podcast.
You make it sound like you're emotionally
held captive here when you're running
the deal. [inaudible]
yeah. Listen to that laugh.
That is the laugh of somebody that's
running a fucking relationship. All right.
That's the podcast for this week.
Anniversary.
Happy yet bursary this TV anniversary.
Uh, shit today. Just be our anniversary.
All right. Why can't we just say the
seventh? I'll remember that. Well,
what day is today? Well,
it's the eighth. Oh,
so it was yesterday.
What kind of life are you leading that
you don't even know what fucking day it
is? You have the nerve to talk about
me. What month is it? Quick. Quick.
There you go. Sure. History month.
Shouldn't you be like lighting a candle
every day until they make a giant black
Menorah with 28 candles and science?
Lack of Nora. Yeah. No, I uh, no.
Then I'll, this day in 1932, no,
I'm reading stories a little everyday
about African American or African
Americans are dead today.
She'll lace,
which was later taken credit was taken
by the light that would actually,
it was three women who are good
at math of African descent.
February 9th,
the first name ship was actually built
by a native American was African blood.
Robert Folden killed. That person
had said, I invented this deep shit.
This happened February night at eight 45
is that it?
February 9th, eighth, eight Oh four.
Thomas Jefferson finally gave
him into his desires. Um,
hopefully it was her desire to, but
that's not how it worked back then. Yeah.
Yeah. Performing next, um,
at the Patrice O'Neal benefit
or Patrice O'Neal benefits.
There's a 54 tickets left.
Uh, something like that. Um,
that's on February 20th. My next
one is going to be in Santa Barbara,
Santa Barbara, which was actually
made an African American named it.
And 1972 people took it over because
they liked the view of the beach.
Are you a, are you sure? Flying to Santa
Barbara? Have you decided yes, I am.
I'm frying playing a helio
copter out there. Are you?
Which will y'all be there and
then flying back. So can I come?
There's no room for you.
What do you mean there's no room?
There's no room in the copilot
and the opener. Yeah. Oh, okay.
Well I guess that's that then.
No two openers to open up your,
so flying out there.
One them's version and I'm going to be
fucking dying laughing cause he hates to
fly and it's going to freak them out.
That among controls,
even though we're going to out the copilot
there, he's going to be freaking well,
tell whoever the other person is. It's
coming with you to film him. Oh yeah.
When we first go into a habit,
because you don't,
when the first time you go into Howard,
this one of the weirdest feelings ever,
other than realizing that you're
attracted to me 15 years ago,
14 years ago, that must've
been, am I attracted to that
orange headed Weirdo? Um,
so negative. Well that's nice
near, that's a nice thought.
Then you wonder why I live in a
world of anger and awkwardness. The,
when I first saw you,
the first time ever I saw your freckles
really handsome and I was like,
oh, what were you like? That's,
that's what I always know
like five years later.
So it was meant to be,
oh, you like me. So I met,
I met my wife in an alley behind the
first in an alley behind the Apollo.
Yeah,
that's the first I was going into do,
I was going into do showtime at the
Apollo. My Dad had booked you on,
it's showtime at the Apollo my day.
I used to book the Comedians on it,
show Timothy Apollo. My Dad is actually
known bill longer than I have. And,
um, I saw, he was like, oh,
I got this funny wipe away from Boston
on the show. And I was like, okay,
cool.
I had just graduated from college and I
went back there and he said hi briefly
and I was like, oh, he's
really good looking.
And then when I saw you years later on,
tough crowd,
I immediately recognize
you. I was like, oh my God,
that's the guy that I met at
the Apollo with my dad Jana.
And you were such a
jerk to me. I wasn't, I,
you kept trying to ask you why
he was such an asshole. Oh no,
that's not how it went at all. I wouldn't
even look at me. You in the elevator.
I was looking over it and I'm just like,
think of something to say.
Sitting with something saying you was
staring straight ahead like those fucking
guys in London with the big furry hats.
Expressionless trying to play hard to get,
but you also had a girlfriend at the
time and I had a boyfriend. No, I didn't.
Yeah, you thought I did. No, you did.
And then when we ran into each other
at the party for Chappelle show,
that's when you told me you
didn't have a girlfriend,
but when we first met you did have it.
I didn't fucking ask you.
I want I had a girlfriend. I know.
Well then. All right then. I know,
but you're still looking
at so what I can look,
I was looking to,
even though I had a boyfriend,
but we didn't do anything until after
we were both till after. Exactly. Yeah.
Jesus, I tell you going to call
Quincy Jones there. Oh listen.
Where you guy kicked the bucket
and kicked a bug and you wait till
I would never do that to you, but I
do. I don't. Why would I give a shit?
I be dead. I had to imagine myself.
No, I don't want to, first of all,
I don't ever want to think about your
time before me. That would be too much.
Well, it's going to happen. I'm 10
years older than you and I'm a guy,
but I do take better care of
myself than you do. Oh wait, I do.
I do the elliptical.
I swear to God you eat keynote where for
three weeks and you think you're some
fucking like health,
like you really need to knock it off.
Fair enough. You're like,
oh wow I just ate. You don't
want to have so much energy.
Yes bill, we are all aware of like
the health benefits of your animal.
Jealous who?
My new healthy diet.
I'm not jealous you are you always nosing
around like a little fucking rabbit we
didn't know is wiggling. Like wait,
what are you eating over there?
What are you going over there? And I'm
just curious what you're doing cause yeah,
you're, you're doing really
well with your diet and stuff.
But I just think be like we're the first
person that discovered Keana was where
you'd go on and on about not what I think.
What do you think?
I think I went to the dentist yesterday
and found out that I was supposed to do
16 weeks of Invisalign,
but because I've left these things in
sometimes even during shows spitting on
the front too. Fucking rose cause
I want to get this over with.
He says it's only going to be 13 weeks,
and I just put in tre number nine,
bitch,
I got another month of these
fucking things. That's it.
Yeah. Do you just know? You know
how excited I was when I got,
I remember when I got you. I
remember my, I got your teeth fixed.
All this shit that I've done for you.
Please don't put it that way.
All this shit that I've
done for you look up.
I see one more fucking piece of clothing
that you just had to have that you did.
Just frisbee down at a fucking goodwill
for some homeless guy to traipse around
in while he's looking
to get his fucking junk.
All right. I gotta get off. I have
to get on on with my fucking day.
This has been the podcast.
We can now play a little bit of
music and then you can listen.
Do another half hour of bullshit
from a Thursday podcast, uh,
earlier this year, 10 years ago. I
don't know how it works. Um, that's it.
All right. Have a wonderful
weekend. You'd come to once again,
congratulations to
everybody. You'd Philly, uh,
please don't eat excrement from an animal,
right?
Hey,
eh?
[inaudible]
what's going on? It's built bar and
it is the Monday morning podcast from
Monday,
February 8th,
2010 one day after Superbowl 44.
Well, um, usually I don't begin
my podcasts with a warning,
but I'm going to this week. Um, if
you live anywhere near Indianapolis,
you want to shut this thing off right now,
okay?
If you one of those fantasy
football playing Douche
bags with you stats and your
Peyton manning poster hanging
above your fucking bed,
you want to shut this thing off right now.
All right?
Because this podcast is dedicated
to you guys. You fucking cons.
Who I've been telling you for the last
five fucking years that Peyton manning is
overrated. I even went off on them last
week. Last week I went off on that guy.
And you cannot believe the emails that
I got from people all just fucking,
not only defending Peyton Manning,
but brushing off Tom Brady and his
three super bowl rings as if, oh,
you can plug anybody into that system,
you know,
but paint [inaudible] hate
manning. Who paint. Manny, he too.
He two for 50 fucking
touchdowns during what?
He threw five touchdowns against
the fucking Buccaneers in November.
I said it last week.
Peyton manning is a regular season
statistical juggernaut. Alright.
If you want to know who the fuck that
guy is, if you're still confused,
the fuck is there an invasion.
You hear that shit.
That's what happens
out here in fucking la.
So many probably just
robbed a convenience store.
They go a little overboard out here.
Um, dude, I'm telling you right now,
if you want to know who Peyton manning is,
you'll know who that fucking guy is.
Picture this.
If Dan Marino fucked Brett Farve,
their baby would be Peyton
manning. That's who he is. Okay.
In this asshole had only one one fucking
time his whole career and all these
analysts on TV, it was ridiculous.
They're all going, you know,
I'm telling you right now, you know,
if he wins here, uh, you're, you're,
you're arguably looking at one of the
greatest quarterbacks of all time because
of what? Based on what? Based on
what his regular season stats.
This guy fucking chokes every year in
the fucking playoffs. He's only one once.
He's only one once and everybody's
just fucking talking about and all you
assholes. Who fucking emailed me
this week where your emails now,
I emailed each you one of you,
every one of you fucking back and I
never heard it from you. You know,
maybe he's still fucking stunned.
Maybe you're still fucking confused.
So you know what?
You know what I'm going to do just for
all of you fucking idiots out there who
think that Peyton manning is
the greatest fucking guy ever.
Totally disrespecting Tom Brady.
Let me,
Tom Brady has to wear,
you know,
he has to wear a fucking welder's
mask at night to go to sleep.
That's how fucking bright is room is
from those three championship rings.
And you guys still disrespect him.
The analysts on TV still disrespect them.
They never talk about him.
The way they talk about Peyton manning
all accounts is what the fuck you do in
January. You know, nobody
talks about Terry Bradshaw.
You guys haven't watched super
bowl 10 it's up on fucking youtube.
Watch that game. Terry Bradshaw,
if you looked at his numbers,
you fucking stat boy pussies.
If you looked at his numbers on paper,
you wouldn't think the guy was shit.
You'd be like, oh, Peyton manning.
He's like twice as good as this guy.
He's closing in on 50,000 yards.
All Bradshaw has a 25,000 yards.
Yeah, in four fucking rings.
Superbowl 10 Terry Bradshaw Fades back
to pass in the fourth fucking quarter,
gets knocked unconscious,
gets a concussion. Okay,
and on that play that he got a concussion,
he throws a 50 yard strike to Lynn
Swann for the go ahead. Fucking score.
All right.
That's what the great ones do and nobody
ever brings up Terry Bradshaw. You.
What the fuck has he ever done by
other than when? For fucking super.
So just in case you guys are still
confused about your boy Peyton Manning,
I'm going to read you some of his stats,
the stats that fucking count. All right?
Yeah, we go the greatest
quarterback of all time.
I've got a little music for you this week.
All right.
December 30th I'm such an obnoxious ass.
This is Carly Simon by the way, sitting
and nobody does it better. You know,
this is what all the analysts have been
singing for the last fucking 10 years of
this guy's career. December
30th all right. CIC,
SAS in the regular season,
dolphins beat the colts 2117 overtime
wildcard game. Oh, whatever. Whatever.
That's his first trip to the playoffs.
He'll get better.
2002 colts lose 41 nothing's in a play
off route against the New York jets,
j e t s jets, jets, jets.
This is the greatest
quarterback of all fucking time.
Potentially with one fucking ring.
Everybody tuned in and watched to
see how he does against the saints.
That's look how we did
January 8th,
2004 cold slews 24 14 to
the New England patriots.
Greatest fucking quarterback,
potentially a better one fucking ring.
Oh you she footwork. He's on believable.
Okay. His hand eye coordination.
He's got the pedigree.
January 60 2005 Colt again
lose to the Patriots,
20 to three greatest fucking
quarterback all of all fucking time.
January 15th, 2006 cults lose
to the Steelers. 21 to 18
greatest quarterback of all time, and
right around then people start going, oh,
is this another Dan Marino? But no, the
next year, see, finally fucking shows up.
Finally grows it.
Dick comes back,
21 points down against the
Patriots wins his first Super Bowl,
and then I'm thinking, okay,
he's a fucking man now, right?
I'm going to see some Montana Shit. I'm
going to see some, some fucking Terry.
I'm going to see some time fucking Brady.
What's he do the next
year he loses at home
to the San Diego chargers. All right.
Maybe you had a fucking hangover,
maybe at a fucking hangover.
What's he do with the next year?
Quarter fucking quarterback ever loses
to the eight and eight chargers at
fucking home, right?
And you hear the song,
this is what these fucking analysts
who been just continue to sing.
He's the new bread farm.
Brett Farve can do no wrong throws
against his body over the fucking middle.
And what is Tom Jackson
say? Well, you know,
he's never been afraid to lose the
game. He fucking blow it. Be Mush.
Those vikings purple nuts right into
the fucking ground and they're still
fucking rubbing his god Damn
Mississippi cocky. I'm sick of it.
So here you go.
She goes up against the lowly saints.
They've never won a fucking thing in 40
fucking years of being in the league.
What's going to be the difference?
Peyton manning. I'll tell ya,
I gotta go with Peyton Manning. Oh,
Peyton manning fist. Peyton manning stat.
Peyton manning lost the fucking
game yesterday. The final drive.
I've got a question for you.
Indianapolis fans.
This Tom Brady throw a pick six
at the end of the super bowl,
there's Joe Montana.
Throw a fucking pick six.
Does Terry Bradshaw does.
Ben Roethlisberger one of the
most overlooked quarterbacks
of all times sitting
at home with fucking two rinks.
Does he know he doesn't?
All right,
so fuck all you fucking idiots out in
Indianapolis. There you go. How was that?
Did you like that right in your fucking
ass. God bless the saints everybody. Huh?
Dude? Did I say drew Brees his name? What?
Maybe three times when they finally
figured out he's going to win the game.
Then they're like, oh, by the way, drew
Brees is about to break Tom Brady's,
you know, single fucking Superbowl
record for completions there.
I got it out. I got a little started
there for a second, but I got it out.
Unbelievable.
Unfucking believable.
You know something.
This is how fucking bad.
Not even bad.
How fucking I predicted that.
I actually got Keith Robinson to
fucking apologize to me. Keith Robinson,
classic black dude doesn't like
white people. Hates cops. Okay.
There's no reason for
him to apologize to me.
He actually apologized. He goes,
you know what? You're right.
You were right about this
guy. Ah, I feel vindicated.
Vindication. What a great emotion.
So there you go. There you go.
Congratulations to the New Orleans saints.
Okay.
And I know what it feels like
to fucking have a great team.
And nobody even fucking talks about you.
Do they even bring you guys up
for half a second? Oh, by the way,
it'd be great for the fucking shitty.
The amount of shit that you guys
have been through down there.
How many Superbowls had
been played in New Orleans.
How many times have you seen people from
other cities come to your town and feel
the joy of winning a championship?
And you just sat there, you know,
with your beads and your check
and foot and you're Voodoo? Go on.
When the fuck is it going to happen for
us? Well, finally did. Congratulations.
You're totally fucking deserve that.
Your defense was the shit.
Even when the culture receivers,
we're catching balls. I mean,
you guys were hitting them. They
look like they, they'll like many,
many explosions.
You will not knocking them off their feet.
Totally fucking deserve
it. Can't be, could not be
happier, could not be happier.
Not only did you know, I know it feels
like to wait for fucking championship.
So congratulations to everyone down in
New Orleans and I also want to thanks the
saints for fucking proven me, right?
Proven me right? There you go.
There you go. All right, so
while you fucking analysts, hey,
then you enter you a pas at
ESPN in Bristol, Connecticut.
You listen into this shit,
why don't you go play it to some of those
jerk offs at Upi have on the fucking
air? Who can't do anything? Dude, I'm
telling you, they'll even go out there.
I'm even watching a little bit of shit
this morning. This loosen. I'm stuttering.
I'm so fucking pissed right now.
They're still not saying, ah Brady.
What's his face? Peyton blew it.
They keep talking about drop passes.
Ms Field Goes, get the fuck
outta here. Pick six nail in
the coffin. Thanks Peyton.
You know what? He's going to lose.
You see how tanned up he was?
Oh
Jesus Christ. It's going to be
a great week. I feel fantastic.
You know? Especially as a fucking
Boston fan. You know what I mean?
I already watched, I watched the
Lakers come in and win another one.
You know I watched the Yankees win number
27 was I actually going to sit here
and have to watch the cult
when to and prove me wrong.
That may be Peyton is let's be puberty.
Peyton maybe is,
maybe Peyton is one of the greatest
of all time. Fucking unreal.
Ed is one guy this week was sending me an
email saying, you know what, Dude, if, uh,
if I, you know, if, if Peyton
played for the dolphins,
I don't know what year this guy's talking.
And he said they definitely would win
at least one championship and it Brady
went there. You know, it wouldn't
have made a difference. Yeah.
Why would it make a difference?
Brady only is cool under pressure.
How many fucking super does that guy
have to fucking win on the last drive to
get some respect? I don't get it.
I don't get it. I don't get it.
And what about Ben Roethlisberger who
has twice as many fucking rings as Peyton
Manning?
Okay.
Let's look at Peyton Manning's brother
Eli Manning against the Patriots.
Tom Brady,
once again,
drives them down the field for the fourth
fucking time for the go ahead score.
Huh? Did Eli get nervous? No,
he didn't drove him right
down the fucking field.
It did what his big brother didn't do.
Oh,
I would love to hear that
awkward phone call today.
Ah,
sorry. I'm sorry to everybody who
doesn't listen. Yeah. You know what?
I'm not sorry. Fuck you. I was
right. I always wait. Okay.
This is the Monday morning podcast.
I'm fucking strutting around like a God
damn rooster here. Loving life. Anyways,
let's get down to the podcast here.
Um,
last week I worked in a, I
worked in Irvine, California,
and uh, I worked at the, uh, the
Improv the first time is just south of
Los Hung Gullies. And uh,
I gotta tell you something.
You guys ever watched that show,
uh, the real housewives of the Osi?
Of course you don't. Why
would you? All right,
but do you have a woman in your life who
dominates the TV once a fucking week?
Whenever that show comes on? You know,
you can't help but see it, right?
I remember watching that show going like,
there's no fucking way.
You know what I mean?
You know, it's a TV show.
They take the extremes of different
areas in the dumber you elected like the
Jersey shore thing. You're sitting
there going, you know what?
There's no fucking way people are that
goddamn stupid. And then what happens?
You go on youtube and you see
bootlegs, bootleg cameras, you know,
shots of the Jersey shore and you're like,
Holy Shit,
there's an element of truth to this.
Now I'm not saying everybody in the OCC
is a 63 year old cougar with their face
yank back. But uh, uh, wow.
After,
um,
after one of my shows I had a group of
women coming up to me who collectively I
think their age was about
606. And um, if you saw,
I don't know, these plastic
surgeons are to get sued to these.
You ever seen Rhianna's mugshot.
All right.
It's not a mugshot.
You remember the picture after she got
the shit kicked out of her by a Chris
Brown or wherever the fuck his name is.
You remember that?
Just picture that face except
wherever her face was swollen.
Just imagine if it was equally
swollen on the other side of her face.
Like it was a symmetrical beat down.
That's what,
that's what plastic surgery looks like.
Rather than ever one
swollen up fucking Aye.
You got to and there and you're like,
wow,
what does this person get the shit kicked
out of them. But because they're too,
and they're exactly perfect,
Ula and you know,
Michelangelo was dead. You gotta be like,
well, he didn't kick the shit out of her.
This must be plastic surgery.
I'm talking like my eyes,
my eyes were watering when I
looked at their faces. And, uh,
they, they, and they all get
like the, these, these, uh,
those, those fucking lips.
And then not even, and it was a, it
was a fucking nightmare. But anyways,
uh,
but you know what I mean?
So of course I bring that up on stage
and it was like a talking about plastic
surgery in the occ in Orange County
is like bringing up Scientology in
Hollywood. It just gets really
fucking quiet and awkward.
So anyways, but I want to thank everybody
who came out to my shows. And, um,
actually, you know what, I
had one person come out, uh,
you know a lot of people who are in this
business and a lot of people who aren't
in this business,
they try to act like they don't give a
shit about fame and they don't care about
celebrities where I am
not one of those people,
I love famous people and if they
even look in my general direction and
acknowledge me, it actually fills me up
inside. That's how fucking insecure I am,
right? So Thursday night I'm doing
my show down in, uh, down enough.
What the fuck was I? Irvine, right?
Yeah. Bill, we know you're there.
We're not arguing. Just get to
the fucking point. I'll, right.
So I'm standing there after
the show, whoring myself
out, I'm selling my DV Dvds.
I'm shaking hands and kissing
fucking babies. Right?
And all of a sudden this like famous
people, they just got that thing, man,
I didn't even know who the fuck this was.
This woman comes up and really quickly,
like two seconds just goes, hey, I
thought you were great and shook my hand.
I felt that electricity. And then she
went away and I was like, God damn man,
who the fuck was that? I just got done
shaking like fucking a hundred hands,
nothing, nothing regular.
All away. Accountant.
Hey Plumber eight a college student.
She comes up fucking unbelievable.
Felt a connection.
And then as she ran away, I'm looking
at it, I'm like, you know, I ain't go,
that looks like a Tonya contain
is how I was saying anything.
Evidently it's tiny contain. And I
walked in there and someone goes, hey,
they just, that was Tony contain, if
you don't know who the fuck that is,
she was the best looking video girl
for my money out of all the heavy metal
movies of all fucking time.
The Whitesnake video,
you know the one she danced on the cars.
I didn't like that one.
I like what she did at
the foot of the bed.
That little miniskirt barely covering
her. A little, a whatnot, you know,
lifted her fucking leg up like
a fucking show pony, you know?
I know that doesn't mean shit to you
kids nowadays, but this was pre internet,
Internet porn and all that type of stuff.
All you had was Victoria's
secret and your imagination.
I guess she could rent
porns at that point.
But I was too fucking
young and I was like lucky.
Go near to you think of booking
mood. So I never rented one. Okay,
so that's as far down the fucking pussy
rabbit hole I had been as far as video
pussy and a unbelievable
unfucking believable.
So
I don't know.
You guys probably think that's a lame
fucking story. I gotta tell you something.
When somebody who you used to jerk off
to comes up to you 20 years later and
says, Hey, great job. That's
a special moment. You know,
I had a lot of special moments this
week. I really did. You know what?
I didn't want to beat on my car.
I like saying that.
I don't want to beat him my car.
The reality is I have a
Toyota Prius and it has a,
what looks like little
breath mints for tires.
And I didn't feel like driving
it down in the fucking rain.
So I went out and I rented a car and I
rented one of those dodge challengers,
black on black.
All it had was the v six,
just waiting for all the gear heads
to get done groaning. Ah Dude.
That's just like a bitch.
Go.
What'd you still could take a few
drove that was a v six 3.5 liter.
It's still moved the car. It
was a, I'm telling you man,
even if you get the V sex dude,
you're going to feel like fucking
Steve McQueen in that car.
That car is the shit.
I think it's way better than the Mustang.
I rented the Mustang when I
was in, uh, Fort Lauderdale.
So all I have left to
rent is the new Camaro.
I like all of those cars and, but I
got to met man, the challenger Man,
that fucking,
you know what it is?
It's the forefront lights for
headlights in the front. I don't even,
I don't even know if one of them don't,
you know,
if two of them are just
dummies or they just, you know,
they'll like blinker lights or
something like that. I don't know what,
but it just reminded me when I was a
kid that was a sign of status to me.
You had the forehead lights cause I
was always into the caddies. You know,
in the late sixties one they had the Ford,
you know,
the two and two and they
were on top of each other.
And then for some stupid
fucking reason in the 70s,
they put them side by side and they
just didn't fucking look right. But, um,
I dunno, I, I would really, uh,
I think I'm going to get one
of those cars at some point.
I've got to find out how much they
are and uh, you know what I mean?
Cause I'm an insecure guy. I mean
that's a perfect car for a guy like me,
you know? Oh look at me, I'm
a winner, right? I'm a winter
dodge challenger 41
nothing. All right. Anyways,
uh, let's get on with the podcast here. I
got a lot of different sections to this.
I'm hoping you guys are actually
listening to this. If you are,
that means I figured out my new podcast
server that Mark Marin of dub did WTF
podcast, who I'm going to try to have
on as a guest, uh, in the next month.
Um,
this is my new server.
It's costing me about 36 bucks a month
and I'm still not charging for my fucking
podcast. This is a little
bit of guilt, so you know,
I figured you guys can pay me back.
Don't steal my DVD online. All right,
go on in order the fucking thing. I'm
giving you a podcast every God damn week.
Now I'm not gonna,
I'm not gonna lie to you.
I don't expect anybody in Indianapolis
or re anywhere remotely related to Peyton
manning to buy my DVD.
But the rest of you,
sons of bitches just go on and
pay for the damn thing. Okay?
We spent a lot of money on that.
We gave you a bunch of extras
or come out to one of my shows.
Pay me back that way. Okay. And whatever.
If you're in between jobs right now
and you're going through a rough time,
here's some free fucking comedy.
But when you hit it big, remember,
remember who fucking held you up?
Huh?
When you look down in the sand and
there was only one set of footprints.
That was when I carried
you with my podcast.
Look at me getting all biblical.
Why are you getting biblical bill?
I thought you don't believe in that shit.
You know why? Cause I have a confession.
I've got a confession to make to you guys.
You know what I did on Sunday and
I think this is why paint man,
he got his fucking ass kicked.
I actually hope you're all
sitting down at this point.
I actually went to church on Sunday
after all the Shit I talked about
organized religion and all that shit.
I actually went,
I went to church,
I went to fucking church. And, uh,
I don't know why it's one of these
deals is something about I haven't been
drinking, I'm trying to clean up my
act and the last 20 years, you know,
I've just slowly become a complete piece
of shit and I'm really trying to get
back to who the fuck I was. You
know, I used to be a good guy.
I used to not be cynical. I used
to believe in people. I had hope.
I gave to charities, you know,
I was a fucking swell guy.
Know 20 years of being on the road,
drinking who was corrupt club owners
fucking me over at the end of the weekend.
You know, you start to, uh, I got
no excuse, whatever, I'm a week.
Um, so whatever. So I was like, I dunno, I
need to, uh, I need to do something good.
So I was actually,
this is how far I went.
I actually considered going to confession
and not even because I believe in this
shit. I just wanted to see what the
priest was going to say. Cause I never,
you know, at the risk of
burning some of my new material,
I just never bought into that shit that
like I have to talk to God through you.
You know,
now you're,
you're some sort of voice and you want to
listen to all the fucked up shit I did.
As you look through the fucking screen,
pretending you're not looking at me,
you know,
plus I got admit,
I kind of want to see how many our
fathers and hail Mary's I was going to get
considering the last time I went
to confession. It was simple stuff.
Like I beat up my brother, you know, I uh,
had impure thoughts about my fucking,
you know,
whatever English teacher or
some stupid shit, you know,
why is that a sin?
Ace have this fucking language teacher.
When I was in, in middle school,
we didn't have junior high. It's,
this fucking girl was so
fucking ridiculously hot. Right?
And she used to wear these dresses with
a slit, go and write up the fucking side.
You know, a little Italian girl. She
was short. So she'd wear the sky, hey,
fuck me shoes. You know, every once in
a while she gave us a treat once a week.
You know, she come in with those
fucking things on it and it was really,
it was ridiculous. Um, and
not only that, she was,
she was my French teacher.
She's trying to teach me a
different fucking language weights.
So one week she comes in,
she literally has a sled
going up both sides.
And she had this habit she'd,
she'd rate whatever she wanted us
to learn and she would step back.
So she'd have one foot,
like,
I don't know how to explain.
It's like if you're a wide receiver
and you're looking at the quarterback
checking for the audible,
you got one foot in front of the other.
That's what she's still,
but she's got a slit on both sides.
So now not only do we see a
slip on the outside of the leg,
I can actually see the inside of
her fucking thigh on the other side.
I am in eighth grade. Okay.
My Dick is at is fucking,
you know,
saluting the troops at that point.
I might listen to what the fuck is
saying in English. Forget about French.
And then she ends up calling on me as
I'm sitting there with my little Woodrow
Wilson, right. And she's
like, ah, you know,
fucking whatever the fuck she
said in French. And I had no idea.
And I tried to play it off.
Then she got all fucking mad at me because
I lied to her and I didn't have the
emotional maturity be like,
really?
Why don't you put some
fucking clothes on sweetheart?
And maybe I'll pay attention to your
fucking language lesson here. All right.
You stand in here with half your
fucking who are hanging out.
You think I'm looking at chalk on
the board? You asshole. But I didn't,
I just sat there and stared at my
books and she screamed at me. And uh,
when she told me to go down in the office,
I did,
didn't even put up a fight that I miss
my bus home and I walked home in the rain
fucking saying all this shit that I wish
I had the balls to say, but I didn't.
All right. That was a sad memory. Okay,
let's plow ahead here. So anyways,
so I decided, I'm like, I
gotta go, I'm going to go to
fucking church, right? I got,
I got to start doing some
something good in my life,
something positive or whatever.
And for some reason,
I don't know why I'm going to church
because I don't believe in this shit.
I don't. But, um, I dunno.
My girlfriend's mom goes to church every
week. She's a sweetheart. I'm like,
you know, fuck this. I'm going to go
to church with my girlfriends mom. Huh?
That's a nice thing to do, right? Then
all my female listeners just go walk.
Didn't you just do that? Of course you
did. It's a fucking nice thing to do.
So, you know, and I'm going all out.
I haven't gone to God's house in like 20
years. So I'm like, what am I gonna do?
Go there with a button down and some
jeans and some shoes. Fuck that.
I broke out the tonight show with Conan
O'brien suit number that's shiny one
that some of you comes bitched about
some I fought this fucking HD and you can
see the inside of my nose.
It looked good in real life anyway,
so I put that on.
I'm looking like a fucking million
bucks or maybe I'm looking a little ray
Liotta. I don't know how I'm
looking, but I'm feeling good. Right?
Went to church and I walk in.
What's the first thing I see?
I see a big Jesus nailed on the cross,
you know?
And is he looking at me now
he's looking down and I'm like,
is he looking down because he's in
pain cause he's slowly dying from this
torturous device or is it part of the
guilt? Oh look what I did for you.
I hope you appreciate it.
You know,
so I'm my guy. You're thinking negative
bill. Don't think negatives is,
it's a good thing. It was a sunny day.
You know, it's been raining out here.
La is never more beautiful
than right after it rains. Wow.
That was the cheesiest
thing I've ever said.
I should just broken into a fucking song
right there. Reminds me of my mother
now.
You'd already as it fuck it.
And I don't know what beats down all
the smog and you can actually see out to
the ocean. It's fucking
awesome. So anyway,
so I sit down into the pew and I got
to admit, it's kind of bring it back.
Good memories. You know, we
used to go with the family.
I used to go to church every fucking week
from like third grade till I was like
22.
I don't think I missed a week.
And I go with my family and then
afterwards we go to fucking Dunkin donuts
stowed and we get from fucking donuts.
I don't know why we get a dozen
donuts and then we'd go home,
have Sunday breakfast, and then we all
sit around eating donuts as while we did.
It was a good thing though.
It was a family thing. It's
a part of, it was like, wow,
this is what I actually felt
better that I was in there
and right as I was
starting to feel better,
first fucking words out of the
priests mouth is, uh, he goes, hey,
thanks for coming out everybody.
I see a,
I see you all came out here
early to get it out of the way.
She could watch the super bowl.
That's what he says right off the bat.
It comes with the guilt.
What do you mean get it out of the way?
Fucking game comes on at
three 30 out here. What do
you got? A three o'clock mass.
You asshole. You don't, I'm not getting
an out of the way. How about this? Um,
I made time for it.
You fucking cunt.
I still have to go to the grocery
store and buy the fucking hamburger.
I came here first.
It was right out of his mouth.
First thing you fucking says right
here you go. All came here. Only
one to suffocate him with that
fucking smart he was wearing.
I was like, no, no, no,
no. You don't try to think fucking
positive. Try to think positive.
Stop looking at the negative cause there
is an element of this that does feel
good. There's an element of this that
feels right. So I'm still sitting.
Yeah. You know, and uh,
then all of a sudden they start reading
the stories and here comes the reader,
if you're not Catholic, they always
have a reader and they read a couple of,
a couple of little,
Jesus did sing a couple of songs and
then the priest comes in and he fucking
brings in home like the headliner, you
know, reads a little bit of Gospel.
So I don't want this guys doing it, these
reading scripture. I Dunno. I Dunno.
I Dunno the fucking words. I don't
know the technical words. So anyways,
the reader for this week comes up,
I swear to God,
he's like fucking 45 years
old and I shit you not,
he's wearing a boy scout shirt,
a fucking boy scout shirt,
and he has facial hair,
a boy scout shirt and facial
hair and you're in your forties.
I am I the only one who sees sex offender,
you know,
and you would think with the scandal that
has gone through the Catholic church,
they'd be like, hey dude, we
appreciate you coming in here.
But could you take off the fucking boy
scout uniform considering that's another
organization that doesn't exactly have
the greatest tap track record when it
comes to little boys, right?
But they don't. So I'm sitting
there going, no, no, no,
no. This guy's a good guy.
This guy's a good guy.
He stayed on the path of the right.
Unlike you, Mr [inaudible], this guy,
he stayed in scouting. All right? If
he diddled somebody at this point,
they would've figured it out.
Maybe he's just a good guy.
He knows how to start a fire without a
match. Let's listen to what he has to say.
All right, and what does he do? He
fucking goes up there and he starts,
this was basically the story.
Jesus is standing on the edge of a
lake as he is. You know what I mean?
James Brown had the cape. Jesus has
the lake. Everybody's got this shtick.
It's fucking show business,
right?
So Jesus is standing by the edge of the
lake and there's a couple of fishermen.
Of course, of course. There was like three
jobs back then. You are fucking black.
Smith of fishermen are a leper, okay? So
this is one of these fishermen stories,
right?
So the fishermen's Simon and some other
fucking Douche bag is sitting there
cleaning out their nets and
Jesus goes a Romy Romy out,
you know, 10 feet to
the lake. And they go,
absolutely wasn't like we weren't fucking
busy over here cleaning up after a
hard day's work. So they roll the dude
out there, he's 10 feet off shore,
and now he's preaching to the
people on the shore from a Robo.
You know, I'm sitting there going,
what? A fucking arrogant ass,
but I got to give it up to him.
That's a little showbiz there.
You stand on the beach,
you're just regular.
All of a sudden you're out
there in the water, you know,
all of a sudden it's like
he's got a stage, so whatever.
So now he's out there like the arrogant
ass. He is. He standing up in the boat,
which you're not supposed to do.
You're not supposed to fucking do that.
He just breaking the rule.
Just like when you see a cop
speeding in a fucking cruiser,
not using this directionals.
He's not even on a call.
What kind of fucking example you
set. So anyways, he starts preaching,
he's done preaching.
He then tells these fishermen to
take their nets and they go fishing.
And they were like, wait a minute, son of
God, not trying to step out of line here.
I know,
you know you came out of that debt
vagina that was never fornicated with uh,
you know,
we've been fishing all day and well,
you know the risk of sounding crass,
sounding crass, we haven't caught shit.
So Jesus goes,
am I not the son of God?
Did I not just tell you to bring your
fucking nuts out here? And they, yeah,
sorry man. What was I thinking? Right.
Okay. I had the little casino moment.
How I sticky head to that little
fucking hole. Yeah, you weren't laying,
that's why he had the fucking money ready.
Right.
So they grabbed their fucking nets.
Ali know that coke is Joe de
Rosa uses that line all the time.
So they grabbed their fucking nuts and
they bring it out to the lake and they go
fishing. And what happens,
not only do they catch fish,
they catch so much fucking fish that
it almost breaks their nets and they're
dragging them back. And Ah, Jesus,
best shit ever. And then he looks at
me, he goes, today, you caught fish.
Tomorrow you're going to fish for men.
And then they all walked away evidently
leaving their fish behind to follow
Jesus to go fish for men.
Can you fuck, I mean, what kind of a
fucking story is that? You're hungry.
You wanted the food. You're going to leave
that to go try to pick up some dudes.
And I'm listening to this with some guy
with a fucking boy scout fucking uniform
on.
I'm not making any of this shit up.
I was waiting for them
to start playing whether
girls, it's raining men. I don't
understand. I know it's a metaphor.
You're going to go fish for men.
Fucking Amway.
We got to get somebody
else to believe this shit.
What a crock of shit and catch shit. And
then he said, hey, put your netsuite has.
Then we got a bunch of
up, he said, come on,
let's go tell it to more people so I can
make more fucking money and live rent
free and not pay taxes. So anyways,
um, but I'm still feeling good.
There's something about,
there's something about going to
church though. It's, it's get me,
get me in my chest is something
that's still feeling good.
Oh my master telling story. Okay. I'm
keeping the fucking, the, the, the, the,
the peep, the blast for
me. People in this shit.
And I'm also keeping the Jesus freaks.
I'm driving you right to
the fork in the row. What?
Is he going to choose Jesus or is he
going to keep trashing organized religion?
Hang in there. Here we go. Getting
into the third act. So then the, uh,
the priest there, the headliner, he comes
up, you know, and I'm thinking, all right,
let's see. He reads the fucking Gospel
and everything and now I'm waiting for it.
He's going to say, and what does
he do? He pops in a CD. All right?
And all of a sudden we'll
listen to some cardinal,
some bishop from the Vatican
doing a guest spot and you know,
and what does the guy said he teaches at?
He does some quick little bullshit
up front going, praise Gigi.
You breed him fruit view [inaudible]
wonderful day and we'll, you know,
give to you to hear me g and g old Jesus.
Right?
And when he's done saying that Shit,
little five minutes of that shit just
stroke and you with the Jesus stuff,
what does he do? Huh? Come on people.
You haven't seen this episode before.
What's his next move?
What is the move after they butter you
up and hit you with the guilt and tell
you how thankful you should
be for, Geez, what does he do?
He starts hitting us up for money.
So I sit ups up for money for some of
the poorer churches that aren't making it
and we got a quota.
We got a $41,000 quota and
we didn't make it last year.
You know, it goes on and fucking
on. Right, right. Then, right?
Then my girlfriend's mother, who
is hilarious, leans over, she goes,
of course you'd have to come this week
because she knows, I think it's bullshit,
right? Fucking guy in the cub scout
uniform. Now they're asking for money.
So we're laughing. And then
the priest, when they finally,
he now he shuts off the boombox. Wherever
the fuck away. I know it was a bomb box,
but they're headed hidden.
So it seemed holy, you know,
then he spends the rest of his
homily telling people, you know,
where to fill in their credit card
number, like in, in unbelievable detail.
You pick up the envelope in the front.
If you look over there on the left,
if you fill in your credit card,
I'm sure a lot of you don't have
your credit card numbers memorized.
Trying to make little fucking jokes. You
know, and one of the things was, you know,
if you don't want this to be a monthly,
uh, um, deduction on your credit card,
just, you know, check the box. I love that
they're trying to get you every month.
And the only way they're not going to
charge your card every month is if you do
something there need,
you know,
they're hoping all those fucking old
people with heart to hear and they're not
going to check the fucking box. And the
next month I couldn't buy ODL pole. Right.
They don't give a fuck. And then
that was it. And then the mass ended.
But there was something down
still. I don't know, it felt good.
You know what it was when I walked
out and they were having their,
their little fucking bake sale and they
will have in their raffles and I bought
my girl's mom a ticket to win some
fucking pots and pans and shit. You know,
it felt good because
you're around good people.
And that's what I hate about religion
is because the people who show up,
they had good fucking people and
they get fleeced. You know, you know,
it's funny is actually I
gave two bucks if you know,
bought a raffle ticket for the pots and
pans and then we walked by another table
and the glaze like, oh, you know, this
one's only two bucks for this raffle.
And I look what they're raffling off
and was one of those fucking, you know,
Virgin Mary pictures with his like
holy blood dripping down her face or
something like that. And it's like, yeah,
I really don't want that hanging
in my apartment. Okay. It's just,
it's creeping me out. I'll take
some pots and pans, you know,
I'll make a rump roast, have
a little get together. Right.
I'm not going to wash anybody's feet
as they come through the fucking door.
I leave that for gcs. Um,
so anyways, there you go.
Actually went to church and,
uh,
I didn't buy into any of the bullshit that
the fucking guys with the uniforms on,
we're saying,
but there was something that I kind of
felt a little bit nice and evidently
they're having a car wash on Saturday.
I'm going to go buy,
I'll go by, I'll get my fucking car wash.
Why not the car wash in my neighborhood?
They're always protest and that they're
not paying the fucking illegals to wash
the cars or fuck it. I don't know.
So there you go. That aren't a spark.
Some fucking discussion.
One side's going to say,
I sold out in the other side's going to
keep trying to push me towards Jesus.
It's not going to work. I know what
the feeling was when I went in there.
That's that overall natural spirituality
that you're born with. Then, uh,
organized religion. Okay. I'm
going to give them a bent.
The benefit of the doubt that they
started off with a good, a good purpose,
but they hoard it out. They whore out.
That feeling. When you do something nice,
you feel good.
You know,
I felt good cause I was there with my
girlfriend's mother and it was a nice
thing to do and I wasn't hung over and
I wasn't a Douche bag the night before I
did my shows. Everything was good.
I didn't hurt anybody. You know,
I can do that without,
uh, you know, you know,
I can do that and still have a fucking
chicken sandwich on, on Good Friday.
Whatever the fuck it is when I'm not,
you know,
tell me what to eat and when I can
jerk off a fucking jerk off all I want.
He cuts. All right, let's
get to the topics here.
Spent a great fucking podcast. She
got to give it up. Come on, man.
It's been a great fucking podcast.
Started off with some music
I got into religion. I'm,
I'm feeling this one and right now. Why
don't you know what I'm doing right now?
You think? You think I'm fucking
pat myself on the back? I'm not,
I'm actually killing time right now
because I'm trying to get to the fucking,
where the hell is it? The questions
for the week. Podcast. Quick questions.
Click twice. All right,
let's get into this.
Let's get into this as quickly as we
can and then I'm getting Outta here.
Um, all right. Oh, here's
a new one. This is,
this is one that I like because as you
can tell, I'm really into sports. Um,
I'm into sports the way I'm not into g
Jewish and is that how I spelled obscure?
O. B. S. C. U. R. E. Sign.
You spell obscure Cy. You
spell anything that's fucking,
that looks weird. That made sense
to my brain when I wrote that.
You know what's funny is I'm so fucking
stupid. That might even be right,
but now I'm looking at it and it
just looks wrong. You ever do that?
You have actually spell
it right and you're like,
there's no fucking way I got it right.
I'm too stupid.
And then you look it up on
the Internet like Holy Shit,
I got to write and actually got it right.
I wish I could retain that information
because I know God damn well.
The next time I write it, I'm going to
go through the exact same process again.
That happens to me with that.
The word restaurant,
I can never remember if it's
Ari, s. T. A. U. R. A. N.
T or R e. S. T. A. Fuck. A. R. A. U. N. T.
I keep always figure out whether
Hugo's all right, here we go. Yeah,
that's, that's what I get to
say. It's a great podcast.
Now it's going to fucking Peter out.
Alright. Obscure movies, bands in books.
If you guys have read a great book,
if you've seen a really cool band and if
you've seen a really cool movie that is
not, you know, I mean, don't, don't
fucking recommend Lord of the rings.
Okay? I'll just check out this band
you to, you know, the guy, the guy.
You've got a pretty good catalog,
you know, just some shit that is um,
you know, under the radar a little
bit. Here's one foyer that uh,
one of my brothers actually recommended.
Uh, they recommended the movie,
the conversation that stars are
gene Hackman, a young Harrison Ford,
and that fucking do to place Frito.
I can never remember his name,
but he is the greatest IMD baby
I've ever seen in my life. Okay,
go look it up.
You know,
he died tragically young of some
disease is fucking horrible,
but you can't mess with his I MDB.
He never did any meet
the parents bullshit.
This guy was in the godfather
that he did the conversation.
Then he did the godfather part two,
then he did dog day afternoon,
and then he did the deer hunter
and then he tragically passed away.
It's not even tragic he did it.
There's no reason for him to continue.
Guy Was the shit. I was
actually reading up on him. He,
I guess he was one of the reasons why,
you know,
Al Pachino moved down in New York to
become an actor and he was like his best
friend who was a really sad story.
He was engaged to a Meryl Streep,
phenomenal actor. And I don't even
know his name, very tragic, whatever.
But the conversation is a great
movie and I think it's very, uh,
it,
it holds up and it's very,
I don't even know what the
fucking word is of this time,
whatever the word is to say that.
All right,
here's something somebody else
recommended. Somebody said, um,
he's a couple movies. Recommend you
there, Woody Allen pictures. Um,
there's not a lot of people talk about,
one of them is called whatever works.
I'm not going to describe
it because I'll ruin it.
All I'm going to say simply say is it's
worth a watch if you've not already
indulged. Also, have you seen the
a flick Alan did a few years ago,
a few years ago called match point.
Definitely not your average woody
Allen picture, but it was really good.
So I'm going to check those out.
And somebody actually
this weekend recommended,
I can't remember what Sylvester Stallone,
I talked about people getting microchipped
and they were trying to say that
semester like demolition man was that
the name of it was saying that movie was
so on point as to what the
fuck is going on right now.
And they basically talked about the
phasing out of cash and everybody getting
fucking microchipped and if you fuck
with the deal, they turn your chip off.
I think it was called demolition man. Um,
if anybody knows what the name of it is,
please let me know and I'll, I'll, I'll
reconfirm it next week on the podcast. Um,
and here's a book that somebody saying,
um, if you don't want to read Socrates,
this woman from Germany,
I thought that was really cool.
Somebody from Germany is
actually listening to this,
actually recommended this saying
Socrates is really dry, obviously,
because it was fucking 9,000
years ago. And, uh, so they said,
if you want to,
I have a better read for you,
which is based on the great philosophies
of soccer, Socrates, Aristotle,
and Plato.
Uh,
it's called Sophie's world is the name
of the book and has the same core ideas
and it really takes you
to the edge of your mind.
How great is that to describe a book? It
takes you to the edge of your mind. See,
I love stuff like that.
There's no fucking way.
I'm not gonna read that Sophie's world.
It's spelled s o.
P. H. I. E. S. Come on man, start
ringing. Stop being a dumb fuck like me.
Come on everyone. Let's, let's try it.
Let's try to try to improve ourselves.
You know, I'm trying, I went to church.
I try not to fucking heckle through.
You know,
it was funny when I was there is I was
saying prayers I had not seen said in
like 20 fucking years and this is one
pray prayer after the homily at in
Catholic Church that is like,
it takes a minute or a minute and a
half everyone to say and it's like,
and it goes to something like we
believe in one God the Father Almighty,
the maker of Heaven and earth of all
that is seen and unseen. Ababa Ba,
I don't even know what the fuck it was
but it was like one of those things where
like I was just,
I was just reciting it like a fucking
Zombie to the point I was laughing because
I couldn't remember it,
but as people were saying around me,
I was just right on it. You know,
kind of like when there was a song,
if you're really into this band in high
school and you hadn't listened to the
song in 20 years and all of a sudden
it comes out and you're just fucking
finding the words like where the fuck are
these coming from? Cause they, they get,
they had embedded in my head 20 straight
fucking years and not missing mass,
um, or whatever it was. 14
years. All right, here's,
here's the last thing I'm going to read
for this week and then I'm gonna do some
overrated, underrated. Um, all right.
Some advice somebody asking me
about abroad over there. Dear Bill,
since you have no idea who I am,
I don't mind writing to you and explaining
my current problem I'm experiencing
with a certain female.
And since you don't know me,
you'll probably be more than honest.
You'll be more honest than the girls I
tell this story to. Okay, here's the deal.
I'm currently chasing this girl that
I've known for a year who for some reason
goes through phases where one
day I'm the greatest thing ever.
And then for the whole next I could die
from cancer and she wouldn't blink an
eye. She also has a tendency to make me
jealous on purpose for no reason at all.
I've confronted her on the issue and her
explanation was that she hates when I
get jealous. All right. Right there dude.
She is standing on top of an old
Victorian House waving the beware.
I'm a cunt flag.
All right,
so you got to get away from this girl.
This is the,
you know what this girl's deal is?
She wants to be in a relationship.
She doesn't want to be in one with you,
but she doesn't want to be alone,
all right?
And in the back of her head,
she knows she's wasting her time by
hanging out with you rather than going out
trying to find Mr, right?
So what she's doing is,
is rather than dealing with that herself
as she's taking it out on you, you know,
and,
and another thing she's doing is really
sadistic is she knows that you like her
and she's playing you. You
know, just playing with you,
playing with your fucking mind and just
trying to see the shit that she can get
you to do. Fuck her. All right, this, you
know what? You want to fuck that girl.
This is the, you got to walk away
from her. Walk away from her.
Go hang out with your buddies. If you
don't have any buddies, go get somebody.
Go hang out in a bar and do what
I always say to do. All right,
cause you're wounded right now and you're
going to be in the bar and you can be
feeling now.
Well,
these girls don't make me feel the way
that each other girl does. Fuck that.
You got to beat that feeling down and
you beat it down with alcohol and hitting
on girls. You don't give a shit
about getting the fucking game.
It's going to build up your self esteem.
Now,
I'm not saying be mean
to these other girls.
Don't take out your heartbreak that
this other fucking chick gave you.
Don't take that out on these other girls
because then you become a cop to go out
there and fucking find out
how your personality works.
You know it's going to build up your
self esteem. Next time she sees you,
you got to fucking broad on each arm.
She's going to get competitive.
Next thing you know, your Dick
is in her fucking mouth. Okay?
And you finish in their son.
All right.
Sorry man. I stood up. I stood up. I
started feeling like a fucking coach.
I want a little big there. Don't finish
unless she says it's okay. All right.
But if you bang are
definitely wear a condom.
You have fucking respect for yourself.
You have respect for your body.
All right to go out there
and talk some shit, son,
you had shoulder pads that'd be fucking
banging on right now and send you out
right through the fucking tunnel
into some meat market. Okay.
Overrated. Underrated for
this week. A overrated.
This guy says children right off
the Bat, I love this guy. He said,
I'm sick and tired of people
doing shit for the children.
We got to do it for the children.
I understand that you need to
look after infants and toddlers,
but I remember being nine, 10 and 11 and
at that age I really didn't give a fuck.
I was too busy trying to hump
some girl behind a garage,
all the while trying not to get caught
by the people who were supposedly looking
after me.
My parents,
half of the little twats just want to
fucking eat cookies and ice cream and play
Xbox 360 all day. So I say, fuck the kids,
help the adults that are struggling
with bills and shit. I love that.
What a fucking great guy.
I love him because he's speaking from
his heart and a right in the end,
it petered out with his ignorance.
Fuck the kids and,
and help the adults who are struggling
with bills and shit. I love and shit.
It really just knocks it down by fucking
90 Iq points right down to my level.
All right, I'll go with that one. Exactly.
Why don't we help out the fucking people
without jobs. And then this is other,
his other one underrated. Uh, he
says whores and he spelled it h.
O. A. R. S.
I think that's hilarious because isn't
board spelt with a B, which is a pig,
you know, which is another fucking
derogatory term from a woman.
So he's kind of combined whores
and bores whores, Hoa ars.
He said there's nothing like a good whore.
Aho Ar.
She will make you appreciate a good woman.
I can't tell you how many times I've
looked at a stripper or some country,
little whore and thought to myself,
thank God she goes,
she goes home to some other dumb
fuck wives and girlfriends hate them,
but until you spend the night at
a club full of skanks and whores,
you can't really appreciate a good woman.
See,
I like that because it's actually
positive for women. That's right.
That's absolutely right.
I totally agree with you on that one.
And that's the podcast for this week
and I'm not going to go long because I
think this was a fucking great one.
I had a blast on this [inaudible] I
say a blast. How fucking old am I?
I had a rock and good time. No,
I did. I feel fucking vindicated.
So fucking vindicated.
Peyton manning was exactly who the fuck
I thought he was and they were crowning
him king crown and I'm fucking king.
And I'm not saying that that
dude one eventually become king,
but you got to do some shit first.
That's all part of that marketing
shit where they're selling.
They're just selling you a f like
before they ever do it. You know,
fucking guys come in and lead.
They get a sneaker contract before
they gain a yard. It's bullshit.
When the Superbowl's when in the end,
drive your team down the field,
tie up to score, winning her over in over
time, and then I'll give it up to you.
I'm not that much of a home or where I'm
going to be. I'm going to be a contract.
You've got to fucking do it first
before people say you're the greatest.
All right. I know I repeated
myself, but you know it's not,
it's not a lot of times in life when I'm
fucking right and I was right on that.
So congratulations to the saints and a,
all the fans are the saints and all that.
It was fucking awesome to
see that you guys deserve it.
I hope you make a bunch of fucking money
down there and you rebuild the houses
and you give them back to the fucking
people who previously owned them rather
than the cons. Who Want
to build cheesecake? Yeah.
Factories down there. All right, that's
it. I'll talk to you guys next week.
Have a wonderful
[inaudible] [inaudible]
you.