Okay.
Hey, what's going on?
It's Bill Burr and it's time for the
Monday morning podcast for Monday,
January 4th, 2016 a brand new year.
Brand New Year. Brand new you.
Are you going to make the changes
that you've always wanted to make?
Where are you going to get up?
Tell yourself you gotta change
and actually go out there. Change.
I always love the pressure at the
beginning of the new year to be like, God,
you know there's that one great thing,
right? Like what? You're like guide,
shaken off the last year. You know, like,
I don't know who the
fuck that guy was. Right?
Like lie to yourself like you're not
the same person fucking one minute later
when it becomes a new year or you do
the real childish thing as you blame
everybody else for your own
fucking problems, you know? Okay,
wait for this year to be over, man. She
spent so much fucking bullshit to share,
to be like towards fucking you. I
can't wait for the next fucking year.
It's like, Dude, oh well are
you going to change anything?
You're going to break up with the person,
you're going to stop getting drunk and
being a Dick and picking fights in a bar,
right? All of that shit. Oh,
you just gonna think that magically,
because this is six there
now instead of a five,
that all of a sudden the world's gonna
Change. You don't have to adjust. Oh,
am I reprimanding somebody right
now? I think I am. I don't know why.
I have no idea why I'm recording this.
Uh, at about eight 30 in the morning,
last time delays time, my wife's
still sleeping downstairs,
so I gotta I gotta try
to stay at medium energy,
medium energy here, um, for the
rest of this fucking podcast. Um,
okay.
But whatever, I'm kind of,
I've gotta be honest with you.
I went to bed last night and I was sad.
I love the holidays and I'm sad that
they're fucking over. I had another great,
you know,
holiday break and to think that it's
all going to fucking start over again,
you know, here we go.
Okay.
Now the fucking year or doing the road
right and shit and doing all this stuff
here we fucking go again. Yeah.
The whole thing just got, oh,
just totally overwhelming with me
and I was just fucking laying in bed.
You know,
you know when you do fucking look too
far ahead into your fucking life, um,
okay.
You know, it just gets
too fucking overwhelming.
And then maybe you start
hearing the saint that,
you know what song I always hear in my
head, I always say that's that song.
Make the world Jolo way.
Sub Did sub dead Ed,
get it off my shoulders.
Um, that's what I feel like the most
pathetic emotion you could have.
Make the world go away. Can you just
get to go in there and just pout,
you know?
Okay.
I got to ask a question about depression.
Is it actually a chemical thing or is
that just an adult world word for like
somebody who's just kind of
sort of powering, you know,
I think a lot of times when people
go, I'm depressed, it's just you.
You're just kind of
feeling sorry for yourself.
And you know the ones that say it's like
a chemical imbalance. You just like,
you just shift your head really quickly.
The chemicals go back to the other
way and you'll chair up, you know,
don't believe the
mainstream media, you know,
in all the pharmaceutical
companies with their drugs, man,
is there anything funnier they want
somebody who's not a fucking doctor,
you know, just starts going on and on
about you. Let me tell you something, man,
I'm telling you, all you gotta do is
just go up, walk up to an oak tree,
can't be a barge, can't be a maple.
Go Up to an oak tree and just bite on
the little sapling. You just not on it,
right?
You got a little piece of bark and you
stick it between you just like Choo.
You just stick it to you go and all of
that. And your depression will go away.
Yeah, it is true.
It is true that native Americans used
to do it and they were never depressed.
That's what they used to do until the
white man came and took their bark away.
Now look at them all grumpy. Just
like the white man cause they,
cause they couldn't get any more
saplings with the tree bark there. Um,
anyways, uh, for,
as he and his wife left yesterday
so the house is empty again.
It just stinks man. I was having
a great fucking time and join it.
Now it's gone. I, I'll
fucking starts over again.
I'm already starting the year
off. My office is a fucking mess.
You know, I'm, I'm the worst.
I can't find this sticker to put on my
fucking license plate. I know. I got it.
I don't know where the fuck it
is. It just, it all starts over.
They just fun times over. Fun
Time is over. You know what?
We still got the Christmas tree up because
Nia liked it extra a lot this year.
So I still have today. I still have to
go through that sad fucking operation,
upbringing, that goddamn thing outside.
And I told you I dispose that
thing like a fucking mob head.
You're never going to find the body by
fucking neighbor already threw his right
out on the street. Just
tosses it out there, right?
Some dead hooker, you know what I mean?
Cut The fucking thing up and you put
it in the barrel. That's what you do.
I get mine might the green barrel, right?
We got the green barrels out here and
that's just like grass clippings and all
that shit.
I have a whole fucking Christmas tree
and then the lid closes completely.
You'd have no fucking idea. I mean,
come on people. How difficult is it?
You cut all the branches off.
They need just left with the trunk
and then he just section it up.
It says drop the thing. Right. The
fuck in there. It's not a problem.
He wait. You safety goggles, you
know, so nobody can see you cry.
And as you're doing it,
I don't understand what the fucking
problem is that God damn it,
get out there and dispose of
the fucking tree. Correct. Um,
environmentally,
wouldn't it be more correct if you just
thought to spread it across your lawn?
The tree is just going to end up in a
landfill or even worse out in the ocean.
They don't, the lack of the Oh shit. Um,
I can't wait to get to this fucking
thing later on in this podcast with this
guy. He's trying to claim that the, uh,
the earth can sustain 100 billion
people. I really cannot see,
I cannot wait to, I just glanced at
it and looked at it and it's just,
I just, how the fuck you, you
will arrived at that number.
And I actually tried to find shit.
I started looking up how many fucking
people the Earth can sustain. And uh,
what I've immediately found was
that nobody could say for certain,
but the numbers estimated we're nowhere
near a hundred billion fucking people.
How to billion. Sorry.
So I cannot wait to read this guy somehow
claiming that there's enough farmland.
Okay.
To feed a hundred fucking
okay.
Billion people. Yeah. I don't know. Okay.
Did we stack each other on top
of one another? And even then,
do elephants get to roam free anymore?
Where all the fucking animals?
Um, if there was odd a
billion people on the planet,
I would think that cannibalism
would slowly start to become legal.
They would have a Beta of
farm people or stock people,
that's what they'd call them.
And they would be simply be, um,
used for food, you know?
Okay.
We just, you know, and of course
it would be, uh, you know,
the evil white man would decide who it
is that gets eaten first. You know, baby,
they'd start with like the pygmies or
something like that because it'd be like,
all right, well, you know, they're
a, they are of a particular race,
but they're not as tall as most
people in that race. So, you know,
there's sort of bite size, little like
sliders, right? Sliders. They like,
she would sliders, you know, get
a little honey bun, you know,
stick a fucking ankle between the
two. Right. Why would you do an ankle,
ankle meet? Um,
so anyways, I've, I still feel fucked
up from the rose bowl man. I still,
you know, I barely got any
sleep with Paul being out here.
And then we also performed New
Year's Eve, uh, down the Orpheum.
And I bought this suit
to wear New Year's Eve.
I found it like over the summertime
it was this all white suit.
Okay.
Jacket and pants. But you know, from,
from a distance it reads all white,
but when you come up to it, it
had these tiny black polka dots,
you know what I mean? Just tiny. And uh,
I walked into the store and it was on
like the fucking 70% off rack because it's
really one of those things like, where
the fuck are you ever gonna wear that?
And I saw, I was like, that's a
perfect suit for fucking new year's.
You put the black fucking
solid black shirt underneath.
They were little black pocket
square, right? And your walk out,
they're like John Travolta. But I bet book
[inaudible] you can tell by the way
I tell jokes, I'm a fucking act.
No time for originality. I'm sorry.
She fucking shit jokes. Fucking the
jokes. I don't like to use concepts.
I know. Anyways.
So that was once again me standing to
the side of the stage going like a,
I am either go that people either going
to like this suit or I'm going to get
heckled the entire time I'm
out here. But either way,
either way it's gonna add to
the fucking show. But, uh,
as I predicted it was new
year's, I addressed the suit.
I said this is the only night I could
wear it. And people left and it was a, uh,
it was a great fucking time.
Great old theater. And uh,
I had a bunch of people come out, um,
a bunch of friends, you know, people
I hadn't seen in a couple of years.
People that you know, kind of
in my life. It was awesome, man.
I love doing new year's
out here in La Cause uh,
I don't have to travel
or anything like that.
And I get to do the job
I love to do. However,
I think that's the last
New Year's Eve I'll do.
I think I'll do like the 30th next time
because I gotta tell ya the second show
ends right. By the way,
I had to do the countdown on like
two jokes before my closing joke.
I was like halfway through this one
pit that I'd been trying to work on.
I kept fucking up the ending and I was
going to try a new ending to it because
the ending was too sad for every fucking
city in this nation other than Dallas,
Texas, Dallas, Texas. Fucking enjoy
the shit out of the original ending.
Um, and I'm right in the middle of
that bit and I see that it's 1159.
So then I had to get out of the pit,
take a pause, and then do the countdown,
and then the streamers came out.
Right. Lovely. Nia came out on stage,
gave me a kiss. All the
guys came, you know,
we fucking waves and everything and then
everybody gets off the stage and then I
had to go back into my act,
which was uh, uh, I dunno,
it just ended up being funny because
it was really weird. So anyways,
um, we ended up doing the
show and then as we leave,
um, we're stuck in this brutal
traffic. I'm like, what the fuck?
There must've been some going
on cause we went downtown La,
that must have been
something going on, um,
down at like la live or some shit down
there that's right near the staples
center.
And then I fucking realized the next day
it was motley crew's final show ever at
the staple center. And
um, so I was like, ah,
fuck, that's the traffic we get stuck in.
And there's actually a clip up on
youtube of, you know, Tommy Lee,
the drummer does,
he has a whole fucking rollercoaster
attached to his drum kit where it turns
upside down and it goes out over the
crowd and then comes back and all that
shit. I mean the right
there alone. You know,
if you're the other members in
the band, you gotta be like, dude,
this better be fucking worth it because
the amount of money that's coming out of
our checks to fucking carry that
rig out on the fucking road.
You know what I mean? That's
one of those overhead costs.
So I don't know if you
guys have seen the video.
It's their last fucking show
ever and the thing gets stuck.
It gets stuck and Tommy is upside down
on this thing in this roadie scamper and
up the side of it,
like the fucking apes and plan into the
apes when they were on the Golden Gate
Bridge right there.
Scampering up the side of this thing
and Tommy is just upside down like,
what the fuck man?
The fuck it digs busted.
He's like, hey la. He's like,
what? You look,
you look at it too soon when I'm hanging
upside down in Los Angeles and he's
just hanging upside down.
It's the most excrutiatingly
uncomfortable thing I've seen her perform.
I have to go through in a long time.
He did. What the fuck he could do.
I mean, once you just go, well,
fuck the role of coach to her man,
and you're still lagging upside
down. I mean, what do you do?
It's just fucking brutal in the fact
that it happened on the very last show.
You know, I don't want
to start any infighting.
I know the band doesn't exist anymore,
but I think Vince Neil did it.
I think the lead singer probably
all these years, you know,
he's used to being out front and all
the chicks digging them, you know,
walking around with his
Barbie hair and all that.
And then all the drama goes all the
way out over the crowd and everybody's
looking at him and maybe he got
sick of it after all these years.
The amount of money that was coming out
of his paycheck to bring that fucking
loopty loop roller coaster with
the fucking drum kit in it.
And he probably went, probably said,
hey, everybody look at that over there.
And then he just pulled a fuse.
Uh, that doesn't make any sense,
Bill. Then he sabotaging
his own show. Wow. You know,
I can have a fucking theory,
somebody could just email me with no
fucking links or anything whatsoever and
just tell me that the earth
can sustain 100 billion people
anyways. So we, uh, we're
stuck in that traffic.
I didn't get home until like a one 31 45,
fell asleep around two and then I had to
be up at 10 if 10 after five to then be
outside for the next 13 hours at the, uh,
at the rose bowl this year we
brought eight people and um,
okay.
One of my buddies who went there,
he just called it the goon parade
and I gotta be honest with you. Uh,
that's kind of what we were,
I don't remember so much of it.
I remember the whole game cause I just
stopped drinking cause I had to drive.
So I just remember walking to the stadium
and after that I remember the entire
fucking game. Um, so I'll take
you through what I remember.
So we fucking get there, right? First
time ever. We get this so fucking early.
They haven't even opened the gates
yet. So when we finally get in,
we're parked outside the VIP parking.
I mean we had like a five minute walk
to the stadium was fucking tremendous.
And uh, I remember Barton, nick
given me a Miller high life,
the big grin on his face,
cause we always had the Miller high
life to start the day law had got his
fucking law. I had made it by
the way he made it, you know,
I'll never smile again. Um,
he made it and uh,
he got all three of his fires going
and getting ready for the breakfast
sandwiches.
And I want to say that I waited
till after I had law heads.
Unbelievable breakfast sandwiches.
The best breakfast sandwich I have
every fucking year is that one.
And it was absolutely delicious. And my
favorite thing was looking over at firs,
he, after he was two bites in
and I was like, Hey Paul, I go,
how's that breakfast sandwich? And he
just fucking shot me. He look like,
are you fucking kidding me?
So I was already site and I knew he was
going to have a great time. And, um,
after that it was like, Hey, I'm like,
who wants a heater? Everybody's like,
yeah, right. So he poured like fucking
eight of them and I had these, these,
those big square ice cubes.
I had made those and brought him over
in a ziplock bag, like a fucking,
you know, kilo a coke.
So I drop him into everybody's
Plastic Cup in this so big,
they don't make it all the way
down to the bottom of the glass.
So the booze is actually below the ice
level and everybody's laughing. I'm like,
well, you just got to fucking,
he got to pull more bows in there and yet
he put your hand over the ice cube and
it'll melt down. And that
became the technique.
And then after that it just became
like a slide shelf just to stuff.
I remember,
I remember a partner does this thing every
year he gets off the dino gets out of
the truck and he just screams at the
top of his lungs. Ladies and gentlemen,
welcome to the grand daddy of a ball.
And everybody's always terrified,
sort of laughing, whatever.
So these Iowa fans, somebody just said,
oh, we do not need that voice here.
And immediately we're
not liking us. And uh,
I dunno. I think that for whatever
reason, they were really, they were like,
I want to say older than me, but I'm
pretty fucking old at this point.
I'm 47 I think they were in their 50s
and for whatever reason they were playing
Drake. All right.
And it was like fucking seven in the
morning and their fucking music was louder
than our music. So we're sitting there,
the sun hasn't even come
up yet and we'll listen to,
you used to call me on your cell
phone, you'll use to you. You too.
And it's just was fucking,
we're doing like, oh God.
I think me playing that fucking song,
like that song is like, that's like,
there's a few songs that get played so
much that you never need to hear them
again.
I think the original song
was in the mood binding.
Benny Goodman, who was
a Glenn Miller Dad at,
at dead dead dead [inaudible] too.
But I bet I never need to hear
that song ever again. Right.
I'd say book ending for way back in the
day to fucking right now it goes in the
mood. Glenn Miller and then a cell phone
by Drake. I know
it can only mean one thing. Oh, he's
such a bitch in that fucking song.
It's basically, hey, I used
to just fuck you. I use to,
I use you and any she moves away and then
he's upset that the woman got on with
the life.
Okay.
You know what a fucking he's is he one
of those possessive guys who wants,
he fucks something and he feels like
he owns it for the rest of his life.
Let it go dude. All you were
doing was fucking, or now what?
Now you want her because
she's not there anymore
to come over and lick your balls
and shape up your beard afterwards.
I mean fucking move on
with your life. Drake.
Yo Yo yo yo Yo yo shit. That's
fucking going on. And all I know.
And they were annoyed with
how loud Bart Nick yelled.
So I don't know what happens.
Somewhere between the beer that
shot and a breakfast sandwich.
I glance over and the older guy
is chirping and fucking Bart,
Nick's ear and Bart. Nick is
just staring straight ahead,
600 yard stare,
just standing there and I see the guy
talk and talk and talking and then I just
see Joe just shrug his shoulders
and be like, well, you know,
I don't like your music.
And I gotta be honest with you fucking,
I don't know what else he said.
But 10 minutes later those people were
just gone and we never saw them again.
I don't know if they had like
some VIP fucking, you know,
Iowa Hawkeye fucking barbecue thing,
that tent that they would
go into. I have no idea.
But we would die and laugh and
they had one conversation with Joe,
like the heck do you mind
keeping it down a little bit?
And Joe just gave him the
death fucking, you know,
the 600 yard stare and uh, that
was it. They just fucking left.
So that problem was solved.
And we would throw in the football around
[inaudible] I remembered everything
but forgot the bacon and
uh, what's his face like?
I was able to call an audible and he had
some bison meat or something like that
and Bacon Grease figure that one out.
I don't know how the fuck he did it,
but um,
okay.
Yeah.
And everything was going great and I was
throwing the football around and then
at some point I was just so
fucking hammered that I fell down
and I was one of those drunk falls where
it took me like 17 I started falling
and it took like 17 seconds for me to
fall. And the entire time I was saying,
I'm sorry, uh, it's now known yet
it's now known as the, I'm sorry,
fall.
And it took me so long to fall that just
about everybody at the tailgates site.
And uh, I think if what I
happened was I was standing,
well, I had had this tent, you know,
one of those four posted 10 things.
I was standing underneath it.
And unbeknownst to me was right behind
me was my cooler and all the other
coolers and all the bags of groceries
sort of sprinkled out. Right.
And I was talking and I did an about
face to start walking and immediately
tripped over the first cooler. All right.
And as I was trying to get my leg to an
open area without stepping on hamburger
buns, I just, you know,
there wasn't any space to put my
feet down and I was doing like,
it was almost like a wide receiver after
they catch a football and they tried to
stay in bounds a dance down the
sidelines. I was doing that,
but in between condiments and food
and shit like that. And I just,
I never regained my balance,
but I didn't go down full of,
I swear to God, if it was probably real
time was probably like a 42nd fall,
but that's a long time, you know, if you
just fall, Bam, you're on the ground.
Yeah.
You know, in under a second. Right.
I would think depending less,
you're really short and you get there
a little quicker. So I just kept going.
Sorry. Sorry. I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
And right is like my buddy Nate came
over to try and stop me from falling.
I just,
I fucking landed on my back and I
twisted my left knee and I hear the whole
place laughing and I was
laughing evidently my last step,
I stepped in some avocado and slipped on
that and I just fucking went down like
just thud right on my back.
I landed like a wrestler so it didn't
even hurt where it was just my entire
backside hit the ground
at the same time. And um,
I remember talking about it
later and I was like, yeah,
but I didn't spill my drink. I didn't
spill my drink. And everybody's like,
yeah, you did. You did. You spilled
it all with the front of your jacket.
So, um,
okay.
Then I remember getting up
the apple pies out. Why?
Remember the brisket and the ribs
being done and those were delicious.
Lai had killing it as
always. And then, um,
I think I smoked a cigar next. Yeah,
I smoked a cigar and then we had the
apple pies and everybody freaked out and
they loved them. And then I was, yeah.
Then I smoked a cigar and I was like,
all right, I gotta fucking sober up
here because, uh, it's six hours,
the game will be over and we'll be
done. And then I gotta drive. So, um,
oh fuck. Hang on a second. Hang on.
Okay.
All right. I'm back. Sorry about that.
Had blew my fucking nose. So anyway,
so let me get into the A,
we get into the game and I still don't
know his fucking name because I was
hammered. Um,
the Ronnie back for Stanford just
was right as we got to the stadium.
You already ran for a touchdown
and then it was just like,
it was like a fucking Hollywood
movie. They couldn't stop this kid.
The kid even had another one. He
ran like 70 yards for a touchdown.
They had to bring it back. They just
couldn't fucking get the kid down. Um,
and before you knew it, it was
like 28 to nothing, 28 to nothing.
Then it was 35 to nothing.
And W we still had like half,
half of the second quarter that
the fucking gay was just over.
It still was the worst rose bowl game as
far as being competitive that I'd been
to slash the greatest individual
performance I've ever seen.
We got to see that kid.
He set the record for the most all
purpose yards ever in a rose bowl.
Um, and this is the granddaddy of a malts.
The original roles, uh, the original,
uh, I guess bull game, um,
even though the Yale Bulls,
the original bull stadium
figured that one out anyways. Um,
so we got to see that.
And fortunately during halftime I
didn't have to watch the Stanford band.
Um, which by the way, it's
just, I mean, could you,
could they be more of a bunch of
hipsters? The whole their whole thing.
It's like they're mocking
the halftime show yet,
not showing how you could improve
it. So there's like no risk.
You just sort of mocking the whole
fucking thing. Like, which is to me,
classic hipster behavior. Uh,
to me that's the difference between
nerds and hipsters. You know what I mean?
It's like, alright, so you think what the,
the standard way that a halftime
show is done is too rigid.
So you guys are gonna be, I just
hate how the whole thing is done. Oh,
these guys are crazy. Oh,
look at the guy with the fucking
rainbow wig play in the drum. Oh,
what's he gonna do? I'll
think it's fucking dumb.
And then I just thought it was a badly
made California look bad when they made
fun of the Iowa people with the
whole, uh, you know, farmers only.
And once again, I don't know, I don't
know anybody in the Stanford band,
but it just seems like that
classic, I live near an ocean,
therefore I'm smarter than you.
There's something about people live
on the coast with their whole attitude
towards the middle of the country's,
the funniest fucking thing ever to me.
Like fly overstate and
Blahblahblahblahblah and all that.
It's like those fucking people that you
sit there and making fun of, you know,
like farmers old, hey, where'd you go
Dan? Go Fuck your sister. It's like,
you mean the people who grow the food
supply for this country? You fucking dope.
What are you doing that
with the flute? Oh,
look at the cool kid with
the clarinet. I Dunno.
I thought it was a hacky joke and um,
I dunno, you know what I mean?
Look, if you guys look, you know,
just decided to trash one
another, then it would be funny,
but it just kind of comes off like a,
it's like when Ricky Gervais' does
that shit at the golden clubs,
you know what I mean?
He hires his staff or writers to write
roast jokes aimed at people who showed up
with acceptance speeches and it's
just, Ah, gee, did you win that one?
What are you going to do next? Slap an
ice cream out of a five-year-old hand.
I just, I dunno. It's
the same thing with that.
I thought it was douchey behavior,
but fortunately I missed all of it,
you know? And yeah, he came out with
the paper, we shake cow, it'll be epic.
Ah, kill yourselves.
It'd be one thing if Stanford
Everly actually put on a
good halftime show, like,
wow, this band is next level.
I get why they're trying to break
the whole fucking format of it.
But if you actually watch a,
the competitions of the best
fucking college bands out there,
they're fucking drumlines alone
would destroy anyone in that
band. So, uh, you know, I dunno,
every once in awhile I'm
a fucking conservative and
I'm a conservative on that.
What do I just say? Yeah, you get kind
of fucking made an assay yourself.
But anyways, and I just hate the
deliberately bad dancing that they do.
I think if you gonna to mock dancing,
you should be able to dance wealth,
you know, to just suck at it and
then be like making fun of it.
Then you just fucking like, all right.
Yeah. Yeah. It just like we thought,
yeah, you don't have any talent.
Yeah.
Fuck the Stanford band. I love
the football program now. Anyways.
Uh, so while all of that
was going on, all that,
that fucking nauseated
hipster behavior, uh,
the looks on their faces, like
everyone in the crowd is like,
their mind is blown. Like,
oh my God, what's going on?
It's the fuck you're in the band.
Okay.
You play in the fucking triangle
out there. You're not a rebel.
You're not freaking anybody out.
Uh,
so anyways, uh,
we actually went out to the
concession stand and, um,
you know, just standing the whole
fucking halftime. We're standing in this,
in this, in this line, and we actually
missed the first three minutes of the,
uh, the third quarter and
I'm standing in this line,
Comedian Sean Coyne from Philly.
He's fucking Hilarious, right?
So we get all the way up there and, uh,
I ordered a pretzel and a water and he
ordered a pretzel and something else.
And, uh, I'm fucking common around.
He's still drinking, you know,
he doesn't have to drive,
so he's still fucking drinking during the
game and they hand him the Pretzel and
he proceeds after we waited
a half an hour for a food,
she hands him the Pretzel.
They fucking just fumbled it.
It was like a bad exchange between
the quarterback and the running back.
You know, they like bump into each
other. The dude never quite has the ball.
He never quite had the pretzel and it
just goes end over end in like slow motion
and falls salts side down onto the
concrete where everybody's standing.
He immediately bends down and picks it up.
And I'm looking at him and he just
goes, he's, I, yeah, it's all right.
It's all right. I'm like, dude, you gotta
give that think back. And he's like,
not sorry. It's all right. He doesn't
give a fuck. So I'm dying laugh.
Like this guy's a maniac.
He's like people walking in and out our
restrooms and then coming over to his
standard and there's food
money out of your fucking mind.
But I'm still kind of
drunk. So then I go over,
we were putting mustard on the pretzel
and then out of nowhere fucking lie ed
shows up. And he asked,
he had Sean for the piece of
his Pretzel and he gave it.
So I almost fucking
faked it. I was laughing.
So hard fuck thing was on the ground.
I was like, it was like
watching a poison of light.
I couldn't say anything. I was
laughing so fucking hard. So, uh,
don't we get, we finally
get back into the, uh,
finally get back into the, um,
the stadium and then just
the whole game just stopped.
I mean there was barely any scoring.
Iowa came back and scored a couple. Um,
I was psyched for Versie cause
he, uh, he went to Betsy,
but you bet Stanford.
And then in the next half a
bet the ovary won both of them.
So he picked up a buck 50 or
something like that. And um,
I dunno. Then we just ended up going back.
The game was over and
then we went back to, uh,
the truck. We were hanging
out, we got the bonfire going,
the sun was down and in the
middle of having a bonfire,
all of a sudden this kid comes
walking by with another friend,
this Iowa Kid. And he just goes,
he just goes, hey. He goes,
Hey ted. Bonfire's illegal. He
can't have it. It's illegal.
And right as he was by Raby
like go like, ha ha ha,
I'm just fucking around the Philly guy.
And he goes, Hey, shut the fuck up.
You fucking Blah, blah, blah. Right.
And then the kid fucking
puffs up his chest.
There's like 10 of us sitting here.
This kid was like, he was like five,
six, five, seven.
He comes running up talk and all this
shit and I'm just sitting there looking at
him like, it's fucking
10 of us here, you know,
do you have an oozy? Like what? What are
you doing? Right? So he gets into it,
there's back and forth
and next thing you know,
versus over there and it looks like furs.
He's about ready to square off with the
guy because the guy kept walking away
but like, all right, all right, whatever,
whatever. And He'd be like, Oh, fun,
fun, fun. Who Fuck you.
Because we'd always had the last
thing and then we'd be like, fuck you.
And it just kept going back and forth
and back and forth. Then finally,
the guy's like 30 yards away versus he's
talking to them and I thought like, oh,
this kid's going to soccer room. So I
got up over there and go, relax, relax,
relax. And then all of a
sudden I hear a bottle break
in this fucking maniac Philly
guy, right fucking place the ball.
That's the funniest thing ever. He
breaks the bottle on the pavement.
He fucking, he did it way too
hard. When he brought his hand up,
there was no bottle left. He
just chatted the fucking thing.
But then he like my him,
like he still had the bottle in
his end and this is the best part,
the Iowa kid talking shit, never fledged.
So now he's pretended he
had a bottle in his end.
I didn't even know what he was going
to do. It was like a fucking movie.
It's like, what the fuck? Right.
So the dude finally goes away as to
yell a few more fucking things and um,
it was so ridiculous.
Then we went back and we,
we was sitting around and all we did for
the rest of the time there was make fun
of Sean and how there was no bottle left
and he actually cut his hand and we all
just sit in, go and like, do, what
were you going to do? What? He's like,
I don't know. I don't know what I
always wanted to do that. It was just,
it's fucking ridiculous. So, um,
and by then, you know, actually as I
was coming out of the game, I, I was,
I was so sober, I had already
gotten into the fucking hangover.
So I just started drinking waters and um,
then had another two hot dogs and a
hamburger and I got to tell you dude,
my body was like, what the fuck?
And I just drove home like with
a splitting fucking headache,
stone sober, splitting,
fucking headache. And um,
and then by then my knee was killing me
and I was walking like I had just ridden
a horse from here to fucking
Massachusetts and I was,
I was shot. I came home
and I just fucking,
just pounded like three
waters. And that was,
it was during that time where I
was just thinking to myself like,
I'm never going to that game
again. I fucking, you know,
when you're out three to six
weeks with a fucking knee strain,
cause you went to a tailgate, you
really got to start like looking back,
going like, what the fuck? But it
happened to me again this year, you know,
every year I go, you know, I'm going
to go a little easy. Gonna go easy.
I want to remember as much
of this tailgate as I can.
Like I passed out for like
an hour of it and it popped.
Part of it was the alcohol,
but the other part was just like I had
only gotten three hours sleep. You know,
there's only so far you can go when
you start the day off with a male.
All right, let me, um, but it
was one of one of the best, uh,
one of the best fucking tailgates
and I loved hanging with fucking, uh,
all the new people that came along and
I am now of course obsessed with the
Philly accent. It's the funniest
fucking accent. You get a beard.
Big Easel. Everything's at John. Um,
alright. Hang on a
second. All right, cool.
Let me type in my password here so
I can do a couple of reads. Come on.
I love what they make. You pick such
a fucking difficult one that you know,
it takes me like three times to type name
because there's some capitals and then
there's some not capitals. Like
if someone broke into my computer,
I don't understand what they would be
getting. Um, all right. Okay. Oh Jesus.
I don't even know if I had the
fucking energy. It usually takes,
it takes me three days to get over the
fucking rose bowl. This is the third day.
All right. Uh Oh look, we start up
[inaudible] me on ds.
No more sweaty balls.
Buddha would do to me and
east Biondi get them off file.
Fall stick some leaves and your
tanks say your bothered sweaty.
Know they're Yay cause you
go NASSSA solved fucking
balls even in 2016. Oh yeah.
Even get 'em for your
check. Right me undies.
What's the secret to New
Year's resolutions? Make
the first step really easy.
Like the first thing you do every day
put on underwear and this year our,
the old in with the new step
into a fresh new para me undies,
the world's most comfortable underwear.
It is the easiest resolution
you'll make had to me.
[inaudible] dot com choose from a variety
of styles in limited edition patterns
for both men and women and there'll
be delivered right to your door.
Do you know what's fucking hilarious
about this is I never throw out my
underwear.
I don't throw my underwear until there's
actual holes in them and it takes a
long fucking time. You know
I have underwear that's still
from when I was in my thirties
I know I do. Me and undies is the
next level of underwear. Every pair,
don't be like me. Get new underwear.
Every pair is made from
their signature modal,
modal model model.
Fabric proven to be twice as soft as
cotton. They don't feel better than,
they don't just feel better than regular
undies. They make you feel invincible.
I'll kick your ass buddy.
My balls are dry and it's guaranteed to
be the most comfortable underwear you've
ever worn on. Your first pair is
free, so don't start your new year.
An old underwear.
Make a change and head to
me undies.com/pir right now
and get 20% off your first
order. Plus shipping is always free
for all orders in the u s and Canada,
some of so for 20% off your first
order of the world's most comfortable
underwear. Head to me,
undies.com/burr right now. All right.
Dollar Shave Club. Everybody,
you're not going to be honest.
As much as it sucks that I
lost all this advertising,
I do like having to read less so
it kind of works out. All right.
Dollar Shave Club. All right
you guys. I figured it out.
I've discovered the key to an
amazing shave. It's simple.
That's exactly what dollar shave club.com
does and why I'm a proud member like
millions of others.
Dollar Shave club.com delivers amazing
raises right to my door for a third of
the price of what the greedy razor
razor corporations charge you need.
I have to go down to the store to get
them both my wallet and face. Finally,
get some relief. Relief. Sorry.
Joining Dollar Shave club.com means you
can afford to shave with a fresh blade
any time you want, which feels fantastic.
And for this smoothest shave ever used
fresh dollar shave club blades with their
doctor. KVCC
[inaudible]
it's not your average shave cream.
It's high quality ingredients
that make your skin feel soft,
smooth and moisturize.
Your blade will just glide across your
skin if you want the most amazing shave
possible. Take it from me.
Use a fresh d s c blade,
um, dollar shave club and Dr Ka Bzz shape
[inaudible]
two reasons to join Dr Dollar Shave
club.com/bar that's dollar shave
club.com/bar and the guys who have
stuck with me through thick and thin
stamps.com everyone you know,
one great resolution you
can make for the new year.
Maximize every minute and every
dollar for your small business.
I know an easy way to,
to start that anyways with stamps.com
think about how much time you've wasted.
Go into the post office
driving there, finding parking,
standing behind the old
lady, you know, priority or,
or or express, which one of these is
overnight. Try to figure that shit out.
stamps.com is the better way to get
postage. Just use what you already have,
your computer and your printer to get
an official us postage for any letter or
package. Then the mailman comes
and picks it up with every stamps,
with stamps.com everything you do at the
post office you can do right from your
desk at a fraction of the cost of
one of those expensive postage meter.
I use rec, uh, I use slash recommend
stamps.com it's so convenient anytime.
I'm setting up my posters, so anything
I'm going to sell after my shows,
I use stamps.com. I'm a moron if I can
figure it out. So can you right now,
sign up for stamps.com and use my last
name [inaudible] for this special offer,
four week trial plus $110 bonus offer
that includes a postage and a digital
scale. Don't wait. Go to stamps.com
before you do anything else,
you click on the microphone at the
top of the homepage. Type at bar.
That's stamps.com enter bar. All right.
And that's it. Mercifully,
that's the last bit of reading I have
to do here for the fucking week. Um,
all right. And with that,
let's get to uh, oh.
Can we talk a little f NFL
football for us and what dad? Dad,
dad [inaudible] booted.
I would say the Patriots in
Seattle entered the playoffs
the exact opposite way.
I'm going to go out on a limb.
A the patriots just could not get
anything going offensively. Um,
our offensive line is
just, uh, it's, it's,
it's fucking shattered, dude.
We got nobody left and every
time Brady went to pass,
there was someone in the back field.
Um, a defense did great though.
I mean it was holding him to like 10
points for most of the fucking game,
but um, hopefully we can
get healthy or I don't,
I don't see us going too deep
into the playoffs this year.
Seattle on the other 10. Huh.
Now, this is the wildcard
t nobody wants to play.
Put your got ask yourself are they
peaking to early Seattle look like world
beaters and the way that they handled
the fucking cardinals yesterday they made
them, I mean I don't know if the
cardinal started to come back or not.
I mean I watched the first fucking half
and it looked like an NFL team playing a
CFL team. Let me check out
the final score here. Um,
I mean I think it's just another
phenomenal coaching job by Pete Carroll.
Um, and he's got like,
he's got him right about 36 to six. Yeah.
They just destroyed them scoring
it. We'll do an evidence,
whatever the fuck they wanted. You know,
Arizona special teams
would look at like shit,
that field goal kicker and
MacTech couple of extra points.
I don't know what the fuck was going
on with them and they couldn't tackle
anybody on punch or kickoffs.
The only question mark I saw with Seattle
was there a kicker missed another one
and Richard Sherman's hair.
That's the only thing I've found.
That's the second time this year. Sherman
has been brought down by his hair. Um,
to the point they actually
thought it was a facemask.
He went down so fucking his head
went down. Uh, but other than that,
uh, I was, I was the guy, you know, a
couple of weeks ago I was thinking like,
you know,
Arizona and a Carolina now I think it's a,
a Carolina is would play Seattle
at home, but I got to tell you,
Seattle doesn't give a fuck. They've been
there the last two years in a row. Um,
if they wouldn't again this year, a
lot of people are going to be like, oh,
they do one play away for
winning it three times in a row.
That's absolute bullshit. That's absolute
bullshit. Um, you went to in a row,
if you win the fucking thing, it
changes. It changes your vibe,
you know, defending versus
bad tastes in your mouth.
You know what I mean? Yeah.
How long do you think Pete Carol's was
able to actually get eight hours sleep
after that super bowl?
Like the drive that he's had to get back
because that they fucked that thing up.
Slash Malcolm Butler may one of the
greatest defensive plays of all time,
like battle. You know, there's a reason
why nobody's ever won three in a row.
It's, you know, it's hard to
stay that fucking motivated,
I think anyways. Um,
and I know watching the Patriots when
the defending Super Bowl champions,
for instance, just being the
Patriots, which is bad enough,
people want to beat you bad enough,
but when you're the
defending Superbowl champion,
even that shit teams try hard
against you. Um, but anyways,
having said all that, um, you know,
the way Seattle's played over
the last month in that last game,
like they look like
fucking world beaters. Um,
so, and us,
I dunno if we could beat the Broncos at
this point with how fucking injured we
are, even with their,
uh, their quarterback.
I though it was hard to see
Peyton manning be a backup man,
but he took it like a gentleman. Um,
I wonder if that was his last game.
I wonder. I wonder. I wonder.
All right, let's get to, uh,
let's get to the fucking questions here
for this week. Right. And by the way,
um, for all the Canadian fans,
I'm not ducking the fact that you
guys destroyed us in that game.
I just haven't seen it yet.
I started to watch it yesterday and after
all the Hoopla and all of that shit,
I got like a minute and a half in
the game and they already scored.
I was just like, oh man. I
think the final was five to one.
So congratulations to Yukon. But um, oh,
I gotta fix my cooler to my cooler.
It took a beating. Both hinges. What?
Broken as the interior
strap. Thank thankfully. Uh,
Igloo makes a repair kit night. You
know, it's obviously an easy repair.
I gotta get that fucking taken
care of this week, uh, that,
that fucking coolest bend
to every Rosebowl. I got to
fix it up here. Who knows?
Maybe when I fell on the one that
knocked the fucking lid off the thing.
All right, breakfast. Here we go.
There's no way I did 45 minutes.
Jesus Christ. It's flame. I
all right. Breakfast bill.
I'm a father of two young children and
I hold a nine to five corporate job.
Don't feel bad for me though.
I love my job. That's awesome.
I want you to love your job. And he goes,
and I don't bitch about how hard
it is to be a parent. Uh, he goes,
I maintain a decent diet.
I was a college athlete,
so I have a basic understanding
of the human body.
Granted you and I spend
our mornings differently.
I freeze my ass off every morning
for five to six months of the year.
Uh, I was wondering what you
do for breakfast every morning?
I don't know. What do you mean you
freeze your ass off? What do you do? Oh,
UK guys. I'm wondering what you do
for breakfast setting every morning.
And then he goes on to say,
I'm always on the go and I'm not
hungry right when I leave for work, uh,
which leads me in the car and at the
office for the rest of the morning.
Not a lot of options. Uh,
beyond a banana and a coffee.
It's too cold for smoothies. What's Amanda
do? What's your morning food routine?
Well when I'm being smart,
I have two eggs over easy and I
have some oatmeal with a, a banana,
maybe some blueberries.
I don't have any a bread
or any of that stuff.
And then between breakfast
and lunch I have an apple.
And then for lunch I have Turkey
slices with the side salad.
And then at four o'clock I have a meat
with a protein in six o'clock meet with
the protein and a meet with the protein
of a protein with vegetables to fuck my
brain is shot here. I have, yeah, I
have a protein with some vegetables.
They meet with the protein and then
I have a bread with some carbs.
Um, that's what I ended
up doing. And then I just,
I stopped beating around six, five,
six is when I had my last meal.
And then I just drink waters after
that. If I get really hungry,
I just have celery with peanut butter and
I got to get back to that diet because
I've been cooking up a fucking storm,
bacon and all that type of stuff. Um,
and I have three goals this
month. I'm gonna make a quiche.
I'm gonna make a fucking Lasagna and
I'm going to make this hunter's chicken.
The last two are Mario Batali
recipes and a Dodgers chicken.
Isn't that bad? The fucking, um,
the LASAGNA is pretty bad, but
there's veal in it and I just can't,
I can't get myself to eat
lobster or veal. I just,
just what the fuck they
go through. I mean,
I know the chickens and cows already
have a bad enough thing, but like,
it just seems extra fucking cruel.
Boiling something alive and
having something just sit
in a fucking cage forever
so it's softer and tastes better when
you eat. It's just, it's fucking brutal.
Um,
anyways. All right, so what's
my morning routine? Yeah, well,
if I was you and I had tea,
I would eat, I would get up,
I wouldn't make the time and I would
at least just have some oatmeal.
Um,
Amanda, but I don't have kids. I mean,
I just hear you guys talking about having
kids. Makes me glad I don't have any.
I mean, it just seems so fucking right.
Um,
just never ending. Never ending. Um,
I dunno. So I will, I will. What
do you do for breakfast? All right.
I told you I did the whole day.
Um, [inaudible]
yeah, if I was you, I would,
you have to make the time.
I would definitely say that you
got to make the time and uh,
I think the best thing for working out
is you do it in the morning and you just
get it out of the way and then you have
a healthy breakfast and that gets you on
the right track to start the
day to start off the day.
If you're eating bad and then try
to be like, well, don't worry,
I'm going to go to the gym later.
The problem is with bad
food is it chemically fucks
your body and it makes you
just want to lay down and do
nothing. So if you start today,
I dunno, just do that.
That the tense about,
I was telling you guys about the tents
start off as like a 10 jumping
jacks, 10 burpees, 10 pushups,
10 alternating lunges, 10 sit
ups. I forget the fucking order.
I haven't done it, but you can,
you can look it up on the
Internet and find it and uh,
and you go from 10 and then you do
nine jumping jacks, nine burpees,
nine pushups, nine setups,
nine alternate leg jumps,
nine squat jumps.
And then you do eight and you go all
the way down to one and then you're,
you know, you pretty much winded.
And then if you want to add a
little more cardio to it, skip,
skip rope for around a two or three
or whatever you want to fucking do. A,
I could do that workout
in like a hotel room. Um,
but that's what I would do.
I would do something like that
and that would just make sure,
you know also if you really
don't have time to work out,
but it really help you during the day is
to bring an apple and to pack a healthy
lunch also saves you money.
Also gives you more of a lunch hour
cause you're not driving to and from
wherever the fuck you go. And you
go right down to the cafeteria,
you knock it out, you chill
the fuck out, you know,
okay.
You have something healthy
in your afternoon break.
And that's the biggest thing, dude.
If you're not putting mistakes
into your fucking mouth,
you're going to get more results
from your workout and you, you know,
you've closed and start fitting better.
And the same way you get addicted to
eating bad salt, sugar, salt, sugar,
you can get addicted to eating well. Uh,
which where is not where I'm at right
now. Um, all right, one trick pony.
Uh, hey Billy balls.
Uh, my wife loves you.
Pie crust video. Oh, by the way,
you know, I tried a lot in my, um,
for my cross for the first time
and it was a total game changer.
The best crus I ever made.
It did feel weird to smell bacon
as I was making the pie crust.
But um,
okay.
Um, uh, thank you to everybody that
suggested that who, you know, the, your,
your critique really helped my pie crust.
Thank you. Um, all right. So anyways,
this person says she's a fan of yours
as well. He loved the pie crust video.
She's a fan of you as well and it's
been exposed to hours of your podcast.
She likes you, Bill.
Let me lead with that.
Well here comes to big
fucking slap in the face,
but of course like all great women,
she still has a capacity to chop a man
down at the knees. After the video,
I casually said, can't
wait for the next one.
She responded in an Oh
sweetie tone with ha ha. Well,
how many of these tricks do
you think he has up his sleeve?
This resulted in a long discussion where
I defended your potential skills and
she went with the, I love bill burr.
I'm just assuming he doesn't have
much more to rival this pie crust.
Uh, whether you can make a full
series out of these videos or not,
can you please explain to my wife
that you're not a one trick pony?
And even if you are a one trick pony,
it's bullshit and unfair to
assume this much. Ah, thanks.
Come back to Wisconsin. Home of
corruption as seen in documentaries.
Um, well, you know something.
As you get older, prism, man,
you understand where that's coming
from. Why your wife, as you said,
like all great women always have to
take you out of the knees what it is.
As much as you gotta stop internalizing
that and taking it personally,
what it is is that's,
it's almost like a subconscious fear thing
that they have. You know what I mean?
Like when they don't know you
and they see you doing something,
they have a positive reaction to a
co, oh look, he can make a pie cross.
I bet he's going to be a great dad.
Right? They think shit like that.
But after they get with you and then
they love you and they don't want to lose
you when they see you continuing
to grow as a person, they,
it's, I can't even, this is a
female thing. This is like a, uh,
thing in general that people
do in relationships is
you actually hold back the
person you love because you see them
expanding on who they are and because it's
something new and different and
moves in a different direction,
I think subconsciously a certain type
of person feels insecure so then they,
they have to tether it to
the ground with fucking, uh,
criticism rather than
encouraging the person.
So I think that that's where
it's coming from. But um,
as far as addressing it,
like I will just say this as
far as my cooking and baking,
like you don't just know how to make
corn flakes and you can also make a pie
crust, you know what I mean?
Knowing how to make a pie crust takes
all of your shit to the next level.
Okay. Like, no, like, no this because
I can do that. Like back in the day,
I used to look at like making like a
quiche or something like that going,
oh my God, that's fucking impossible.
The cross the loan or making a Turkey pot
pie or anything that involves having a
crust. Um,
you can add that I recently have
learned how to smoke meat. You know,
I smoked ribs. Uh,
I can make all of my, my, my mother
before we, when we all moved out,
she wrote out all of her recipes,
hand wrote them all out on cards and we
have all of them and we can all cook the
meals that she made when
we were growing up. Like,
I can make you a Hungarian Goulash and
you know what else I can make the fucking
noodles from scratch. I took a
pasta making class, you know,
as you suspected, sir, your wife has no
idea what the fuck she's talking about.
What it really was. It was coming from
a place of insecurity and jealousy.
And right now she's going to roll
her eyes and be like, oh my God,
the Blah Blah Blah. It's
fucking true. You know?
Cause that's really just like
a, just like to have like that,
that Oh sweetie tone, you know,
they do that shit. You know,
you go out, you start looking a little
too good, you get a new new suit,
right. You look in a little bit.
They got a fucking, they got,
they got to make a comment. They fucking
do it with each other. It's hilarious.
I think that's one of the main reasons
that's fucking them up by the way.
You know? And they always talk
about the wage gap and all that.
One of the biggest problems
with the wage gap is not men.
It's the fact that women don't get
together and create businesses enough.
They just don't do it cause they're
too busy going look at this bitch and
fucking look at her. She's too fucking
skinny. She needs the eat something.
She's got on too much fuck out. She
knows what she's doing. You know,
they don't work well together. I don't
know why, but that's not our fault.
I'm sure it is though.
If you watch the video,
I'm sure they could spin it
around to us. So, um, yes sir.
I actually absolutely love cooking and um,
it isn't the only trick
I have up my sleeve. Um,
I could obviously make more of
those. But the thing about it was,
was that was the specific
skill it was for the holidays.
And people have suggested, well,
why don't you do one on how to smoke
meat or why don't you do one about making
positive from scratch? My thing is because
you could watch Mario Batali do it,
you can watch champion smokers do it.
So I guess what makes mine
different is that I make it funny.
You know,
I just looked at it as a one fucking
random thing that I was going to do,
but you know, now that she's been
a douche about it, you know what,
I'll make another one at some
point I guess. Um, I'll, let's see.
What the fuck will I do?
The Turkey pot pie on the
big green egg. I mean,
I've watched you two
videos of all of those.
I just did a really saw somebody do
like, is there a pie cross video?
I don't know. I just thought it'd be fun.
I literally feel like I'm in a
relationship or right now I have,
I'm sorry that that video annoying. Okay.
Oh God, that's so fucking
moody. Uh, yeah, I will,
I will figure out something
else. Um, to make one of those.
I'll do like one a year. Well,
it's actually given me some
ideas like maybe I'll do one. Oh,
the summer's coming. All right.
You're going to show up to 4th of July
as a quick fucking thing you can make.
You know what? Maybe I'll
do it. Maybe I'll do it.
I just don't like committing to shit
like that. I love not having a job,
which is why I'm a fucking comedian.
I've really enjoyed this whole,
I work when I want to rather than it
being okay, we need 20 episodes of this.
All right. Thursday afternoon podcast
got me laid bill. Oh, something positive.
Oh John, do you really think he could
get somebody else laid fucking disease?
Um,
it's probably why we die eight years
earlier just because they just won't give
it up.
But if you get yourself out in front of
it next time you wife does that to you,
sir. Next time she takes
you out at the knees,
just come up to her and stroke the
side of her face. You know when you,
when you go out and get a new
car and you say, oh honey,
don't you think you're a little
bit old for that car? You know,
does one of those things
makes you feel stupid? Right?
Just walk up stroke the side of
her face if has golf, sweetie,
don't worry. I'm not going
to leave you. It's okay.
Nah, it's okay. Okay. I know I
look it in the car. I'm sorry.
Something like that. Some creepy. All
right bill, last week on New Year's Eve,
my wife and I listened to your
podcast after we put the kids to bed,
we drank wine and laughed
our asses off. That's great.
This woke us up energized us. Just
as the throwback clip came on,
it appeared that we may have
sex during in the new year.
Well Boyle boy, not more than a
few notes into the outro song.
We were going at it.
It was all over just moments
after the song ended,
so maybe four minutes or
so of ball dropping bliss.
My Dick. Thanks you for the
laughs and the soundtrack.
Did you guys fuck to the me on the song?
I don't think I needed to know that.
Um, all right. Oh, here
it is. There it is.
This is the one I wanted to read. This is,
this is amazing overpopulation myth bill,
how you're doing and I'm just checking
in on you a to inform you that if you go
online and see for yourself
how much arable Ara,
B, l, e Farm Land and resources
there actually is in the world.
You'll see that there is enough to feed
and home at least 100 billion people for
approvable fact.
Okay.
I Dunno what that sentence
didn't make sense.
Did you like voice Texas
or did you actually,
this is how you actually type
out sentences. Person goes.
So anytime you hear anyone say that
7 billion people is too many people,
I'm there.
Okay.
T H, e I.
R either seriously misinformed and or
too lazy to do some research or flat out
lying through their teeth, like are
so-called leaders in scientists must be,
oh yeah, they gotta be
lying because you're not,
you can't even spell their right
because within one to
do two days of research,
you can find studies
that prove what I say.
It's going to take me one to two
days to find it on the Internet.
This is fucking hilarious. Why don't
your days to one to two days to research.
You can find studies that prove
what I say is true. Parentheses,
at least 100 billion. Now I
know you're in the business.
Oh,
waking the masses up just like the lake
group. Great. Bill Hicks. No, I'm not.
But do you realize how serious the
situation is regarding the distraction and
brainwashing as organized by big business
and they're controlling family owners.
So as great as, I think you and your
comedy are mentioning, overpopulation,
which is a complete myth,
is doing them parentheses,
big corporations and
the [inaudible] on them,
a big service and adding to
the brainwashing. Anyway, Bill,
I know you're a great man because of
the subject you talk about during these
shows,
but please look for yourself and how much
admirable arable farm land there is a,
and consider the fact that all
food grows completely for free.
Um,
wow. All right, well, I'll tell
you this buddy. I know I'm a moron,
so I just looked up. I looked at how
many people can the earth sustain.
Um,
and it says a hundred people
can. The earth support.
So 10 billion people is the utmost
population limit where food is concerned.
That's the first one.
The next one says more than 7 billion
people currently on the planet compared to
3 billion in 1967. Then what does it say?
Okay.
Oh, I'll just go on. It's a
video. I don't want to watch that.
Okay.
Current population is three times
this sustainable level. That's a,
the next article. Um,
how many people can the earth
sustain? I'll click on this one.
I'm trying to find anything that says
anything even remotely close to a hundred
million. 100 billion. Here's a staggering
stat. According to the United Nations,
the world's current population is 7.2
billion is now up to 7.8 is projected to
increase by 1 billion
over the next 12 years,
which would bring us to 9.6 billion by
2050 how can we sustain all these people
on the planet or rather how many
people can this plan to sustain?
That is the question Alan Weisman explored
in his latest book countdown our last
best hope for a future on earth.
Question Mark. Uh, Jesus Christ,
a bunch of conversations,
bunch of words. [inaudible] number.
Where's the fucking number?
Okay.
Alrighty. As the charter or
it's kind of the next 50 years,
we will need to produce as much food as
it's ever been consumed for an entire
human history. Well, that makes sense
because there'll be the most people,
there'll be the most farts ever
in, in the history of human beings.
Well, there's no fucking number
there, sir. All I can tell you is,
is if you see the environmental
damage that 7.8 billion people did,
if you're going to have
100 billion people, like,
yeah,
I mean, at this point in Africa, there's
barely any land for, for wild animals.
It's all,
it's all like for the most part down
in the southern part of the country,
uh, it's all like roped off.
Yeah.
It's finite. You know what I mean?
They're completely surrounded.
I'd have to say that I disagree
and not just by your spelling,
cause I couldn't read half
the fucking words you said,
even when you spelled
them. Right. But yeah, no,
there's no fucking way 100 billion people
and there's any sort of animal life
left that isn't stuck in a cage.
You know what I mean? Um,
and also in this last year I traveled
to Singapore, Hong Kong in Mumbai,
India. And I saw what that next
level of population look like too.
And I was breathing that air
that's Singapore. Singapore was,
was different. Um, but Hong
Kong and Mumbai, India,
you could almost taste the
fucking air. And it was just, uh,
it was just way too many
fucking people. I can,
I can tell you that there's
no way 100 billion people. Um,
yeah.
And I don't understand why I need
to look it up for one to two days.
Why could you just send me a link? I
would love for you to be right, but, uh,
I'm going to go out on a
limb and say you're not,
I'm going to go with the
scientists on this one. And also,
this also sounds like, you know,
when people denied global warming,
not to get all political,
but one political party adamantly
denied it for years and years and years,
and now they've decades and
now they finally just go, yeah,
we are causing climate change. But
you know what? It's too late now.
So I imagine that that's what's
we're going to do out here.
We have a fucking methane gas
leak that's been going on,
and I guess that's probably,
it's like 10 times worse than carbon
dioxide as far as getting put into the
fucking, uh, atmosphere as far
as heating it up and all that.
We're completely fucked. We're
fucked, we're absolutely fucked.
Um, and selfishly I hope I, it doesn't
happen by the end of my own life,
which is the exact sort of thought process
that got us into this mess to begin
with. But sir, you're,
you're correct in assuming that I'm a
fucking dope and I don't know what I'm
talking about, but uh,
yeah,
I'm just kinda going with
having traveled extensively,
you know,
for the last 20 years on the road and
watching the population increase just in
this country. Um,
okay.
It's a weird thing when the population
keeps looking like it's sort of leveled
off and I don't know if because
there's no factories anymore.
All I know is like I've, I
used to be back in the day,
if I jumped on the highway at
two in the afternoon, I was good.
And now everywhere I go
there's like traffic.
And I'm just looking at these people
going like, you guys all stand up comics.
Does everybody work the third shift?
How the fuck are all these
people out on the road?
I didn't know what's going on.
Do a lot of people work from home and
they're all driving out to get a sandwich
at that time. I don't know.
You know what? Let me look up.
I heard the u s population has kind
of leveled off, which excited me.
That's exciting to me. You know
u s population.
Okay.
Oh Jesus Christ. Still can
you fucking population.
Okay.
By year, let's do this. All
right. Let's see what we got here.
US population by year
a right?
Let's go back to 1997 there was
2.726 5 million and now
there's 322.0 7 million.
So it's gone up by like 50
million. Is that enough to notice?
Well that's actually, you know, that's
significant, right? That's all I could,
I could get 20% increase.
I think I make it a point.
All right, let's move on here. All
right. A advice changing high schools.
Dear Bill,
I'm a freshman in high school and would
like to know your perspective on my
situation.
I currently attended a performing arts
high school and Major G in jazz studies.
Oh, that's fucking cool. I
enjoy it. And all, but this, uh,
the first semester has passed.
I found out that jazz is something I
don't want to do in life rather than carry
on for what the next
three years of this major.
I'd rather change and majored in something
that would benefit me in the long
run, especially if I want to
attend big schools like Harvard.
A well, let's go ahead man. You tried
something you've realized early on,
you know, like it and he got enough
strength to be like, I communicate.
I don't want to do this. Anyone need
something else? It's all good so far. Uh,
the problem is that in
leaving my current school,
I could possibly devastate
the bands I'm in.
Ah, Jesus there came in an ego out of
nowhere and also hurt some friends.
My director has placed me in some good
bands and I even get paid money for
playing gay. I'll see you crushing it out.
Phil Chow wrote to leave my director as
he has put me in a position that many
others would gladly take this question.
It's been tearing me apart for a while.
What do you think, Bill? Should
I stay or should I go? Also,
if I do decide to leave,
do you think I should tell my
friends and directors that I,
that I am or should I just go out
quietly? I'm told you have to do in life.
If what makes you happy. If you
try to make other people happy,
that's all you're gonna do when you're
not going to be happy and then you're
going to be miserable to be around.
You're going to turn into a bitter person
who didn't do what they wanted to do
in life and no one wants to
be around that guy. All right?
So as much as it's gonna hurt them, uh,
you gotta leave and you gotta tell them
and you have to tell them why you're
going to leave and just say, listen,
I'm just not happy doing this.
I understand that I'm lucky.
And then a lot of people would
kill to be in my position.
So I feel that someone should at
least be happy and be excited.
You know,
if we'll be people desire to be in my
position and I'm occupying that position
and I'm not happy, I'm doing an
injustice to myself and one of you guys.
All right, I apologize. I'm sorry.
And then that's it. And you know,
and it's a great life
lessons sometimes. You know,
when you ask for what you want,
people get hurt and uh, you know,
I don't mean you physically
have to hurt them,
you know that bottom lip quivers a
little bit. That's all I'm saying. Um,
that's it. But don't go out quietly.
Don't sneak out the back door.
Be a man or woman about
it and fucking, you know,
be an adult. All right. That's it.
And you should be commended
for understanding that you
don't like something and,
and not just staying in it. All right.
Book recommendations. All right.
Hey Bill, I'm not to start off
by blowing smoke up your ass,
but f f F is for family is a phenomenal
show as me cracking up nonstop.
But I'd aggressed well,
thank you. I appreciate that.
It gives me a chance to promote the
show. If you haven't watched it yet,
please check out. F is for family.
Evidently we're doing great
on the all Netflix. Uh,
this person says, I remember
you mentioned you read
open o that you read
opened by Andre Augusti.
So I picked it up and started reading it.
It truly is one of the books that's
tough to put down was wondering if he had
any other recommendations that
you've read of late. Thanks.
And Go fuck yourself. A that
comedian book that I mentioned. Um,
I have it downstairs. Uh, it's like
the history of a standup comedy.
Let me look it up here. Uh, which
has taken me forever to get through,
cause every time they bring up a name
I'm like, who the fuck is that guy?
And then I look them up and then I'm
on the Internet. But it's been a,
it's been a joy,
the history of stand up comedy book.
There it is. All right. This
is what I've been reading.
It's called the Comedians, uh, drunks,
thieves scoundrels in the history
of American comedy. Jesus Christ,
Hubbub Brilliance. Do you
know any geniuses in there?
No. No, no. Nod to Pryor,
Lenny Bruce, none of that. All
right. Um, yeah, so I would,
that's what I've been
reading and uh, I don't know.
I'm in another one of those modes where
I'm just playing a lot of drums and I'm,
I'm cooking in that type of stuff. And uh,
also feeling the pressure to put out
another cooking video to shut up somebody
that I'd never met before. How
fucking ridiculous is that? Um,
I should just let it go. You know I
should, but you know what? I'm not gonna.
You know what? Maybe I'll make a
fuck. I'll make a breakfast one.
I made a pie one. I'll make a
breakfast one, I'll make a lunch one.
I'll make a demo or a supper one.
I'll do it all throughout
the fucking years. All right.
That'll be all basic cooking
by a basic cunt. All right,
that's the podcast for this
week. Go fuck yourselves.
I'll check in on you on
Thursday. I'm to brand new year.
I have like two standup gigs booked
because I'm trying to figure out what the
fuck is going to go on with this show
for going to get a second season.
I need to know, but a, I think I'm
just going to start booking shit. Um,
cause that's how this business
works. You know, if you, uh,
if you book a bunch of
Shit then they just go,
oh well let's fucking give you something
right in the middle of all that other
shit that you booked. If
you don't book anything,
then you're just going to be staring at
your phone and it's never going to ring.
What do you fucking which billion
to sue unit's superstitious stuff?
Well maybe I am, I have no idea.
But a Paul Versey is going to try to
not drink starting today until the
beginning of April.
And I told him that I w I've sorta half
ass committed that I would do it with
them. Um,
so I'm sort of on the wagon right
now. I didn't drink last night.
I don't really have any desire to
do it today. I'm fucking wiped out.
So we'll see. I'm going to try and
see. I'll try and go as long as I can.
I'm all right. That's it. Go Fuck
Yourself. So I'll talk to you on Thursday.