Hey, what's going on? It's Bill Burr and
it's time for the Thursday afternoon?
Just before Friday.
Monday morning podcast.
[inaudible]
How's it going? Oh,
that's wonderful. Did you,
did that happen this week? Good for you.
You know, it could feel good for you.
Um, you know, I, I'm going to be, oh, I'm
going back down the rabbit hole. This,
this Thursday. I know it's supposed
to be about you on Thursdays.
Mondays it's about me, but on Thursdays
it's supposed to be about you.
You know what I mean? You sit there,
you sit in there with that
Styrofoam Cup drinking a cup of Cho
America that don't work without you.
Now he's singing those condescending
songs to the working man. Hey,
gay puts his fucking pants on
one leg at a time. Joe. Six pack.
Yeah.
Okay.
Goes the track every once in a while
has an occasional [inaudible] again,
you know, laughs that are racist,
choke every 7.2 days. You
know, never questions it.
Um, yeah, I'm going down the rabbit
hole this week cause I, you know, I,
I would like a little bit credit after
the Superbowl for being a fucking
gentleman as a Patriot fan. Okay.
And you Bronco fans better know what
I'm talking about. I was a gentleman,
you know, it's so funny. A
lot of you are in chickens.
Get your fucking head so far up your
fucking bronco is that you don't even know
what I'm talking about.
You think I'm talking about because
you guys kicked my team's ass, right?
Not really kicked her ass.
Fucking won in the last second.
Took the whole fucking game
to win. Right. You take that.
I'm fucking saying that I was nice that
I actually rooted for Peyton manning and
the Broncos. Now that's
not what I'm talking about.
You know what I'm
talking about? After tar,
Brady went to that fucking to deflate
gate thing went to the entire baseball
season. Air Pressure. Okay.
You know, you would think of, that's
what happens with air pressure.
What if a certain, someone had a certain
something shipped to his certain house?
To a certain wife.
Okay.
And that certain someone is in the
fucking super bowl, Jesus Christ,
if they can make a fucking
air pressure in eight months,
fucking Goddamn story on ESPN,
how long is this thing gonna last answer?
Zero seconds wasn't even a fucking story.
Okay. And you know what? And
I loved that it happened.
I love that they didn't make a big
fucking deal out of it. You know,
cause I don't think they should.
I think we're all going to be on
roids in the future. In the future.
We're all gonna be Jack.
Right. And the future,
they're going to have like a fucking 80
enrolled or like heavyweight division,
you know? Um, sorry,
meet the Hershey's cuss.
I just had some salty, I
apologize. Very rude. You know,
I'm just saying
what I loved about how that happened is
I'm never going to lose another fucking
argument that there is a fucking witch
hunt or that was a fucking witch hunt.
Okay. If you're going
to fucking, you know,
go fucking ballistic about
that Horse Shit, you know,
then all somebody has to come out
and says, you should, you know,
just makes me sheer cool. Oh
girl, you where'd she come from?
And then that's it. It's over. It's
over. Done. I don't know about you guys,
but I don't have any more
questions. They down place that
close the book. Take it off
the board. Now the case solved.
I'm fucking unbelief. I was a
gentlemen. Oh, I was general. Give Up.
Not even naming names. You
know what I'm talking about?
Everyone knows the fuck I'm talking
about. I'm just being a fucking gentleman.
I'm just a gentleman right now sitting
in here and some fucking basketball
shorts, eating Hershey kisses. Just
talking. Just talking to myself. Oh,
I'm having [inaudible].
Who's the fucking annoying
content makes Hershey's kisses.
I don't fucking get it.
Okay,
thank God we've made sure that kisses
also doesn't make popcorn or you have to
fucking unwrap each
goddamn colonel. Pop Dry.
Am I doing 80 standup right now? Why
or would you go do so small? You know,
I bet they make bigger ones now for
fat fucks. I got to look that up.
What should I Google here? The
Hershey kiss for a fat fuck.
I gotta do it now just to
see if something comes up.
Do my dog looks so fucking cute right
now. She's completely just like,
she has her bed and um,
nobody fucking lies down
on a bed like a dog.
Just cause they're pack animals and
they don't need their space. They, they,
they like being in each other's spaces,
laying down on top of each other.
She fucking, she's laying there right now.
She'll say a fucking lion
just laying in a cage.
Except she's got a bed and there's no
cage. Surely doesn't look like a lion.
She's like a dog. She's chilling. That's
what I'm trying to say. All right.
Alright. I say Hershey. Kiss her.
She is the one chocolate I
have. All right. Hershey kiss
for fat. Fuck.
You know there's going to be a hit
here. Hershey kisses. This annoys me.
Irish people taste test. Hershey kisses.
Oh, let me guess. They're going to shit
on America's chocolate when the fuck go.
Europe is just enough
already. You know what I mean?
Isn't it enough that we accepted the
fact that you stole Blues Music after we
stole it and then brought it back to
us? We were nice about it. Then we, um,
all right, I bet I would supersized
supersize Hershey's kits and then,
and there's no way they're going to say
for fat. Fuck, come on. Let's, let's,
let's be intelligence about this. All
right. Hershey kiss for a supersize,
but then they're not going to be able to
say that because McDonald's uses that,
right? Supersize which all just
means for fat fucks, right?
Hm.
Kisses giants, milk chocolate,
seven ounce package images for her.
She kisses [inaudible] super
cy. There they are. Oh yeah.
You know somebody fucking complaint,
you know some fucking [inaudible].
You know as people that
breathe like biggie smalls,
that kind of out of shape, they have
sleep apnea even when they're awake.
You know, they called up the Hershey
[inaudible] department,
please, I want you,
if you work so much, okay, you
gotta burn so many calories,
you know, it's just so
fucking gross to him. Like,
it was just gross to you that they just
said five, five and make them bigger,
you know, just imagine how much
more aluminum foil that was
some poor kid fucking, you
know, thrown out his back,
picking up those giant
chocolate fucking kisses.
Okay.
They're really not that
much bigger. Oh fuck.
You may have those peanut butter
ones. What am I talking about here?
Jesus Christ. Let's, let's
continue on here. So anyways, um,
I am going to have a good
time with that. When I go to,
I'm actually going to Cheyenne,
Wyoming and Denver, Colorado,
and uh, all the fun.
I'm going to have a Denver wishing them
a happy celebration for the Superbowl
wind and uh, you know, you
know, and I'll have a couple of,
you know, choice words to say,
okay,
and you know what? The best
part is as much as if I do,
I don't think I'm going to do it,
but if I do it as much as they bow and
as loud as they do in the back of their
heads, they know I'm fucking right.
I challenge anyone that you guys send me
a fucking email right now and you tell
me that there isn't some
unbalanced fucking going
after the Patriots thing after
that fucking horse shit.
If the flight date is an eight months
story and that fucking thing is eight
seconds. Oh, what a gentleman
I didn't say shit to.
I alluded to it, but I, you
know, still not naming names.
We had protection issues.
That's not a story.
Nothing to say. Um, anyway,
so I'm going to Wyoming and uh,
I drove through it a long time ago and
saw these things that look like deer,
but I knew they weren't, you
know, so I was just like, wow,
where the fuck am I even I
knew I was in Wyoming, right?
This podcast is all over
the place. Um, let me, uh,
so I looked up Wyoming on Wikipedia.
Who's kidding? Who? I went to Wikipedia.
I didn't even go to Wikipedia. I just
wrote Wyoming. And Wikipedia always,
always comes up, right? It's
just a great website. You know,
you just read a bunch of things about
the thing that you looked up and
afterwards you feel like you something
and then you throw it out at a party and
you go, yeah it does.
And then eventually you run into somebody
that's an expert on it and then you
realize halfway through it and then
you're like, Yo, I had fuck Yale.
And you just walk away during the, uh,
the Wikipedia shuffle as you walk
away. 20 ways I found out that Wyoming
is, um, I bet somebody
there named their kid oming,
you know their first name Omi,
so they can be like Wyoming.
How are you doing? Sorry. Jesus.
Brutal podcast. All right.
This article includes a sortable
listing of the United States 50,
50 United States by population density
cause I immediately found out that
Wyoming, Wyoming is the, um,
second least, uh, densely
populated state. All right,
so here we go. Let me get
to the list here. Density,
state ranks. Here we go.
All right, the top one.
What do you think it is now? This
is density. This is not population.
This is like elbow room. Okay.
Density. Uh,
the most densely populated state is
you'd never guess this and they shoot New
Jersey. I never would have guessed that
most densely populated was New Jersey.
That's cause of all it cons that can't
afford to live in Manhattan right along
the coast. I think. Then there's
Rhode Island. It's a number two.
Massachusetts is number three.
It's all the small ones on the east
coast where the white man first landed,
right first started banging away.
First said to the native Americans,
what do you call that stuff,
man? Can you teach us? Right?
Four, they took it from them. Um,
Connecticut, Maryland, Delaware,
New York, Florida, right.
Wherever he lose it with a
dream from the east coast.
Fucking vacations deal with
going down to Fort Myers.
My cousins has a boat.
Uh, Pennsylvania in Ohio,
that's the top 10 most densely
populated. I was surprised.
California was 11 was not
in the top 10. Granted,
I live in Los Angeles. All right. Least
populated state. What do you guess?
What do you got? What do you got?
Alaska. All right, here we go.
Is the top the least populated from
number 10 all the way down to number one,
number one being the least densely
populated. All right. Kansas,
Nevada and Nebraska. Idaho, New Mexico,
South Dakota, North Dakota,
Montana. Wow. I mean in Alaska.
So there you go. In generally speaking,
I guess we are a not a very densely
populated country and a, you know,
you'd think I would notice that
the amount of traveling I've done,
the only time I really noticed it was
when I went to Asia and I was like,
Jesus Christ, there's a of fucking
people over here. You know?
That's all you do when you go to Asia.
Go holy fucking shit. Look at all these.
Look, they fucking just look at all these
apartment buildings. Look at them all.
They're all filled. There's
laundry hanging out every window.
Um, isn't it amazing that there's a
billion people in China and they all have
shirts? Have you ever fucking
thought about stuff like that?
Like who the fuck made all those shirts
you take with all those fucking pee,
all those shirts that needed to be made.
What do you think that you would know?
Somebody that makes shirts. I don't know
anybody in the clothing industry yet.
Everybody, everybody in the
fucking, that's unbelievable.
As much as many rollerblades as they
sold, right? Everybody didn't have them,
but everybody's got a shirt, right?
Everybody's got to cover up the junk.
Even the strippers,
even strippers have to walk out with some
clothes right before they take it off.
All right. This article is
about the u s state. Wyoming.
Wyoming is a state in their mountain
region of West, so we know all this shit,
the United States, but
booboo, popo populates a,
where the fuck is it? Come on.
The Western two thirds of the state is
covered mostly with the mountain ranges
and the range lands in the foothills of
the eastern rocky mountains is has God's
country here. While the eastern
third of the state is high plank,
high elevation prairie,
known as the high plains.
Cheyenne is the capital in
the most populous city in
Wyoming with the population
estimate of this is
the most populated city
in Wyoming,
a population of 62,448 people as of 2013
62,448 people.
Do you realize what a let them
that that is, that's a dream.
Okay.
It's a dream. You know what the sad
thing is? Most people like myself,
I would go there and I would go crazy
because there was nothing to do.
Look at these fucking pictures. It's
all the second Clint Eastwood movie.
You don't know. Oh my God. Look at the
sunset. Yeah. I'd go out of my mind here.
Jesus Christ.
Okay.
It's fucking unreal.
I mean at the have you run to a native
American that it doesn't even know that
they lost, right?
Yeah.
Like back in the day when those Japanese
soldiers stayed on the fucking islands,
it kept fighting. World War Two is
old faithful there. Yellowstone.
Yellowstone is in fucking Wyoming.
I never knew that. Oh Man.
I wish I had the time.
I would drive all the way up there
on the John d Rockefeller Jr memorial
parkway. I would go all the way up there.
[inaudible]
why I'm asking me a fucking amazing
state. This is all like fucking like,
like the people that live there.
You got the regular people that
are from their generations,
generations of people that you know
first went across the country and had the
balls to pull up stakes from east coast
and go west and a didn't have the balls
to continue. Like all those real
men that settled in San Francisco,
in Los Angeles, particularly Hollywood.
They stayed there. Right.
And then what you have now is you have
rich Fox and a rich Fox meaning just like
business people and then uh,
celebrities, celebrities,
a big on going out there and buying
someplace where they can just get away and
clear their head, you know,
become a singer songwriter,
wherever the fuck it is they want to
do. I'd like to do that Shit, man.
I'd like to fucking rent a log cabin
out there. But like one of those,
it looks like a log
cabin from the outside,
but on the inside it looks like a
house. Right. Like an updated one,
not a real one with a
dirt floor, you know,
so grizzly bear sticking his face
through the fucking kitchen window.
Like there is a kitchen that's
just a fireplace. Right.
Fuck all that. You know what I mean?
I, I, you know something, this is what,
you know what I always enjoyed most
about fucking skiing cause this time of
year, I'm sure there's great skiing.
Uh, even with global warming, right?
Which we're not causing evidently
from the documentaries that I watched,
I didn't watch him. I just saw the
links and I was just like, you know,
I'm too fucking busy. I'm too
busy. I'm staying with the,
I'm staying with my life, you know? Um,
well the thing that I like most about
skiing is after skiing and going down to
the lodge and sitting by the fire
and getting shit faced, you know,
the whole skiing itself and worrying
that I'm going to blow out my knee.
I fucking hate skiing, man.
I respect the hell out of it.
I think it's an amazing workout.
But like a, I should take a lesson.
I never took a lesson. I was
like, I can skate. Right.
And I just started going down
the blue square ones, right?
Then of course you know your ego, then
it's black diamond, double black diamond.
I don't wear a helmet.
It's really fucking dumb and I don't
know how to fall and whatever I do,
one knee goes one way, one goes
the other way and it's just like,
you know what I should just do,
I should just buy all the ski ship Shit
minus the fucking poles in the skis and
then just go do cardio like a
fucking maniac for two hours. Okay.
Then I put all the ski shit on a roll
around on the snow and then I come walking
into the lodge and just say I went
down some quadruple black diamond.
I would like an IPA night.
And then I sit there,
a couple of snow bunnies
come walking up, right
little have she have fun and I'm in
there. Um, but that's not going to happen.
I'm just going to go to Cheyenne
and tell some shit jokes.
That's what's going to happen.
You know what sucks is I'm
barely into that beautiful state,
mark my words. At some point I'm
going to a, I've got to do a tour,
uh,
you know, of all I, you know, go from
fucking Wyoming over to Nebraska,
up through the Dakotas, through
Montana, down through fucking Idaho,
back over to Yellowstone. And
then I'll fucking hit home.
I had to do one of those fucking
runs. That'd be a fun one.
Cost a fucking fortunate gas. It'd
be fucking city. There's like nine,
eight hours, nine hour
dries between each of them.
I run into some comics that have
done those runs out there. Dude,
that is not for the fucking faith of
heart. I can tell you that right now. But,
um, I'm definitely going
to do that. You know,
I'm psyched cause I haven't, I haven't
been in Nebraska in a long fucking time.
I used to all of those things.
I was just watching better
call Saul and when they,
when name and some of the cities,
you know, I was going like,
I fucking know those Hays Grand
Junction. I bend to all of those.
That's on route 80. Route 80
goes through Nebraska. I'm sorry,
what the fuck am I talking about? Let's,
let's back up here for a second. Oh,
freckles flew yesterday in the helicopter.
I flew with my instructor by
and we flew all the way up to
Santa Barbara and came back and um,
was fucking incredible. And I went
along the coastline the whole way.
I was trying to get a,
a a three point. Um,
I needed 3.4 on the Hobbs
me to have 100 hours right.
And uh,
ended up getting a 2.9 cause we had a
tailwind and I also took the coasts back
rather than going along the
one-on-one and down the four oh five,
but just was too beautiful. Did
Not do it. And on the way back, um,
you go over this, uh, navy airstrip,
which is restricted
area, but if, you know,
if they don't have any planes
coming in, they let you fly over it.
So we were flying along the coast of
it and they let us go in and they said,
you know,
and then they came back on the radio and
they said they had a couple of planes
coming in to basically
keep your eye out for it.
And of course my instructor finds
him first and I look, I go, dude,
I only see one. Where's the
other one? Where's the other one?
Where's the other one? I'm
like, freaking out. He goes, no,
they're like fucking those FAA teens,
they fly like really close together.
And sure enough when they turned the
corner there was like two of them.
And they do this fucking sick ass approach
that they do is they come in right
turn base and turned final.
And as they come in, right,
one of them peels away. Neither one
of them lands on the first pass.
They fly right over the runway.
One of them does a tight circle.
And the other does a bigger circle and
then they just fucking one lands and the
other one comes in right in and after
them it's fucking and say what was funny
was the tower was going on once the
other hotel that keep a traffic in sight.
And I'm like, yeah, keeping
traffic at site once Sierra hotel.
And then I'm like going like,
like I could do anything if that
fucking thing was coming at me.
Like this thing was like in like a
f, like not even like a Lamborghini.
He's like in a Ferrari, not a fry me
enough to fucking Batmobile. Right.
Whatever.
It's more like one of those land speed
fucking things they have out there in the
, uh, the, the Salt Lake,
whatever the fuck the salt flats,
the fucking salty dirt out there
in Utah. And I'm in this fucking,
I was basically in a Chevy Chevette.
Like if it came at me, like,
what was I going to do other than be
like, and then that would have been
what a way to go. Um, but
when we were coming back down,
um, we got to a point on the,
a lot of geography in this one.
We got along at this point on the
California coast, which is called, uh,
I think, I think dunes point. I'd
never flown up there before. And um,
there's a sick ass fucking house
there, right as you go up there.
It's got like a fucking a pool that's
shaped like a fucking cutlass. Oh,
like a sword. And we will
looking at that as it,
as we came down a little bit further, um,
we saw something splashing in the water
and we looked down and it was a whale
coming up by breaching, I
believe is what you call it.
And we did a little loop around, I got
some video, I'll put that up there. Um,
it was fucking amazing. And then there's
just this point, I think maybe it's,
maybe that was further up.
I think it was further up north
when we came around dunes point.
Like all of a sudden you could start
to see lax and then Santa Monica,
Culver City,
and then downtown La is one of the most
beautiful flights that I've been on.
But the big thing was, um,
I flew by lax and I made all the
radio calls, which is, you know,
Bravo airspaces I've mentioned before,
and that's like the shit where I'm,
you need explicit permission to go into
that airspace where they have to read
your whole fucking tail
number. And, uh, I dunno,
it's like you feel like you're fucking
talking to God when you talk to those
guys. So I had rehearsed the radio call
like fucking 30 times on the drive down.
And, uh, I was able to say it
with enough confidence, um,
that he didn't sound too much
like an asshole. And, um,
and he let us go through and
it was kind of anticlimactic.
I had really built it up in my fucking
head. But anyway, so I went back,
I got a 2.9, so old freckled says 99.5,
um, 99.5 hours. So, uh,
I was supposed to fly today but I was
tired and I don't fuck around doing that
shit. I'm just like, yeah, I'm feeling
tired. I'm not feeling it. Fuck it. Um,
so anyways, another thing
that I was looking up is, uh,
is beautiful as these
states are, you know,
that I've been going to all of
these states that people, you know,
consider fly overstates and fucking
what the fuck goes on there. You know,
just shitting all over him even though
they're absolutely gorgeous and there's
great people out there is um, you know,
just to the drug use and that type
of shit is really fucking bad.
The heroin man, everywhere I go
is this fucking heroin problem.
And they keep linking it
back to these, uh, you know,
people having an injury,
I saw this on real sports.
People have an injury and then they
get like whatever they get the fucking,
was it percosets Viking and I don't know
what the fuck it is. Oxy and that shit.
And then when that runs out, they still
want that high and heroin is cheaper.
And it's just like, you know, once again,
once again you would think, you know,
with all this shit of talking
about terrorism, you know,
and people doing shit to
this country for some reason,
you can fuck with the food supply and
you can get your own countrymen addicted
to heroin. And as long as you've got
enough fucking money, nobody gives a shit.
It's completely flag. Isn't
that like an act of terrorism?
Am I out of my fucking mind? How
can you do that to fellow Americans?
You'll ruin people's
lives. It's fucking brutal.
But it's one of the reasons why I stay
out of the politics shit. You know,
every once in awhile I look at
this stuff and it just, I dunno,
it's like overwhelmingly
depressing, you know, like,
um, I saw us up to the other day on, uh,
for some reason I was looking up Chelsea
Clinton cause I saw her on TV with
Hillary and Hillary was giving a speech.
Yeah. [inaudible]
right. And I was literally going like,
there's no fucking way I can listen
to that voice for four fucking years.
I just can't, I am not against a
woman being president whatsoever,
but you cannot sound like somebody's
learning how to play a trumpet, Dee.
I just, I don't give us, you could have
all the answers to the fucking universe.
There is no fee. Can't
hear what she's saying.
Yeah, yeah.
You know, my dog's looking at
me right now. Like, really? Um,
so anyways, so I looked up and I was
just going like, how old is she now?
And when I started out in comedy,
she was just a kid. And, um,
you know,
she was at that awkward age and it
was kind of this nice unwritten rule,
you know, you did make fun of her
wishing that fucking awkward age. Right.
I was like, was she like 12 or
something like that? And, uh,
I went to go look it up. You
know how old she was final,
she was in her thirties,
which fucking blew my mind,
even though obviously it was
20 years ago. Right. But, um,
what killed me is what I saw was
they had a stat on our wedding.
Do you know our parents fucking
through are a $3 million wedding.
Okay.
Like these politicians is so fucking
dishonest. They don't even try to hide it.
It's like, how the fuck could you afford
a $3 million wedding? The most money,
either one of you ever made in public
service was, was being president,
which was 400 grand of fucking year.
Dude, you make 400 fucking grand a year.
They're going to whack you in half.
You're going to maybe walk with 200,
right? Nowadays probably less
than that. Probably one 95.
What the fuck are you getting
off playing for a fucking
[inaudible]?
You got a fucking $3 million wedding
house on fucking math is vineyard.
Give me a fucking break. These
cars go around, right? All right,
got another Hershey's kiss my mom. So
you know I'm playing them true. Um,
these guys go around.
They just give speeches and his wife
two 53 in a grand a fucking whack.
Just giving speeches. Can you imagine
paying a trainer? Granted, listen,
sunny for an hour ago,
right, right.
For a fucking hour.
Now you got sickly Clinton with
that awful face lifted he got,
which just made his head
look fucking huge. You know,
he's lost all that weight and
he got it. You got a chin,
whatever the fuck he did to his
chin, he yanked that fucker back.
He looked like a bobble head version
of himself and I'll tell you,
his shit's Yag back so tidy. Can't even
clap anymore. You know what I mean?
Either that or that's his true
failings about his wife. Right.
What you can't blame,
you really can't blame Bill Clinton for
going out and taking a cigar and putting
it in that woman. You know what I mean?
If like that's what he's laying
next to his bed. I mean I, you know,
Jesus Christ, if I was married to
Hillary Clinton, she would have to have,
you know, those, those surgical masks
that Asian people wear when they get sick,
cause they don't want to get anybody
else sick cause they're fucking courteous
or because it's like nine zillion
people that live next door.
They get turned into an epidemic. I
don't fucking know why they do it. Right.
I would make her wear one of those all
the time because maybe then she'd sound
like a muted trumpet. Right.
And every once in a while she'd hit a
couple of notes that remind me of a miles
Davis song and then maybe I could just
stop myself from strangling her in the
fucking Oval Office.
Yeah.
She reminds me like an animal that
like is getting eaten alive. You know,
you ever hear that? Like, just like
time I saw that fucking monkey,
that other monkey alive just digging
meat out of its back. And he's like,
you know, it's sort of like, not
as sharp but not as quick as that.
Um,
anyways, and they fucking that,
that Bernie Sanders guys with his
fucking [inaudible]. You look at Bro,
you know, you wonder why Bill Clinton
got a fucking face lift and then you,
yeah, you're fucking, you got his neck
done. Then you look at Bernie Sanders,
you're like, oh, that's why Jesus
Christ, he looks like a fucking,
he looks like a bloodhound
eating a fucking Turkey dinner,
jowls flopping all around. We go,
you're in a federal job. All right.
All of these guys that Jerry
Jersey guy looks all fat,
then everybody else just looks
like an extra to me. Granted,
I have not listened to one fucking word.
Any of them have said, but it's a, it's
going to be interesting. Oh really?
Bill, you think it's
going to be interesting,
a presidential election that
might Pique your interest?
You have freckled arrogant country.
Um, anyways, so,
so what else? I'm doing a,
I'm doing a show tonight.
I got some new fucking material. I'm
really excited about it. And, uh,
I want to thank everybody
who bought tickets out and
Cheyenne at Denver, Denver.
I'm, I'm, I'm, I'm not gonna come
there and shit on your fucking team.
I would do that to you. I'll have fun
with it. And then at the end of the day,
no matter how much I fucking allude to
the 800 pound roided up elephant in the
fucking room metal, how much I allude to
that you can just sit back and be like,
well, it gives a fuck. We
won the Super Bowl, right?
Rocky map had Colorado.
All right, let's read
it. Let's do some, uh,
let's do some goddamn reads here
for this week. All right? Okay,
me undies May, undies me undies.
Your wife's taking h, g h Badu
Dude to be on these B and e's.
Sorry. All right.
This year don't be predictable and show
up at Valentine's Day dinner with some
last minute box of chocolates or a bouquet
of roses that are going to die in a
week. Anyways, shots fired. Give the gift.
Everyone is talking about. Nobody
is talking about this underwear.
Hey man, did you hear about me undies? No.
Do you want to know? All right. Dead.
Show your special somewhat. Just
how much you care. What the present.
You'll both love a gift that looks great
and feels great to sometimes something
that says you deserve the best.
Treat yourself and your boo two
a matching pair of me undies.
Creamy. The world's most comfortable
underwear. Please include the fall modal,
modal, Motown, the and this underwear
is coming is as comfy as it gets.
His coming gross me undies
are made of micro modal,
modal fabric, meaning they're
twice as soft as cotton.
You know what? I'm sick of saying that.
I'm going to fucking look that
up right now. Modal verse,
Cotton Bump, bump, bump,
[inaudible], googly ugly little
tonight mode. Albertsons, con,
a men's underwear. Fabric types.
The ones considered artificial
silk. Oh, it's artificial silk.
Holy Shit.
Okay,
wait a minute. Once considered
an artificial silk silk,
it was once considered, considered
an artificial silk. Gross.
What the fuck is that? Jesus Christ.
All of a sudden this ad came
down and it was a shredded duty.
Looked like a diver. I
remember I was shredded.
Greg Louganis was with these little
skivvies on at his fucking package.
Jesus Christ. They should've been
awarding a package delivery on the way.
All right. Once considered
an artificial silk modal.
Modal is a type of ray on what they used
to make slacks in the 70s that's softer
than cotton and is smooth and
thought and breathes extremely well.
They you go, there you go.
No more sweaty balls and luxurious fabric.
My mistake, excuse me,
it's cool to the touch absorbent,
gross and similar and textured as silk
or cotton. Unlike cotton, however,
it is resistant to shrinkage
and less likely to fade or pill.
Well, Jesus Christ. Don't I owe
everybody fucking me undies in apology.
I'll never be a current again
when I read this. All right,
the twice as soft as cotton. It's an
artificial silk. Okay, I'll go with that.
Keeps your balls dry. It's cool to the
touch and they don't just feel great.
Feel Great. They look great
to me. Undies comes in.
Tons of cool prints and styles and
new designs come out every month.
That sounds like a lie. Anytime
they say tons, give me a number. Oh,
there's tons of them. Got them right
around the corner. Just give me the money.
A,
you won't want to miss February's limited
edition design from legendary artists,
Keith haring. Oh fuck he. Aaron.
What the fuck is Keith? Eric,
hang on a second. Keith.
The fuck is Keith Herring.
He probably opens for Clinton
when he fucking gives speeches.
Can I ask them all of them?
Silky underwear for she sucks.
My Dick Keith Herring wasn't.
It was an American artist.
This guy's fucking dead. How the
hell is he designing underwear?
Yeah.
1958 to 1990
he was 32 Jesus Christ. He died young.
He was an American artists and social
activists. Oh, of course he died.
Those are the fucking people that the
government puts shit in your coffee.
Whose work responded to the New York City
street culture of the eighties concept
of birth deck set death,
sexuality in war. She's crunchy.
Going to put this on underwear.
Okay.
Oh yeah, the stick figures. Oh yeah.
This guy had his own style. I
actually know what this guy's shit is.
I've seen that before. I don't get it.
I mean it looks like a fucking better
version when I drew in kindergarten.
But then again, a lot of
modern art does. Hey Bill,
why don't just read the
fucking copy? Alright.
It's retro design is inspired by love
making it the perfect Valentine's Day
gift.
Grab yourself a pair and celebrate the
holiday sporting matching underwear with
your sweetheart groves and me
undies has to keep it for free.
Guarantee has it. Keep
it for free guarantee.
If you don't fall in love with your
first pair of Cape Them and you get your
money back, no questions asked.
So what are they going to do?
Return them and then you're
going to resell them. All right.
This year when Valentine's Day
head-to-head me, undies.com what?
This year when valent this year
when Valentine's Day, head to me,
undies.com/burr now to get free
shipping at 20% off your first order.
See that I just saw when and then head.
So when head to head I
went to a sports place. Um,
don't wait till the last minute.
Get a matching pair of this month's
limited edition print while you still can
and get 20% off your order at Mandy's
me
undies.com/burb that's Mandy's dot com
slash bar for free shipping and 20% off
your first order of the
world's most comfortable.
All right. Legal Zoom legal
symbol for another year passes.
Take the time to get your life organized
with legal zoom. Do you have a family?
Do you have any assets? The old property,
if any of those answers were yes,
you should have an estate plan.
Don't worry if that sounds,
if that sounds complicated,
legal zone can help legal
zooms, estate plan bundles. Uh,
eliminate the guesswork.
You don't have to figure out on your own.
You don't have to figure out on your
own whether I will or living trust works
best for you. Instead,
you work with an independent attorney
available in most states, wouldn't it?
In that how you do it anyways. Uh,
they'll walk you through the options
and recommend in a state plan that best,
uh, that offers the best
solution to fit your needs.
Since legal zoom is not a law firm,
you can count on efficiency and value.
It's such a [inaudible]
weird sentence to me. Everything is
on your, yeah, we're not a law firm.
We'll fucking breeze right through this.
Everything is on your
schedule and your turns.
Plus you'll know what your state
planned bundles cost up front instead of
worrying about hourly rates.
That's how legal zoom has
become the leader in helping
small business owners and
families with their legal needs.
You get legal help and you'll
walk away feeling great. God Damn,
that was awesome.
Get your life organized with an
estate bundle@legalzoom.com today.
Don't forget to enter burpee. You
are in the referral box at checkout.
That's Code
burr@legalzoom.com. All righty.
There we go. All right, that's going
to be the Thursday afternoon podcast.
Once again,
Andrew Families' is going to give you
some cool music that I know nothing about,
um, as he does every single week.
Uh, thank you guys for listening.
I hope you have your wonderful
weekend, your constant bronco fans.
I'm just fucking with you.
Okay? I don't give a shit.
You think I'm not going to be
on Roids when I'm, you know,
I was going to say older.
I'm going to be 48 this year,
so I should probably
start taking it, you know,
start showing up to gigs
with no neck. You know,
seeing if people fucking, dude,
you know what fucking Peyton
Manning's neck and head look like.
Do you remember when Steve Was Shimmy?
You got stuck in that chipper in Fargo?
Do you remember when his leg was
just sticking out with the foot?
That's what paint man, his neck
looks like. You just stick a head.
Stick a head on it. Sorry. Got
The hiccups. All right, that's it.
Go Fuck Yourself.
Enjoy the throwback podcast for the
last half hour and the wonderful music.
I'll talk to you on Monday. [inaudible]
[inaudible]
I never know about. I do now.
Valentine's Day advice. Billy boy,
dear his billion. I know
this is last minute.
I had a question about Valentine's Day.
I am a single guy in my
mid twenties rejoice,
dude, I'm going to tell you right now,
if you're a single guy in
your mid twenties and you
live in America and you're
living on your own, please
dropped to your knees and thank whatever
gods you pray to every day because
you're never going to
be free or in your life.
I know you've probably got
student loans at Blah, blah, blah,
the stress and all that
bullshit. Fuck that. Okay?
Do you never going to
be freer in your life?
Go get three years
supplies of condoms, okay,
and bang away my friend. Maybe you
don't need to do it for three years.
Maybe you're one of those
guys for only three weeks,
but you need to get it out of
your system. All right? He says,
I never really had a girlfriend for
whatever reason. Oh, Jesus Christ.
All right, we're gone the whole
other other way. Truth be told,
my friends could name numerous
reasons why I don't have a girlfriend,
but that's an entirely different
issue. What? Jesus Christ,
there's a fucking can of worms.
They can.
You don't seem defensive or argumentative.
So I don't know if it's an
anger issue that, look, I'm,
I'm so sick of trying to be
fucking Hannibal Lecter here.
Trying to guess what your shoes look
like with w with the way you write,
you know. All right. I'm just gonna
read the rest of the shit. Uh,
as of right now, I am currently
sleeping with three girls off of,
see you fucking, you'll
get knocking it out.
I thought you'd like never
had a girlfriend like,
and you've never banged
anybody. Alright. My fault.
All right.
Do go fuck yourself.
You're a guy in your mid twenties and
you fucking three girls right now and I'm
on this. You need advice? I
keep doing what you're doing.
Um, anyways, depending on what day of
the week it is and how much I've drank.
Okay. That depends on how
many girls he's paying it.
I've never lied to any of the,
any of any of them about where
our relationship is going.
And although they never met each other,
each of them has an idea that I'm seeing
other girls. It's kind of a don't ask,
don't tell policy. Um, yeah, dude and
I, you got to come with that. You know,
you can open with that, you know,
what are you doing? I'm dating,
I'm playing the field. I mean,
people you're dating right now.
A couple of people kind of seeing
just having a good time. Well,
I don't do stuff like that.
Well there's the door sweetheart
then they'll respect like that.
The honesty of that. Some won't,
some will actually have
self esteem and walked out,
but a lot of them they'll hang around
eventually that if tired their neck gets
weak and they'll fall right
in your fucking Dick. Um,
birthdays and Christmas are always a
piece of cake because all that requires a
quick text or a phone call or at
the very most drinks at the bar.
But Valentine's Day is tricky.
Our dates consist of bar
hopping and drunk sex.
So flowers and a nice dinner would
completely send the wrong message. Dude,
you selfish Kahn?
Are you asking me how to keep banging
these three chicks while getting through
Valentine's Day?
Why don't you just look at the Valentine's
Day like that's your pussy getting
all star break.
Just take three days off the day before
the day after on the day of just say,
uh, what are you doing for
Valentine's Day? Um, uh,
I'm going to be a Jesus. Where are
you going to be? I don't, you know,
I don't have a good one for that
one. All right. You know what?
I just put myself in your shoes
and I understand your problem now.
You said I got to do a
little bit of trouble.
Last year one of the girls
texted me and said, you know,
every girl likes flowers
on Valentine's Day.
He said, I knew my response couldn't
be. Yeah, but if I get you flowers done,
I have to get you flowers
for all the other girls.
So I just post out and
responded. Yeah, well, oh dude,
you shouldn't responded at all.
You know, every girl likes to give flowers
on Valentine's Day. Isn't that funny?
And that has nothing to do with most
likely her having any sort of feelings
towards you. It's just
the bitch next to her.
And the other cubicle probably got some,
you know why the girl on their fucking,
whatever the fuck you want to call it.
Some guy broke my balls this
week was fucking hilarious.
He was trashing me say come off as a
pompous ass because I always talk about
anybody who doesn't do comedy
works in a cubicle, you know?
And for some reason he decided to take
that seriously and tell me that he
actually works at the u n and
travels all around the world.
Okay.
If that's actually true. Sarah, why
don't you just get on with doing that?
You work at the UN and you
travel all over the world.
Why would you give a fuck
what some absolute jackass.
You say it on a fucking podcast. How
insecure are you? Your insecurities?
Probably a great thing cause that's
probably the thing that drove you to be at
the UN where you travel all around
the world. You know what sir?
Good for you. That's awesome.
I hope working at the UN and traveling
all around the world fills you up some
point where it fills you up high enough
where you don't have to respond to a
silly joke on some dumb ass podcast. Um,
I travel all around the world. Um,
you know what? That's
actually a great fucking job.
Do you feel like you get
anything done? You know,
do you sit there wearing that headpiece
next to that guy who's wearing the water
buffalo hat? I buy their beer
at the above doing that shit.
And you're sitting there trying to talk
to him about how you can sell your rich
crackers. Did their country, is that
what you're doing when you're traveling?
All around the where I
travel all around the world.
I can just see you on the plane
with the of fucking dress socks on.
You have a dash cunt. Oh,
just sitting there or what movies am I
gonna Watch on this flight as I travel
all around the world? Um, anyways.
Yeah.
You know something sir? You had you,
you had the James Bond job and then
you fucking, you played yourself.
I don't know why you did
that. Why would you fucking,
that's like me responding to people
on Twitter. Why would I do it?
I should pretend like I have
better things to do. Um, anyways,
I want to keep seeing all these
girls back to this guy, but this,
but at the same time, I don't want
any broken hearts on Valentine's Day.
Oh two. You know what? Go [inaudible].
I don't know. What is your problem here,
dude? Yeah. You like a Gemini. It's
like you're this fucking lady killer.
Then also you kind of like you
how you want to hurt anybody. She,
I get her some jam jams. I can't even,
I won't talk to the fucking UN guy.
What the hell was going on here again?
Valentine's Day got a little
trouble as you, well listen,
you're anticipating trouble. Didn't you
learn anything from last year? You know,
every girl likes flowers
on Valentine's Day.
Okay.
Um, what, what would I write back?
I know what my response would be.
The second I read that if it was just
some girl I was banging and then they
wrote that I would get this
awful feeling in my stomach
and I would, I would read it and
as I got that awful feeling, I'd go
and make that noise.
Yeah.
You know that thing like when you're
just banging a girl and then all of a
sudden she just fucking
makes that comment. You know,
you think she's on the same page as you.
When did, she just makes that comment,
you know, I was thinking about you today.
You just feel that feeling in your
stomach. Yes. Oh yeah. Well a don't
fucking worst. Ah, you
gotta be one and done,
but one had done is scary. You just gotta
be honest. I don't know if some girls,
what would I say? You know, every
girl likes flowers on Valentine's Day.
Um, what would I text back? Yeah.
You know, that's what I heard.
You know what I, you know when
I shouldn't give you shit,
I don't have a good
response to that. Well,
maybe someday you'll meet a
guy who wants to give you some,
you want to get drunk and fuck. Um,
and I got nothing and you can't ignore it.
You know what I would've done?
I would've ignored the text
and I would have called her,
but a good three hours later, three,
four hours, three hours later,
that's a good one. You call her,
you ignore that text and then you call
and she goes hell hour. And they're like,
hey, what's going on? What
are you doing tonight?
I got no plans Valentine's
Day. What are you doing?
He just started with
that and then she, well,
what are you at it there?
And she'll be seen.
If you're going to take
it in some romantic,
you know, direction and you don't,
you just keep it in the fuck buddy.
I figured we'd go down to our
meet hammers or whatever the fuck
we go down to. Uh,
take it the face and have a couple
pitchers of beer and see what happens.
Dude, you know what? You're, you're,
it seems to me you're not
just fucking these girls.
You're actually having like these
mini relationships with them.
You know the, the key to
having a fuck buddy is,
is the time between fucking them.
And I don't give a shit how much a
woman says that she can handle it.
Most of them can't. Most of them can't.
If you fucking come on over
there and you, and it just,
eventually they're going to
get feelings. They're more,
I don't know if they're more mature
or if it's a defect. It's just,
I just respect the fact that
that's how they're wired. So
if you have a fuck buddy, okay, let's,
let's just do the math. Okay, now, now,
February is a very short month here. So
let's just say right out of the gate,
you fucker on February 2nd all right?
You shouldn't come around again
til at least the 17th and progress.
You Fuck and you leave
f and l,
you fuck them and then you leave.
You don't bang her on the SEC.
You Bang around the second and
then you bang her on the seventh.
You're in a fucking
relationship in their world.
You know,
unless you,
literally this second you have
an orgasm as you're coming,
you're scooping up your clothes
and you walk out like half naked,
then you just bizarre is another
good way to keep them at bay.
And why don't I just read the rest of
the, to see what his question is here.
He says, I want to keep
seeing all these girls,
but at the same time I don't want to Bray,
I don't want any broken hearts
on Valentine's Day. Yeah,
you want to keep fucking all of
them now do what you have to have.
You have to have a road involving door.
You have to have a stable of women if
you're going to this life or you have to
give into fucking rubbing
one out. All right?
But you can't be a relationship guy
with three different women cause you are
going to end up hurting them. So
what you have to constantly be doing,
you gotta be like a
college coach. All right?
Every year you lose some top prospects,
but you're out there recruiting. Okay.
See you. So you maintain, but it's
never ending. It's fucking exhausting.
But if that's the game you want to
play, that's what you have to do.
So that girl who says, you know,
every girl likes flowers on Valentine's
Day right there, you put on waivers,
okay, for a fucking piece of
ass to be named later, you got,
you got to get rid of her.
Okay. And you got to look,
go back and analyze what the fuck you
did wrong that she felt it was okay for
her to text you cause you fucked up. That
right there shows that you fucked up,
that she felt that she could send that
to you if you think you're just fucked
buddies. All right? So
anyways, he continues. He says,
I know that like it or not,
this shit is important to women.
If I take one girl out, I'm playing
favorites and setting a bad precedent.
Plus if she does that check in Shit
on Facebook, I'm completely fucked.
Yeah Dude, you're doing dirtbag shit.
If you're a single guy and something
could happen that fucks you on Facebook,
you're leaving these
girls on anyways. He says,
if I take none of them out or do nothing,
I have three irritable
ladies on my hand. Dude,
are you going to marry any of
them now? Well then let them go.
Why don't you have the
balls to do that? You know,
when a team halfway through the season
just realized their weight went in this
shit, just pull a fucking
Marlin's. Just get rid of everybody
and then your fan base is your
Dick and they're going to,
he's going to be pissed for awhile.
Um, but then you build it back
up again. Build it back up again.
You know, I dunno, look to it. If you
want to be in a fucking relationship,
you know, there's other ways
about going about and doing this,
but you're trying to have your cake
and eat it. Um, told you, get you,
you got three women right now, you're
banging in three different women.
Where's your confidence?
You know what you're doing.
All right.
Dump to keep one at bay
and then get two more.
Then dump the other one and get
the other ones. You see them.
You don't even dump them. You
just phase him out, phase him out.
But the new recruits that you get in, you
gotta be straight up honest with them.
You know, unless you actually feel
failure, if you're feeling no failings,
you know, don't keep coming back
fucking them. Unless you know,
you get that 15 day,
you fuck them on the second
you fuck them on the 17th,
then you're into March and
then bang her on like the 11th.
All right? And even then, they
can't catch feelings doing that.
But before you know it,
you know, that's like 14,
15 days out of the year taken up while
you, well, you got to bag somebody.
This is such, this is a,
this is really should be eye opening to
women that I'm actually saying this is
really, uh, this is really awful
that I'm speaking this out loud. Um,
he says, in a perfect world,
I'll take all of them out at once and
have the force and I've been chasing after
my entire life, but we don't
always get what we want.
Any advice from the lovely neo
would be much appreciated as well.
Love the podcast. Go Fuck Yourself. Uh,
yeah,
she probably wouldn't have been is a
understanding is I was even going to give
you a lot of shifts.
[inaudible] [inaudible]
I've been asking some of the
ladies to Reagan and uh, finally,
I haven't even read this yet, but this
already seems like goals. This is,
this is the, the
and the subject line
of this email. It says,
I think the guy I'm dating is a pussy.
Hello Bill. I am a 21 year old student.
I began listening to your podcast recently
and I heard you complaining about how
women have not written in,
in awhile and being a woman myself
decided to do so and asks you for advice.
Well, God bless you. Uh, I live at
home with my mom and go to college.
I recently found a very nice guy. Uh,
they were at college and
was really into them,
but then I started
suspecting something strange.
I started suspecting that
maybe he was a pussy.
At first I thought it was pretty harmless,
but then one night we had a house
party and everyone was pretty drunk.
And a friend of mine who I haven't seen
in a while was there and when everyone
was way, way, way past drunk,
she tried to get into a fight with me
and eventually pushed me down the wall,
then stole my iPhone and he
was there and did nothing.
Jesus Christ.
I was so scared that I called
my ex to come get me any did.
Wow.
Right. You think you're dating a pussy?
I mean that right there g and he just
stood there and let this other guy who
used to hook up with you come
in riding in on his white horse.
Anyways,
my ex was more of a man than the guy
was dating now even though the guy I'm
dating was drunk, I felt like he should
have protected me or done something,
anything.
He did nothing and later he even confessed
to me that he was scared of my drunk
friend and even scared of
me. What the fuck? Right.
Even though he says this
will never happen again.
I have enough knowledge to know that
people do do not usually change like that,
you know? That's really wise that
you're really wise for your age at 21,
if you, if you are already not
buying into the, I'm gonna Change,
that's a, you're, you're wise
beyond your years. You know,
they say that your, basically,
your psychological makeup is
done by the time you're three.
So if you see some little toddler standing
there while somebody is taking his
blocks, that kid's going to be a pussy
anyway. So should I be upset or give him
another chance? Is this a deal breaker?
Is there no way to change a
guy from a pussy to a real man?
Should I just break off
things off with him and if so,
should I remain friends with him? Thanks
bill. And I hope you read this. Uh,
I love you in the Oh,
that's nice. Um, all right.
This is the deal. Uh, you ask a question,
is there no way to change a
guy from a pussy to a real man?
No, I don't think. I
think that that happens.
I think it happens way more in movies
where somebody has a life changing moment.
Uh,
and then they just decide I'm
not going to take shit anymore.
But even then,
that just begins the journey of not
being a pussy. You don't just say,
I'm not going to be a pussy and then
Bam, you're not a pussy anymore.
You have to, you got to work your way up.
It's like if you were a hundred pounds
overweight and you're like this,
I'm done. I'm not eating
fucking ice cream anymore.
The next day you don't
have a six pack, you know,
takes a fucking year or something. You
really gotta turn it around. So, um,
I dunno, what are you
looking for in a guy? I mean,
I think the fact that you're
writing me and you're saying,
I think the guy I'm dating
is a pussy. I mean that,
that actually hurts me on some level
just because I insert myself into this
story and the person I'm dating would
be calling me a pussy or it could be the
ex, I guess. I don't know. This isn't
about me. This is about you. Come up,
you'll stop being selfish. All right. Um,
I think you've totally
lost respect for this guy.
And if you don't respect
the person you're with,
eventually you're going to
blow somebody else. You know,
if you don't break up with this
guy, that's what I'm predicting.
If you don't break up with this guy,
you just going to cheat on him just
to facilitate getting out of the
relationship because uh, you know,
to get to that ll cool j moment,
we can just be fucking on us.
But I don't think you'd like that when
something about you knowing that people
don't change your age and the fact that
you like, you know, this guy's a pussy,
he's not sticking up for me.
And the fact that he didn't stick up for
you and then you took charge and say,
well I'm going to fucking
call somebody who will,
I mean technically you should have fucked
your ex boyfriend that night and he,
and he shouldn't have been mad.
He should have been like Eddie probably
wouldn't have been cause he's a pussy.
Ain't I stared, oh man. You know when
you needed a big swinging dick. I mean,
God knows it wasn't me. So, uh, yeah.
Um, I think if you don't
break up with this guy,
you're actually fighting
nature. All right? And
you guys are wired to too,
I know you guys aren't wired
to just have kids with pussies.
You know what I mean? You want a
strong son, right? You know, like,
you know what that Pussy DNA and your
kid, right? Oh, that's going to kill you.
Imagine that you have a kid with this
guy and you want this kid to be like a,
like your ex boyfriend and it comes down
and it's like this fucking little wormy
worm guy. Ah, that'd be awful.
Walking down the aisle to marry
this guy with dead sheepish.
[inaudible] you do you know what?
That you want this guy to be the man
standing down there in a white Tuxedo,
like fucking Roger Moore on James
Bond. I think. I think, uh, look,
I don't know if this just
happened and you're really upset.
So, uh, you know, and like,
and in three days you're not going to
care and you're going to go back to having
a picnic with this guy because for all
I know, your ex who came coming back,
maybe you broke up with him
because he cheated on you.
Maybe he was too much of a
guy, if you know what I mean.
So then you said, well,
all right, I'm gonna.
Maybe I'm this next time I'm dating a
nice guy to now you dated a nice guy.
The thing about is sometimes
you'd date a nice guy.
They can be so nice that they're
pussies. All right? And look, I'm not,
I'm not sitting there
acting like, you know,
if I'm out with my girl in some
fucking 200 pounds, 300 pounds,
Jack fucking 25 year old comes
up and starts doing shit,
then I'm going to start swinging
because I'm not, I'm not,
I'm not getting my fucking head
kicked in just for the fuck of it now.
You know what I mean? I mean,
it's not like just, you know,
straight across the board as a guy,
you have to fucking go and get
your Goddamn head kicked in.
But this was a fucking woman.
This was a, I mean he's Jesus.
It is a weird situation
in defense of him where,
how do you get the fucking iPhone back?
You start wrestling with her and now
you're kind of fucking throwing a girl
around so you're looking at that possible
assault charge cause God knows that's
how the world worked. Works
right now. Your honor.
I was trying to steal a phone and he,
that this guy is salted me and you're
going to be sitting there going,
she was stealing of phone and then
not gonna be able to get past your,
you're a guy and she's a girl. But um,
yeah, he should have just,
he should've just held her by the back
of her pants so she couldn't leave and
just stayed out of reach of her swinging.
That's what you do. If you're
in that situation as that guy,
you just reached out,
you grabbed by the back of your pants
and you just start running in a circle
until cops get there. So they can't swing
at Ya. That running backwards. I mean,
I don't know what you,
you gotta you gotta fucking do
something and he didn't do anything.
That's the big thing. If
you told them, honestly,
if you told me that this was some giant
guy who could kick the shit out of him,
uh, I wouldn't say that the guy's a pussy.
You know what I mean? I mean,
what is the point of going
and getting a concussion?
Getting your tooth driven up
through your fucking nose.
The Guy Still gonna leave with
your phone. You know that said old,
uh, Richard Pryor. Bit Macho, man.
I'll take that knife and stick it up
your ass macho man. It's like, no,
you're going to get the shit kicked out
of you. But this was a woman. Alright.
Pill for fuck sakes. Quit. You have
God damn rambling. Wrap it up. Um,
I think you know what you want
to do when you should do it. Um,
you are dating a pussy. The
fact that when he was sober,
he said that he was scared
of her and have you, uh,
he seems like he's a
little for clamped and uh,
I just can't imagine there's
going to be a stereotype,
but a guy like that actually putting it
on you in the bedroom. I really don't.
He probably stares at you in the eye. Am
I hurting you? Is Everything okay? God,
you're so beautiful. I mean,
come on right. Flip her over.
What's your face in the pillows? I'm
always, she says in ps, don't worry.
Uh,
that con I used to call a
friend who pushed me and
took my phone is no longer in
my life. She gets your phone back.
Well, what happened with you guys?
Now wait a minute. What can
I hear the followup here?
There's so many different ways that this
could be gone. Was that like a girl?
Like when you thought that maybe you were
a swinging another way and now all of
a sudden you broke up with her and
a problem.
[inaudible]
anyway, I got them into the biggest,
dumbest fucking fight last
night with my girl, right?
We had this great day, you
know, everything's going great.
So I stay in, I take a night off from
comedy and I say, Hey, why don't we watch,
why don't we watch your
movie? You know what I mean?
Cap Off this wonderful fucking
day. Everything's going great.
What could go wrong?
This is like the beginning of a horror
movie where they just show like the
perfect family and everything's great
and people are wearing like white linen,
you know?
And then all of a sudden they just
start showing the camera in the bushes,
like a POV of like Mike Meyers.
This is basically what happens.
So 60 minutes comes on, right?
Who doesn't want to watch that show
and pretend they're smart? You know,
I like it some more that Morley
safer comes on and you know,
we smells like an old person. Some old
people don't smell like old people,
but he looks like he smells
like an old person, you know,
smells of cigars, ash trays,
you know, a couple of wars,
maybe a date rape. Um,
so he's interviewing
Meryl Streep, all right.
The Great Meryl Streep,
and they're going through all our old
oral frigging life and all the movies and
all the different characters that she's
played. Oh, first of all, they start,
they start the report off with
Morley safer just sitting there,
right smelling of fucking Ben
Gay in Whiskey, right? And, uh,
he says, how, you know how
over in England, you know,
they, you know, I dunno, they
make their, their actors, they,
they award them by calling them
Lords and they knight them.
But over here at America,
all we do is just give them the
shiny statue and it's just like,
starts off right off the bat for some
reason, just shitting on America.
I don't know why. Like an
Oscar is somehow beneath
sir, uh, Anthony Michael
Hall. I mean, or, or Lord,
what Lord of what, what are, what,
at least you can fucking hold our
statue, your lord of what kingdom,
that phony horse shit that you have
with Prince Charles in the popper or
whatever the fuck is going
on over there. You know,
look, if the Rothschilds
knight you over there,
then that fucking means something.
Then you can come become part of their
yacht convoy as they go around the world
figuring out how to take over another
currency, right? Then you're in with them.
Okay. But if you're, if you're fucking,
you know, Lord of this and you're,
your wing man is the Duke
of Elton John. I mean,
it's a whole thing is fucking
stupid, right? So right off the bat,
it's already bugging me. But I know Nia
hates when I talk to the TV, right? So,
you know,
I keep my big fucking Yap shut and
they start talking about Meryl Streep.
Babababababa gone through the whole
thing and then I'm the old guy.
They're smelling, have a, you know,
prescription meds goes, uh, you know,
whenever they talk about the roles
you play, they always say, you know,
you play independent minded women,
very strong women. And Meryl Goes,
I know that's, yeah, that's what
they say. You know, when a guy,
they never say to a guy, oh, you're
playing a strong willed character,
Yada Yada Yada. I let that go,
whatever, no Biggie, I'll take that.
It's probably true. The fuck do
I know I'm not a Horman right.
But then they show her after she played
Margaret Stature and she's given a
speech to a bunch of women's young girls.
She's trying to inspire them and she,
she takes a quote from Margaret Thatcher
and it was something along the lines
of, if you want a bunch
of people to talk around,
talk is standing around talking
about doing something, you know,
something a Golden Eagle,
you got to talk to men.
But if you want it to actually get done,
you got to get a woman and then all
the chicks go, Woo. Like flipping out.
Right. So I laughed and I'm
like, Yay. Reverse sexism. Right.
Just seeing, you know, my,
my whole fucking theory how
everybody is just a piece of shit.
You just don't have the power to act
out what the fuck you want to do because
that, that right there, if
you flip that around as a guy,
if you're running for president,
it's fucking over. He can't be like,
let me tell you know,
tell you what after I get you jobs
and after I fixed this economy,
okay? And I'm the man to do it
because I'll tell you right now,
if you're looking for someone to stand
around and talk about doing something,
you get a woman. You want to
get done. You got to get a man.
Here are my nuts right here on the podium.
Vote for me November 4th go fuck
yourself. Right? You did that.
Your presidential campaigns
over. She does it.
It's fucking adorable and it's just as
fucking ignorant, you know what I mean?
What a fuck do you get off saying
that we stand around and do nothing.
Meryl Streep. Huh? Or quoting Margaret
and you too. Margaret Thatcher.
Let me taste you bitches something.
Alright? We faked a fucking lunar landing.
Okay. You think that's just talking.
Anybody can land on the fucking moon,
that's easy.
But to pretend you did it all right and
get everybody to shut the fuck up about
it. That, that, that, that right
there, that takes skill. So whatever.
So I make that little comment and um,
then I just go with that, that, that,
that, that suddenly fucking porky pig. So,
so I make that comment and like, you know,
I've been with Nia long enough that I
can tell by the side of her face when
she's just thinking about like,
what if I just grabbed everything I
really cared about and walked out of this
house right now? She got
like that fucking mad at me,
you know? And I'm like, she's just like,
right after the story was over, she
just shut the fucking thing off. And uh,
I own half an extent. I'm walking to seven
11 and get some ice cream. I haven't,
I've done even what happened
was all going great. You know,
am I the asshole there?
What am I supposed to just fucking sit
there with my mouth hanging open with
drool coming out when I watch TV,
if somebody says something Douchey,
I'm not supposed to say
it, whatever, whatever.
So I just finally just said, you know
what? Fuck this. I take the dog out.
I go around the block. What do I do?
I'm calling my guy friends, right?
They're all backing me up. I'm not
saying who I called. I don't name names,
right? And they're all laughing their
ass off and they 100% agree with me,
which is all I'm looking
for at this point.
I just want people to say that I'm right.
I don't want to learn anything from this
experience. Just tell me I was right.
So it can be an ignorant
ass again. I don't know.
Why don't you guys weigh in on
that? Am I a Dick for saying that?
Should I just let that one go? You
know? Oh, you know what she said?
That fucking drove me up the
wall. She goes, why are you,
she didn't say intimidated.
She was one of those words.
Why are you threatened by what
she, it's like I'm not threatened.
I, yeah, Jesus Christ. Then
I take the bait, you know,
it just sends me right over it, like
threatened about what? Oh my God.
This person that I don't know who has
never called me, nor will ever call me,
who has no effect on my life. How
do you get threatened by that?
I'm just calling it for the bullshit
that it is. Cause you know what?
This is what fucking drives me nuts.
I can't stand when somebody tells me that
their shit sandwich tastes worse than
my shit sandwich. Okay, go fuck yourself.
At what point am I supposed to have
empathy as I'm sitting here eating a shit
sandwich and you're telling me how much
worse your yours, yours is, you know,
at the end of the fucking day. You know
what I mean? Sure. Mine might be on,
you know, a better slice of bread,
which I guess would make it
taste a little bit better,
but at the end of the fucking day,
right the end of the fucking day.
All right. I'm going to end up
in a FEMA camp with you. Okay?
You think on the next fucking a psycho
comes along. I'm gonna make the cut.
What the fuck? The white board, what
do I bring to the world? Huh? Exactly.
And to be standing right next
to you. So go fuck yourself.
You just fucking woman.
Every time she sneezes,
they give her another God damn
award. She's still pitching,
still fucking pitching. You know,
I remember when I did this
Oscar nominated part out.
Go Fuck yourself with your wigs
though thing. Just, you know,
that's what fucking pisses me
off when I watched this shit.
If you want to know my perspective
is from where I come from,
I can't bitch about shit cause
everybody's like, oh go fuck yourself.
You hit the lottery. Right. But I got
to sit here and listen to you bitch.
Even if you fucking killing it,
even if you're killing it, you know,
Yale School of drama and
he's stepped on the bull.
Go Fuck yourself with your
goddamn yachts. Alright,
there you go. That felt good. It's
probably ignorant or whatever.
I love you.
Yeah.
[inaudible]
[inaudible].