Yeah.
Hey, what's going on? It's Bill Burr.
It's time for the Thursday afternoon,
just before Friday. Monday
morning podcast. And Ah,
I'm just checking in on you.
How are you?
Um, I am in Warsaw, Poland and
I actually have a special guest,
my only friend here,
the only person I really know in Poland.
Mr. Paul Versey.
Paul, how are you? Thanks
for having me here.
Um, excellent. Maybe I'll do it like this.
I'll just sit there and I'll try to move
this cause I don't have the equipment
that I need. Um, Paul, um,
since we last spoke. Yeah.
Well it's been a long time since
you've been on the podcast,
but this week we've been to Germany,
Estonia,
Latvia,
hungry
in Poland. Yeah. And uh,
it's been a great time.
Hands Down Budapest and down Budapest,
hands down Buda, Buda and pest.
Last night Budapest was, Budapest
was, they were all great,
but Budapest was so good.
Last night I was on stage and I,
and I had that thought in my head like,
dude, I think I take a special here.
That was what? That felt like
a hot American crowd. Yeah.
It didn't matter where you like, it
didn't matter. We were in Hungary,
they were ready. It was great. Lot
for was the best tackles. Lot fee.
I enjoyed Lafayette. I the
one, the one, uh, you know,
there was a couple of
times in a lot for you.
You felt alone up there
with dude Astonia well,
10 minutes before I go on
stage and granted I'm going,
obviously I'm going cold.
The only thing I got is Kenny going,
we have a space.
You're really gonna love 'em clumps,
soda. Kenny shout out to him.
He brings me up and uh,
10 minutes before I go
up, the guy goes, yes,
stand ups only been here for eight years.
It got introduced in 2010.
And I was like, that's a little unnerving
to hear before you go out there.
But like, you know, they were dressed
up really nice to theater was beautiful.
Yeah. And uh, you go into something and
it was just, it's like you said, man,
those Baltic states,
it was fucking in a little bit.
This is a little bit something
like differently. They're very,
very fucking smart and logical.
Astonia was like the best look and crowd.
They were like dressed so nicely.
I felt like a, I felt like out of
place. It's theater was too nice
for what we were saying. Um, but Munich,
it was also like Budapest
by the unit picked Munich
in Budapest where uh,
we're four fuck and Munich was with
three 30 show and they were all hot,
crowded but all of them have been a great,
but like those were the two cities that
you didn't have to even think that you
were over somewhere. But like, so anyways,
I've been on the road when now for like
a week and I'm a moody son of a bitch so
I know I'm driving them nuts.
But uh,
you know it's funny is to your way
of talking like I was just joking.
Like what did you just say? Like
volume it up. Volume up. Yeah.
You said volume it up like
I was trying to, yeah,
figured out cause of recording seemed
like you just have your own way of
speaking and I have to try to figure
out what the fuck you talking about.
I'm like, this, this is coming to, it's
too quiet in a corner. You're just going,
well, you know, just, just
volume it up. Well, volume it.
You mean turn up the volume?
Uh, oh no, no. You just, uh, oh they
did, they had bread before you came in.
You did they, I mean, just they, they,
what'd you say? Wipe it down with Windex.
Windex that
now imagine if they want. Yeah. Well, you
know, the thing is to me and my mother,
I got this from my mother. My mother
always says, um, like turn the lights.
Uh, like we don't say turn the lights
on and off. We say a cut the lights. No,
not cut the lights. What is
it? Uh, AH, fuck. I forgot.
I have another thing in my wife goes,
I'd never heard that turned the lights up.
Now turn the lights off. You don't even
know this. Your language is so crazy.
You don't even know what you saying.
Yeah.
I don't say turn the lights
the way that other people do
funny as shit today. So we're, we'll
leave in Budapest. Oh, this is great.
And we've been taking these
small propeller planes and shit,
cause you know there's short
little flights here and uh,
so it's one of those deals.
You go to the gate and then you get on
a bus and then you'd take the bus out to
the propeller plane and there,
you know what I like about them?
They don't give a fuck. You
bag doesn't fit. They're like,
I just shove it under the seats.
They get on the seat next to you that
it's not like this fucking post nine 11.
You know,
why are you being hostile?
Get your bag off the fucking plane
the way they are in the states.
So I get on the thing,
the bus versus he got on the
bus first and I said hey.
And he had a weird looking face. What's
up? He said, dude, you just missed it.
This guy just asked me to sit next to him.
Like some total like gay shit.
Like he like pat the seat next to him.
I saw Paul and he pat on the seat
or whatever. Right. So I am like,
really? I go, oh, maybe it's like
a European thing or whatever.
But I didn't think it was weird cause the
bus was so big and there was all these
seat, there was all these seats. Yeah.
So then later versus he's looking at
the guy and he's laughing at him going,
dude, look at his little hat.
His hat doesn't fit his head.
And I'm just looking over it.
And I knew it wasn't Jewish.
I knew it was something religious.
It turned out was like a Muslim.
It was definitely bigger than a Yamaka.
Yeah. It's bigger than a Yamaka.
So it was like, it was the Muslim at
right. And then we finally realized,
I'm looking at the guy and he looks
just like [inaudible]. And I'd go,
wait a minute, this guy's probably
Muslim. Thought you were Muslim.
He's in fucking Budapest and he wanted
to hang with you. And then he ends up,
and then was funny, he's, he's,
he was freaking you out and you'll see it
was like 10 [inaudible] and Kenny goes,
watch, he'll probably have 10, eight
and then the fucking guy, dad gets on,
he's at 10,
eight and then he goes out to you.
Yeah. Are you Arabic? But the
ones that, so bill was right,
but the one thing you left out in
the story is when I did get on alone,
when he said, uh, I, you know, like
I'm a free people that don't know me.
I'm kind of like, even you said, I get a
little too nice with my small talk. Like,
oh, so it snowed here. I
like the obvious shit, dude.
You talk to that kid with the sneakers
that went on forever. Yeah. Yeah. So, uh,
I can just talk to a stranger. My
grandfather was like that, right?
So I look at this guy, I smile and
he smiles back overly like too much.
And then he goes,
he said something I didn't understand
and then he patted the seat next to him
and looked at me like, hey, I
have this seat waiting for you.
And made me like a little weird because
it was all empty, right? So I'm going,
Oh shit, maybe this guy. So,
but bill says, dude, he goes,
he may think you're Muslim.
So sure enough, like he said, like
he said, the guy comes next to me,
couldn't have been sweeter. I go, sorry
about the bed. No problem, no problem.
And then he leans over and I'm just going
fuck and oh go fuck your bill is right.
Let not let him, it's bad that you are
right. But he goes, are you a Arabic?
And I go and I go, what? Cause I
didn't, he goes, Arabic, you Arabic.
And he like pointed to my face
and I go, no. And he goes,
you look at her beck and I go,
mother fucker. Ville was right.
Literally wanted me to sit with them.
He thought I was Muslim. How fuck.
And I didn't want gay. You thought
he was a gay guy with a little hat.
That's the funniest shit ever.
Oh my God dude.
All right.
I want to talk to you because this is
something that is gradually going into
your act,
which I think is going to make you stand
out and it's going to be your voice and
it is your, uh, your ideas of luxury,
your ideas of leisure,
amenities, amenities. You
have your big into amenities.
Like if there's a mint on your pillow,
when you come back,
you feel like that means
something. It does. And this is
why I love working with you.
Not only that, we're friends.
You got class never in a back to school.
[inaudible] you've got classes
because I rubbed off from you buzzing.
The guy that read in his college dorm,
remember he made the college dorm,
he knocked down walls. No, but you go,
you like your five star. You know, you're,
I wouldn't say you got five, you've
got a cunt about it, but you like,
you like Nice Shit. You know,
I love, I love listening.
I stayed in a bunch of, yeah,
super eights in motel six is yeah,
but I don't, I don't stay at the,
the fucking Ritz Carlton Penthouse.
No, but I like working with you too
because you just like, you know,
certain things and I liked that. But
uh, yes. So I love the little things.
I love to slippers. I loved it. I
loved the chocolate. Now I love the,
I love the joy that you get out of it.
It's just so fucking funny.
I don't know why, why those little things
mean something. Cause those slippers to,
if you've got those slippers
for Christmas, you'd be like,
it's my wife cheating on me. Yeah.
These things are so fucking cheap there.
They never fit your feet. But
you know, you come in like, dude,
you just see the robe. Yeah, I know.
Oh my God. I don't know why bill,
they had chocolates. Yeah, you
would think that I was raised.
You would think that I was raised
in the streets. I don't know.
I don't know what it is. You sitting
there. We were on the airplane going like,
Dude, you know, we should start an
airline first of all, like the cost,
like billions of dollars.
And he goes,
we'd call it luxury air and I
immediately go, I wouldn't fly that.
You're like, why you wouldn't fly? I guess
too on the nose is trying too hard.
I feel like I'd go in there and
they'd be like, you know, like a,
like a faucet that was like gold,
but it wasn't real gold but it
was golden color. Like look good.
The luxury imitation rum. Yeah.
Yeah. All of that shit. Yeah. Yeah.
Um,
so we were trying to come up,
but you would fly an airline that
had 25 all first class seats,
leather skull beds. All right. This,
this is what we were talking about
right when I was like that there's a
difference between, uh, like classy
Gaudy.
There's refined and then this showing
up and there's just certain people,
I don't know if either one
is right or whatever. I got,
if I look at like a Ferrari,
a guy my age can drive a Ferrari
and not look like an asshole.
You keep yourself in shape and you
can tell it. This guy is, he's into,
he's into like, he knows how to
work on cars. He worked his way up.
I'm not talking about some fucking jerk
off, you know, pinky ring type of thing.
But like a Lamborghini, a Lamborghini
is a young man's car. That's for like,
you're in your 20s,
you're shirtless,
you've got like a cheetah on like
a fucking leash. Like, like I,
I feel like the Lamborghini is
obnoxious where the Ferrari is the shit,
right?
Like they,
like if they were people like the
Lamborghini would be walking around and
talking about how much money
had had where the fucking,
the Ferrari guy would be like,
chill. See, here's the thing.
My Greek side is the class here,
but my Sicilian kind
of goes in and is like,
and we have that battle.
But most of those cars are Italian.
That was made by Italians though.
So, no, I know, but that's why. See,
I like the chain. I love the gold
chain. It's like, pardon me, I love it.
But when you got to kill chain,
you literally said that the
gold chain completed yet. Yes.
You and Yan is love that yon is
almost cried when I said that. Yeah,
the gold changes did something,
but I can't go pinky ring.
That's where I draw the line. So I think
that that's the Greek where it's like,
now you can't wear my father hundred
percent full blooded Italian,
the whole thing. He just goes, he's
like into the Jew. He goes, he goes,
where'd you go? Second chain. I would
go second chain if it complimented this,
the right. So that, that, that's the
high water mark. That chain. Uh, yeah.
I mean I would go one more.
No, no, no, no. But I'm saying,
but the other one would,
would, would compliment it. You wouldn't,
you wouldn't then now maybe even like a
little thinner than this around it would
compliment it. That's it. Okay.
Just an accent. An accent.
You'd look good in the chain.
Now I really want to get a chain now.
I think I got a thin rope. It would
look good on you. A thin one. Yeah.
But then I would start looking
like something that I'm not,
which I'm not something you ever
wear a chain with a cross ever.
I grew up in the 80s.
Of course I did.
I had the a but I wanted the smooth
one around and my mother got me the one
that's like that,
which wasn't in style than the other one
was the total Guido fucking the flat,
the rope. I had to be like, what are you
at? Oh, you got this? Yeah. Okay. So,
um, yeah, no, I think this,
there's a certain thing
about if you have a chain,
there's a certain level as shit you're
going to talk. There's a certain level of,
of, you know, there's something, you know,
you can go out and get. I would wear it,
something like that if I was
playing a character in a movie.
But like I know I'm not a chain guy.
No.
Are you a leather jacket that you're
wearing a nice leather? Uh, yeah.
I like what Jack was like. Uh, but
I wouldn't get a motorcycle one.
I get one that was like really
like top leather leather,
but it was like a, it was, I'm
wearing it because it's less.
It's cold outside. Yeah,
you're not alive. Yeah.
I'm not trying to wear it to be
like, oh, look at my leather coat.
I can't pull it off, dude. I'm,
I'm a fucking pasty northern
European guy. You know?
I didn't grow up in Southie when Southie
was Southie. I wasn't like one of these,
you know? I mean, I basically,
I didn't care about fighting somebody
else until I got to junior high and
everybody else grew and I didn't grow
and then kids really could fucking fight.
Once I started seeing people getting
their teeth knocked out, nose is broken.
I was just like, alright.
You know, I mean, I don't,
I don't want to go into this world.
I'm too fucking slow. You know,
I have the anger to do this, but I'm going
to lose. And you don't read Ed's dude,
you barely touch us. We look like
we fucking fell off a motorcycle.
We just bruise so easily. Were you ever
a, are you, you're not a sneaker guy.
You're not a, you're not, were you ever
like, uh, I liked sneakers when I was,
when I was a kid and I do
like some old school ones,
but I got to admit that subset of
American culture where you know,
you're in your forties,
you're in your 50s and your still dressing
like it's the first day of school at
the bus stop.
We have like the brand like I
receive made me like respect Jordans.
I like them in that type of shit.
But it is hilarious to me that we've
worked some of the greatest theaters in
America and you walk out with a pair
of sneakers on and like, you know,
Shane out and shit like that.
And to you that's like dressing up.
But where I'm from like, um, oh,
uh, what's his face? Nate Cordrey.
I worked with him on
a, on a fucking uh, uh,
the heat and we would joke
in about Boston. We were
shooting there and he said,
he goes, dude, it's like
totally acceptable in Boston,
Massachusetts to show up to a holiday
party wearing like a Tom Brady Jersey.
Like people be like, oh, you got the
away one. Oh, that's cool. I like that.
It's got the Superbowl patch on it.
So I came from more like a sports culture
like that, but um, there is something,
uh, I think, and it's also, I think
it's because of being in this business,
which has so much shit about your age,
you know, you gotta you know, you,
you've got to always try to look
younger. You got to do all this shit. Oh,
he's fucking women bench like that.
That doesn't happen to guys too.
You know what I mean?
Like if you go bald,
that doesn't affect the
fucking parts you get off for.
So I as usual,
my cunty way rather than giving into that
and getting the hair plugs and fucking
trying to, you know, get, you
know, do whatever. I steer into my,
I keep myself looking good,
but it's just like I'm willing to lose
whatever I'm going to lose to not come
out the other side with
the fucking ant leg,
Caterpillar hairs coming up at the top
of my head and fucking know face yanked
back and shit. And I'll tell
you what's fucked up, dude.
It's been in this business long enough.
You know,
you're going to see it right now at 40.
Yeah. I mean switch. You're going to see,
as you're going to say,
you're going to see the first few
people that you start out with go crazy.
Someone's going to go legit crazy.
Uh, someone's going to quit.
It's weird when they quoted forties a
fucked up one for people where they just,
cause people start panicking.
If they don't have something going on,
they're going like,
this is my last port hole to get out
of this shit and actually have a legit
career because I have this 20 year gap
now in my fucking resume that I went out
and I,
I told jokes and shit and then you'll
see the other people that just doubled
down. They got nothing going on and
then they start getting a little botox.
Uh,
you know,
best shoe Polish is going into the fuck
and they start throwing hail Mary's.
Yeah, no, it's not a
heron Belzy at this point,
but there's definitely the throwing the
hook and ladder is definitely a halfback
option. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
All of a sudden they think of the rating
bags thrown in the back, the fake punt,
the fake plants coming out right on this,
this, this time. So it's scary, man.
The thing that thing is, and when I
was, I might say we were talking about,
but we would, you know the business
thing that I was talking to you about,
how you carry yourself in
this fucking business, right,
is there's that thing where you got
to want it, but you can't chase it.
You have to really believe in
what it is that you're doing.
And in stick to that with this weird thing
where you have to be flexible if, if,
if, if what you're doing isn't
working, but if you, you know,
if you're not hurting anybody,
you're not being malicious and you really
have this fucking thing that you want
to do, you have to stay on that
thing. And when people tell you, no,
you don't take it personal,
but then you don't keep chasing them.
When they say no to you,
you keep doing your thing,
you keep fucking killing and all of a
sudden they start hearing about you.
Then they come to you and then it's
everything that they said before is water
under the bridge and
you have to let it go.
You can't ever do that a mother fucker.
You fucking said no to me back in 96
because they're not going to remember it
now and it's not,
and you're just going to come off and look
like a fucking insecure asshole. Yeah.
I remember what you said
to me like five years ago.
I had just moved into the
house upstate and I go, uh,
I remember I wanted to get the tonight
show. I wanted to get something. Uh Huh.
And uh,
and you go, why the fuck are
you auditioning for that gun?
Like they're going to hear about you and
then they're going to want you and I'm
lit. I literally thought when
I got off the phone, I'm like,
not thinking you're delusional. You've
been in the business longer than me,
but I'm going like bills 10 years ahead
of me. Like what's he talking about?
It's easy for him to say, right. You know,
he's not an angry way, but just like he,
I'm trying to get something
like he's there, you know,
I'm trying to get something and then like,
sure enough,
like last year I did this monster set
at Gotham and the booker of the tonight
show and he was just like a hey dude,
guy. Oh yeah, just send me like whatever.
And you know, obviously I want to work
on it. This year and time went by,
I was working on this special, so I, it
didn't happen the way I want it to yet,
but he just goes, yeah, send me so well,
and it was just weird how he did kind
of say, I don't even need a tape.
Well just let me know. Send a
transcript. Like, like tell me.
And I was literally like, Oh my God,
that does happen. Yeah, but don't do it.
I chased it. I, you know,
I chased it right up til about 2001,
2002 when that's when I said fuck this.
But I did the whole thing when it
was like, whatever the look was,
I tried to have the look,
you know,
the fucking goatee on as I got old
standup clips and everybody had a goatee.
So I grew up fucking goatee.
I had like a, you know,
it's funny now because now people will
look at those things and they'll make
comments like they figured it out,
which is one of the things that I like,
like literally people listening right now.
You guys are ruining so much shit
that you could fucking, you know,
I don't know.
I,
I saw there was something on Twitter
today was like check it all these cool
clips of people hanging out in Hollywood
and all these fucking amazing parties
and shit. Uh, that no longer happened
cause social media ruined it. And,
and it's just like,
and I know everybody all boohoo they,
they can't fucking hang out with their
fucking infinity pools. It's just like,
dude,
I haven't,
when I came in the business like that's
all you wanted to hear all those stories
about so and so going
to the playboy mansion,
all these crazy fucking parties and
all of that type of shit. And the,
the thing was was they were fun and now
everybody's sitting there acting like
every fucking party.
There was some sort of like,
I don't know what me too thing that
happened and everybody just had their
fucking dick out and shit. And
it's just like, it's just this,
it was a total fucking overcorrection
now and I'm to tell you something right
now there that people are going
to run from this shit. The way,
remember that if the AllSeen for awhile
they were acting like the all scene was
going to bury like comedy clubs and
then that just ended up fizzling out.
Now how many clubs are thriving,
thriving and now all those dudes a slither
in back into the comedy clubs, right?
And it's just like all of that shit.
But they,
any sort of like extreme thing like that,
it can't sustain itself. It just
eventually what happens is it's not a,
it goes away tears. Well, it levels
out. Yeah. Because right now,
like the behavior that was wrong is
going to be reported from here on out.
But now that just go in like that,
like that junk that I do on my act,
it's like now what if
somebody did something or not?
Somebody has to get in trouble.
Like they have to throw a body on the
fire every four to six weeks just to keep
it in the news. Yeah.
Which I have a theory.
I think what's going to happen is I
think with the whole me too thing and
everything, I think what's gonna make
it die down. And I could be wrong,
but I think things are going
to start coming out about
females did stuff. Uh, no,
that, that, that's,
that's a fucking pipe dream because
shit has and nothing happens to them.
It's just, well, you daddy actually,
you know what the Nick Cannon, yeah.
That nick cannon think they're all
good. Why are you being so petty, nick?
It still was the guy's fault. Where
if somebody fucking did that to a guy,
if those are all guys,
nick cows looking out for his friend
and he just peaced some if he just said,
hey man,
if I don't want to do this cause I don't
want to get the people that he said in
trouble.
Of course all of their tweets that I
read were clearly them joking around.
They're all jokes that are all just
the point is it's all jumped though.
Like Kevin Hart's did is he was joking
was 10 years ago it was in his standup
back and these are comedians.
Yeah and they're acting like they heard
him say this at like at a party with no
setup and punch it.
I don't want to keep bringing this up
because I don't want to come to keep
mulching that over cause I'm sure
he wants to fucking move on from it.
But it is like this. No, it's just this,
this fucking thing that where everybody's
go to a, they get a lot of this talk.
They get that fucking Guy John Legend
Shit. Because when he took a pit,
because he wrote music for that Dude's
movie and it's like w what is supposed to
be standing in his shower to be
knowing what the fuck he's doing. Yeah.
Like you don't know what somebody's done.
If you went to their party and years
earlier, you don't know. Yeah, I Paul,
it's might as well as I know you.
I don't know what you do. Well,
I mean I call you, we call each
other enough to bitch. I know,
but you start like you don't know, recall.
Wait, what point would you ever call me?
I to say a pill.
You wouldn't believe in this man.
One time I took my deck out
and I was blocking this door.
You would never tell me that. So,
but the thing is is I never did that.
But that's what I'm saying. I
shouldn't have said you, but whatever.
But if you knew somebody like that,
then it'd be like,
how could you have been
friends with this guy?
It's like he had fucking
tell me that shit. Yeah. Yes.
People who are friends with people at
work and the finds out there like a
fucking serial killer. How could
you take a picture with this guy?
He had already merged in 40 people.
It's like,
well he wasn't bringing that up when
we were fucking hang around the water
cooler,
you know,
to man like I feel like a lot of these
head coaches we were talking about before,
like you got 53 man roster,
you love him and one of
them does something and then
they're like this piece of
shit new. And it's like, you
know, it's taller they had,
that becomes that that'd be becomes at.
And then all of a sudden it's like
this program is corrupt and everything.
Like everybody knew and
everybody, everybody knew.
And it's like everybody knows,
dude, I remember, I'm not gonna say names,
but one comic got in trouble and this
guy tried to suggest that the entire
comedy club all got together
and protected this guy.
And I almost did a spit take. It's like
the second that guy got in trouble,
all anybody underneath him was thinking
is great. Now I can get his spots. I mean,
they just don't,
and it's always people who aren't
in the fucking business is just,
they don't understand how
fucking cutthroat this
business business is fucked.
It's all actually,
it's no,
it's no different than I imagine if
you were in the oil industry, you know,
if you're on Wall Street,
just all of it,
when you're going for something that
in the end, at least back in the day,
you're going to have a yacht dude
and is going to be models on it.
Like your fantasy when you're in your
20s, like the shit that people are, uh,
are willing to do.
Dude,
I remember after I did my second
show ever in New York City,
I crushed and I walked off and I literally
was like, dude, I'm going to be like,
I'm going to be, he started
thinking, you're like, oh my God.
Cause you're like nobody could do,
you don't realize that there's
other people out there. You know,
when you first started doing it like
this, I'm going to be a fucking, you know,
your business. The first thing everybody
thinks is I'm going to win an Oscar.
I'm gonna, I'm going to have a fucking
special and all that type of shit.
And then once,
what I,
what I liked about this business of
in the last 10 years is I've actually
figured out where I want to be in it.
So any of that shit I would love to
still happen or whatever. But like,
it's just like if I could just traveling,
but I'm wearing fucking Warsaw right now.
Like I just looked out there
and I'm looking at this shit,
I can't fucking believe I'm here.
I can already tell this is going to be
like Budapest where I remember we were
walking around Budapest yesterday as a
pot. I was just, I liked this place, man.
These people are fucking cool.
And I got that vibe from the,
the dude who drove us over here,
he was funny.
He was the oldest of five minutes Donia
when I saw the guy and he was like,
oh dude, dude. And I was like,
this might not go this. Yeah.
And then when I got to Budapest and that
woman was like, Oh, here. And she said,
my mother in law and if your
throat hurts, take this. And,
and all of a sudden I said, oh it's going
to be great. I got the same vibe here.
How funny did that, I still like a Kia
motors building at a fort night poster,
which made me think of my son. I'm going
to going to be great here, you know.
But I will tell you this bill,
I noticed this and I told you we were on
a train from Munich to Frankfurt and I
just started watching people, you
know, and people are the same.
Like I saw this 80 year old woman and
they gave little candies out in the thing
and she took whatever her daughter or
whoever did it and I saw her get her purse
and open up personally.
My grandmother used to do with cookies.
My grandmother was like,
I dunno if it was from when she grew up
cause she came here and my grandmother
came to the United States,
10 years old from Sicily,
didn't speak a lick of English or like
would like go to a park and learn English
that way. At 10 years old. Oh my God.
She was, she came at 10 years old.
A rest her soul.
She died.
I think she died at 80 80 in her
mid eighties so she'd probably,
I need a year.
I'm trying to do the math.
They thrown out shit when she tried
to do the year when she did, she,
I'll do it for you. If she passed, I
believe in o nine oh nine eight days.
So that's like 1929 she probably
came in the twenties 29 no wait,
no.
Is that 29 was that 1919 told us
that (394) 095-0960 nine yeah,
it'd be 1919 right. So she got here,
let's say 1920 New York City depression,
10 years old.
Never spoke a lick of English.
And then she did this thing where like
when we would go out, she would go, hey,
if they take those cookies and I'd
be like, grandma, I don't need,
she would literally take
two cookies that were,
that wrapped them and Napkins
and put her in bed. Still.
Just that depression era shit.
So I saw this German woman do it and then
I saw like the little kids and I sold
little girls from Germany on their
phone. Like it's all the same shit. Yeah.
You know,
I'll talk about a fight with my wife and
then even the journey [inaudible] they
get it.
Everybody's the same human beings that
that's what this trip has shown me is
that human beings are really all the same
in a way, which is now your bad ones.
If like this, this will change
how you then view foreign policy.
And when this, when they're sitting
there, you know, trying to make,
I still want the wall. I don't want those
town halls gum kit. It's no, but no,
but uh, I yeah, it makes you think like,
well you know, do we know, but there's
shit where they sit there and they,
oh you know what I like your idea of,
of say the Middle East and stuff
like that. It just changes your life.
Cause there's that grandmother there.
There's the version of there,
there's the me there,
and then what you have is the lunatics
at the top and they just get everybody
all fucking stirred up beneath them
that these fucking people are gonna come
over here and they're going to do this.
They're going to do that and all of
this shit. So I don't know. You know,
it's fucking
hilarious about that. That whole
fucking Trump thing with the wall is,
I didn't realize this. They're already
really, basically there's a wall there.
There's some areas where to get an area.
He's trying to get the area,
the south that doesn't have as much,
which they're saying is doing stuff,
but he doubled down so much on it
that that's why he's not, it's like,
well this is the thing,
like I don't think either side's going
to back down because the Democrats can't
back down and he's just
getting up and walking out.
A guy that prideful that tweets late at
night and celebrities that don't matter,
calls single comedians' names out
as the president nodded states,
that guy that said we're getting the wall
done and doubled down and promised his
thing. He can't. Yeah, I can't
tell if he's like, uh, not yet.
Stay here and know if it's insecurity.
Like I'm not a psychologist,
but however he is made up, um, is,
is he is,
he isn't going to back down.
I love that tweet that you show share
demands. We'll just say share what?
Oh yeah, I saw, what was
the word that they used all
these headlines on the phone.
Um,
shared demands,
shared demands that Polosi don't die on
this hill tops to shut down and don't
die. The share demands it shared
amongst your demands. It yeah, the pups.
The sinner. Yeah. The, the,
the demands it well shared demands that
this politician doesn't listen to this
reality TV star that is now president.
Like that's where the fuck were at. Bill.
Do you know how funny that headline is?
Shared demands.
Well,
what's funny is transplant presence is
so fucking long that you forget that this
is the guy from the apprentice.
Yeah, yeah. It's, yeah,
it's bad. You know, I just liked it.
Now people are finally being able to kind
of question financially what the fuck
we're doing over in Iraq because that is
the big fucking thing. And that is not,
that is not liberal or conservative.
That is just black and white dude.
Where it's just like, how the fuck
yeah. Like do your kids' kids' kids.
I'm still gonna be paying
that fucking tab. Do you know,
and I think that they should
fucking investigate those
corporations that is made
zillions of dollars off of this.
I think of the ones that are prolonging
whatever the fuck it is we're still
doing there. Um, I dunno. I mean, I
don't know enough about it, but I,
I do. I do know how to
balance a fucking checkbook.
And I do see money coming in versus
money going out assets and liabilities.
And there is, there is no other
fucking business where you wouldn't,
you wouldn't right now
just be completely fucked.
That's another funny fucking thing
about him wanting to build this wall.
It's like with what? Money? Yeah.
Cause they're gonna be on as well.
That's going to create jobs
and blah blah blah. Yeah,
but then you still have to pay for the
fucking wall. Yeah. And He fucked up man.
He fucked up dude by saying Mexico is
going to pay for it and now American tax
payers are going to pay for
it. It's fucked up. But uh,
talking about money let we did.
Yeah,
because nobody's going to remember that.
And all people do is like getting people
who are for Trump to admit that this,
this financially does it
make sense or whatever.
We don't have the money or
whatever the fuck it is.
It's literally trying to get somebody
who's like a die hard whatever fan to
admit that that bullshit call that went
your way was actually a bullshit call.
Like I would say like last,
not this past season,
the season before when that Steeler
clear clearly caught the ball against the
patriots, clearly caught a fucking
touchdown and they called it back.
Now the amount of patriots fans,
I'll throw my own friends under
the bus or be amount of them.
That would have to be there.
They would all do.
Clearly he didn't make a football
movie rule is the rule. Yeah. Hey,
they would say that, but
it's just like, you know,
I'm one of those guys all the way along.
The line was saying the Tuck rule is,
it's a stupid rule.
I understand that they wanted to
have clarification or whatever,
but it's just at the end of the
day it's like, dude, he had it.
The guy slapped it out of his fucking
hands and fell on it. It's a fumble.
The fucking game is over. The top group.
I remember Tom Brady being like, hey man,
it's the fucking tucked role.
It's just like whatever,
but like trying to get people politically.
Now you see kids to look at
people like trying to get,
like most of my friends are liberals
trying to get them to see things about the
Clintons or the Obama's or whatever. They
just think, oh, but they did the best.
They'll say they're not as bad
as Bush than not as bad as Trump.
It's just like they always just steer
it into this fucking argument where it's
just like,
you know,
if this guy's really a man of the
people and he's really such a great guy,
why are his first two speaking engagements
with two of the biggest fucking banks
out there when all of these people are
upside down in their houses because of
these fucking cons?
Because at the end of the day,
they're getting paid by the same guys.
They got their faces in the fucking
pig trough and this is too big for this
podcast.
I don't know why we're talking about this.
Maybe at a talking about spending money.
Let's talk about spending money.
You can balance a budget. I mean you can
bounce that. Fuck. You want to know what?
I'm not good at it. Now I'm getting
better. I'm getting told me again.
Paul told me cause his special did so well
and now he's selling tickets. He goes,
Bill, I'm not going to lie to
you. I'm going to go through.
I'm going to go through a fur coat
phase. I wouldn't, I wouldn't do that.
I actually think that that's too much.
I do think of [inaudible].
It's a little ridiculous. I do.
I don't know. I you liked them.
You liked when will that fighter came in?
When he goes,
it's his fucking polar bear. The guy
that he looks like the Burger King Guy.
The fucking, he's got the Oh, fast.
What's his name? Irish guy. Yeah.
Notorious Conor. Yeah.
Conor McGregor. Yeah.
He came out with like a white
one and he just started walking,
but he did it like no shirt
chain underneath. Like that guy.
That guy's not only one of
the best fighters in the
world. He could be talking,
he's up. Maybe take five. He could
be a great standup comedian. So yes.
Yeah. I think kind of regret, but he's
shit talking. I'd put him top five.
He's at wrestler level. I love that
one. One time when he was doing a promo,
don't do promotion. You'll
do fucking know, dude.
My favorite one was
when, when he goes, uh,
this guys tried to give him shit
and he just turns around and goes,
oh the fuck are you?
Who the fuck is this guy?
And even the guys started laughing at me
like, yeah, I know. Nobody knows who I am.
I was trying to get famous
off for you calling.
Had all of them laughing. I remember
Rhonda Rousey was another thing.
He was who the fucking, who the fuck
is this guy? I love what he goes,
Yo do nothing. And he gets, he gets into
the AH, he's, he's, he's on there man.
He's up there with that level.
But I will tell you this too.
I know he was going to,
I told you I heard things from people,
but when he was talking that extra shit,
somebody goes do it. This is rocky three.
When that guy beat him like it
seemed like he what his wall,
cause I feel like right
now what he's trying to do
do constitute those guys are
all pieces of meat. Yeah.
So what he's doing right now
is I think he's realized that.
So he's trying to get on the other
side where it's just like, all right,
how the fuck can I get the most amount
of money without getting my brains beaten
? And so he took all that
money to fight like Mayweather.
It's kind of like in the porn industry
where after awhile they're like,
fuck this.
I'm starting my own website.
Yeah. You know, if I'm going to take all
these hits, man, I'm fucking make it.
The money's coming to me.
Right.
Probably a fucked up analogy. Can wholly
shots taken all these shots to the face,
man, I'm going to fucking stop milk.
Yeah, exactly. That's exactly it.
All right. I got to read a couple
of advertising then we're done. Hey,
do you have any, a club dates or anything
that you can, I've got a ton, man.
I've got a ton. I'm going to be February
through July. All kinds of dates.
I believe my,
uh,
late February date that helium and
buffalo tickets are on sale now,
but I have a bunch of dates, so
I'll go. What I love about you,
what's your website? You know,
[inaudible] right now if you go to the,
it's all done. The website's new
Paul [inaudible] dot com via Arzi.
The show's page has all the dates from
now through a 19 and more are being added.
Yes. And I can tell you that when
we were at Gotham, uh Oh yeah. Uh,
what was it, a month ago or so? Yeah. I
went and I did a show for the Mozillians.
I love those guys. And they, uh,
they were nice enough after we did the
Gig in New York the month before they had
the after party or the cake boss make the
cake. They just the best guys ever. Um,
Steve and Chris. So I was like, I
am and come back, I'll do a night.
So we did at night and you were on stage
in front of me and you didn't know that
Seinfeld was coming down? No. Yeah.
So we were having him
stretch and Paul's thinking,
why do they keep having me do more time
builds in the room and I've watched you
do like 35,
35 minutes and you will refund
and you were fucking around.
And I was just like,
wow man,
this guy's like a legit headliner
and I'm telling you dude,
hours are going to come easy.
Much easier for you then then
somebody who like is like a joke.
Right?
Which is why I love Joe graders cause
it's like like how hard much harder it is
for them. But you're like a storyteller.
He will fuck them with the crowd.
I mean I was like a, I was really
like you came into your own dude.
Definitely check Paul out.
Thanks a lot bill.
Well you know you've always been
Fred. All right Robin Hood, everybody.
My one and only read here.
Robin Hood is an investing app that
lets you buy and sell stocks, ETFs,
options and Cryptos all commissioned free.
I have no idea what any of that means.
They strive to make financial
service services work for everyone,
not just the wealthy,
not intimidating wave for stock market,
a non intimidating way for stock market
newcomers to invest for the first time
with true confidence,
simple and intuitive.
Clear design with data presented
in an easy to digest way.
Costs Slash no commission fees.
Does that make sense to you?
You just said cost. No cost fees, no
commission phase. Is that what that means?
Anyways, I lost you. You
looking at your phone here.
Other brokerage charges are up to $10 for
every trade. I love what he said. No, no.
And he kept looking at your phone. But
Robin Hood doesn't charge commission fees,
trade stocks and keep all of your profits
easy to understand charts and market
data.
Okay.
Place a trade and just four taps on your
smartphone. Can you tell if I don't,
I don't live in this world at all.
I can barely even read this.
Robin Hood Web Platform also
lets you view stock collections,
100 most popular sectors like
entertainment and social media and curated
categories like female CEOs.
Ah,
AH,
um,
and analyze how about good CEO and analyze
ratings to buy slash hold slash sell
for every stock. Learn how to invest as
you build your portfolio. Discover new.
How about redheaded CEO's? He got any
of those fucking companies. Disco,
bald, redheaded male CEOs
discover new stops and trade.
Favorite companies with
personalized news feeds,
custom notifications for price movements.
So you never miss the
right moment to invest.
Robinhood is giving listeners
a free stock like apple, Ford,
or sprint to help you
build your portfolio. Sign
up@billburrdotrobinhood.com
that's bill bird dot Robin,
hood.com if you render that shit, check
it out. All right, that's the podcast.
Enjoy the music here and there'll be a
half hour of bonus material from a old
school throwback Thursday afternoon just
before Friday, Monday morning podcast.
All right,
Paul.
Oh, and did a stream. That
stream is special still
streaming. Uh, I'll say this,
comedy central broke their online records.
Please check it out.
Subscribe to the comedy Central App,
and you could get the special.
We're going to be putting out more clips
and the website. Is it comedy central?
Yeah, it's common sense.com. But it's
also, you could get it right from my
website@paulverseydotcombutifyougotocomedycentral.com
and
you,
you
could,
uh,
or subscribe to the APP and you could
see the special there and check out
poverty.com for the new dates.
Beautiful. All right.
Have a great weekend.
You said Monday might be a little bit late
because our,
unless we a record when we're in Vienna,
but I'll be coming back I
think flying back Monday,
which might be your Sunday cause it's
so far ahead. I don't know. All right,
I'll see you.
[inaudible].
Hey,
what's going on?
It's built bar and it's the
Monday morning podcast for Monday,
January 10th, 2011 how are Ya? Hello?
It's me.
Why is that song in my head?
Lionel Richie. Lionel Richie.
There's a good looking fellow.
Huh? That was one weird look and son of
a bitch, wasn't it? You know with his,
his Jerry Curl,
he had a Jerry curl,
a mullet and an afro all at the same time.
Three of a two out of three of
the worst fucking haircuts ever.
I think the Afro was cool if you
were in the Aba. Other than that,
it was probably just another
reason for racist to not get along.
You know, you sit there, you're
trying to be open minded.
You write a fucking sporting event or
maybe at a movie theater and some guy
comes walking in with a big
doctor, j Afro, you know,
it doesn't have the decency to put that
Frederick Douglass part on the side.
So maybe you could look down as
part and see a little bit of jaws,
part two or whatever the fuck was coming
out when people had hair like that and
what it creates. Um, animosity.
That's what it is.
Everybody thinks it's that slavery stuff.
They think it's the Holocaust. That's
not what it is. It's the haircuts people.
That's why people don't get along.
You know,
you look at other people's hair cuts cdoa
what kind of people will get hair cuts
like that,
you know?
And then there's some little psycho in
the corner with greasy hair and a weird
mustache and the shit starts.
That's how it goes down. People,
you might be sitting there
right now going cheap bill.
That was really fucking ignorant.
Don't you watch the history channel?
As a matter of fact, I do. I
do watch the history channel.
Thank you very much for not asking me and
allowing me to create your question in
my head. I do watch the
history channel and there's,
there's no history left on that channel.
All they show is pawn shop on that.
I don't know what the fuck is on that.
You know,
it's just become like every other channel.
I was reading something today where
they were doing a mini series on the
Kennedys. I, uh, get
shade a bridge and, uh,
am I really going to do a hacky Ted
Kennedy? I think I've got a, yeah, yeah.
We went down to the bottom of the
logo, add a, I took a deep breath.
I finger fucked her a couple more times,
left her in the car and swam to the
surface. Actually the size of my head,
maybe so buoyant. I just sort of floated
unconsciously, your honor. Uh, yeah.
So they had a mini series about the,
uh, the Kennedys and they canceled it.
They canceled it yet for some reason.
Uh,
evidently if you have a bunch
of shit in a storage shed,
they want to go down and film it.
Um,
was that a little social commentary?
Is that what I did?
Two minutes and 49 seconds
into the podcast that I
really just do some sort of a
, what is the state of the history
channel commentary? I think I did.
Um,
okay.
Well I have an announcement to make and
it's with heavy heart that I have to
tell you that my three week
vacation is over, you know,
uh, yeah, it's back to the goddamn grind.
And I know a lot of you right
now going on three weeks, dude,
I get fucking two weeks for the year.
Well, you know what? That's your fault.
All right? You picked that career.
It's a free goddamn country.
Go write some fucking jokes.
You can't, maybe then you,
you could take a three week
vacation and buy vacation.
What I meant is a,
I didn't have to get on a plane.
I didn't have to go to any airports
for three weeks was awesome.
I was actually hanging out with
some people a the other day and uh,
they weren't Comedians,
but they traveled a lot.
And we just sat around talking about
different airports and it blew my mind how
much I knew about all these airports
and places where you could get something
decent to eat and buy decent. Of
course, I mean by airport standards,
you know,
I know whenever I land in Dallas,
I'm going to come down that fucking
escalator for, for my connecting flight.
And there's that awful Mexican
restaurant that's right there.
And every time I go in there because
I'm hungry and I hope against hope that
they're going to have the real cheese
and not that cheese whiz. You know,
that cheese come that they put on the
burritos and every time I order a fucking
Burrito I said, hey,
listen to this burrito.
Does it have the real cheese or does
it have that nuclear waste Cheez whiz
stuff? And the waitress
never knows. You know,
because who's kidding who?
If you're a waitress at an airport,
you don't give a fuck, you know, I don't
know. Let me go in and ask the chef.
Then they go in and they come back.
So what's the verdict there? Uh,
what's a good Texas fucking
named? Taycee. You what's,
what's the verdict there sweetheart?
Is it the, do you have the real cheese?
We certainly doubt nodding the head.
You know, mind fucking, you're like,
you got to get an, you know, nodding
up north means yes. Down South.
It could mean yes or fuck no.
Why? We most certainly do not.
We absolutely doubt,
ah,
with your big fucking
those big fucking Texarkana
for those Oklahoma,
that fucking huge white face that,
that Hugh Hefner loves.
He loves those girls.
Those big panhandle faces.
Huge fucking heads.
Texas, Oklahoma, Arkansas,
white girls got the biggest round is
fucking heads I've ever seen in my life.
Jesus fucking Christ. They played
football. You couldn't get in my helmet.
You'd have, you'd have to custom make
helmets for the beautiful bodies,
you know, big Vanilla titties, Huh?
That's right. Big Vanilla titties.
Yeah. Big Medela. Titties ain't got the,
you know,
the stars at night are big and bright.
Just like my big fucking head,
you know,
if I had to slap the shit out of any
woman, I don't, I think I can't. Yeah,
I think it'd be what some chick from
fucking Texarkana, Oklahoma, you know,
just get a big 12 ounce
glove, right? Boxing Glove.
Just hit a big fruit card
of a fucking head. Um,
all right. Speaking of which,
I will be in Addison, Texas,
now that I've trashed your women,
you're women.
I'm going to be there the last
weekend, uh, in, uh, in January.
So if you get a chance,
you know, you know,
you put on your best pair of boots.
Is that what you guys
do out there in Dallas?
Why am I shitting on this is the second
week in a row I've shit on people in the,
in the Greater Dallas area. Um, and I,
and I still have the audacity to think
that I'm going to sell tickets down there.
Jesus Christ.
Is this the Chinese Year of arrogance?
Because that's what I'm
feeling. Um, anyways,
so two more weeks of no Busan
and I've made my 100 days,
100 days.
I think about you in a hundred ways.
What song was that?
Was that a Jane's addiction song or
was that when they were porno for
Pyros Pyros Huh? Was that to Haitian Moon?
Is that what I was just singing there?
Who Was it? Bali and
my eyes. Um, I the, uh,
anybody else in the podcast? I'm, I am.
I like the only person
who ever bought that CD.
[inaudible] the second porno for Pyros.
I like Bali.
That song.
Bali.
I don't like the weird high pitch
singing that Perry Farrell does in the
beginning of it,
but I really liked the sound of the guitar
just in case you were wondering if it
would just sitting there going,
you know,
I wonder what bill thinks about
that obscure track. What does it,
the fucking last song. Second
side. Oh, fucking gives a shit.
All right. What the hell am
I talking about? Okay, let's,
let's talk about something in sports
that really fucking bothered me this
weekend. Uh, I was watching the
Bruins Canadians game. Okay. Hey,
horrific loss for the Bruins.
We were up to the north and then we let
up to fucking goals and then right in
the end and then lost in overtime.
But this is what pisses me off
about the fucking Canadians is uh,
the Canadians are sort of like,
they're like Matt Matthew mcconaughey's
character and dazed and confused.
Remember that guy?
The 26 year old guy's still hanging
out in high school where in his fucking
Letterman jacket asking where the
parties are. That's what they are like.
They are a stilled the most successful
NHL franchise in the history of hockey,
but they have not dominated
the league since pre Gretzky.
We'll talk in 1979 we're talking
Jimmy Carter in office. All right.
We're talking about the AMC Pacer being
a viable option for a car of the future.
Then I just realized
because I drive a Prius,
that I bet if me live my was my age
in 1979, I would have bought it.
I would have bought a pacer.
I really just learned that about myself.
It makes me feel bad. So anyways, um,
just to give you a little bit of history
between the Bruins and the Canadians.
The Canadians kick the shit out of the
Bruins for a good 50 fucking years.
All right.
Dominated the league.
We met him in the final seven
times and we never beat him.
And every time we went up to the, to
the Montreal forum, they always be this.
And it was like this Hex, we
just couldn't beat it. Right.
And this is the weirdest jinx in sports
because in 1987,
88,
we finally went up to the Montreal forum.
We finally had a better fucking team,
or a couple of times we had a better team,
but we would still lose.
But we finally had a better team
and we fucking paid them. Right?
It's over. The fucking Hex
is over. Oh, thank God.
Right. Just for better
measure. Two years later,
we beat them again in the
fucking playoffs, you know,
and then over the next 20 years,
we pretty much went tit for
tat and the playoffs playoffs.
And two years ago,
we beat Montreal every fucking
game in the regular season.
And then we swept them in the playoffs,
the final two games in their own building.
Okay.
But for some fucking reason,
they still always talk
about this fucking hacks.
Like it's still going on.
I, I for the life of me,
can somebody hockey fan please fucking
explain it and don't even say it's
because the Bruins haven't won a cup
because we did during that 50 year fucking
drought.
We one in 70 and we won in [inaudible] 72
that would be like if the red sox won it
and 70 and 72 when you're still talking
about the curse of the babe.
I don't know what this fucking curse is.
Is it because we haven't beaten
him in the finals ever? We can't.
They realigned the divisions.
We've played them in the playoffs.
We've beaten since 87 we're
pretty much 50 50 against him.
I don't fucking understand.
I understand it.
When Dan Shaughnessy says something
because Dan Shaughnessy like if an old 80
like an 80 year old woman
became a sports writer,
she would be Dan Shaughnessy because Dan
Shaughnessy never talks about the game.
Dan Shaughnessy loves ghosts and
Goblins and fucking urban myths.
He's everything about the fucking game.
He will talk about all of it.
Like he doesn't know shit about
hockey. All right? As he asked,
actually called for the end of
the winter classic this week,
he said, you know, it's time to retire
the winter classic. This is this.
This is what I'm more on this guys.
He talks about how the first fucking
three years were awesome and now we stood
next to Bobby. Your arguably the
greatest player of all time, you know,
if not top two, if not top
three, if you're a cunt, you know
the fucking arguing,
greatest player of all time stands
next to Dan Shaughnessy when the,
the winter classic was at Fenway
Park and he says to Shaughnessy,
this is what real hockey is. This is what
it is. This is it, this is, this is it.
And it's, it's, it's most pure form.
This is how we all learned how to play.
All right.
And then this year,
just because you know one year that
you're going to have bad weather,
it was kind of raining out in the ice,
wasn't good.
Shaughnessy says that
they should cancel it.
He's such a fucking retard.
It's like Dan,
those first three years,
that's pond hockey in
the middle of the winter.
What you signed Pittsburgh is pond hockey
at the beginning and the end of the
pond hockey season. All right. If you
ever fucking played in, in your life,
you dumb ass.
The second I saw that
Pittsburgh Washington game and
I saw the ice surface with
those puddles, I immediately was taken
back to my youth during the, you know,
just to be getting when it was just cold
enough to play hockey or you'll coming
into spring and what would you do?
You'd take big rock should throw
them up in the fucking air.
See if they would go through the ice
and then you'd send the fattest fucker.
You've out of all your friends to walk
out on the ice. And if he didn't drown,
game on,
you'd go out there and you would skate.
You know?
And if you started losing,
you try to trip one of your
friends into the big puddle,
so whatever. So anyways, so I
want to know seriously, okay,
now Montreal Canadien fans,
I'm not disrespecting you
guys, you guys, you know,
other than the New York Yankees,
uh, you're, you're the most success.
You have the most championships.
All right?
And if I had to rate franchises,
I would say Yankees,
Lakers,
uh,
Canadians and then Celtics.
And I know a lot of Boston fans aren't
gonna like that, but this, this is why,
all right. Yankees cause they got the
most and they've won in every era.
Then I would go,
I would say I would go Lakers just because
they've won 10 championships in the
last 30 years, that know Canadians
haven't Yankees having, I mean,
that's fucking unheard of in
the modern era with free agency.
[inaudible] that's fucking insane. Um,
well, so I guess I would put there,
maybe I would say, okay, well I don't know
where to put the Lakers. How about that?
I'll put the Lakers is the best
franchise to the last fucking 30 years,
without a doubt.
Um,
yeah,
and I can't remember what the fuck I said
about the rest of this shit. All right.
But I don't understand like
what exactly has to happen?
How many fucking times do the Bruins
have to beat the Canadians in the fucking
playoffs? I don't get it. And we've won.
We won two Stanley cups during
I, I just, I don't get it.
I absolutely,
I do not fucking understand
why every time I watch
the Canadians Bruins,
they have to bring up something
that ended that fucking ended.
Jesus Christ. Oh, almost a
quarter of, a century ago.
The Canadians have not dominated the
Bruins for any significant amount of time
since, uh, 86 [inaudible] 1986.
I Dunno if I got the Canadian feed.
I have no idea what,
but that is the most overrated
fucking thing I've ever heard.
Overrated fucking thing
I've ever heard at anytime.
The Canadians when like they did, came
back and won there. There'll be like,
you see, you see and, but they'll,
they'll ignore the fact that we swept
them for a whole year and in the playoffs,
the final two games in their
own fucking building. You know,
how come the Red Sox, how come their
thing ended? I don't, I don't get it.
Whether that w shouldn't,
shouldn't that,
that thing of continued the whole
fucking thing doesn't make sense.
It's just this classic a
thing as a Boston sports fan,
which I'm so fucking sick of,
is I can't stand, first of all,
I don't believe in curses.
That whole Dan Shaughnessy old fucking
lady thing where it's such a pussy way of
looking things where you literally
take your hand off the wheel,
you have no control of your destiny
because there's a god damn Gremlin under
your bed. It's like, isn't
it really that aside?
In fact that Montreal was a tremendous
fucking franchise back in the day.
All right?
As tremendous as they were,
the Bruins were horrific,
wasn't it? That, uh, you know,
Harry Sinden didn't embrace free agency
and he resented fucking resented the
fact that players were now in control.
Any absolutely categorically
fucking refused to pay top
dollar whether they were
worth it or not.
It wasn't.
That wasn't that more likely than that.
There was some sort of fucking ghosts
floating around a fucking hockey arena.
I don't know. I don't know. So whatever.
So for the 900 fucking year in a row,
I got to watch a Bruins Canadians game.
And despite the fact that the Montreal
Canadians are not a factor in the NHL
anymore, they're in first place
now. But you know what I mean,
that they're not an elite
franchise anymore. They just not,
and they haven't been. Okay. They haven't
won a fucking cup since 93. It's over.
It's over. Okay. It's fucking over.
I mean, I, I don't, I don't
know. I mean, it's a Celtics
fan. I, I admit that it did.
It's over it, it died when Len
bias died with Len bias died.
It was fucking over and it hasn't come
back just because we want one sense then.
It hasn't come. It's fucking
over, you know, speaking of which,
I've actually started to watch a lot
of hoop and I gotta tell you something.
When the fucking Boston Celtics,
I've never seen so many
goddamn ace bandages and knee
pads and my entire fucking
life, I think they have the oldest
legs in the NFL and the NBA,
every one of them is taped from
the ankles up to their hips.
I don't think that I have, I really just
don't see them winning it this year.
I don't, I think that, uh, I
think Miami Heat's going to do it.
I actually think they're going to
do it. They're, they're, they're,
they're much younger.
The fucking,
everybody's dressed like Marcus
Haynes on the Goddamn Celtics.
Now he has an old reference for you.
Huh? Markus Hanes. Look it up. People,
he was a, the, the, the magical
fucking the guy on the globe trotters
[inaudible]
right.
And each slide around on the floor.
You know what black people bitch about
fucking Hollywood in that type of shit.
Don't we do the white
people, you know, for the,
the stereotypes and the awful roles,
which they've been given for
decades in Hollywood, you know,
to white people get any sort of credit
for being on the Washington generals and
just being absolute stooges.
You know what I mean? Just
going out there, paid to lose,
paid to fall for the same fucking
trick every goddamn night.
Just looking like absolute fucking
buffoons. Do we get any sort of a credit?
Can Can Spike Lee make a tragic film
about white people who had played in the
Washington generals? Anybody? Can anybody
back when that back me on that one?
Back me up. People. What's the deal? Um,
how far did this fucking podcast
am I 20 God damn minutes. Alright,
so what is there to talk about you guys?
Uh,
what do you guys want to talk about?
I sound like a headliner right now who
is run out of jokes and he's done an
hours worth of material in 20 minutes.
So now he's just going to try
to fucking play with the crowd,
which I can't do because not here.
So why don't we read this, uh,
this email under the provocative
name corporate bullshit. Uh,
Bill,
uh,
dear bill recently I had to
return some items at the mall.
Uh, it was the day after Christmas and
I was with a girl. I was dating, uh,
with the girl that I was dating.
She wants to return some shoes.
So we went to the journey store
where the shoes were bought.
Uh, when she got to the
counter to return the shoes,
the girl behind the counter asked
her for her name, address, email,
and phone number.
Oh my God.
The amount of fucking people who
actually give out that information.
My girlfriend just gave the information
over. As soon as the girl asked for it,
we were leaving the store.
I remarked that I thought it was bullshit,
that she had to give away personal
information to return a pair of shoes.
She said, uh, it was not a big
deal, but I didn't like it.
All right.
Why the fuck would you give somebody all
in information and just in case you're
new to my podcast,
just say you can say no,
can I, you know I, I go out
to buy shit all time. Can I
have your phone number? No.
Yeah.
I don't even say I don't
even try and make it nice.
I just say no and then they
go, oh, okay. You know,
why do you feel like you've got
to give them their information?
You're trying to buy something.
I'm sorry I can't,
I can't sell you this unless
I get your information.
Well then go fuck yourself or buy it
somewhere else. I don't even need it.
Anyways. So anyways, he goes,
next we go to American Eagle.
You guys hit all the hotspot,
Huh? Then we went to Cinnabon.
Next we went to American Eagle where I
had to return his shirt. That was a gift.
There was a long line for returns.
Watch your return the shirt and did it
not fit or was it ugly as hell or was it
both?
As I was waiting in line,
one of the employees comes up to me
with a clipboard with the little form to
fill out. Now is anybody else kind
of getting the prison camp vibe here?
You know,
they're standing in line to get processed
and there's a guy coming up onto the
VAT. Is Your name please? Your phone
number? Uh, I stopped the employer.
Uh,
I stopped the employee and asked her
why she needed this information and she
says that it was to verify my purchase.
How fucking dumb are people?
You're going to verify my purchase. Well,
here's the sales slips there, sweetheart.
This verifies it.
That's it.
I don't know what to tell you.
Why don't you and your clipboard?
Why don't you hold that clipboard between
your little fucking beef curtains and
take a fucking walk down the street? How
about that? Hi Sweetheart. There it is.
The reasons you use that type of
language. Go Fuck Yourself. Oh,
how about I fucking grab that ponytail
and just, no, let's, let's, let's, let's,
let's keep it clean this week,
shall we? People. Anyway, she,
he goes before I could protest further.
She said that I could
just put my name on it.
Oh,
on
the clipboard.
Yeah.
When she walked away, I pulled out the
gift receipt Ppas said to my girlfriend,
oh, here it is. Yeah. This is what
verifies my purchase. Exactly.
The clipboard employee wasn't as
far as way as I thought she was in.
Heard me say,
did I read that wrong?
Get hurt me say it's heard me say this.
And she began to explain further why
I needed to give over the information.
This is the part of the email I hate.
He goes, I apologized and told her.
I realized it wasn't her and that it was
just a company's policy that she was in
forcing. She walked
away again. I felt bad.
So the next time I saw
her I apologized and said,
I realized that she was just
doing her job, but she ignored me.
She was probably pissed because it was
the day after Christmas and I was causing
her grief. But you could at least
accept my apology. You Bitch. Um,
I love how you go from being
totally liberal and seeing
somebody fucking side of
it too, being yeah, man
up, you can't. Um, anyway,
I got up to the counter and there
wasn't any further problems.
The guy at the register just took my
name and didn't ask me for anything.
I felt as though I had a small
victory against the big corporations.
Then this week I had to go back to the
store to return a hat my girlfriend got.
Did you guys not make Christmas
lists or all your relatives blind?
The seems to be a lot of,
uh, returning of gifts.
This is hilarious. You're returning a
hat that your girlfriend got. You Dude.
How horrific was that hat? Can you
please send me a picture of it before I,
if you took one before you returned it?
Yeah.
Picture one of those, uh, plaid Charlie
Chaplin Hat. Um, I had the receipt,
but again, the girl at the register
asked me for my address and phone number.
I said,
I didn't want to give that information
to her immediately panic sets in and her
face and she says that I have to,
I said that I didn't have to the day
after Christmas and I wasn't going to now,
good for you.
She calls over a coworker and they both
get defensive and hold to the idea that
I have to give over my information
in order to return a stupid hat.
Even though I had my receipt,
I asked why and they let me slide.
Why the let me slide on this before
and they maintained that I had,
I had to give them my name,
address and phone number.
So what did I do in the face
of corporate opposition?
I caved and I gave it to him.
You fucking Pussy,
dude. The second you saw
the panic on their face,
you knew that they were gonna
lose. All right. He goes,
I just don't get it, Bill. Why is a
receipt not enough? Nowadays it is enough.
They say they need our
personal information to verify
purchase. They're not, dude,
they're not. All right. All of that shit.
All those little safe, you know you
want to get when our discount store,
they're creating a file on you.
They figure out what you want to buy,
what they can mark a towards you,
and then they take that information and
they sell it to other fucking companies.
Even though they say they're not going to,
they sell your information,
your information gets up on the Internet.
And that's why there's all these creepy
websites out there right now that have
all this fucking information
about you, about, you know,
how many siblings you have,
your brothers and sisters names.
They all use that information to
fucking, it's, I'm telling you
this,
don't give them your information.
You don't have to give him your
information and people out there
who just have this fucking attitude
towards these corporations just sitting
there going like, wait, you know
what we do? What are they going?
You mean as long as you're not
doing anything wrong? I mean,
what do I care if they know where I live?
What do I keep this fucking morons.
You,
I don't even,
I've explained this shit till I'm blue
in the face and then I always get these
emails from these people.
Um, he just, I don't think,
I dunno, I can't, if I said
something the other day, you know,
I'm sitting there listening, I was sitting
there, I was listening to sports radio,
you know, cause I'm a deep
thinker, right. And uh, this,
this new guy got on sports radio out
here in Los Angeles and you know,
he does what most people do when they
have nothing to say, which is they,
they just start,
they just go over the top arrogant.
You know what I mean? Like he was
talking about how he wanted to get some,
some sort of sports culture
personality on the show,
but he doubted he could get him as
a guest because the guest hated him.
And he goes, you know, cause
I disagreed with them on some,
he was talking to a coach and he was
actually disagreeing with what the fucking
coach, he's disagreeing with the guy and
he goes, you know what the problem is?
You know, he goes like, I'm, I'm
just like such a good debater.
I actually ended up like convincing
myself of my own opinion.
You actually said that over the airwaves
and I just sort of muttered to myself
that the confidence of
morons is staggering.
You know what I mean? Morons think
they know everything. That's,
that's what makes them fucking morons.
And like the emails I get with
people who don't question this shit,
um, which is, I don't know,
like last week when I,
when I went off on my
little fucking rant there,
just some of the fucking emails
I get, it's like people are, are,
are sending me shit. That kind
of is backing up what I'm saying.
And then telling me that it sounded
like I have tin foil on my fucking head,
which obviously I am out of my
fucking mind on some level, but, um,
I'm not out of my mind when I don't
trust corporations and I don't trust them
when they say we're not going to
do anything with this information.
The other day I was in cvs and I go to
buy something and the lady asked me that
I have a saved card and I said, no.
She said, do you want one? And I said,
no. And she goes, well
that's okay. I'll just,
and she swiped the fucking thing
anyways. And I was like, lady,
what did I just say to you now? See if I
use my credit card, they'd have my name
and then to match up to that fucking
number and what the hell I just bought and
just a little bit more information about
me and my question to all you people
who have these, this faith
in these corporations,
why does that person do that?
Why are they so hell bent on trying to
make that corporation less money in that
moment?
They give me this card,
you know like everybody has those cards
so you're not saving any fucking money.
It's just, it's a big fucking
shell game to make it seem, Ooh,
look is saving money.
What they're really doing there.
I'll look at this hand over here is you're
giving them all your personal fucking
information that they can then use to,
to very lease sell the other corporations
to increase junk mail and it also to a
limit.
You're fucking level of privacy.
The fact that they can put all that
shit up in the Goddamn Internet.
People have been sending me these random
websites where they have like your name
and your address, where you fucking live
and all this type of shit. It's like,
how do you think that they
get all that information?
Do you think there's somebody sitting
there with the phone book and just typing
all of this shit in? I don't
know. I have fucking though.
If some [inaudible] kills me.
If some fucking random creepy guy,
you know you're standing there waiting
for the subway, came up to you,
asks you what's your name,
your phone number and your address was,
would you give it to him
now,
but for some reason you're inside of
a fucking store and there's socks and
sweaters and somebody has a name
tag. Now all of a sudden you, you,
you give them total fucking trust,
you're out of your mind. So sir,
don't cave in. All right, all you get,
you just, just say that's
unacceptable. That's unacceptable.
I want to speak to the manager what
they're doing. It's not legal yet.
It's not legal yet,
but I can guarantee you there's somebody
lobbying for it that in Washington
there's some sort of fucking
high powered lobbying group.
I swear to God is probably
lobbying that from here on out.
We need to have a law that if
you're going to return a hat,
you have to give us your name, your
address, and your social security number.
Just so there's not another nine
11 could guaran fucking tee it.
So yeah,
you don't have to.
That's actually one of the highlights of
my day. What I do now is when they say,
do you have our little savy safe card? And
I say, no, I don't. Would you like one?
No, I don't. I then say, and
please don't swipe another one.
You know? And then I tried to
pay with cash. I love cash.
Cash is fucking anonymous.
All you guys out there who was sitting
there watching these commercials where
they make look like credit cards
is so fucking easy. You, you're,
you're idiots. You're, you're,
you're buying into exactly
what they want you to buy into,
which is a cashless society.
So they can keep track of where you
are at all fucking times and every last
fucking dime that you make so they can
get their greedy little fucking hands on
it.
You're out of your mind and you're giving
up an unbelievable amount of fucking
privacy by creating a paper trail.
Everywhere you go,
everywhere you go, what you're
doing, where you're at, you know,
and the sea of morons who are
going to sit there and go, Whoa,
have you doing anything wrong?
I mean, I guess maybe,
maybe I'm a paranoid cycle.
You look at all these fucking idiots
who do reality TV's and [inaudible] and
they let cameras come into their house
and they don't seem to care about it.
Maybe, uh, maybe the average jackass
doesn't give a shit. But sir,
for the love of God,
you know,
in the end he says,
I'm not crying conspiracy.
It's very plain to see what they're doing.
It's not malicious or evil. Yes it is.
It is malicious and it is
evil and it is a conspiracy.
They're conspiring to get everybody's
information. Find out what they buy,
and they're lying to you
saying that they're not going
to share the information.
It's everything that you're saying. It's
not. It is. All right. And that's it.
That's two weeks in a row. I'm
on the soapbox. See people,
don't you like it better
when I talk about sports.
Um, anyways, let's talk
about football this week.
You're going to hear me say something
this week that I've never said before ever
on a podcast.
I feel bad for Peyton manning.
Peyton manning got fucked this week
by his own Goddamn coaching staff.
Um, he played a great God damn
gate when they needed a score,
he drove him right down the fucking field.
If that bomb caught that ball,
they were right in there. And even
still, and by the way, Anna, Vinod Terry,
it's a shame that jets one the Goddamn
game because that guy is the most money
kicker of all time.
I was actually joking with my buddy
when I was watching the game. Um,
I was saying that the most pussy ever
gotten by a professional kicker has to be
Adam [inaudible] Vernon Terry.
It's gotta be, it's gotta be,
and I actually learned that there's
no kicker in the NFL hall of fame and
there's no fucking way. It's just a shame
now. Cause I even that I hate the jets.
It's not, it's a shame that the
jets one that fucking game because
[inaudible] people are gonna forget that
he actually hit that fucking 50 yard a
man write down the fucking
middle right down the middle.
But uh, I don't, I,
I was right there with
Peyton manning when he was,
had his hands out when they called,
when the fucking cult called
timeout with 29 seconds to go.
Can somebody explain why
the fuck they did that?
And don't even say, well, your
point, you realize you jet,
we're going to kick a field goal and
they want to make sure that what they'd
have 17 seconds to get
down the fucking field.
There wasn't gonna be enough time.
You add a second year quarterback who had,
who,
who fucking had that deer
in the headlights look,
he was overthrown all his fucking
receivers. You take a timeout,
you give them a chance to gather himself
for their coaches to give them the next
three plays so we can fucking relax.
And what comes to comes right out. He,
it's a fucking 18 yard pass
and that's the end of the game.
And when Peyton was sitting
there with his hands out like,
what the fuck are we call a time out for?
It was the one time I have,
I actually felt bad for that guy.
I just sat there and I was going,
I think they are in the process
of losing this fucking game,
not just giving the game away.
Um,
it was fucking brutal. Absolutely
brutal. So there you go. Pate.
Manning did not lose that game.
He fucking stepped it up.
He played a hell of a Goddamn game. And
I actually feel bad for the guy that he,
that he lost. And if I'm
going to be honest now that
I think about it, about five,
six years ago,
you know,
he drove his team down the field and
their idiot kicker would talk shit about
Peyton choking in the playoffs. He went
on and he missed the fucking field goes.
So there's two years,
two losses. I, I won't,
I won't blame Peyton manning
for all, right? There you go.
See that the can make trying to
be a little more forgiving in a,
in this year. And, um, and
I realized this week too,
that I've been feeding into
exactly what Rex Ryan wants,
which is people just talking
about him. Um, you know,
what are the odds he think he think he's
going to say something outrageous this
week. Uh, it's really like watching
Madonna's career. You know,
where you have a woman who,
uh,
has a mediocre voice and has made mediocre
music for the last 30 fucking years.
Yet somehow it,
whenever she wants to be is in the news.
And you know why?
Because she knows when to
take her clam up. All right?
She knows when to go on Letterman and say,
fuck 38 times during an interview.
You know,
when you really think about Madonna,
what does it have to do? Oh Wow,
look how good shape she's in.
They just see when she did the book
and she fucking spread her legs,
you know? Did you see when
she said, fuck on Letterman,
did you see when she did the video,
Eh,
fucking Jesus was black
and then she kissed him?
Of course. That's what you talk about.
What are you going to talk board a land?
So you're like,
okay,
bye by rarely 30 year career
off of that horse shit.
What's his face is doing the same thing.
He's doing the exact same fucking thing.
Dropped a bunch of f
bombs during hard knocks.
That was his Letterman episode.
All right. He put a wig on.
That was him showing his clam
and then then he made a
controversial video. Other than that,
he lost the division,
backed into the fucking playoffs.
Playoffs. I, yeah. I don't know. You
know? You know what I realized this week?
I didn't even know what the name of
the coach was for the Atlanta Falcons.
I given this guy no hype whatsoever.
Mike Smith.
I had actually actually had to look it up.
This is a guy who went 13
and three who actually has,
has actually has a franchise
quarterback in Matt Ryan.
He actually has a franchise quarterback,
you know,
but it's not in New York. So
who gives a fuck? Right. Um,
with that, my predictions for
the week. Um, Pittsburgh Ravens,
I have no fucking idea. Uh, patriots jets,
I have no fucking idea.
Just for the simple fact that I have no
idea which defense to patriots are going
to show up with.
You know,
I am not a guy if you realize that
I'm not a guy who buys into hype.
That's why I've have not bought into
rex Ryan for half a fucking second.
And that's why also when the
Patriots won 45 to three,
I didn't go well there you go.
Cause I realize we also lost 28 to 14.
I also know that we suck against the run.
So I think if we're going to win,
I'll tell you, found the patriots.
I gotta be taken. I gotta Stop
Lt. No, seriously. We, if we,
if we can stop the run and,
uh, go up by a good 10,
14 fucking points and put Sanchez into a
situation where he feels like he has to
make a play, we're going to
be in it. We're going to be,
we're going to be all right. That's what
we need to do. That's what we need to do.
And I have faith that we're
going to fucking do that.
I hope for the love of fucking
God, because if we don't, uh,
you're going to listen to the sounds of
a blubbering jackass next week on this
fucking podcast. Um, and
that is it. So that's it.
I'm really hoping, uh, oh, look at this.
Look at this. I got some offers coming in.
I got some offers coming
in. Yeah. We go where,
where am I going to be performing? Oh, by
the way, I'm actually in the process of,
uh, of, uh,
getting a Detroit and Milwaukee date.
Now.
I have not played in Detroit since I did
the rich bitch tour way back in the day
with Charlie Murphy and a ashy Larry
and I have not played Milwaukee ever.
I know I did a college in that area
because a long time ago I went to a bucks
game.
Um,
but what else do I got going on here?
Of course I don't get the
fucking Internet here.
Yeah.
My bedroom, the hell is wrong with me.
I'm stepping up my life in 2011 people.
Um, all right, let's go with youtube
videos for the week. All right. Um,
yeah.
Oh, here's something I've been, you know,
watching a lot of basketball lately and
Kareem Abdul Jabbar always gets credit
for inventing the Sky Hook and a,
I always took that as law
and I was just like, yeah,
the guy invented the sky hook. Wow.
People must have been like, what the fuck?
You know, they went from the
set shot to that, you know,
the way they traditionally
shoot now with the one hand,
the other hand guide the ball and
then he comes out with that shit.
People must just been like,
where the fuck did that come from?
And then I was looking at some old,
a Celtics video and that was sort of a
shot that people already took in the 60s,
but they did it from their hip and it was
one of the gayest looking shots you're
ever gonna see.
You just sort of jumped in the air,
had one leg up in the
air bent at the knee.
Like I don't think that there's a physical
way to do that shot without going.
We as you throw it.
But uh,
he just thought he changed it where
he didn't shoot it from the hip.
He just put it over his fucking
head. So there you go. Um,
here's a nice conspiracy theory. One
from people in the, I believe in Seattle,
you go to a Seahawks game,
they have a large beer and a
small beer in the large beer,
it's like a dollar 75 more.
They come in two different glasses.
So somebody filled up a small glass
with water and poured it into the large
glass in it, filled it all the way
up. It was classic. The small glasses,
a little fat one,
and the other one's nice and tall.
So you think you'd get more and you're
not and they charge your next to dollar
25 a. So we made a video of it. Um,
what else? What other videos
do I have here? Oh, this is
one from a new website. Uh,
totally crap. Totally crap.com.
They got a lot of good,
good videos and there's one
there called five minute fight.
All of these by the way will be up
on the [inaudible] podcast.com. Um,
and what else? Oh, this one is a,
a video also on a totally crapped.com.
Uh,
and it's also an underrated and
it says underrated ass whooping.
So many things would be salt if people
would start their kids outright.
And the name of this video is
old school ass whooping. And uh,
I don't know how to describe this other
than this father puts on a video camera.
He makes his kid tell him he's not going
to be in a gang and he starts beating
with the belt and the kid tells his dad
he's not. The gangs are bullshit. He goes,
don't tell me,
tell it to the fucking camera.
And he continues to beat
his ass with a belt.
It's a sad, it's funny. It's
everything you want it to be.
And then there's another video that I
saw right after that five minute fight.
And this fight is fucking hilarious.
There's two white kids,
they're calling each other bitch in
the colony, each other, the n word.
And I swear to God,
they might both throw 700 punches
and I think they missed 698 each.
It's the classic thing where you've
got two people who want to fight.
They don't know how to fight and all they
know is they want to punch the person,
other person in the face, but they
don't want to get hit in the face.
So they won't commit to coming inside.
And they just sort of punching the
atmosphere around the other guy's head.
Or as I like to say, uh,
an NBA basketball fight.
You ever watch our NBA basketball
players fight? For the most part.
They pulled their head behind
their shoulders and then they,
they throw punches like they're trying
to throw a fucking baseball from the
outfield to home plate. Um, all right.
I'm just really just giving information
this week. I don't feel like I'm fucking,
Oh, here we go. Nope. That
was from last week. Oh,
for Christ's sake. You Cook the shit
out of it. Where the hell am I here?
What the fuck is my underrated
overrated for the week? Oh,
overrated or underrated. Here we go.
Overrated. NFL celebrations. Seriously,
how many times do we have to see these
unoriginal athletes do the jump and the
chest bump after a touchdown?
It's been, it's been done so much.
It's become lackluster and automatic.
Remember the throat slash they would all
do before the NFL banned it for being
too violent a gesture.
I remember even Brett Farve doing that
one and still managing to come off too
white when he did it.
Or what about the fact that
the celebrations aren't
even regulated to touchdowns
anymore? Every sack tackle
first down and catch warrants,
a dance and a, hey look at me moment
for the player. This is the NFL.
I expect defenses to wrap a
guy up and make a tackle. Uh,
may expect the receivers
to catch the ball.
They need to show some class and act like
they've done it before. Not to mention,
yeah, I'm totally with
you on that. That whole,
every time you catch a pass and
then you get up and you got it.
You know the Jerome Bettis was,
was the guy always stands out in my
head where he would, he would fucking,
you know,
his first 10 carries,
he get like 12 yards and then he ripped
one off for like 11 and then he get up
and start stomping around,
taken off his fucking Chin strap.
I can't stand that shit. Braylin
Edwards does that Shit, you know,
drops like nine passes and then catches
one for a first down, gets up fucking,
ah, it's the worst thing ever. The
key, Shawn, the Keyshawn Johnson will,
you stomp around and you take off you
fucking Chin strap. It's like, well, I,
I, I hate that shit. I hate it. I
can't say, I don't mind actually,
if you catch a touchdown, you do
a little fucking dance. Actually,
I've always liked that shit.
But like the, uh, the first,
you know what's even worse is when your
team is kicking the shit out of another
team and then the other team makes a good
defensive play and then that guy gets
up. Ah, I'm screaming at the people in the
end zone. It's like, dude, you're, you're,
you're down 28 to six.
All right. Why don't,
why don't you go back to the defense of
Huddle and figure out why the fuck you
weren't doing that for the first
three and a half quarters, you know,
so I'd go with you. Um, uh, yeah,
I'm over all of that shit. And, uh,
I think the worst thing I saw this
year was the t o show show. Well,
you had a team that was
absolutely shitting the bed,
yet there are two best players had
the time to do a reality show, uh,
during the fucking, uh, during the season.
Do you think bill Bellacheck
would put up with that?
Do you think that those guys would not
be shipped out for third round draft
picks?
It's unfucking believable,
the level of disrespect that
that is to do that fucking show
during the goddamn season as you proceed
to Lee lose fucking eight games in a
row.
Uh Oh.
And then you go on the show and you
throw your coaches under the bus.
There you go.
Um, and for those of you who wonder why
Randy Moss was traded for a third round
draft pick, that's why, because of
that type of shit, because it's really,
it's just not worth it. Like you ever
see a beautiful girl in a bar, okay.
Or whatever. Or you start
dating a beautiful girl and
no matter how hot she is,
she's just such a cunt.
It's not fucking worth it.
She's just so fucking high maintenance.
That's what all those players
are like in all the, all the,
all those types of sports.
It's at the end of the day,
no matter how fucking good they
are, they, they just not worth it.
They just not worth it. Kind of like
listening to the rest of this podcast.
It's really not worth it.
I feel like I haven't had anything to
say for the last fucking 12 minutes.
Alright. Underrated,
uh, bat baseball's code,
although it's definitely
borderline juvenile sometimes.
I do like that in baseball. If you show
up a pitcher by celebrating your home,
run a little bit too much,
you can guarantee he's throwing
at you the next time you're up.
I liked that players get to police
themselves a little bit. Well, sir,
why don't you come over to the NHL?
You'd love Nhl Hockey.
You just basically described why
there's fighting and hockey and why.
That's why hockey's awesome and uh,
you know,
cause they let the players police each
other and I know people who don't like
the NHL, they're going to be like
by fighting. Yes. By fighting.
It has to be done.
Okay.
You got a guy skating around the ice
if fucking 20 miles an hour with the
goddamn club in his hand.
Okay.
If you don't slap the shit out of them,
every couple of games,
he's going to hurt somebody severely.
You know? So that's, that's,
that's what needs to be done.
You know,
think of all the pieces of shit players
that are cheap fox in the NBA. All right?
And in the NFL and all that,
just imagine if they actually had a club
in their hand and they could walk up to
your best player and just
fucking slam 'em over the head,
right in the fucking grill or
in the side of his fucking leg.
You know,
you'd have to beat the shit though,
or you have to be allowed to
beat the shit out of that guy.
So it wouldn't happen.
And I know what you guys were thinking.
Well if anybody does that just banned
him for life out of the league.
Well then you would end up with nobody
playing hockey because I don't know what
it is. If you've ever played
hockey, there's something about it.
It's just a very physical game. And at
some point you're going to think about it,
that mother fucker gets you for
like the fifth God damn time.
You just that you got this club in
your hand and you just used the,
I'm going to fucking come over there.
I'm just going to fucking take two
hander right to his fucking neck.
But you doubt because their biggest
player will come over there and beat the
living shit out of you in front of your
fucking girlfriend or wife who's in the
stance. Did that makes
sense? Speaking of which,
I'm actually playing hockey tonight and
yes I do suck. I am upon hockey player.
I can only go frontwards and
crossover on one side both. Okay.
I got the helmet with the full cage,
you know that's,
that's usually a sign that someone's
going to be a cheap piece of shit.
Anybody who has all the extra padding,
that's because they know somebody is
going to come up and try to retaliate.
So they want to make sure that
their directs to protect it.
I actually wear it because I know that my,
if I was ever gonna make it to the NHL,
that would have happened by now.
I'm going to go out on a limb
and say that as a 42 year old,
I don't think I'm going to make it.
So there's really no point in me getting
the required 18 stitches that starts
above my upper lip,
goes through my lips and comes down.
I remember the Gary Galley one that was
the most insane fucking scar I've ever
seen. Gary Galley, former Bruins,
he's playing for the Boston,
then went to the kinks, right?
He's playing for the Bruins.
He's in front of the net.
Somebody gets crosschecked in their chest.
The guy like he gets hit so hard that
both his legs fly up into the air.
He's like in the air in this
seated position. He basically kicks
Gary Galley in the face with his skate,
just sorta
like as his legs are going up, the blade
of the guys skate catches Gary galleys.
Fucking Chin goes right through both his
lips and right up the side of his face
and he had stitches from,
I think the side of his nose,
right down and right.
Yeah, through both lips.
In a, I was one of the worst ones
I ever saw. And uh, you know,
and I think that's good to conclude one
of the worst podcasts I've ever fucking,
uh, I felt like a Sanchez
during this whole podcast.
At no point that I feel comfortable.
I don't feel like I settled down.
I feel like all my jokes went 10
feet over everybody's fucking head.
And if I could have handled this mic off
to somebody for the second half of it,
you know, and let somebody kick the last
joke through the uprights I would have.
Yeah. Fuck, I got to redeem myself. Did
anything funny happen to me this week?
I went out,
I looked at some houses.
I think I'm getting ready to go right
back on the wheel again. You know,
have to talking about
having no god damn dead.
I'm thinking about just
going out and buying a house,
maybe buying a fucking car.
I want to buy something.
You know,
I want to fill the void
like only an American can.
Somebody sent me an email talking
about how America is over, you know,
talking about how China is now. Now
there now they're going to be the shit.
And you know what I say? Well,
it's about fucking time. You know,
China,
how many Goddamn fucking people the have
to make before he can take over some
shit.
China,
that's the most overrated Goddamn
fucking country out there. You know,
they got like a third of the world's
population. How the fuck are you?
Not the best. You should have the
best guitar players, the best singers,
the best actors, the best scientist.
Just out of sheer fucking numbers.
What do you guys been doing over there?
I've been slacking off.
Slacking off with your fucking awful
food and your dirty goddamn restaurants.
Do you know I won't eat
Chinese food because of that.
I'm not saying Chinese people. A bad
food or bad people. Bad food, bad people.
It was like a,
that was like a Jeffrey Dahmer comment.
I'm not saying Chinese people are bad
food. I'm not saying that they're,
that they're bad people.
I'm not saying then that's my,
I'm just saying I lived
in New York City and uh,
I used to be a fan of Chinese food.
I am not a fan anymore.
All right. And until they start getting
some clean goddamn restaurants out there,
I'm not, I'm not fucking eat him. That's
it. I'm not saying you're bad people.
I'm just saying what the fuck.
Filthy. I'll only, I'll only
eat Chinese food. Who's getting,
if I'm shit faced, I'll lead
anything. I don't give a fuck,
but if I'm sober or the only way I'll eat
Chinese food is if it's a cloth napkin.
Sit down. Nice fucking place. All right.
And it'd be fair.
That's why I don't eat barbecue.
I'm not going into those goddamn
shacks with those fucking flies
the size of Goddamn bumblebees.
I'm not going in there. And again,
it, that's the whole year. You poor
people food. Yeah. It looks like it.
It looks like it. It looks like you've
been dominated on some fucking level.
Oh, with the dirty floors
and the peanut shells.
Fuck Barbecue and fuck Chinese food. All
right. Actually had some Lebanese food,
uh, yesterday, which is just sort of
all like Middle Eastern food like that,
that a chicken kabobs and all that
stuff was fucking insane to bully salad.
All right. I sign off on that.
I sign off on Indian food.
I sign off on a, these are all the
ones I'll give you the that I like.
I like a Japanese,
I'll go with Korean barbecue.
We'll go with that. Thai food.
I like that shit. Chinese,
I think Chinese was the only
one I won't fuck with. You know,
and I'm Mexican food.
Mexican food has to be a certain
cut or I'm not fucking with it.
You know when you go to the,
so some of those,
some of those little shits shacks there
and they get the refi re fried beans and
it just looks like, you know, it's like,
does the health department even
know this place exists? Okay.
This is like a restaurant slash
it's like you turn the garage area
house into a fucking burrito factory.
I'm not eating here.
Macro likes to gives me shit because
I'll never get Chinese food, you know?
And she thinks it's that,
that there's something like borderline
racist that I won't eat Chinese food.
It's like I have no problem
with those people. You know,
that's like over like
overly think it's something.
What I'm saying is is I want to clean
God damn restaurant. Is that so wrong?
All right. That's the podcast for
this fucking week. Um, I dunno.
I am. I am I wrong about that shit? I
just don't want, I think Chinese food.
I think dirty restaurant.
That's,
that's what the fuck I think because
that has been my experience. So go ahead.
We're going to take the next call
or after this break. Uh, hey.
What would you guys do if I started doing
commercials on my podcast as a way to
make money if right in the middle
of calling somebody a cunt.
I just did something for
like true value hardware.
Do they still exist or where they
bought out? Bought up by best buy.
Do they still exist? All right.
Anyways. Oh, you know what?
I actually forgot tonight that
I can't see this shit because I
know, fuck it. I'm going to say it.
I'm actually gonna go see one of my
favorite drummers of all time tonight.
Okay.
And Joe.
Joe Mayor is doing a drum clinic and
I'm going to go check that shit out.
And uh, if you want to see
this guy drummers out there,
you got to fucking check this guy out.
This is going to,
I'm going to have this up on
the [inaudible] podcast.com. Uh,
Joe Joe mayor performing,
I plays like that drum in a drum and bass
music and it's him performing at the,
I believe 2005 modern drummer festival.
It's just a three minute clip.
He could do like a role with one hand.
He's got that push poll molar thing.
I don't know what the fuck he's doing,
but uh,
this guy is the shit and I'm
actually starting to like,
I can't get into drum and bass,
but I'm downloading some of his shit
just because it's played by human beings.
And I'm actually fascinated
with drum and bass because it,
it melds both the capabilities of
technology and then the abilities of human
beings to adapt to the
technology and raise their
level of performance. You know,
remember that time when I told you
guys about that, that whole, uh,
have drum and bass music, that whole
video that basically explained it,
it was like a fucking drum
brake from a B side of a 45.
And then Djs took that drum loop,
isolated every sound,
and then switched it all up and created
a whole bunch of different beats and
then sped it up to the point that no
human being could play it until a guy like
Joe Joe mayor sat down and figured
out how to fucking do it. It's,
it's incredible. It's absolutely
incredible. I'm going to
watch that guy tonight.
I'm going to get my ass kicked out
on the ice tonight, play in hockey,
and that's it. I'm going to be in New
York and I'm gonna be doing spots, uh,
around the city before I
go down to Atlantic city.
So I make sure that I am in shape for my,
uh,
my big gig down there with Jim Norton.
Jim Breuer and David Tell Eh,
uh, I will probably be popping
in at Gotham comedy club.
I will be popping in at the comedy cellar
and a stand up New York and Co the comic
strip and danger fields and be doing
the whole fucking loop. Like
I used to back in the old
days, back in the old days,
which I guess they don't
do that anymore now.
They booked the club's a month out
and they just want you to work at the,
at the same club the whole week.
But back in the day,
he used to use to work like three, four
clubs. If you could on a weekend and you,
you,
you'd have a nine o'clock here at nine
45 at another club at 10 20 here and 1130
here all the way to like two o'clock in
the morning and you get $50 a spot and
you'd blow like a third of it on cabs
just driving all around the city and you'd
have a new idea for a bit.
And uh,
in one night you can hash
it out just doing like, you
know, sometimes up, up, up.
I think the most,
every day I do like eight sets in a night.
Who's fucking unbelievable and it just
caused you to write because you didn't
want to say the same thing eight
times in one night and uh, you could,
you could flesh out a bit.
I mean that was basically like doing,
you know, almost headline
weekends you only do six shows,
so you would get eight
shows on average six.
So it was like doing an entire weekend
worth of shows in one night as far as
running that same new bit.
And it's incredible.
And I wish the New York clubs would go
back to doing that because I really think
that that was the system that created all
the great comics that I watched when I
came to New York.
That's just my,
that's my 2 cents and I'll fucking
sticker what that, that's it.
You guys watch 60 minutes,
by the way,
that just reminded me of fucking
Andy Rooney guys been watching the I,
we watched that every week.
Me In the there and we just laugh our
asses off at that curmudgeony old bastard.
And what the fuck is going
on with his upper lip?
It's receded on both sides yet.
The middle part's still is fleshy.
So now it looks like he has a pimple.
This upper lip.
All right,
I got nothing people.
I'm talking about fucking Andy Rooney's
upper lip. Okay. The podcast is overbuilt.
Tap Out. It's over. Oh,
congratulations to Pete Carroll.
I was wrong about that.
Docker wearing white shoes.
Jerry Seinfeld sneakers,
son of a bitch.
They came out to fucking play.
Worse defensive performance I've
ever seen with the saints at uh,
I don't know. I don't even know who
the fuck they're playing next week.
I'm just hoping that my patriots and
praying that we're going to beat the jets
cause I have no fucking idea
which defense is going to show up.
But I'll your phone, the patriots,
you gotta be taken. All right,
that's the podcast for this week.
Everybody have a great week. Uh,
don't give out your information to these
fucking corporation for the love of God.
And if you want to go ahead and do it
stupid. All right, go ahead and do it.
But then don't be surprised when a,
you know,
some psycho you dated from high school
is standing on your front porch and has
your fucking, uh, all your
information. All right.
I couldn't even finish that sentence.
Who gives a fuck? Go Fuck Yourself.
I'll talk to you next week.
[inaudible]
[inaudible].