Okay.
Hey, what's going on? It's Bill Burr and
It's time for the Thursday afternoon.
Just before Friday.
Monday morning podcast and
Ahhh,
just checking in on you.
Just checking in on you.
What's going on? Let me do that.
Like I'm falling off a cliff.
Oh,
I woke up this morning.
[inaudible] I had the dumbest song in my
head and I can't get it out and now I'm
going to sing it to you so
it'll be stuck in your head.
It's a very vengeful thing for me to
do. It's something that, you know,
pieces of shit guys. Do
you know if I'm going down,
I'm taking you down with me and
all those kinds of pieces. Shits,
you know they do that. Uh, the ladies,
the ladies like to dabble in that. Well,
fuck you. This is in a relationship.
At least I'm getting some
of your tee shirts, right?
They're going to get
something from it. Well, look,
this song's going to be stuck in my head.
I'm sorry to say that it's going to
be stuck in yours head too. All right,
and I've given you a good, I've been
talking about this for a good 18 seconds.
Says plenty of time. Even if
you're driving in the car,
he hit pause and you're choosing not to.
Why do you do this to yourself?
Why don't you just choose the road that's
going to bring you true happiness is
the,
because you grew up and you watched
people being abused and you felt like you
didn't have a choice in life
that this is the way it was.
You know what that last 10 seconds is
probably going to be worse than the song,
but here it is.
[inaudible] I hold up my head
and at the edge
it's something. It's up dead.
Huh? I don't know who sings that song.
I don't think I've ever gotten past
those first two lines of that song.
It's always comes on session presents
love songs from the 70s or the,
yeah, this one
[inaudible] big [inaudible]
right,
and you sit in and go look at this
fucking horse shit and you start thinking
about your childhood. Next thing you know
you're on the phone with the operator.
Could they get the deluxe edition? Yeah,
I still have a CD player in my car.
Well, because I'm frugal.
It's not because I'm failing.
And I resent you saying that.
Of course. I still want the CDS.
I'm speaking of my old car, my car.
I've had it since, uh, October
of 2007. It's a 2008. Oh,
is it brand new? It will hit it
fucking stars in its eyes, right.
Just stepped off the bus here in Hollywood
with a piece of Straw between its
seat. Like axl rose in
the guns and roses video.
A welcome to a welcome to
the jungle. I'm there now.
Look at it. Oh, this thing,
it looks like somebody attacked it
with a fucking can opener. Right?
It did as until as of the other day.
My, uh, my wife was out of town.
She was in New York City for the
great Patrice O'Neal benefit.
I want to thank everybody who came out
and I want to thank everyone who did the
show. I unfortunately was not able
to get a fucking flight in and time,
if you can believe that. I
actually missed the benefit.
Fucking brutal. I had a
flight out a Saturday morning,
Saturday,
and I believe that when I was on American
Airlines and they just gave me a call
and like, like a, you know, when
a one 800 number and I went hello.
And they were like, hello that says
American Airlines at four McGill,
they have like two nighter was three
as by gads you're then relocated.
No, you might want to grab
a pad. You'll now bed.
Rebooked like ever. What? Zev it thanks.
Zero out of l a x on Tuesday,
January 26 at 1:50 PM a the benefit was
on the 26th I was supposed to be flying
out on the 23rd.
They pushed it three fucking days and I
was gonna leave for 15 east coast time
when the show starts at seven. So
I'm like, well that's not gonna work.
So I call my travel agent, you know,
and so she got me a flight on JetBlue,
7:45 AM on, um,
Sunday, the 24th. So I'm like, no
worries. All right, so I miss a day,
no big deal. Blah, blah, blah,
blah. Right. And then I get a call,
I get a call like the night before,
I'm all packed and got my shit right
next to the door and there's like that
[inaudible] blow inmate one out of
their bed and a piece of paper, right?
And then they fucking Bob me to fucking
Tuesday. So I said, fuck these guys.
I call my travel agent again.
Now I'm on virgin. All right.
I don't know why they call
it Virgin Airlines and then
it looks so dizzy in that
fucking thing. It's like at the
w hotel was a plane, you know,
with the fucking aquarium lighting that
just says no one wants to see a good
look of their face in a mirror after
they do what they do in here. Right.
So they booked me on that fucking
thing and they're like, well,
the time we can get you out is right when
the New England patriots game starts.
And I'm like, oh, that guy, you
got TV, I fuck it. Put me on it.
Right. And then that one got canceled.
So at that point I did deduced
if I'm using the word properly,
that uh, that the fucking every,
every poor bastard from Saturday and
Sunday now that those flights at all been
canceled, we're now eating up all
the Monday and Tuesday ones. So, um,
I had my travel agent go after another
flight and then meanwhile I called my
manager, who knows all
these big guys and I said,
can you get me a
replacement in case I could,
I'm not going to be able to
get it. Long story short,
I wasn't able to get in in time.
We got a replacement and a,
I wish I could have been there because
a rich vos who crushed it as a host once
again this year and he said,
a blah, blah, blah, blah.
Unfortunately bill burrow can't be here.
And everyone's like, oh, what the fuck?
Where is the red country? Right. And he
said, ah, that's the bad news. He said,
the good news is Louis C K and Louis
C K walked out and they would fucking
absolutely mental. And, uh, you know,
I was replaced one balding redhead
with another balding red head with more
credits so nobody missed me. Um,
and I guess he fucking murdered it.
And then the only to do is 15 cause
he's such a great guy, didn't like 25,
um, and just fucking destroyed and
everybody had a great time. And uh,
somebody sent me a picture of, um, I've,
everybody in the end coming out, Al del
Benny flew in all the way from Sydney,
Australia.
That's another reason why I didn't want
to reschedule cause this guy flew in
from the other side of the
fucking world. And um, Oh,
who else was there?
Rachel phones find saying Greer
Barnes who absolutely murdered,
you know, one of the greatest to
ever did it. Greer Barnes. Um,
Jim Norton, I don't have it in
front of me. I wasn't there too,
so I know I'm going to end up forgetting
somebody. But uh, anyways, everybody,
God freak did it. Everybody fucking
killed. And uh, they had a great time.
So anyway,
so I was out here and I was supposed
to be in New York from Saturday until
Wednesday. So nobody knew that I was
out here, you know, so I was just like,
well fuck it. I'm not
telling anybody I'm here.
And I just started handling a bunch
of shit that I'd been putting off for
months, if not years. Um,
I did everything from, uh,
get my last will together, my,
you know, when I die or whatever,
make sure that everything goes
to the people who needs to go to.
So there's no fighting
hopefully. Um, which is actually,
it's really morbid, but it's also fucking
kind of cool. It's, I can't fucking,
you take this and you take
that in a, I'm out of here.
Good luck to is I had a
great time and a great ass.
Um, I rolled change that we hadn't jars.
I handled that and I dropped my fucking
Prius off and I had all the fucking
dense repaired you should
say. Looks Brand fucking new.
There's a couple of little ones
that they just stay left in there.
They buffed the whole thing up. I didn't
get new bottlers because you know,
you have new bumpers out here.
They last for about three days before
somebody just bumps into them. So a,
I just had them bought those things
up and it looks fucking great.
And I'll tell you right now,
having a paid off Prius with
80,000 something miles on it.
I'm in La. La is the greatest fucking
car you could ever drive. It's just,
it's the shit and it takes the hits
too. It's like Ben Roethlisberger.
It just fucking shakes him off and he's
get keeps going and amount of how bad
the gas prices get. I've never
paid more than 40 bucks a gallon.
I don't give a fuck if
somebody runs into it. Um,
I could park it wherever I want. Nobody's
gonna take it. It's fucking perfect.
Right? I bought my wife a nice
car. It's nice. I can't stand it.
I can't, you know, I feel like
when I'm driving that thing.
Do you guys ever see that
fucking hilarious Howard
Stern's movie, private parts?
Do you remember when he was showing
himself when he first became a DJ in lake?
When he went to put the needle on the
record and he scratched and he fucked the
whole thing up. Remember that noise?
Who's making, who's going home?
Hello? Hello? Hello. That's
what I feel like when I drive that car.
Like I'll be going to the grocery
store and I'll just be thinking like,
God damn and I need to go in there and
buy some fucking hamburger. But you know,
if I don't see a bunch of wide open
spaces, I won't parking in there.
Cause I know somebody's going to come
in and just park right next to it and
fucking oh fun door right into the side
of it and it's gonna make me fucking
sick. You know, it's like
when you go to a movie, right?
Like right now is a great
time to go see star wars.
Maybe in another fucking week.
Right? Nobody's going to be there.
You go see a matinee, right?
It's during the work week.
You're a comedian, you got a Gig
that night. You say, fuck fucking,
I'm going to go.
I'm going to go see a matinee showing
of star wars fucking six weeks after it
came out, right? You go in there,
there's nobody fucking there.
You get your feet up,
you having a great time.
It is fucking inevitable that someone's
gonna walk in during the fucking
trailers.
They're gonna sit down or right behind
you and they're going to talk much
popcorn fucking loudly.
Or they're going to be fucking dress
like Chewbacca and there's going to going
to be getting hair in
their mouth or their thing.
Gonna be doing that the entire
fucking time. It's a net the same,
the same way that is inevitable. If
you park in a, in a, in a parking lot,
some con,
even if there's a bunch of fucking spaces
is going to pull in right next to you
and they can open their fucking
door right into it, you know,
and that's just regular people
forget about out of shape.
People who they,
they gotta like put stress on their
hinges of their doors to just make it wide
enough, you know? You know,
that's where you know you're fat.
When you get like one of those Formula
One fucking steering wheels that just
pops out so you can get your gut out.
You keep lying to yourself. I'll tell you,
they don't make these Ford Broncos as
big as they used to. Yeah, they do. Yeah,
they do. They most
certainly fucking do. Um,
so anyways, speak at a cars too. And I
saw there's somebody up the street, man.
It's going to kill a fucking car.
It's one of those Volkswagen. Uh,
it's not the bug. It's not the Carmen
Guian. It's the fucking station wagon.
And they put some white walls on
it and some fucking fog lights.
They got the luggage rack on
it. It's fucking cool as shit.
I love station wagon. Ah,
I love a station wagon.
I'm sorry, I got a little fucking,
uh, who's that guy? It's as big as oh,
well, and it's about test sets sail.
So,
um, hang on. Sorry. Sorry. I'm
singing all these fucking songs.
It's a little old place where you
could get together and do what,
what kind of depravity
goes on in a love shack.
Okay.
Does that song even make sense?
They just went out to a shack
and they fucked, I mean,
maybe I'm taking it too literally. Uh,
what was I looking up? Oh yeah, the, uh,
the Volkswagen station
wagon. The Volkswagen.
This is Zyvox Vox Vargon
station. Vagan uh,
classic VW station or Wag on,
let's see what this thing's
called. There it is.
The fuck is it called? So I got
all the, uh, the pictures of it.
That's such a fucking cool car,
man. I love the front end on it.
And the guy also had it in a stick shift,
which I think is a picture below a rear
view of the Volkswagen beetle from 61 to
seven 67. That's not what I
wanted. One of these days.
One of these days, I'm
just going to look shit up.
Yeah.
You know, before it starts.
And I'll have a nice news
podcast. I'm imitating my,
my science teacher from a
okay.
From high school when he was talking
about some sort of biology thing, he said,
there's, there's rough and smooth, I
forget what it was. And he was like,
this is all rough and smooth.
And he used to make a joke out of it and
everybody would laugh and you'd never
get it wrong on the test. Bam.
You know why there's not more funny
teachers is because they all become
comedians. Cause it just like, all right,
I'm basically doing stand up here and a,
I'm not making any money,
so fuck these kids and their future.
Yeah.
Volkswagen type three square back.
That's all it's called. Come on.
They had to give it a
better name than that. Oh,
this is some fucking gearhead
thing. God Damn fucking bastards.
Can you just tell me the
name of the fucking car?
Well, he did formation.
You think I could look it up
by the mid sixties it was clear
that Volkswagen's iconoclastic,
thinks small campaign on behalf of
the lowly beetle had succeeded in
transforming the third
hike. Wait a minute. Wait,
what the fuck is this about Hitler?
I'm trying to read about the fucking
Karmann Ghias type two maybe it is a
Karmann Ghia. I, you know what the
fuck I'm talking about. You know what?
I'll just put a picture up. How about
that? I'll, I'd put a picture of that.
Hey, did anybody see bill
Bellacheck a football life?
It was a two Pi and I gotta
admit I was bored shitless.
I,
I've never been more bored watching a
football life even when it was him and Tom
Brady's sitting in the office. I
was, it was fucking egghead shit,
but it was just all monotone. Just
calling. Yeah. Yeah. Lions have a,
uh, a good defense. So, uh, you know,
I'm gonna put together a game plan
and then Tom Brady be like smiling,
but just going like, yeah, I
thought maybe we could have the, uh,
the running back come out
of the backfield. We could
explain some things, uh,
the underneath of their a secondary.
Okay.
Oh yeah. Tell him I'm going
to look into that. Okay, Bill.
And that'll be like seen. It was like
fucking, even when he got emotional,
when he went to giant stadium,
I was just like, this is a no,
he didn't get in volt motion of like,
if you want to see the emotional why
you got to see the Dick from meal one.
But I was, I, I can't even watch
it. I feel like a bad patriots fan.
I cannot get fucking through it. Um,
maybe I will eventually. So actually, um,
that was another thing I did when I was
here. I was just binge watching shit.
I watched the whole first
season of top boy on Netflix.
It's only four episodes
a fucking good show, man.
And I just started the
second one last night and a,
yeah,
I watched this documentary
on na's who I never got,
I never got it. When illmatic came
out I was like, I don't like this.
I don't get it right. And now I went
back and listened to it as like, oh,
wait a minute. This is fucking
unbelievable. You gotta admit.
Okay. When you're younger, there's a lot,
sometimes there's albums that come out or,
or artists that come by and you just
don't see them cause you're like, Eh,
you know, he's an older
guy. Like, like David Bowie.
I never want to see that guy
live. And now doing the classic,
now that he's dead, let me take
another listen to his fucking music.
And I, you know, I had that fucking
album. Like everybody has that album.
I had the Ziggy stardust one and a,
that's still an amazing fucking album
obviously, but it's been played to death.
But that was killer. But I downloaded
diamond dogs. It's fucking on.
It's unreal. And I was like, I many
times could I have seen this guy,
I could have seen him on the
let's dance. Toilet dance.
Well yeah, red shoes, a little blue.
Um, I could have seen him on
any of those and I never did.
You know Bob Newhart's play
playing out Friday night.
I'm not going to get a chance to see
him. His fucking show is sold out.
It's like way the fuck
out in the desert and a,
I got something nine 30 the next morning
so I can't go fucking see the guy.
And uh, so I'm trying to make a bucket
list of guys I gotta go fucking see.
I hope they don't,
none of nobody plays this farm cause
I'm going to see them because not only I
respect him as an artist, but I also,
it's, I'm afraid they're gonna die,
you know? Uh, I don't want to
jinx anybody, but you know,
they are our even you just want to
see before they quit touring, right.
Everyone from Tony
Bennett to Stevie wonder
to Bob Newhart to Morton Downey jr right.
I'm joking. I already saw him and he's
dead. All right, let's plow ahead.
I think I got to do a read
for the week here. Um,
why don't I do the read and I'll be
singing the melody to one. I need. Love,
Delilah. Shaky.
Hello.
Lots of play.
I'll be spotting playoff bits
now that the poles seasons here,
leaf.
I can't do the whole thing that to the
pros kickoffs a year the right way with a
fresh blade shave.
That's why me and millions of others
have joined the dollar Shave club.com
Revolution Dollar Shave Club knows that
the key to getting an amazing shape is
simple. One,
use a fresh dollar shave club
blade to use their fucking doctors.
Ca Bzz shape
that said,
those shake club delivers amazing razors
right to my door for a third of the
price of those greedy
mega razor corporations.
That means listeners who switch now
can afford the luxury of shaving with a
fresh blade anytime and save
hundreds this year. And uh,
what do you combine the
fresh blade? Any what you do,
if you really want to feel like a rich
guy is get one of those barbershop chairs
and fucking lay back in it and have one
of your drunk friends shave your face
for you. Don't have them go
up. You'll get ingrown hairs.
And when you combine that fresh blade
with the doctor cabbies easy seat,
it just glides. It's
like lube for your face.
It's unimaginably smooth.
Uh, I'm telling you,
it's not the average shamed shave
foam. It won't dry out your skin.
The all natural ingredients.
Leave your skin feeling soft,
smooth and moisturize after
every shave. Take it from me.
Use a fresh dollar shave club,
bay blade with doctor cabbies.
Easy shave butter if you want to.
The most gentle shave imaginable.
Joined the dollar shave
club.com/bird revolution today.
That's dollar shave club.com/bar
hi
dollar shave club.com/
[inaudible] all right, legal zoom.
All right,
before another year pass is take the time
to get your life organized with legal
zoom. This is what I've been
doing. Do you have a family?
Do you have any assets of property?
If any of those answers are yes,
you should have an estate plan.
Fuck you, man. I already did this.
This is for other people. Uh, don't
worry if that sounds complicated.
Legal Zoom can help. Yes,
they can. Legal zooms.
Estate Plan Bundles eliminates the
guesswork. Yes, they do. This is,
this is a personal testimony.
You don't have to figure out on your
own whether a will or living trucks.
Trust works better, best for you. Instead,
you work with an independent
attorney available in most states.
They'll walk you through your options
and recommend an estate plan that offers
the best solution to fit your needs.
You know, it's funny, you know,
if it's not available in your state,
they don't think your state's cool.
There's not enough fucking
for them to make money on.
Like if you're out there and wow,
wow, I think I'm doing a Gig.
They're coming up and Cheyenne, I've got
a gig coming up in Denver. All right?
They'll walk you through your options
and recommend an estate plan that offers
the best solution that fits your needs.
Since legal zoom is not a law firm,
you can count on the F
on efficiency and value.
Everything is your schedule in your terms.
Plus you'll know what your estate plan
bundles costs upfront instead of worrying
about hourly rates.
That's how legal zoom has become the
lead in helping small business owners and
families with great, with their
legal, with their legal needs.
You get legal help and
walk away feeling great.
There's the great that I was
looking at a fucking line below.
Get your life organized with an estate
plan bundle@legalzoom.com today.
Don't forget to enter, burn the
referral box at checkout that code.
That's code bar@legalzoom.com.
All right, there we go. And
that's the end of the reads. Uh,
what did I just want to talk
about? Something in there
reminded me of something.
Oh yeah, the fucking, I'm going to be
going to Denver when I go to Denver.
They're either going to be super bowl
champions or they're going to be depressed
that they lost,
but they're probably still going to
give me shit that they beat my patriots.
But I've got to tell you this,
man, this is pretty cool.
Do you know Denver's the only team,
the New England patriots
have a losing record too.
And I know a lot of you
guys love fucking Denver,
and I'm actually thinking like,
I can't believe that's true because I
watched the Patriots before Tom Brady.
All right?
And I think there was very few people
that we had a winning record against.
And the fact that, uh,
who's kidding who bill Bellacheck came
in with drew Bledsoe and that really
started turning shit around and, um,
just the way that they've won over this
since like 2000 or 2001 by really like
the last 20 years, the way
they've won, they were, let's see,
20, 35, they were 35 years or 35,
33 years in or 32 years in when drew
Bledsoe took over and drew Bledsoe took
over 24 years ago. So, you know,
that's what it took.
It took two and a half decades to undo
fucking three decades of fucking up.
And, um, I think that's amazing. Now
you're probably going, well, why,
why the fuck? What are the Broncos doing?
You always got to play in that
altitude. It was always snowing.
And then they had Craig Morton and
the orange crushed defense in the 70s.
And, uh, I think before that they had
that Floyd little great running back,
Randy gradish shack, um, Hayven Moses,
Rick up church there. They
always had some fucking guys.
And then they got John Elway in 83
and that fucked after Craig Morton,
they went, you know,
a few years and then 83 Elway came
in and that fucked us from 83 to 98.
So even when we had drew Bledsoe
for the first fucking six,
seven years, it was against, uh,
John Elway who's like top three all
time, I think, you know what I mean? Um,
I'd actually put him ahead
of a Peyton, Manny, um,
personally, personally speaking. Um,
so I'm actually excited that there's
32 fucking teams were one of them.
So up the 31 other teams, 30 of them,
we had a winning record against.
Can anybody else make that claim? I
don't think they can. All right, sorry.
So Anybody Watch, AH, 60 minutes.
This past week they did a, um,
they did this feature Phagia on mountain
lions and now California is the only
state that has mountain lions.
Just walking around. I, I'm
gonna fuck this up in a,
in a park,
I guess maybe the size of like
Griffith Park or Runyon Canyon or,
or whatever those ones are out in, uh,
out in the valley. I guess they have
these fucking things. And, um, so anyways,
I was watching it because a few of the
places was where I hike with my dog and
this thing has intermittently, this, this,
this group of fucking mountain
lions has been around there.
But fortunately they, they
try to avoid you I guess, um,
at least during the day if then I fucking
hungry. But they showed this fucking,
uh, these people, this
mountain lion, right, okay.
They were having some work done.
So they had somebody going underneath
the house into the crawl space of their
house and they were right
up against this park.
And the guy went down there
and he immediately came
back up and he was fucking
like white as a ghost and they
were like a don de s, you know,
fucking white people turn to
speak Spanish three Oh eight. Um,
is it French? I don't know. Um,
and a guy comes out of the fucking hole
and was like, yeah, man, I fucking, uh,
there's a mountain lion down there. I
just came faced and I get outta here.
You shy.
I asked that and they
will let, he's like, yeah,
it's fucking down there.
And, and so anyways,
they interview this fucking La couple and
they are the quintessential fucking la
couple, you know what I mean? He looks
like the leading man of a B movie,
right? She's got like bleach blonde
hair. She's wearing fuck me pumps.
She's on 60 minutes. Where in fuck
me pumps. It's fucking hilarious.
Walking around, done up
to the nines. And um,
I actually, uh, was pretty cool. I was
trying to figure out where the house was.
I Google mapped it and I
think I was able to find it.
But um,
fuck this state is so fucking
insane with the droughts, the fires,
the rattlesnakes, the coyotes,
the mountain lines, you know,
and everybody's in this place is so
phony and so plastic. Well, you know,
it can get, uh, that can all go away
pretty damn quick with the wildlife.
It's sort of like a fucking
Australia light, like super light.
You know what I mean? As I
was throwing that out there,
I just heard everybody
down there all flow.
Give me a fucking brain of flipping
out about how dangerous their fucking,
you know, how dangerous Australia is.
Let me tell you something right now.
There's no fucking snakes in
Sydney, Australia. All right?
There's all that shit's in the
middle of their fucking country.
Every where there's
some at the zoo, right?
Every once in a while you'll see
somebody you know goes to pick up a snake
thinking it's a garden snake.
He goes fucking bit and that goes jogging
and it racist through his veins and he
fucking dies. Yes, that does happen. But
you know, people don't, you know what?
Let's, let's actually, let's
look up some stats here.
Let's go to the stats here cause I don't
think you're going to hear enough stats
between now and the Super Bowl, you know,
is that as they sell the game layup
start new talent cab note and whether his
whole career ahead of them cover it up
against the Lally lance on the plate and
LATIC though went to Germany
and God knows what happened,
but he's not on the patriot.
So ESPN is not gonna cover it.
Um, I'm not, I don't even think
he did anything, but you know,
but the accusation was out
there. I mean it came from algae.
Xera I mean who knows more
about NFL football than Algiers?
Z Al Jazeera.
All right, what was, what the
fuck was I looking up? Alright.
Okay.
Snake by death.
And Australia comes right up.
This is all touristy shit. Like,
am I going to die if I go
down there? Snake bite debts,
2015 list of fatal snake
bites in Australia.
Gotta love the Internet. I'm not
saying the information is right,
but they always have an answer.
All right, snake bite. Dell,
east eastern Brown snake is responsible
for about 60% of deaths caused by snake
bite in Australia. All right?
Is the numbers the 2000 tens?
All right. Uh, in 2015, there was one,
one brown snake or tie pant.
The species is unconfirmed. You know why?
Because the snake left
didn't hang out like Yo,
I did that shit like the little found
as a snake. You get it. I'm sorry.
Um, in 2014, there was two a right?
That's big, bad, dangerous fucking
Australia. Let's check out the u s
okay.
Where then the fuck love
United State's
list of fatal sneak bites in the
u s all we got to do is be one.
One ties it and it goes in overtime
and the 2010,
whoa, we crushed them. One, two, three,
four, go fuck yourself.
Australia, Paula Herald,
wall forest,
39 year old female, a
green, Mojave rattlesnake,
Russell Lee Davis, 39. Jesus 39 was
an unlucky year. Timber rattlesnake.
You want to hear the story?
Dave was sitting around the fire at his
family's camp when he was bitten by a
rattlesnake. Jesus Christ. In the balls
right in front of his whole family.
He was taken to the hospital and from
there air lifted to the a Pittsburgh area
hospital. While on route,
the helicoptered Davis
suffered a cardiac arrest.
Jesus Grant Thompson 18 male.
Yeah,
a Cobra. Who the fuck has a cobra?
He got hit by a car.
Wayne Thompson was found unresponsible
in his car in North Austin.
Lowe's in North Austin, and
a low store parking lot.
How the fuck do you get
by a monocled Cobra? Oh,
it's got the one fucking glass
on it too. What little I grass?
Because I said it was evil like it's
a James Bond villain. All right.
It's a Colbert species, which
is widespread across the
south and Southeast Asia.
Oh Jesus. Somebody fucking ordered one.
A Monaco Cobra that he was known to own,
was missing and was
later found dead nearby.
Haven't been run over by a car.
Wait a minute, I, I'm sorry. We got,
we got to get to the bottom
of this fucking story.
So this fucking kid
ordered a Goddamn Cobra.
Wait a minute.
Do one of these people gonna
fucking La. Let me, let me, let's,
let's not get crazy here. Let's, let's
find out what happened to this kid.
Jesus Christ. Greer Thompson
grant t h o M.
Thompson Cobra. Alright.
Grant Thompson committed
suicide by allowing a Cobra.
Okay.
This is the most, this can't be true.
Suicide by Snape by question mark.
Is this click big?
Okay.
I was going to say this kid looks just
like Lance Bass and it was actually
clickbait on the side.
Says Lance Bass shows us the most
expensive item from his wedding registry.
Isn't that a little disrespectful
to have next to this kid? All right,
so the kids sitting here,
okay.
What the parrot from one of his, uh,
like one of those Beretta parrots,
police,
Texas teen's death after he leaves
a cryptic message on Facebook.
The decks death of a Texas teen who was
killed after being bitten by a Cobra
last Tuesday is being
investigated as a suicide.
Austin police confirm to people.
Is this people magazine? Yeah,
they're in deeper into
what people are doing.
Grant Thompson was found unresponsible
inside his car and a Lowe's parking lot
last week with puncture wounds to his
wrist and a snake cage beside him.
Yeah.
KWTX reports. He was discovered surrounded
by a large, by a number of animals,
including a non venomous snake.
Six tarantulas in a frog,
but as pet cobra was missing,
this was in his fucking car.
Thompson was rushed to blah, blah,
blah, or he later died. Yeah,
I don't think in Austin they're going to
have shit for a cobra unless they got a
zoo nearby rang. It was
located above. Above.
Police believe that Thompson committed
suicide by allowing the venomous snake to
bite them. Surely before
he was found Tuesday,
the team posted a cryptic message to
his Facebook page. Writing, I'm sorry.
Thompson's family owns a
pet shot in temple, Texas.
He'd worked for the
store most of his life.
He could handle tarantulas
like they were kittens.
He loved the animals and loves
spreading awareness about animals in the
community. NAHB Saatchi
was performed Thursday,
but authorities at waiting
for the toxin. What the fuck?
Jesus do that as hardcore. Do you
have you heard those things that
there is nothing like the hiss of a
fucking reptile and that fucking reptilian
look like what are the look are
they going to have in their face?
How is Lance Baz reverse aging?
Jesus Christ fucking teeth of like,
does he even eat anything? His teeth
are like brand new, like out of the box.
Um, all right. I think it's time
to wrap this up. Wrap it up.
I'll take it. Um,
wait a minute. Where the fuck am I here?
Where's the rest of this shit? Ah,
Jesus Christ. Bill. What are you doing?
All right. And that's not it.
Is this it? That's not it.
That's a shit about my will.
I don't know what this is and I don't
know where a very maybe with everything
went. I give up. Oh, fuck it. Anyways,
that's the end of the
podcast. Jesus Christ.
Mike and Dolan says to
anybody knew that kid holy.
You know what are the odds for this?
No Way. He was covered for that, huh?
And your fucking insurance.
Accidental death accidentally getting
bit by a Cobra and the wrist in the
parking lot of a Lowe's
in Austin, Texas. All,
all right. Anyways, that's the podcast.
I hope you guys have a great weekend
and stay away from the snakes.
So you know what Australia,
alright, that was deliberate.
So we can't count that one. So we, we uh,
we had three times as
many deaths as you did.
So why don't you tone down how fucking
nuts you stayed as or your country,
whatever it is. Right island, you know,
it's not that fucking
dangerous. You know what it is.
We buy into it because of the fucking,
uh, the shrimp on the Barbie guy,
Paul Hogan and then the
crocodile hunter. You know,
and when you really think about it,
how did the crocodile hunter die?
Was it one of those snakes that
he was constantly fucking with?
Was it any other, the land animals
that he was constantly fucking with?
It was not,
he fucked with the sting ray and he
forgot that those things always are armed.
They always have a shank.
He got stuck right,
like a fucking prisoner. Um,
as enough time gone by that you can
actually address the foolishness of that
death. Like, let me fucking go. Just
jump on the back of a sting ray.
You know, and I'm not talking
about the corvette people,
I'm talking about the actual fucking fish.
Where do you job boasting raid?
You gotta Watch that tail a
little stab you in the heart.
You swim to the surface and police out.
I'm sorry. Anyways, that's, that's the
podcast for this Thursday afternoon.
Have a wonderful weekend you cards. Um,
my condolences to their kid in the Lowe's
parking lot into the crocodile hunter,
even to Paul Hogan. You know,
I don't know what he's up to.
I hope he's got a new hat though,
you know, nice new, fresh head. Um,
and with that,
here's a little bit of music from
Andrew [inaudible] and a little bit of
throwback podcasts
from a, from a year ago.
[inaudible]
I'm not crazy like my brother,
but it's where the
Achoo whoever this auto,
I know Brown with the session when I
got Gamblin who is what y'all bread,
man, mom, all that. I was that positive
and that wasn't a
[inaudible].
That is, it built a bit of a
dilemma here for you. I'm an
18 year old male who is about to graduate
from high school. Congratulations.
Um, over the past few years I've
been told I'm a really good dancer.
Not Ballet or artsy stuff, but
just good dance floor dancing.
Oh my God, I'm going to take
over the dance floor. Hey Angie,
watch me your John
Travolta. This is great.
Do you go out to the a Staten island
bridge and do headstands with your,
with your buddy Bobby? You
know, if he didn't have an Afro,
he never would've fell off that
bridge if he had it high and tight.
Like all these Armenians out here, all,
every Armenian looks like they know, uh,
they, they know m m m m a moose.
Last time you saw in our Armenian
dude in his twenties or thirties,
and he did not look like he could put
you in an armbar within two seconds if he
wanted to.
If I W if I was Dana white and I was
running the UFC at one point that this
point, what are up to like what,
like UFC 2006 you know,
they're like running, they've run out
of adjectives this time. It's really,
really personal, right? Not Saying
I'm not a fan of a huge fucking fan,
I'm just saying, you know, the way they,
they have those things like every other
week there's only so many like you know,
redemption. I mean you've
run out of words. Um,
I'm such a fucking idiot.
This is what I would do if I was dating
white at some point I would have,
you know, you know what I would,
this is what I would branch off.
And when they had those
tough man competitions and
they would have just people
coming in, throwing haymakers,
which is some of the best boxing ever
is when you watch people who just aren't
trained whatsoever and
they just start, you know,
cause somebody is going to connect. Right.
I think that they should have one week
they should have the Armenians versus the
Russians. Tough man competition.
Because I really think that that needs,
it needs to be decided who is
the tougher of the two? Uh,
cause more now when it comes
to white people, that's,
that's who I got my money
on. All right. That, those,
those are the crips and the bloods of
white people is the army and the Russians,
all of them, they just have that vibe.
This something you just like, yeah.
I'm not fucking with that guy. Just
really, I'm really not doing it anyways.
Uh, not a ballet or artsy stuff. Uh,
but just ballroom dates in a
full contagion over here. Uh,
I kinda think of think dancing is
gay from an outside point of view.
Um, I it isn't, it really isn't.
That's just how white people look at it.
It's considered gay cause it involves
like letting yourself go and actually
admitting that you have emotions as a
man, as a white male. Yeah. It's, yeah,
it is. It's considered gay. Um,
as is crying,
as is showing any sort of emotion as
is not dying for no good goddamn reason
before you're 56. I'm
not dying, I should say.
If you live to be 60, I believe amongst
white men, that's also considered gay.
Cause that means at some point you cried
something out of your chest and you
didn't have a heart attack. Um,
anyways, he says, I think, uh,
dancing is gay from an
outside point of view,
but I'll be the first one to admit that
I'm actually a pretty good dancer if I
didn't think so, I wouldn't be out
there doing it. Yeah. But Dude,
you gotta be getting some, I'll, I'll
fucking, women love a guy who can dance.
If you can dance and you're wearing
like a silk scarf, it's fucking over.
It's going to be rain and pussy.
As far as my outside view,
my freckled view from over in the bar
trying to stand out from underneath those
hot lights so I don't
get burned. Uh, you know,
red heads with the closest
thing to vampires. You know,
we have, we, we have none
of the powers of vampires,
but the sun affects us the same.
Okay.
A friend of mine who is a female dead
keeps telling me I could make money doing
it on commercials or music
videos, parentheses clothes on.
Or You could go to fucking Broadway and
be like one of the five straight men who
dances on Broadway and just tag every
fucking lonely chick out there who's all
stretched out. Just make
sure you keep their shoes on.
Dancer's feet are always fucked up.
Uh, here's where it gets complicated.
I plan on becoming a policeman. Oh
Dude, this is, this is a no brainer.
You need the dance it Bachelorette parties
dressed as a cop. All you need, dude,
is that a fake uniform on a boombox
and you're on your way to making money?
Dude, you should fucking
do that in a second.
And then you write a book about it.
I was a gyrate and cop
for Bachelorette parties.
You write a tell all book
about how many fucking broads,
who bought ready got married, go
get married, sucked your Dick.
You really need help on this one. I
mean I'm going to read the rest of it,
but I think I've already come
with the solution anyways.
How is anyone supposed to take
me seriously on the force?
If there's a video going with me,
pop and locking next to little
Wayne at the same time, I'll, dude,
you should fucking pull people over.
You should pull people over and fucking
moonwalk up to their car and just freak
them out. Even if they
were reaching for a gun,
they'd be laughing too hard and
they, they, they wouldn't shoot you.
Then you could rest them and then
you move up. Next thing you know,
you're a commissioner, right?
Nothing. Anyways, at the same time,
I'm getting laid a lot because of
it. Of course you are. I'm a seven.
On a scale of 10. I like this
guy. He's honest and um, uh,
and like having a jumpshot, it's
put me up to an eight, five,
um, Bang, intense. I've always
wanted to be a cop at the parks here.
Seen better. If I was able to make
money doing it over in a dancing thing,
I wouldn't just be getting hammers
for letting gross moms off on speeding
tickets. I could be banging
J-lo. She's into dancers, right?
Thanks. Yeah. APP's a fucking lutely dude.
You're basically saying,
what should I do here?
Should I bang j Lo's beat down at the
club and make all this fucking money?
Or should I take a job where I'm going
to get shot at and not be appreciated?
You know, I'll tell you every cop
out there with dance, if they could,
as opposed to being a cop, I don't care
if they'd like seven generations in.
Dude, this is what I think of as
far as like dancing. I think if I,
if I like compare it to
being a comedian, oh,
the open mics would be getting a piece
of part cardboard and being on a subway
platform, making money that way.
And then when you move up to hosting a
show that would be addressed as a cop and
you fucking dance it. Bachelorette
parties, that's what you do on the side.
That's like your fucking day job. That
bullshit. And then during the day, I,
yeah, I would try out
for those. Fuck, I don't,
did they make music videos
anymore or fucking, uh,
I dunno. I believe it or not. I don't
know how to climb the ladder as a dancer,
but dude,
apps a fucking lutely if you
could make money doing that shit.
And then what the great thing is, is
once you get to a certain level to, to,
uh, make more money, you know, once
you've got some credibility, you can,
you always have the fallback where
you can teach your class. They can,
you can be like,
I danced for nine years and Chitty
Chitty Bang Bang and fucking banged every
fucking broad on there.
And then if you'd like to know how to
fuck the women in your cast while still
not losing your job, come on down the
Frankie's fucking data studio or whatever,
just you'll figure it out as
you go in there. And, um, yeah,
absolutely. Absolute fucking
Lulea. I would definitely do it.
You want to do what you want
and taking the time, um,
to write in. So your big fears should
be whatever, everybody's big fears.
Like what if I fucking go after this
dream and I'm 30 and I'm sleeping on a
fucking futon and it hasn't happened yet.
Well, I gotta tell you something, sir.
I'd been there. I was there at fucking 34.
I was still sleeping on a futon and a
fucking studio apartment that they call
the one bedroom,
cause they slammed a fucking wall
in there and put a door on it.
And then one day I was trying to bang
the girl upstairs who had the fucking
apartment, right, right, right above
me. And it was the exact same unit.
And hers was a studio,
but she had been there longer so
they never slammed a wall in there.
And I realized, Hey, wait a minute,
I'm getting fucked. You know,
I should go down there and try to
get some money taken off of this.
I should go down to the A, they're fucking
me over rental board. But I didn't,
I said, fuck it. Just keep
writing jokes. Right. So whatever
all you gotta do, you just gotta
commit to this shit. And, uh,
and then realized that, you know,
sleep on Futon when you're 30 is
not the worst thing. It isn't.
You don't see what, you know, it's
worse than sleeping on Futon at 30,
sleeping in a king bed next to a fucking
woman you're not really love with,
but for some reason and a,
you've got a couple of kids and you've
got a job that you fucking hate. Okay?
You'll be laying there fantasizing about
fucking sleeping on a, on a, on a, uh,
on a futon there.
There's no risk when you go after
a dream, it's all fucking reward.
It's all gonna lead to
something good. It always does.
There's a tremendous amount of
risk to playing it safe and uh,
that leads to unbelievable
levels of regret,
which is something else I've also
experienced. Cause I'm an old man.
[inaudible]
no man. Cross
[inaudible] to and
say
down. This is titled the frayed
break up with girlfriend.
You Man, I'm gonna read slow.
So this takes up as much time
as possible. Hey Bill. Um,
I'd like to get your advice on something.
I've been dating my girlfriend for
almost a year now and I've been thinking
about breaking up with her. Well,
it's time to break up with her, sir.
All right. And dating her for a year.
You know you have to still even
thinking about breaking Ed's time.
Okay.
I says we get along fine and we rarely
argue. I was just thinking of a great,
a great way to break up with someone
they should invent like a breakup suit,
right?
Just something where you just cannot get
injured and you just put the thing on
with the fucking helmet.
You don't wear the helmet,
you just put the ones he'd zip up on
and which totally protects everything.
Right? And then you get in the passenger
seat and you let her drive. Oh,
why are you gonna let me drive?
Why did you just drive tonight?
But you always liked to drive
honey. You just drive. Okay,
why are you wearing that suit? It's all
going to make sense at about five miles,
right?
You get out on the fucking highway and
you just start talking to her and out of
no way. He just put the helmet on, you
know, when she says, what are you doing?
And just say, listen, I don't
want to go out with you anymore.
And then she goes, what?
And you go, hey, watch this.
And he just opened the door and you
roll out of the fucking car. That's it.
You're out. You know, type
up the fake police report.
You tell him that you died,
then she feels bad for you.
You don't have to deal with any sort
of repercussions. Um, anyways, he says,
we get along fine and we rarely argue,
but I'm starting to realize I don't
really want to be with her for the long
haul. When we started dating,
oh, this fucking thing.
These iPads suck by the way. All
right. You know what an iPad is?
It's fucking laptop for pussies. What's
the matter? Your laptop is too heavy.
You fucking douchebag this thing doesn't
have a keyboard. It's got nothing.
You think that they don't know how to
make this thing into a fucking laptop
already. Of course they do.
This is the Steve jobs way of doing things
rather than just giving you the whole
fucking thing.
He's going to give you an intro
increments like a God damn drug dealer.
You know? That's why I haven't bought one
of these yet. This is Nias by the way,
borrowed this fucking thing
and I am not enjoying it.
As you can tell as I'm throwing a
temper tan from here. You know what?
I'm going to buy a fucking iPad. I'm
going to buy it when it is a laptop,
when it is a little light
laptop. Until then I'm not,
I'm not having this
fucking this. This is like,
this is like when you know you go,
I know I really want to get the new
Camaro and then you get the one with the v
six engine rather than getting the
full out one with the stick shift,
which is a laptop, right.
It's too heavy, you know,
fucking deuce. Do Shoulders at the
gym next time you do that. Okay.
Maybe do that. Maybe to do some stuff
to build up your risks. Oh God. Bill.
Can you get through the question?
All write a well, um, he says, uh,
when we first started dating,
I loved hanging out with her,
but I'm just not into it anymore. Does
that make me an asshole? No, it doesn't.
Why would your own true feelings
make you an Asshole, sir?
How awful were your parents? Um, he
says, I'm 23 years old with a somewhat,
why am I, you know, I'm a
really being a cunt this week.
This guy's him for my advice. Let's
try to bring the anger down. Bill,
you're frustrated. It's
fucking hot in here.
You can't open the window
because you say cunt too much.
This building's a co op and
they'll kick you up. Okay.
That's what's going on here. It has
nothing to do with this person. Okay?
Why don't you just try to be a nice guy
so I should've done off the Mike like
I'm scolding myself. Just
try to be a nice guy.
Let's not take out your bad
day on everyone else. Okay?
You're embarrassing me.
All right. I'm 23 years old,
but somewhat of a decent job and really
just want to go back to being single for
a while. Exactly. Dude,
you're 23 years old, dude.
You're fucking movie star at that age.
I don't care what you're doing for a
living. Should definitely be single.
I said, the problem is
she's got a lot less,
she's got a lot of stress in her
life right now. Not your problem.
She's finishing nursing school and
trying to find a job. All right,
well tell her to put on the outfit
Banger one more time and hey, watch this.
You bail out of the car.
That's mean. Um, anyways.
He says, oh, and she has a history
of depression over the past year.
I feel like she is becoming
emotionally dependent on me.
Like I'm keeping her going or
something. Well, Jesus Christ the one.
Do you want to get rid of
her? You don't want this.
You know,
you want something that someone
that's gonna be fun to be around.
You don't want her, you know,
it's sunny out and she's like,
it's raining out the fucking
head under the pillow.
One of these days, you know,
he stayed with that long enough one
these days you just gonna it's going to
smother with that pillow. So anyways,
so how do I go about breaking up with
her while causing the least amount of
damage? Uh,
he said also she always leaves some
of her shit in my apartment. Yes.
Cause she's, she wants to fucking
Oh yeah, she's calling an idea.
You says clothes, blanket.
Other random shit.
I tried to get her to
take a shit home with her,
but how do I avoid after the after
breakup coming over to get my stuff?
I hate that. Anyway. Go
Fuck Yourself. All right,
look,
there's no way. There's no easy way
to break up with somebody. All right.
There's just easier ways. Uh,
the sooner the better. Um,
oh Diane, I'll do this is, this
is like dismantling a bomb.
So you know what you would like to do
is say, Hey, can you come by today?
I want to talk to you about something.
Right. And she always share.
I'll be right over and then
immediately just take out a box,
put all over shit in it. Tape it up
and then she rings the Bell Bing Bomb.
You Open the door, you get, yeah,
don't want to date you anymore.
And he just handed the box
and close the door right
to there's money to be made in this man.
Does anybody have a professional breakup
service at such a pussy thing to do?
But that would be phenomenal.
You know, you feel,
you make your person
feel like they got fired.
You're like what a corporation fires you
and just two security people show up,
you know,
confiscate your computer and then escort
you out of the building when that'd be
great. Do, that's what you should do.
Just hire two of your friends to dress up.
Like security guards. Tell her
you want to break up, you know.
And then they have all their shit
in the box. Then they escort,
escort or right out of your apartment
building. Like she got fired.
They come off as professional
rather than like personal. Um,
how do you go about breaking up with
it? You know what I would do? Um,
I wouldn't put all this shit in the box
cause that's going to come off cold,
you know, and you don't want to hurt
her feelings like that. So I would just,
uh, uh, fuck it. I don't know.
I don't know how to do it.
Why did I drink last night? And
then I got up and did open Anthony,
what the fuck is wrong with me? I
knew I had a podcast to do. Yeah,
he embarrassing. Um, I don't know.
Fucking no. Have a come over
and just say listen. Um,
I'm not happy. Oh, that's a great
one. That's a classic. You know,
like if you were a singer songwriter
the second you said that the whole crowd
would start applauding,
recognizing the big hip.
Well, of all the girls I do before, you
know, they all start fucking clapping.
You know, if they just came out, you
just did classic breakup monologues.
Listen, um, I'm just not happy everyone,
just that smattering of applause.
You wait for it to die down. Let
the orchestra come around again.
She jumped back in on the one, um, match.
Tell you're not happy. I'm
not happy anymore. And Dude,
let me tell you something. Her being
depressed is not your fucking problem.
Alright? Her being depressed
is the fucking problem.
How can you do this to me?
What do you mean? How can I do this
to you? You don't want be wars.
If I fucking stayed with you and I didn't
love you, I don't love you anymore.
I don't love you. Depressed whore.
I just called you a whore as a
generic term. You know, I don't, I'm,
I'm not happy I want out, okay? I just
feel like I want to be single right now.
I just don't feel like I'm going
to be with you in long haul. Uh,
we'll just be wasting each other's time.
My time is important and so is yours.
All right? I don't want to go
anymore, but I'll tell you what.
If you go to stamps.com they'll
give you $55 free stamps at a scale.
That's what you do. Just tag every mean
thing you say with all the advertising.
You know, if you go to amazon.com
through bill burrows website, you know,
click on the Little Amazon banner,
whatever you buy, you know,
portion of that money goes back to bill
burn and then the percentage of that
goes to the wounded warrior project.
So I know I'm breaking up with
you right now, but you could,
we could also support the troops,
right,
sir? Look, there's no
fucking easy way to do this.
And you're going to be sitting
there. How many more holidays?
How many more birthdays? How many more
Christmases, which is a holiday? Sorry,
you always need three examples. Do you
want to go through with this person?
How many more times do you want to go
out and rent bikes? Go to a picnic,
sit there on a sunny day.
Is she sitting there with that
cloud over her fucking head?
You know,
dude, you know, don't do that yourself.
You want to fucking people who have just
wonderful human beings and they just
end up with assholes. I
swear to God, assholes.
They look for wonderful
human beings because other
assholes are not going to put
up with them. You know, so you need to
be an asshole here at, you know, the,
the how society looks as an, as an
asshole. Like you're being selfish,
not being selfish. All
right? Choose yourself.
Choose your own fucking life
dumper you get on with your life.
You know,
this is what you do.
You get yourself a six,
a fucking Pale Ale or
whatever beer you like.
You stick a couple of glasses
in the fucking freezer.
All right?
Like anticipation of this championship
that you know you're gonna win. You know,
like they did the red sox dugout when
they had the champagne on ice and game six
in 1986 before they had to
quickly wheel it out, okay?
Except you're not going to let
this one go through your leg, sir.
You kicking this one, right?
The client and you'd taken home the
fucking championship and when it's over,
all you gotta be just thinking about
those frosty fucking bruise in the fridge.
Just think about that. Just look at
the clock when she walks in. All right.
Let's say she comes in at 10
past two. Just say to yourself,
worst case scenario by three fucking 30,
I'm going to be sitting down on
this fucking couch. All right.
With my goddamn phone off,
drinking a couple of five
or six of these things
and then that's it. All right. Okay.
And then don't fucking
have a post breakup sex.
Don't do that. Cause then she'll
think that you're back together again.
Fuck all of that. All right. Your
mind just see got to come back.
Yeah, my staff. Okay. When
do you want to come by?
This is coming off really cold.
She's going to do all of that and just
try to keep dragging you back into the
fucking thing. Um,
I dunno if this is a punk thing to
do, but after you break up with her,
just don't answer the phone when she
calls and then she'll find, just say,
listen, I gotta I gotta come by and
get my stuff. Can you text her back?
I fucking just be a man. What does
she going to do? Body Slam you.
She's just going to make
you feel bad. All right.
[inaudible] is it you
little blue? You would.
No, it's cause you're a mopey.
You're sucking the life out of me.
You know when, when you get
that sad look on your face,
you look like a muppet
there. I said it all right.
There's your shit over
there in the corner.
I've got a couple of cool ones in the
fridge, so why don't you do me a favor.
All right, get over there
Ben down. Lift what you need.
Get your shit and get the fuck out of
here. What do you say that touch? Yep.
Prince Jarman is out there somewhere.
You know and ain't here.
I'm not riding that horse anymore. Okay?
I just shot it in the back of the head.
It's over. Okay, so why don't
you trudge on out of here?
They're fucking Cinderella.
Go look in a mirror.
Go climb up in a tower and
fucking drop your hair out.
Whatever the fuck you
supposed to do. Kiss a frog.
All right. I got drinking to
do, but I don't want to bait it.
Something like that.
Like I said, all that bullshit.
I said 10 past two which over by
three 30 by three 30 at Busan.
All right. I don't know
now the fucking brutal breaking
up to something as brutal, brutal,
just awfulness at this
five minute podcast.
But other than that
[inaudible] [inaudible]
I've been all over the map politically,
but it's why like, you know,
certain ways of looking at shit,
like when people talk about guns,
like let's just make them what? Let's
just make them illegal and then no,
we all have them. You know,
like that sort of like
thought process is your,
you're acting as though the world is a
utopia and that there's not morons and
that there's not, uh, people who say,
I don't give a fuck what the rules are.
You're totally not even taking
into consideration sociopath,
which is why that new fucking
thing that Obama signed,
that whole defense package where now they
can just arrest people without a trial
Jay and put you in jail forever with,
without a trial because they just
think you're a fucking terrorist.
You can't give people that level of power.
I'm a fucking moron. And I know
you can't do that. Historically,
no one has ever handled
that level of power. Well,
anybody here want to go live in China?
Now we out there practicing your nunchucks
wearing your wooden slippers and all
of a sudden a van pulls up and you
disappear and that's it forever.
You want to live there?
Of course you don't.
You want to live here where they can't
fucking do it. Well, they can do it now.
You know? They just put in a fucking
order for a bunch of black fans.
That's what I heard. According to Holy
shit.com that's what's going down.
I don't understand why stuff at that
level that affects citizens to that level.
Why we don't get to vote on it.
Do you think it's because we'd
say, Hey, you know what? Fuck that.
Do you understand like that
is just a jump off point.
Do you think like that's just how it's
going to stall as though you're not a
terrorist there, you ain't
going to fucking problem.
You think it's just
going to stop with that.
That's not how you take away freedom.
You don't just fucking do it all in
one fell swoop. It's incremental.
It's just like when you're dating some
fucking woman and you're not paying
attention and she just gradually, every
day takes another foot of real estate.
Next thing you know you're
in goal line d going,
how the fuck did I end
up in this situation?
We started at the 50 little push little
pole, right? Everything was fine.
Next know you're up against the Golan.
The you think that they're just going
to keep it with the terrorist thing,
you know?
You know they'll wait for a whole nother
generation of babies to be born and
they always grew up with government having
that level of power and then they add
something else to it. Then they
had something else. Then that's it.
You can't have it. Okay.
If Tiger Woods can't handle the
level of free pussy on a golf tour,
how the fuck is our government going
to handle a new defense package,
which basically gave a mute
button when you love the egg,
how would you handle that if
you had that power, do you,
how long before you just
started abusing that?
If you could just hit mute on anybody who
ever disagreed with you and then just,
and you could have them whisked away.
Okay.
I mean, that is the sociopath's
wet dream. That's what that is.
That is a fucking mute button, Mr Style.
And don't you think that's it? He hit
mute. You're done. You're gone. See Ya.
I think it's, it's
fucking insane. And I'm,
the only thing that I get out of it is
that I feel like I was proven correct
that I don't think it
matters at that level.
Whether you vote Democrat or Republican
Obama, the first black president ever,
you would think this would
be the most liberal, uh,
politician in the history of this country
because of his background. You would
think that he signed off on that shit.
Okay.
All right. I'm telling you, I don't know
what happens when you become president,
but I think they let you peek just
enough behind the curtain and you there,
there was a fucking agenda that we
are moving towards because it does,
I don't think of fucking
matters. I really don't,
which is why I always
vote for the Ralph Nater,
the fucking Ron Paul,
all those guys that all those fucking
idiots go to cause you did that.
You've ruined the election. Really? Did I?
I feel like those guys wouldn't
have signed shit like that.
I feel like their track record shows
that they would not sign shit like that.
I don't know. I have no, I imagine I'm
going to get a ton of fucking emails.
I'm almost,
somebody was yelling at me one time saying
that because I voted for Ralph Nader
in 2000 that's why George W.
Bush won and they was just going on
and on and on about it. And I was like,
dude, I live in New York.
Al Gore won my state.
Okay. Do you understand that?
So your whole fucking theory
right now is out the window.
I voted for Ralph Nader in New York
and Al Gore still won the state.
So go fuck yourself. What?
I'm trying to do a mister
fucking red and blue tie here.
I'm trying to fucking encourage
more people like that to vote.
So mission accomplished. That's what I'm
trying to fuck and have to vote to run,
you know
uncorruptible how far can you get if
you're uncorruptible I would say that you
could get to the uh,
okay.
Whatever level politics is when you
decide whether or not they should put a
gazebo in the center of town. I
think beat. Once you get beyond that,
you gotta you gotta be
a little dirty. Right.
I love talking about this shit cause it
just people up, you know. Oh you know,
maybe you should all read a little more
before the next time you fucking own.
Really. What are you reading and what
are you reading? What they give you?
Is that what you're reading? Fuck head.
Why you acting like you have clearance
to the bottom floors of the fucking
Pentagon? You're guessing? Just
like I am. All right, Mr. Informed.
I read the pamphlet. I know
by a fucking word of it.
You know,
you can use Coca-Cola to take rust
off of metal. You can use it for that.
You know,
you understand that yet they're
still able to sell it to us.
Like it's refreshing.
I don't know what that point man either
[inaudible] [inaudible]
ladies and gentlemen.