Okay.
Yeah. Hey, what's going on? It's a
bit, Whoa, that's really loud. Oh yeah,
that's really fucking loud.
Damn. What's going on?
It's bill Burke and it's time for the
Monday morning podcast for them. One day,
one day. One day. Um,
August 21st, 2005. Jesus, I
got a cough drop in my mouth.
I got a halls, mental lip. This,
you're not going to want to listen
to this are you? You know what?
I don't have time to start it over again.
I just don't, you know
where does things ever is when you have
to go on a microphone and you got a
fucking hauls and you God damn mouth.
And what w like how do
you make it go by faster?
My supposed to just spit it out. Is
that what you want from me? All right,
I will. I don't know where to go here.
You're just going to have to hang on a
second. Just hang on. Hang on. Hang off.
Fuck on. Spit this fucking
thing out. [inaudible]
why does that make noise?
It's still a podcast.
It's still a podcast as long as I
make noise. All right. I'm back.
I'm back and I got the energy. All right.
This is the Monday morning podcast
for it's for fucking August 21st,
2017. You know, they ain't got no
August over there in the Middle East.
You know why they don't
believe in Christ. Do you know,
believe in crash? God's like,
well, email worked and guess what?
You ain't got no more August. Right?
I just want to so mad all the time.
Summers goes by some fucking phased.
That's true, man. You can look it up.
Go look it up on the
pooter over there. Shit.
Um, I'm on a great fucking mood.
I've got a bunch of shit to
do. As always, as always.
I'm recording this quarter
at five California time,
um, on Sunday. You know, and I put all
this money down on the red sox. Right?
You know, I've been betting
the red sox gambling. Okay.
I'm betting on the Red Sox, two
of my friends at Yankee fence,
right?
It's on the Ed yet. Yeah. P D gap
yet yet. Yeah. All this fucking shit.
All rise. Court's in session. Can
we hear from the bailiff weekend?
His last name is judge
Jesus fucking Christ.
How do,
how do people in sports get away with
the fucking punch or just basically the
newspaper industry in general?
My God.
Have you reached a verdict?
Yes, we have. Your honor.
That was a home run. You get it.
There's so bad.
Okay.
There's so far I wish.
I just wish sweet Caroline was is funny
bad is all those Aaron judge punts.
If they could just make it that far
as opposed to just watching a bunch of
people who you know on fucking
black Friday have their
face pressed up against a
Walmart window going. Yeah. Right.
How that song became
part of the tradition.
When the fuck did that
happen? When did it happen?
When will it go away? You know,
it's bad enough. They sing. Take me out
to the game. It never used to do that.
In the seventh thing,
he just stood up and stretched and then
so then Harry Carey did it and it was
great. You know why?
Because he believed it and he was shit
faced and he was hanging out the fucking
window and you like, is that
Guy gonna fall? You know,
you know those guys who
to booze their whole life,
they get this big round belly. Then they
got those little pretzel Rod Sticks.
So when he started getting a lot
of that fucking keg out the window,
you know, that's why they have that net
above home plate. You know what I mean?
Over the fans. It's, you know,
that goes back to it has
nothing to do with foul balls.
It has to go to back in the day there
was so many fat alcoholic sticking their
head out, you know,
doing God knows what back then.
You know. I imagine initially
they were just amazed that they weren't
on the second floor of a structure
sticking their head out. Like, you know,
gee willikers how the hell do steaks?
It was probably people underneath
me, but I can't say right.
Then that gradually morphed
into, Holy Shit, look how far,
you know La writer drama I babe rose hair,
right far right fucking power. Right.
That morphed into that. And then
somewhere in there it was like,
oh my God, is that a black guy on
the field? You know, they weren't.
They've always been hanging out the
window for years and years and years,
and that's why that net
was there. Everybody thinks
it's to protect the fence.
It's not to protect the fence. Back
in the day, everybody wore a hat.
They will fine. Okay. The
ball wasn't juiced up.
It was the dead ball era. It'd
go up in the year or you know,
those people were tough back then.
They built railroads with
their fucking hands, you know,
and that's just the Chinese. Okay,
forget about the people
that fucking built the A,
I dunno what the cotton gin. All
right, I'm off the fucking rails here.
I don't know what I'm talking about.
All I know is that I'm like, all right,
I got to get back into baseball. You
know what I mean? I'm an old man.
It's a slow game and then all of a
sudden it gets exciting and then it slows
down again. Right. Just like
that thing. As you get older,
every once in a while your heart
does something and you're like,
am I gonna fucking die here? Okay, no,
I'm good. Right? That's what baseball is.
The rest of the time it's just
fucking sitting there, you know,
like waiting for a cough drop to dissolve
so you can start your fucking podcast.
That's type of shit. So anyways, um,
I decided out of the fucking boom to um,
to bet with two of my friends, both
Yankee fence, right? Once again,
key and giant fan. The other a Yankee
and a Patriot fan figured that one up.
It's one of those Connecticut stories,
right? You heard of a Bronx tale.
This is the sequel called Connecticut
Story and this guy's a Yankee and a
patriots fan. The, the most bizarre,
one of the more bizarre combinations
of fans I've have, I've ever seen.
Um, so I bet at both, you
know, 50 bucks each a game.
So they stand to lose 50 again 50.
I'm dropping a c note of picking
it up on the last two series.
We've won two out of three on both
of them. So I'll freckles here.
It's up a hundred bucks, right?
Is that right? Let's see.
I was down a hundred then I was,
even then I was up a hundred then it
was up 200 then I was up a hundred.
Now I'm up 200 bucks.
Do want a boots, right? I loved it.
I almost meant an extra 50 cause the
guy's got don't up Tonya right now to
fucking Aaron judge.
You know everybody's gonna rise and
coach going to be in session and they're
going to reach a verdict and then
he's going to hit it again and again.
He's going to hit a home run.
And I was like,
you fucking cock soccer that guys like
all for 50 with guys on base against the
red sox the last couple of
weekends. Of course the guys do.
It's God Damn Paul Bunyan going
up there swinging the bat.
And then I thought about it, I was like,
all right, fuck it. I'll bet ya. Um,
but I was voice texting and I said,
I'll bet you 50 bucks. He doesn't,
but it wrote, I bet you've
fixed 50 bucks. He does it.
And then I didn't hear back from
him and I was like, all right,
you got until you know midnight
tonight to get your bed in her,
the offers off the table.
And he said he fell asleep,
but he was probably sitting going like,
oh dude. I said he was going to do it.
Why would you? I said
he'd do it for 20 bucks.
And then you said you also think
he's going to do it for 50.
I think I weirded him out.
He hasn't called me all day.
So that might be the end of
that friendship. It's funny
how that happens, right?
15 year friendship can end on a voice
text that somebody doesn't understand.
Um, so anyways,
so red sox took the fucking series
and you know why they took the series?
Because we spent 200 million fucking
dollars in God damn it. You know,
we better beat the fucking Yankees
if we could spend that kind of money.
I didn't want to yet. I didn't
want the Yankee spent this year.
I just know they have most
of their own draft picks.
So it really doesn't
matter. Right. Or does it?
I have no idea.
Did you guys see in Spain they set up 800
checkpoints to catch that fucking cunt
.
Um,
did they catch the guy? I Dunno.
Okay.
Desperate to ease public
fears and neutralize a
terrorist cell responsible for
the deadliest attack in Spain or
they going neutralize the, uh,
the terrorist cell. It was actually gonna
I guess going to be way more deadly,
but the fucking dopes accidentally blew
themselves up trying to make a bomb.
That's the greatest thing that can happen.
That's my favorite terrorist story
when they were building it and then it
fucking blows up. It's such
a fucked up world, man.
Okay.
It's just people on both sides that
are just out of their fucking minds.
I don't get it. I just don't get it.
Why can't you just fucking
be like me and you know,
battle booze and watch sports and get
excited. Things that don't matter.
Why do you have to have a fucking cause
and get all into some invisible fucking
guy that you never fucking met and then
everybody around you have to die if they
don't think the way you
think. Okay. What is it?
There's a tipping point in religion
and it's a combination of like
you believe too much and
you got too much fucking,
I don't know what you know,
I used to a bit about that.
Do you have like too much power and
get too much into fucking religion?
Like it always goes bad. You started
pressing other fucking people. You know,
like when my people really get into Jesus
white people, it gets fucking scary.
You know,
black people get really into Jesus and
that's a fucking great service killer
band. That's it.
They're confined white people.
It's an open fucking field.
Whatever the fuck they think. They
just, they just, they run with it.
No checks and balances.
That's the problem. Okay,
so I don't know what
goes on with these fires.
I didn't know what the
fuck I'm talking about,
but I don't know what goes on with
these people or the fuck you convince
somebody that they less fucking move on
the planet is you're going to walk into
to a group of people sitting
there watching a show or
eating a fucking slice of
pizza and you're going to kill all of
them. And a then God's going to be like,
Hey, nice going, woo. Hey Buddy,
I want to talk to you. You know,
I would have done that but I could dig
to thank God you thought to do that.
I Dunno. So anyways,
so good luck to Spain.
I hope you eradicate those cops right
out of your fucking beautiful country.
Um, anyways, I know. Why
do I talk world politics?
Why know why? Cause it makes you
guys feel smarter, right? Hey bill,
maybe next time you bring up spaying,
maybe you could fuck ag. Go Fuck Yourself.
I'll do what I want. Oh, by the
way, I got some a, I got some,
I got to give away this week for the
first thousand people all ran away to
second before you take
out you fucking first,
the first thousand people that text a
particular phrase to a particular number,
we'll win some all things,
comedy merchandise. So
they're basically stickers.
All right. Texted, is that what it is
yet? And I'm just letting you know that,
that this is so they can build,
build up their email fucking database and
let you guys know what's going on with
this site. Okay. So it's
fucking transparent.
What we're trying to do here
for the price of a sticker.
That's what we're trying to do. You know,
we're trying to get more social media
and all that type of shit because, um,
we've got big shit coming up on all
things. Comedy relaunched the website.
Um,
next month for Chrysler has a cooking
show on there called something's burning a
, I'm going to be doing those road rage
fucking videos where you got the fucking
camera on me and all of that shit. And
then the person that did whatever they,
uh, Philippe spires is going to be
doing a, a home improvement show.
Basically your favorite comics doing the
shit that they like to do. Being funny.
Um, we got our first stand up
special release with Paul Versey.
We got a bunch of stuff going
on and uh, talks of yes,
all kinds of other things, sports shows
and all this type of stuff. So, uh,
we're trying to gotta let you guys know
what's going on. So here's what you do.
If you want a sticker, if you don't
want to do it, don't fucking do it.
But if you want to do it, all you
need to do is text all capitals.
No Space Bill Burns, B I l.
L B U R R two four four two two two.
Reggie Jackson, Doug
Flutie, Derek fucking job.
Fuck that. Jerry Remy, the
rem dog. It was his day today.
I would've said Derek Cheetah, uh, 44,
22 to two fours, three twos.
You got it for a sticker and
then we'll be bugging you.
Let you know what's going on with all
these great shows. We have coming up,
you know, we got Bobby Lee, we got al
Madrigal, we got all these fucking people.
All right, we have Ari shifts here. Um,
all right. So anyways, and I
gotta be honest with you, uh,
after these last six
games, red sox, Yankees,
and having money on the game,
I got to be honest with you,
after all these years saying, Pete
rose shouldn't be in the hall of fame,
the man was right betting on
baseball. It makes it better.
It does makes it fuck. It
makes you care. You know,
you think October, baseball is exciting.
Puts your paycheck on a fucking
game in August. All right?
You don't need Joe Buck and all those
extra fucking microphones to make that
exciting
do to my gay Camaro with tee tops.
Am I going to be homeless? You know,
that's the type, but that's,
that's the type of stakes that you want
to raise a, I'm calling it right now.
Patriots, giants, the
rubber game this year.
Super Bowl patriots.
Finally fucking win, right?
No helmet. Catch no fucking owl Brady
to Welker fucking two foot pass.
It goes in complete Nova. Sanjay
Samuel dropping the fucking ball,
none of that shit. We're finally
going to beat those constant,
you know why Tom Kaufland? No, Tom
Coffins going to be the difference.
I love what the giants giant's doing.
I think. I think they're going to,
you know, and they got fucking Eli.
He's got ice fucking water
in his face. All right.
Their team is looking good.
All right. And I'm telling you,
that team's looking good cause I've
paid attention for about eight minutes
during this preseason and uh, I've,
I've just been hearing a lot of
chatter about weapons being added in,
in field goal kickers and all of this
type of shit. And people questioning Ely,
right? He's, he sits there and he's
dockers in his fucking, uh, you know,
I dunno what he's, you know, oh,
he always looks like he just did the
right thing the way he dresses. Right.
The loafers, the fucking
pants, the sweater, you know,
just like he dresses the way I should
be dressing in my age and he's like
fucking 12 years younger than me and
the man gets the fucking job done.
The later the season is and forget about
in January the man, his light's out.
Okay. Telling you,
telling you it's going to be a
rematch and we're going to win and I,
that's the fucking team I want to play.
That is the fucking team I want to
play cause we got nothing to lose.
They got everything to lose.
Cause if they're two one oh they can talk
shit for the rest of the fucking time.
I want another shot. Right.
The fuck two one oh three
and oh I don't give a fuck.
That doesn't make any difference.
But if we get that last one,
the guy then move and then we can give
them shit. I, you know what the fuck.
You know it's not they I dropped the
fucking ball and it was a screenplay,
you know, whatever. Whatever we
got you then it's 10 it's over.
Then when we got that thing we can say
back. That's what I'm saying. You know,
cause I've ran to a couple of giants
fair. They're like oh direct. No,
you don't fucking want, why don't we
want it that just logos at this point.
Eli's probably the only guy left
from that 2017 and I bet at least,
I don't know, three quarters of the
both teams are gone since the last one.
That's why I never get
into those types of stats.
Go and let these guys will store ugly
if not the little good, little bigger.
It's like it's all different.
It's all different people wearing
the same clothes with better drugs,
better drugs, better drugs
in their system. Okay.
Just like the drugs that was sent to
a particular quarterback's wife. Okay.
Cause she hurt her arm taking
cookies out of the oven. Okay.
It was a complete non-story. However,
had that guy taking a queef
worth of air out of a ball,
all of his rings would've been
questioned. That's how it works. Okay.
We're taking callers. Um,
you know what I did today,
you know, he was funny. I did so much,
so many fucking positive things today.
So many. This, this
podcast is not one of them,
but I did so many fucking
positive things today. You know?
And then my wife, my wife,
she still had the nerve to be moody.
And I don't know about you guys, but,
oh, what the fuck goes on. Thank you.
I don't know about you. I
don't want to put up with that.
I don't put up with the moodiness.
Okay. Come on. What do I gotta do here?
What happened? Fucking
thing just died on me here.
There we go. Um, I don't put up with
that Moody Shit. If I did something,
you got me. I'm sorry. All
right. I said, I'm sorry. No,
that Moody Shit. If I do
fucking nine things right,
and then the 10 things wrong and then
you're going to get home booty with me,
I swear to God, I swear to God, I just,
that's it. You know, and I do, I, I
go, hey, hey, grumpy. What's going on?
And if she doesn't fucking snap out of
it, then then, then I just shut down,
you know? And then you don't, you
know, I'm fucking German. Irish,
you want to play the silence game? I
could do this all fucking do this forever.
All right. You think there's a
lot of silence and master of none.
Let me tell you something right
now. I can do fucking silence.
I don't know why I'm making this motion
with my hand. I grew up with that shit.
Rage. Silence. You know, days going by.
Hey you dumb consol. Gonna Stare at
the sun tomorrow. Do yourself a favor.
Just wait for the pictures.
You know what I mean?
Looking at a fucking lunar
eclipse or solar eclipse.
Whatever the fuck's going on
here. It's a lunar eclipse, right?
Is it the lunar eclipse?
There's the one I learned that when the
earth is between the sun and the moon,
the moon turns red
cause it deflects the
fucking light or something.
The only reason why I know this is cause
this shit's happening on Monday and one
of the writers in the
writers room knew this shit.
And then there's the other one with
a moon passes in front of the sun.
Oh my God. Is Avid nap in
for 37 38 fucking years.
Um,
did you see that little,
not a meme? Was it a Jif,
that thing going around
about that newscaster that
actually we'll use to like he
used to watch him when I was a kid
and he said a that little that,
that a club said I was a
little [inaudible] and there's
not going to be another
one in 38 years and
let's hope that when it,
it fucking happens on a world
that knows nothing but peace,
you know? And everybody's like, Whoa,
okay,
wow. He said that and then wow.
It's just like, what are you,
we've never been at peace ever, ever.
Never will be. They'll never be world
peace. They'll never be world with the,
the level of, of violence that would
have to occur for there to be peace.
You'd have to be the last person on
earth because if there's another person,
if there was just two people,
at some point the other person is going
to annoy you and then there goes to
peace.
Right.
That's what happened with Adam and eve.
I hate to tell you what all you people
out there that believe we came from
fucking the ocean. I
actually believe in, in,
in creationism, whatever
the fuck they call it.
All right.
There was two white people that
started all of this in somehow we had,
yeah,
all the other races out of them.
Um,
he's two white people,
right? Adam and eve,
and they got annoyed with each
other. So she goes for a walk, right.
The snake gets in a rare,
next thing, you know. Right.
Hm.
She goes over and she bites an apple,
which for whatever reason is, is healthy.
It's a good thing. It's got fiber in it.
You know?
I don't understand why the man,
the visible guy was upset by
that because you know what?
It was an apple with
the sugar in it. Like,
because there was no weed or coke
or meth or anything like that.
Like apples where I guess the
heroin back then. And he said,
let me tell you two little
shits something. All right,
you want to live in this fucking
garden of Eden here? Well though,
yeah. Stay away from
the fucking apple tree.
That's it.
She went down and she'd
probably be like, Hey, you know,
I'm going to go down and eat one of
those fucking apples and fucking,
what's his face, whatever.
Was it a brother?
I don't know what went and the none
of that fucking is anybody religious
listening to this shit. How to
fuck the two white people. Okay,
fuck and create all different
races of people. Forget about that.
How have you just have to f two fucking
people and then they bang and then what?
How do you keep it going?
Their kids have to fuck.
Exactly. You had nothing. Didn't yet.
And then their kids kids. Fuck.
Is that how we went from Adam
and Eve to fucking cavemen?
Neander talls and those other fucking
people with those slopey foreheads,
you know? And that that
fucking Frankenstein brow,
which I kind of have is that,
is that what happened?
Because Adam and eve banged and then their
kids had to fair to sit down and say,
children,
you have to fuck one another in
order to keep this thing going.
All right.
None of it makes sense.
None of those stories fucking make sense
anymore than the fat guy in the red
fucking suit going down a God
damn Chimi okay. First of all,
if it was fucking true,
all these new homes without
fireplaces would not have a Christmas.
What a parents who live in
houses without fireplaces, say,
okay.
You know, up on the housetop
reindeer paws out jumps,
good old Santa Claus looking for chimney,
but there isn't one gets back and say
you have no fun. Go Fuck Yourself. Right?
No, guide him toys. Go Fuck
Yourself. Go to child world.
All right, now he, that's,
that's part of his contract.
You leave cookies and there's a fucking
chimney or that's it. It's over.
Okay.
That and evidently he has no interest
in anybody who's not Christian.
He makes toys for everybody
unless they're not Christian.
You know what it is? It's everyone.
We were tribes and we had these tribes
and we just came up with these fucking
stories.
And as it expanded and everybody started
fucking interact and all the holes in
our shit, you know, once she got
that global view, that all fucked up.
All of a sudden the world
wasn't flat, you know,
depending on what basketball play you'd
talk to, it was round. He followups.
I needed to found out that it was fucking
round. These people aren't Indians,
they're not from the fuck. And then I'm
from India, they're from American Mac.
Right? The greatest fuck. Oh by
the way, I forgot to say, you know,
if you go to tech, I just fucked up.
If you go to texts that they were not
sending a sticker oversee. By the way,
this is just for Americans
only by Americans.
I mean United States of
America, maybe Canada,
I didn't know he can't do it
cause it's a fucking sticker.
And then they got to fill out forms.
I should have said that earlier.
You know, I should have done a lot of
things in life, but I gotta tell you what,
not telling you guys that, you know,
if you text that fucking number and it's
in international and the stickers.com
and that's probably one of my biggest
regrets other than the fact the last time
I didn't watch an eclipse, you know,
there was a guy wishing for world
peace the next time it came around.
And now here we are 38 fucking
years later, 38 years later.
Are we any closer?
Yeah.
You know,
I'm sure somebody said that in the 1940s
after fucking Hitler and Stalin and all
that shit a, you know, there was a,
uh, last night there was a typhoon,
I hope the next time
there's a typhoon, it's, uh,
killing innocent people in a peaceful
world. It's never going to happen.
Well, Jesus,
build that with that fucking ad to the
children have to fuck when we return.
Part two of the Adam and Eve story,
the story no one wanted to show you.
Um, all right. So anyways, I've been, uh,
only fucking minutes into this pilot's
Shit podcast that I do in my 25,
26 minutes,
people 26 minutes as some of the most
ignorant shit you're ever going to listen
to yet you continue to listen,
you continue to listen.
Um, all right. You know what I did to I,
so I did all this productive
shit today and yes, my wife,
she started pulling the
grumpy thing, right?
Like I was going to wake up
this morning, bad, do what?
They'll do it and I was going
to go play drums. All right.
Which I'm still gonna do, but
I'm gonna do it tonight. Okay.
But I could tell she was
tired or whatever. Okay.
So the advantage macro half that you lady,
hey ya lay has, is when the kids crying,
they always have the option of the boob.
Bam instant shut it, right.
Puts the kid to sleep.
They feel comfort and
all that type of stuff.
The only way that a man can compete in
that arena is you have to either put the
kid in the car and drive
around block a few times.
Or what I think is better,
you just put the kid in the stroller
and you just walk around the block.
Now you're burning some of your
dad bod calories. You know,
your kid gets to look around
and see a bunch of stuff.
Fucking acid trip birds flying
around, jets, cars, trees, right.
Everything's amazing to them. And
then eventually they fall asleep. Um,
so anyways, I could tell my wife, my
wife was really sleepy, so I said,
all right, you know, she goes,
it'd be really nice if you
can just take it for a walk.
Cause she was up and my wife wasn't
and I was just like, all right,
I was going to work out. I'll go play
drums. You know what? Fuck it, I'll do it.
So I did, went on a nice long walk, did
the whole thing. We had a great time.
She finally fell asleep
after like 20 minutes.
She finally falls asleep and then I
walked around like extra, you know,
take an extra long, you
know, walk home and you know,
walking further past the house, coming
back up, come back up. You know,
my wife's still downstairs. I can tell
she's still sleeping. We hung out.
We had breakfast together,
right? I watched a little, the,
the Jerry Remy, you know, Jerry
Remy Day at Fenway Park, um,
just did all of that. And then she
didn't come upstairs till like fucking,
I dunno, 1130, 11 o'clock or something,
something like that. Then she goes,
all right, let's go out today. We said,
we are gonna go out and I'm God,
let's go out. Let's go out. So
she gets the kid ready and
everything, but the fucking shoes,
I tried to put the shoes on, I
just can't do it. I can't do it.
She tries to kick them off. I start
laughing and I can't get him on.
And I finally got one of them on.
I realized they had it on the
wrong foot and I was like,
fucking and undo the buckle. And
then I finally got it on right.
And she just kicked it off. And I
just laughed. I said, I can't do it.
I can't do it. And they left. She's like,
really? And I said, yeah. I go, look,
there's some things you're better at
than I am. You're just better at this,
right. So I leave. She goes,
where are you going? I said,
I'm gonna go watch the red sox. She
goes, well come down here and watch it.
So I said, okay.
So then I went upstairs and she told me
how her tire pressure was down and uh,
I was trying to remember how to do that
cause I knew I had the tire pressure
fucking thing. You know,
you stick the thing on there so you don't
overinflate you don't under inflate.
I'm looking up that we got a little
water bubbler. We're all out of water.
It's a good opportunity to
clean the fucking thing.
I'm looking at Shit like that
when I'm up there. So, uh,
I didn't go back downstairs and she came
upstairs fucking pissed at me cause she
spent like whatever the next 15 minutes
trying to get ready with my daughter
downstairs for change to stand. There
must have been a pain in the ass,
but I was up there
fucking, you know. Yeah.
See she gets in a mood now.
She's in a mood, not yelling,
you know, not flipping out just in a mood.
You know, they know when
they get in the fucking mood,
I get this look on their face,
they stop looking at you and they make
sure that they keep walking into the room
that you're in. You know what?
You talk to them and they barely say
anything back. So you, you know what?
So you know what? Come on guys,
let's, let's learn something here.
So you are aware that
she's in a watt [inaudible]
hmm.
Oh Jesus. Somebody is
in a mood. I'm sorry.
Did I do 99 out of a hundred
things? Jesus fucking Christ.
Okay,
so she's in a fucking mood.
Then I gotta go out. You know,
cause I got my fucked up driveway.
I got to get my car out of the way.
Bring her fucking car out. Cause you
got to get the fucking air on the tires.
Oh and I'm out though all you think I'm
muddle. I put on a clinic of Muttering,
Huh? Fuck. [inaudible] gonna kill up
to Goddamn fucking, he'll come down,
make a pack of fucking [inaudible]
and clean out the water bubble.
And I got to come home, right Henry Hill.
Um,
so that's it. And I'm like, all right,
I will match your mood with an
even dumber moot. So that's it.
So then she starts to sense,
then I'm going to fucking mood.
Now we'll share mood.
Put me in a fucking mood.
Now she's sensing that I'm in this
fucking mood. So now all of a sudden,
what does she do? She starts
flipping it around, being nice,
right? Then I'm just giving
a fucking quick answers.
Like Jerry Lewis rest his
soul passed away today.
Dick Gregory few days ago, and
now Jerry Lewis, Jerry Lewis,
arguably one of the funniest
human beings that ever lived,
ever lived.
He actually spoke at my college
graduation and he was phenomenal.
He did the parent student
breakfast. And when he did that,
he was crazy. Jerry. And then
when he spoke in my college,
he was, uh, coming down the aisle. He was
still crazy. You know, when they bring
[inaudible] [inaudible] know fucking
the fucking with the Dean and all those
people come down with there who we have
a special colored Tassel, you know,
we're higher than you. You know,
they come down in their robes.
Well he was coming down and he put his
hands on the shoulder of the person in
front of him.
He hit one of those dumb hats on too
when he put his hands and when he walked
down, we just going whoa down
and everyone was dying laughing.
But when he went to give the speech,
he was telethon. Jerry, it was great.
You got to see the full gamut of the guy.
Um,
absolutely love that guy. That guy
made me laugh like nobody's business.
So very sad day in a Dick Gregory.
I learned about him obviously being a
comedian long time ago. Read that book.
Callison my soul. Um,
all those stories about him being one
of the first black guys to ever worked
like white rooms. You know,
the playboy mansion in Chicago playing
that because what's his face there?
Hugh Hefner was cool enough
to let him play there.
So rest and peace to both
of them. Um, so anyways,
so now this all pales in comparison
to those two comedy giants. All right,
so I match my wife's mood
with my mood. All right,
so now she's not done. Okay,
now she's trying to be nice to
get me out of my fucking mood,
cause then she realizes this
is all silent. By the way,
this is all body language, all Kurt
little answers, one of these things.
Now she realizes that, oh, I took my
mood too far. I overly made my point,
which justified him now being
in his fucking mood, right?
So then at some point she
finally just goes, Hey, I,
I you just gonna like she goes,
are you going to be in a bad mood
for the rest of the day? I'm like,
I'm not in a bad mood. I'm in a
great mood. We have an awesome house.
I tell jokes for a living, we're going
to go get, we're going to go out today.
I'm in a good mood. I have the
day off. I am in a good mood.
You on the other hand, I don't know.
She goes, I'm over it. I'm over it.
And I go, fine. Somebody
is just going to like,
you know, like that talked
to me. I said, look,
we're going out shopping for kid's
shoes the second I see kids shoes,
it just puts me in a good mood.
[inaudible] they fucking adorable.
Those little Jordans,
the little shell toes.
It's a kids clothes are the
cutest fucking things ever.
They're not even for
kids. They're for adults.
See some little sport call you
like, no. Yeah, you can't help it.
So I told her, I said,
just let me get to the fucking kids
sneakers and then that'll put me in a a
better fucking mood. Um,
do you know what I saw
today? It's some fucking, um,
okay.
Over on Labrea they got
this, they got this store.
It's just all these crazy signs
and all of this basically junk,
just shit from businesses
that shut down or remodel.
And this guy just has all these
fucking sad, sad did and went then.
So I'm walking up and they
actually had the old school,
the little McDonald's arch with the Arrow
that said drive through open 24 hours.
That's what put me in a good mood.
All that. All the childhood memories.
We were a McDonald's family. We
were not a burger king family.
That was a big thing back then.
You know, nobody talked politics.
She didn't talk fucking religion. Okay.
You talked about sports and what do you
like better? Coca Pepsi, coke or Pepsi.
McDonald's at Burger King. Those were
the big fucking debates back then.
And um,
okay,
I was out. We will have a
McDonald's fucking family.
We used to go to this McDonald's, I
don't even know where the fuck it was.
I was like in PBT or north Redding way
back in the early seventies it was off.
It was near these railroad tracks.
And I remember there was these fucking
seagulls and pigeons and shit and you'd
be eating outside then
throwing them French fries
and then you got to see a train
go by and it was the cool,
this is like pride pad's pre
Fuckin, you know, Internet.
There was nothing to do. Cartoons,
we are, our UHF antenna was busted.
I could only watch cartoons on Saturday.
So this was a big fucking deal.
I'd always get a cheeseburger,
small fry and a chocolate shake.
That's what the fuck I had, you know,
for a long fucking time past when
it wasn't filling me up. You know?
But you were afraid of
your dad. It's like,
I'm not gonna ask for a quarter
pounder with cheese. I don't know.
I don't know what this is going
to do to the whole dynamic. Every,
everybody's in a good mood. I'm not,
I'm not going to try to
fucking go up a size here.
That's how Americans got fed. Once Dad
became dad's, became their kids friends,
they weren't afraid to, to
fucking supersize their meals.
The last four years of
ordering a cheeseburger,
small fry and chocolate
freak chick, I was still,
I was fucking starving at the end of it.
I bawled and my younger
brother's cheeseburger like,
you're going to fucking finish that
high. You little fucking gummy bear.
You know your fucking
teeth. I'll eat it. Um,
so anyways, I saw that thing today
and I was just like, I would fuck it.
I don't, I'm not in the
junk. I'm not in this stuff,
but there's something about that thing.
I just think it's fucking cool to
get it fixed up as the f the a,
the fucking base was all bent in shit,
but to fix that fucking thing
up, I was like, I just don't,
I won't say I'll stick that at the end
of my driveway. Yeah. That thing lit up.
Okay.
Well my wife's like, uh, you know, say
no neighbors would hate us. It's like,
I know the anus, I would never stick
it out there if I had like, you know,
buying some giant fucking house. Right.
You know, and there was some sort of,
I don't know what, you know,
those fucking houses, those,
those Republicans have them, you know,
I'm not saying there's not rich liberals,
but the Republicans live in those states
where you can fucking have a house and
then another house on your property.
You know, you have an old barn,
you know, you just let your wife, your
wife gets the fucking house. They,
I'm telling you, this is my
fucking dream, my dream. Right.
Um, you know, but I mean,
I would love to live.
I can't live out their interracial couple.
I can't go out there and to
fucking Nazi land, you know,
all these fucking people marching around.
Okay.
Uh, but anyways,
I would love to have a fucking old house
in one of those states that still has
clean air, if that even exists.
And he just got a giant
fucking what used to be a barn.
And on the bottom you'd
have your daily driver,
your classic car, and like a
fucking sick motorcycle. All right.
And then up top I'd have it fucking close.
They'd be at, I always told you this,
be a drum room fucking place to workout.
And the rest of it is just a
fucking cigar bar, you know,
and did some stupid fucking reason.
I would five find a place for that
McDonald's drive through side,
you know?
But the more my wife hated it, the more
it would drive me into the barn. Um,
anyways, let's read some advertising
here for this week, shall we?
Okay.
I always it at Burger King. Try to act
like our burgers are flame broiled. Yeah.
And then frozen and driven in a fucking
truck across the country. You know,
you still, we showed it in a commercial,
like to sit in there with some
fucking open grill back there,
cooking these fucking things
in. I cook at these things.
A logo was hey. Oh my God man. Boop, boop.
[inaudible] [inaudible] Burger King
or Mickey Days Dodo too. To me.
[inaudible] [inaudible]
bold fifth. You please,
but comma fat fuck and your
stomach saying it over tidy.
Fucking whities wages not.
Wouldn't it be nice if they were cradle
in a nice piece of fucking velvet?
I'm beyond. Is everybody
okay?
Do you want to look good in your
underwear and be comfortable?
Well, doe, yeah,
but that right balance is hard to find.
Don't sacrifice style or comfort.
Checkout me on these dotcom man and
find the best pair of underwear in the
world.
Talk about why me undies is the
best underwear you will ever own.
Feel free to improvise.
I don't fucking know.
You know why? Because you don't
have to go out to the mall.
They just deliver them right to
you. You feel special, right?
You order enough of them,
you can kind of heap them all together
and you've got a giant soft pillow and
your head gets to feel
what? Your nuts feel, right?
The big head gets to feel with the
little head feels. How is that me on?
These will be the most comfortable pair
of underwear you will own made from a
sustainably sourced,
naturally thought fabric that is
evidently three times softer than cotton.
Jesus though that as
fighting words right there.
Ultimate feel good on these for when you
want to feel naked but not be naked for
the fellows. Me, these
diamonds seen pouch cradles,
uh, for you.
Cradle for your jewels.
Lack a rhinestone nut sack.
You know,
he's saying that last week and my
mother-in-law was upstairs and gives lady,
it gives you stuff. I'm sorry.
Gives you stuff to support it
needs without feeling too tight.
And ladies will love this
soft ecofriendly fabric.
So soft and so touchable covers it
up. But lets it breathe. Ladies.
Right now me undies has an exclusive
offer for just my listeners.
Get 20% off your first pair and
free shipping and undies is so sure
you will love the underwear.
They even offer 100% satisfaction
guarantee you you order a pair.
If you don't love your first
pair, get a full refund.
This is a no brainer to try 20% off
free shipping and 100% satisfaction
guarantee.
What are you waiting for to get 20%
off free shipping and their 100%
satisfaction guaranteed and get the best
and soft decided where you will ever go
to me
on.com/birth that's me on these.com/birds
this is a limited time offer.
So what are you waiting for?
Start wearing the best
underwear of your life.
It changed my life, Tom.
Let me unease change yours.
Go to [inaudible] dot com
slash bar [inaudible] um,
all right. Dollar Shave Club dote,
dollar shave club, dollar shave club.
Is this mad at choice? You'll get
a great shave at a great price,
conveniently delivered
right to your door. Uh,
you no longer have to Schlep to the
fucking store to buy a cheap disposable
razor that gave you a cheap shave or
spend a fortune on a razor with gimmicky
shaving technology yet l
fucking need it right now.
When you use dollar Shave Club's executive
razor with that doctor Cabbie thisi
shade
[inaudible]
label, Janet, just glide gently, gently
glides, giving you a smooth shape.
Dr Carver's shave butter is
transparent for a more precise shape,
helps prevent ingrown hairs and
fights. Razor bumps, in other words,
works on White People's faces
and black people's faces.
Make the smarter choice by
joining Dollar Shave Club today.
For a limited time,
new members can get their first month
for free of the executive razor with a
tube of Dr Cathy.
Cc Shave butter for only $5
with free shipping. After that,
razors are just a few bucks a month.
That's a $15 value for only five bucks.
There's no hidden fees, no
commitments cancel anytime you like.
You can only get this offer
exclusively@dollarshaveclubdotcomslashbarthatisdollarshaveclub.com
slash
bar oh
look who's here. It's
our old friends. Old Zip.
Are you hiring barrio?
Do you know where to post your
job to find the best candidates?
Talk about the challenges of finding
great talented and or the importance of
finding great talents to
a successful business.
Toyo go joy. You know when
you look up to Schober,
you got to make sure you get the right
person with those people out there that
are fucking morons.
They would really be great if there was
a way to shift through all these mouth
breathing for on state
going for different brooder.
How's ZipRecruiter is
different with ZipRecruiter?
You can post your job to 100 plus
job sites with just one click.
Then their powerful technology efficiently
matches the right people to your job
better than
anyone else. That's why ZipRecruiter
is different. Unlike other job sites,
Sip Ben doesn't depend on candidates
finding you. It finds them. In fact,
over 80% of jobs posted on Zip.
Yeah,
okay. Get a qualified
candidate in 24 hours.
No juggling emails or
calls to your office.
Simply screen rate and manage
candidates all in one place with zip.
Um, easy to use dashboard. And right
now my listeners can post jobs on zip.
Good from running of ways to do
it for free. That's right free.
Just go to ziprecruiter.com/burger. That's
ziprecruiter.com/burr one more time.
Hey, try it for free. Go to
ziprecruiter.com/burke um,
production hosts a production knows
hosts are not to mention any competitors
including, why would you say
all of these fucking places?
I almost read that.
Okay.
How has ZipRecruiter been
advertising with me this long?
And they don't really have stupid ims.
You fucking, you never saw anchorman.
God Damn it. Who put that question mark
there? That's me. I will. If it's there,
I will read it. stamps.com everybody
stamps.com saves you time and money,
which you can use to grow your
business. I can mail any letter,
any package using just my
computer printer in the mail.
Man comes and picks it up. Avoid
the hassle of post office and mail.
Everything from postcards to envelopes
to packages, domestic or international.
Create your stamps account in minutes
online with no equipment to lease and no
longterm commitments. Click print
mail, shoot shit, and you're done.
Unlike the post office,
stamps.com never closes. Not Man.
They got to go better than that.
Unlike that whore down the street,
like the horse legs down the
street, stamps.com never closes.
Okay,
well wait a minute. That would mean
the other hurts her. She closes.
I don't like that. Prude down
the street. I fucked it up, man.
Read print postage for letters or
packages at your own convenience. 24,
seven key words, descriptors.
Oh, descriptions I'm
supposed to say convenient,
easy, reliable, flexible.
Just like a whore, right?
She's right down the street.
She's easy. She's reliable.
Always wants to fucking, God knows
she's flexible. Um, call to action.
All right. I use stamps.com because why?
Because every once in a while sell
fucking posters after my show,
I go out and meet the crowd and God damn
and I don't want to the post office.
Okay.
If my assistant can figure out how to
fucking use stamps.com that God damn it.
So can you,
and right now you too can
enjoy the stamps.com service
with a special offer that
includes a four week trial plus postage
and a digital scale without commitments,
go to stamps.com click on the
microphone@thetopofthehomepageandtypeinburthatstamps.com
enter
burrs,
stamps.com never go to the
post office again. You know,
I'm one race behind with the MotoGP. My,
um, I really fucking
enjoy that and I actually,
I think I like it better than Formula
One because there's all kinds of passing.
There's no passing in Formula
One, it seems after, you know,
as far as the first guy, that's my
big complaint. And they're like, God,
there's all this amazing racing and in
position four and five and six, well,
fucking show that. Um,
anyways, let me, let me just plow ahead
here. Uh, me undies every, no, no,
I already did that.
Let me, let me ask. No,
I'll read the questions for this week.
This is what we're supposed to be doing.
All right. Okay. Boyfriends, Facebook,
all this is never good. Alright.
Hi Bill. Straight to the
point, me and my boyfriend,
we've been together for two years
now and we're happy. Smiley face.
The thing that concerns me is that a
few times on his Facebook messenger,
I saw that he is writing on a weekly
basis with an ex college colleague of his,
a beautiful young lady.
The thing is that they were
close at work back then,
but he quit three months ago and
I just don't believe in Male,
female friendships. I'm talking from
experience also when we were one.
Basically if I, you know, if
we're having a conversation,
if we're talking eventually we're
gonna fuck is what you're saying.
Also when we're watching
some videos and stuff on his,
on his phone in the search field,
I saw a list of a few girls names.
Other than that,
he has been great to me and hasn't
shown any signs of a man who are yet,
am I too suspicious or do
I have the right to worry?
Thanks and go fuck yourself. I
don't fuck. That's not enough.
That's not enough
information. Um, I wouldn't,
you know this ex colleague,
that's a beautiful lady.
Yeah, that's weird. That's you're
right. That's fucking weird.
Um, I dunno about the fucking phone
shit. That's a, I have no idea.
I have no idea what that's about.
But that, that thing there, yeah,
that's definitely a red
flag. You know what I mean?
Like we'll put yourself in his
position if you will fucking, you know,
close with some guy and you left the job
three months ago and you still chat on
Facebook and you know,
here's the thing about women that
they can sit there and be like, oh,
I thought we were just friends. They
seem to be able to get away with that.
But I would always say to the woman
I was with, I was like, listen,
can I tell you something? That
guy wants to fuck you. Okay.
I don't care how much you have in common
and how you both like fucking Rosé and
whatever the fuck it is. And he
really listens to you when you talk.
He wants to fuck you. Um,
yeah. So I don't know.
You do there because you went on
his Facebook and you're snooping.
So that's one of the thing, you know, if
you're going to pull that ah ha moment,
you better be right. Cause if you're
not, then they get to play the, you know,
how dare you snoop, you know,
how dare you fucking snoop on me.
It's just like, I mean,
don't women have the out?
Why you snooping on me?
Because you have a dick sir.
Okay.
That's why I trust you. I don't trust
you dick. Alright. Missed opportunities.
I I, I would bring it up.
I Dunno if you bring it up.
I don't have enough information.
That was a really quick and to the
point which I, I really appreciate,
but I'm watching some videos
and stuff in the search field.
I saw a list of a few girls names. That's
not good either. I don't fucking know,
but I don't know who the girls
are, but that are right there that,
that fucking ex colleague
think. I Dunno. I Dunno.
Um, that seems like a blow job in the
future to me. That's what I would,
if I was standing in front of a
green screen, a little meteorologist,
there'd be a fucking, you know,
Dick floating towards a woman with
their mouth open down south. Alright.
Missed opportunity. Hey Billy Buckaroo
I'm going back to school soon.
Within the next week.
Actually I got an offer a couple of
days ago to register for a class a this
upcoming semester that is
essentially a paid internship. It,
it entailed working with a
company called Sun Corporation.
Why is my stomach growling?
Because I'm on a diet, um,
called Sun Corp on a software project. Uh,
if you complete the internship, you
get paid a couple of hundred dollars,
like two or 300 and of course something
worth putting on your resume for job
hunting. But the thing
is that I turned it down.
I didn't think it would mean that much
to take it as I don't really need the
money and software engineering
majors are for the most part,
guaranteed a job after graduation. Plus,
I only have one semester left and it's
looking like it's going to be pretty
tough and it's locally. It's going
to be pretty tough anyway. All right,
so you gotta concentrate in schools.
What's the problem? He says, however,
I cannot help feel a bit pissed
off at myself for saying no.
It's one of those things that has
virtually no negatives to it. I get to,
I get work experience and money.
What more could I need anyway?
I can't help but see this as a wasted
opportunity. My question to you is,
have you ever been offered an opportunity
in your community career that you've
pissed out, pussied out on and
then heavily regretted later?
And could you offer me advice on this?
Thanks. And Go fuck yourself. All right.
First of all, dude, it's a fucking
internship. It's your last semester.
It's going to be tough. You know,
you want to fucking go out
and party a little bit.
It's not the worst thing. It's not the
end of the fucking world. And absolutely.
I had, um, oh my God.
Even all kinds of times I pussied
out early in my career. I was afraid.
I was afraid to go on stage.
I was afraid of bombing.
I was afraid of the
whole fucking, so yeah,
there was a whole bunch
of times that I did. Um,
so what I would do, I started
to doing moments like that.
My fucking stomach will start,
hey, I gotta eat dinner. Yeah,
I was good today for lunch.
I had lentil soup and a fucking salad and,
uh, you know, I've just been trying, I've
been trying, I'm laying off the booze.
I don't eat fucking sweets, you know,
the writer's room we have fuckin Fridays
and where we just order whatever we
want and, uh, fucking they got
barbecue and I just, you know,
that's like at my age, that's, that's
like nap food. It's a like drinking,
like fucking Nyquil ACEM Shit.
So I can't do that. Um, anyways.
Uh, let's see. How would,
how would I answer? Sorry,
just click that fucking elbow. Hit the
button there. How would I answer this?
I would basically say when I did, was I,
okay.
I always remember what it felt
like when I pussied out that night.
When I put my head down on the pillow,
my big Charlie Brown fucking head,
I put it down on the pillow and I just
would always remember like that awful
feeling of of Pussy and
out, you know? And then I,
so then the next time that moment
happened, I'd be like, all right, tonight,
whether I kill, whether I
bomb with I just to, okay,
I'm going to feel way better
then if I didn't even try. So, but I,
I think you'd be in too hard on
your cell phone. This one. I mean,
you didn't pussy up, you just said no.
You seem like you weighed your options.
If you are too afraid to do it, then
I would say that you pussy that.
But I don't think you did. But, um,
I don't know if your reasons for
doing it were different. You know,
if there was some sort
of fear involved, uh,
you gotta figure out why you did it and
then you got to forgive yourself for
doing it because it's part of like, you
know, you got to fail to succeed. Right?
You remember that Michael
Jordan commercial, you know,
missed all those shots.
[inaudible] missed all those shots.
They failed over and over and
over and over and over again.
That is why I succeed. There you go. Same
fucking thing. Same fucking thing. Um,
all right. Nose job. Uh, dear Billy.
Mozzarella legs. Um, wow.
Hello? Yeah.
My daughter yelling at me in there.
Yeah,
she does this hilarious thing when you're
on the phone, you have it on speaker.
She sees you talking into it
and she just starts going, wow,
what do you yell at about, I can't
find a single pass. You know?
I was telling them that
story of how, you know,
I did all that stuff for you this
morning. Then you got into a mood.
So then I matched your
mood with that, my mood,
and then we had that little
game that you play with.
Then you try to be nice to get me out
of my mood. You know that little thing.
No, I don't know what
you're talking about, Nia.
I don't know what you're talking about.
Nia. What do you want me to say? No,
I'm saying,
well I don't know what he's talking
about either. Nia, what, what,
what that funny game or you know
you're going to mood and then then,
and then it puts me in a
mood. Then he'd go, okay,
maybe I've took my mood too far.
So now I'll be the one to turn
it around and then you know me,
you always gotta fucking pull me out of
the anger mud, right? Fine. Yeah, sure.
Oh yeah. Can you tell
guys you hear in a voice?
I won't look how beautiful you
are. Find that pacifier. Hey Buddy.
How you like to compute or anything
with the screen on it? You like,
what are you yelling for? It's
cause you got to have my DNA.
Is that what the problem is? You realize
as you grow up every time you screw up,
I'm going to get blamed for that cause
I'm the screw up in this relationship.
That's right. Talk to the people.
Tell the people what you're feeling,
Huh? Huh? What do you got there?
What are your feelings about, uh,
global warming? What should we do?
Yes.
Nothing.
The baby senator was surprisingly quiet
on some of the biggest issues out there.
Hey, how are you liking a
you love and the Avocados,
aren't you the mushed up
Avocados? You liking them? Yeah,
she's shy. She, she have Mike
Fright. She doesn't know what it is.
It's probably she didn't grab
it. All right, here we go. Hey,
somebody's gonna ask you a question about
a nose job. Some reason my fuck, oops,
sorry. Too many Chris here. My
stomach is growling. I'm hungry too.
Yeah. Alright. Nose job.
Dear Billy. Mozzarella lakes.
Wait like the white, like the Mozzarella.
I'm a 43 year old married
father of two. Yeah,
he liked that up. Very happy with
my life but could use some advice.
You see I have a Schnoz. Oh my God. Do
this. And your nose is still bugging you.
43 you married a woman, loves
you. You got a couple of kids.
A real honker a really big nose a
day. I got a big nose over here.
Now you want to talk? Huh? I've been
able to get by with the successful life,
career and marriage. Um,
but in the back of my mind and okay,
the back of my mind and
whenever I look in the mirror,
I just can't get over my nose.
I kind of look like all
the old joke, Groucho Marx,
all those old joke, Groucho Marx
with the glasses without glasses. Um,
now my question is why are you yelling? I,
I you,
I gave you the floor and you didn't want
to talk and now you're yelling there.
Acuity. What are you doing? Huh? Well,
you say are wrinkles. My Little Sharpei.
Um, all right, where am
I now? My question is
being that I've come this
far in life and at my age,
do you think it's super vain or
silly to get surgery done? Money.
Money. Your wife is not an issue.
I just think it's silly of
me to really want to do this,
but it's really affecting me where I
don't want to look at myself in the mirror
when I shave or put on context.
Thankfully vice and go yank
gage, let's go. Yeah. New,
the greatest promo ever. Wheel of
fortune if you can ever find it. Um,
when they went to New York, I
guess went in New York. Huh?
That was it. Two second clip.
Um, here's a thing too. I,
I actually don't get surgery. Yeah,
you've got to learn to love yourself.
But here's the thing, when
you got a frigging giant nose,
it's really defines your face. Like
people, that's what you look like.
And then when you shaved
that thing down, you not,
you're not going to look like yourself
anymore. And people are going to be like,
you know, I bet. I bet you're
what's wrong with you?
I bet if I talk quieter,
I bet that the only person that really
has issue with you knows as you,
you know, your wife loves you, your
kids love you. You got friends,
you find, um, I wouldn't
do it. I wouldn't do okay.
You think, you think that I
haven't looked into, you know,
whatever Michael Jackson had bleached
out of him to put a little bit of that in
me so I can walk where shorts,
can I have some of that
leftover pigment? Um, look, the,
you always going to have something
by yourself that you don't like.
I am a firm believer in just
keeping yourself in shape,
yelling over a baby and,
and basically, uh, you know,
aging naturally you look
way better. All right.
Whoever makes us knows what
they're doing. Um, however,
if you're going to go that road
road, I don't know. I don't know.
You better make sure you find somebody
good cause you could end up like that at
a, that chick from dirty dancing.
I thought it was gorgeous and I
loved her nose. Yeah. I love to know.
She looks beautiful. Yeah. She dyno. I
know she looks at, she looks so cute.
She got the lead in the movie
with that nose. Barbara Streisand.
Who else has a very strong
knows Sarah Jessica Parker.
Well what are, who are the
guys that have like strong knew
Joe Pardoning Joe by Joe Clark.
Nick. Yeah. That was that lady,
that lady when she made fun of his nose
and he said you need to lose about 40
pounds before you talk to me.
Bitch. One of the great lines ever,
and that her husband turned
around and when she complained,
looked at Joe to one look at Joe and
then started yelling at me. I was like,
you fucking, oh, sorry. Um, I'm not
gonna lie. That's what I would've done.
I would picked the smaller guy.
Wow. What are you saying? What are you
sure you say, pay attention to me, man.
It's odd to you. Oh, you can talk
to me anytime you want. All right.
As girlfriend's dad for hand in
marriage and he denied. Oh No,
whoa, whoa. Okay. We've got to read this
one. Whoa. Maybe that'd be quiet. Okay.
This one's is riveting. You gotta
listen to this one, Kiddo. All right.
Hi Sir. Hi Sir. William Berth. Hey Lauren.
You know what's so funny is the amount
of people they're going to say mean
stuff. I get it. She's
cute, but I swear to God,
if you bring your kid on
that bucket. Um, all right.
Long Time Fan. Uh, thank
you for all the laugh.
She got me through some hard times
and I am thankful to that. All right,
that's all. Thank you very much. Anyways,
I've been dating my current girlfriend
for five years. Come this November.
I'm 25 and she is 24 I've
been thinking about proposing,
so I decided to do an old tradition by
asking your father's hand in marriage.
Now that's f that's a classy
move. The Dad's like that stuff.
I also asked her mother to be sure to
be there as she is very close to both of
them.
I took them out to dinner and I told them
how much I loved her and how much she
means to me, et Cetera, et cetera.
Once I was done giving my speech, they
just stared at me like I had three heads.
They didn't give me their blessing to
marry their baby and went on saying that
they don't think that I
get along with all that.
They don't think that I get
along with their siblings well,
and it seemed awkward when
we, the family are together.
Oh my God.
They said that they felt like I would
try to move their daughter away from her
family because of my job and
she belongs with her family.
Oh No.
Should I keep dating hoping that something
changes or that the relationship with
their parents can't be repaired or
should I just give up on this five year
relationship? Any help would be greatly
appreciated. Thanks. I call that sucks.
Yes. And I can tell you this
right now, marrying into that.
I know that f a nightmare. That's
going to be a nightmare. Yeah.
You better love this girl. Cause I'll
tell you buddy. Yeah. Yeah. That uh,
that sounds like those
parents are going to screw up.
Did they live on a compound that sounds
like the Rayburns in bloodline or
something you're trying to marry into one
of those families? Yeah, I would walk.
He's got to talk to his girlfriend
about it and be like, listen,
I wanted this to be a surprise.
But I went out and I asked your parents
about getting married because I wanted
to do it the right way and this is what
they told me and see what she says.
Like, and I think you just
kind of go from there.
But what are they free masons
or something, you know,
you marry into the family too.
So if you don't get along with them on
that level and they're already looking at
you [inaudible] it sounds like some
blue blood. Yeah. I don't know.
You know the hedges never
need clipping her away.
She the youngest is she like what
I, I'm just, I'm curious as to,
did you not see this coming whatsoever?
Cause I would find that a
little hard to believe. Um,
but maybe he hadn't spent much time with
the, well, if he didn't see it coming,
that would mean that he's a dope and
maybe that's why they don't want him to
marry the kid.
Sky's got no anticipation
skills. He doesn't see what's,
what's the hand in front of his face.
Obviously you know that you don't
get along with the siblings.
I feel like that probably
wasn't a surprise to you.
It sounds like nobody in the
family likes you, but that woman,
so she's going to have
to then make a decision,
you or them,
which is very romantic for somebody in
their twenties but eventually as you
start having kids and stuff, Christmases
and all that or a gun. Oh Dude, I,
I swear, I don't know
how much you love her,
but this would be a great thing to
walk away from if you could do it.
That's five years. That's a long, you
know, now he's 25 it's a five year,
25 it's c shouldn't the first three
years he shouldn't have been in a
relationship. You gotta be a
free agent in college. Huh?
You gotta you gotta get the
lay of the land out there.
I mean no pun intended over there. Yeah.
Maybe they think you're
just too young or, well, no,
they said why they don't approve.
So I think you, if you're really,
you gotta talk to your girl about
it. They don't like Ah, yeah,
you gotta talk to your girl and see what
she says. Do a favor. Just dump her.
So then she doesn't know why and then
she won't blame her family's it because
you're not going to marry into that. I
would leave. I would leave right now.
Okay. We're moving onto the next
question. I would leave. No, you went in.
He's got a Tazza about it. Oh
my twenties. I wouldn't have,
cause I would have been smart enough.
But in my forties if your family
was just like, yeah, you know,
we just don't like it though. And
I would just be like, all right,
well yeah and I agree with that,
but he has to talk to her about it.
You gotta tell her what happened.
Can you get the little crazy
person here crawling all over me?
Where'd your she just dropped it.
She just dropped it. It's right.
It's right here. She's going for the
computer. Oh, there. There you go, buddy.
Here you go. Okay, come here. All
right, let's look at the last one.
Girlfriend's sociopathic
mother. And yet can you give me,
can you give a woman,
because women never writing into this
podcast cause I'm such an asshole.
Can you give some quick advice
here? This woman went on Facebook.
She's been with this guy for two
years. She says they're happy.
He does everything right, everything's
fine. But she checked his Facebook. Why?
Because you guys are happy
and everything is going okay.
Why did you check to see how
much my check was for today? Huh?
Oh my God,
I can't believe you're just putting me
out on front street like that because you
guys snoop, it's what you do. Um,
anyways, I was just curious. See,
now you're going to have everybody with
the gold digging. W h. O. R. E comments.
That's not why you did it was
because we did a job together.
And you wanted to see what I made versus,
yeah. Job baggies for the family job.
Becky's for the family. Yeah.
And you wanted to see how much
I made versus what you made.
Obviously I know you're gonna
make way more than I make. Okay.
I was just happened to be there.
I mean they did request me,
but that's a whole other story. Anyway,
boyfriend's Facebook straight to the
wait, wait, wait, wait. Let's
go back to the check there.
Why I want to either is I like watching
new twists in the awkwardness that I
live in day to day. So anyway,
she goes to check the Facebook
messenger and she said,
I saw that he is writing on a weekly
basis with an ex colleague of his,
a beautiful young lady. Uh, the thing is
that they were close at work back then,
but he quit three months
ago. Okay. Keep going.
That's it.
I just don't believe in Male, female
friendships. I'm talking from experience
bap, bap, bap, bap band. What'd
he say? What'd he say? Uh,
and what's the question?
What are you doing? Go back.
We're watching some videos and stuff
on his phone and the search few.
I saw list of a few girls names.
Other than that, he's great to me.
Uh, yeah. Listen, this is why you
don't go snooping in social media or,
and phone. Because if you find
something you could, the thing is,
if you are looking in that direction,
you're looking for something.
So any little thing,
no matter how innocent is going to
get you all fucked up in the head.
So if you're going to go looking for
stuff, you're going to go find stuff.
So either drop it or confess that you've
been a little snoopy snoop and you're
paranoid and you're insecure.
But I think you should just zip it
and move on and not look at his,
his social media or his phone anymore.
Wow. I said she should actually
ask them about that. That guy.
Sure. The lady, I will listen to the
lady here. Well, I said it either one.
You gotta like fess up
and be like, listen,
I've been feeling kind of insecure lately
and I went on your Facebook and I saw
that you messenger
somebody in, first of all,
I apologize for invading your privacy
because I wouldn't appreciate it if you
did that to me. But second of all, since
I've done it both, who is this bitch?
Alright, girlfriends
sociopathic, we mugged shit.
But you know you're wrong for
looking at his Facebook and you know,
you're looking at wrong for
looking at his phone. You're wrong.
You're wrong for that.
So just know that girlfriend's
sociopathic mother.
Hey Billy boule. I can't see that
in front of about that word. I know,
but still, uh,
not sure if this is the right
place for m m questions,
but I'm in dire need of
redheaded. See Note, wisdom. Uh,
so I've been dating this lady for about
a year now and her mother is a next
level piece of crap. Uh,
there are countless examples.
Her site psychopaths the of psychopath up.
There are countless examples.
Her psychopaths that they always leave
out words I already read bad enough,
but to trim the fat on the
story story. I'll uh, do,
I'll cite a couple of scenarios.
She has repeatedly asked me whether I use
protection whilst banging her daughter
and when I've responded yes,
she goes on to say she has no
evidence that I do use protection.
What would there be evidence?
Yeah, where would they be evidence?
No effing clue. Unless
you're banging her house.
Did she checking the wastepaper basket.
Don't want her daughter to get pregnant.
I am 21 years old and she is called my
mother on multiple occasions to ask to
meet up with her and my girlfriend
dad to talk about my girlfriend and I.
My mother's obviously
declined the invitation as
she's continued to pursue yet
she's continued to continue
to persist. Other than that,
she is the helicopter parent
of the century and calls
my girlfriend at least 15
times a day to tell her
how to live her life.
I hate this woman with a burning passion,
but I don't know what to do
about it with my girlfriend.
My girlfriend is tried to set
boundaries with the mother,
but it has had no luck or
just don't answer the phone.
I think about the future and I
never want to see this woman again,
let alone have her be in the law,
be an in law or the grandparent to my
children. I'd love to hear what thanks.
Thanks. And go after yourself. Yeah.
I mean this scene where this
guy is thinking at 21 that
other guy should've been
thinking at 25 like you're
gonna marry into that.
So I mean you're young enough
where you know, I'm sure, Huh?
Your girlfriend's only a
few years out of the house,
but she needs just don't
answer the phone. Yeah,
she just doesn't and she's worried her
daughter's too young and is gonna like
leave her forever and all that stuff.
She's like attached. She's not,
I don't think she's associate
man. Who knows who's kid who,
neither one of us know this woman.
Neither one of us know this woman.
We don't have enough
information, but we're going out.
We have to go off of
what people write to us.
That's the only way that we can
do, we have to let go all in.
It's like when you watch a TV
show, you're just got to watch it.
You can't be like, well,
that would never happen in Babba
that you just got to like, yeah,
this isn't Dr Phila.
I'm not pretending to like solve
somebody's problems within 22 minute.
Yo need to stop punching her in
the face and stop doing math.
Okay. When we return. Yeah.
You gotta talk to your girl, your
obviously your girlfriend knows, but yeah.
You just gotta ignore the mother. Yeah.
Just ignore. But yeah, I know a
piece of truth. She's divorced.
She's calling like 15 times a day and
she's asking about this sex life and she's
calling their parents. That's weird.
That's really, that's crossing the line.
Shoving off the Buffalo. Yeah.
You gotta respect your kids, uh,
boundaries, like their own personal space.
You can't be calling somebody's
boyfriend asking them if they're using
protection. Ask your daughter if
she's on the pill and if she's not,
get her some otherwise, what are you
calling me for lady? Yeah. That's weird.
Ah, Jesus gets you pause out
of my pants. A lady. Exactly.
Alright, that is the podcast for
this week. Congratulations to me.
But when it all this money
on the red sock socks,
making baseball exciting by gambling,
there's your lesson. You are so
adorable and all you do is smile.
A happy baby. Be In a good
mood all day. Look at you.
She's getting mobile.
Everybody in anything's that she
sees she wants to get her hands on.
Then she gets her hands on and then she
wants to go to something else and I'm
going to tell you something right now.
Nobody can flip over faster
than this one. By the way.
Shout out to Rick Flair.
I'm hope he's doing better.
I heard that he's a recovering and I'm uh,
looking forward to seeing them doing
the flare chop, the flare Strut,
the flair flop, all of
it. Absolute legend. Um,
we already lost one of the funniest
guys of all time. And Jerry Lewis.
Yup. Dick Gregory.
Do you realize how many stories went
with those two guys just today and forget
about Don Rickles.
That just closes a
porthole to like Sinatra,
the whole rat pack, Red Fox,
Richard Pryor, all of that.
That porthole just closed.
So I hope somebody made a documentary.
All right. That's the podcast.
Everybody or I did. I type on my
dad's saved today on the couch.
She was a fiery, the face plant
right off. And I just like,
like lightning quick near lightning
quick like a freckled pasty Cobra.
I was able to grab her. All right. That's
it. She started, she's going for the,
uh, the mix of here. All
right, you guys, I will,
I'll check in on you in Thursday. Set
a nice cause the kids here. All right.
Let's see. All right.