Again. Hey, what's going on?
It's Bill Burr and It's time for the
Thursday afternoon. Just before Friday.
Monday morning podcast.
and ahhh
just checking in on you, just
checking. Can I stop doing that people?
I don't have any new way of doing it.
Can I just say I'm just checking on you.
I'm going to do that for awhile and
every once in awhile I'll screen. Okay.
It'll make it special. Um,
anyways, as you're heard, the, uh,
the laughter in the background, uh,
we're welcoming the lovely Nia to the
Thursday afternoon podcast just before
Friday. Um, um, and you wanted
to clear your name so to speak,
for drugging the man you
allegedly love. I didn't drug you.
You took it voluntarily. No, I
didn't get, yes, you're taught,
you're taught while you're talking to me.
You ain't doing nothing because I
didn't like flipping into your fucking
cornflakes or whatever. Okay. I asked
you if you wanted and you were like,
all right, you fucking,
you're just a lay liar.
I'm not alive. What do you mean liar?
How many times did you ask me to take
it before I actually took the fuck?
I don't remember. See that's the
magical powers of the pocket. No,
you'll be a pulling of Ronald Reagan
right now. I'm really magically erases.
I don't remember. Probably a
couple times now. It's like,
I don't want to do that. It's going to
get me all fucked up. And you said no,
no, no. This is mellow. Yes, I did say
that. Oh, this is coming back to you now.
Yeah. Yeah. And then like
flat grounds. It was a mellow,
but you're kind of a lightweight when it
comes to the we. Yeah. So, well, yeah.
One day if you didn't drink at
all, I wouldn't be like, hey,
have a couple of fucking Yeager's.
That's nothing. Tastes like syrup.
I wouldn't do that to you. I'd let
you sip on a beer or something.
Here is disgusting. Get your like
a wine cooler. Not for nothing.
Wine cooler as our wine coolers, I
used to drink those James puck cookies.
Don't, don't really taste sector do they?
They definitely taste more like
weed than cookie. All right.
And Yeager definitely tastes more
like Jaeger than licorice. Well,
I would just like to w which
is a gross too. Why do people,
is that what Yeager is
out there? Bass note,
I forgot to talk in like perfume terms
like you're talking in musical sense.
No, I've gotta be honest with
you. I don't even know what,
I don't even know what
it is. It's disgusting.
It's like what is it
considered a vomit? I never,
I never I liquor isn't it
now I all, I know the core,
it's just,
it's one of those things that like when
I was first living in New York and we'd
go hang out at this awful bars on the
upper east side with a bunch of like
banker kids and young stockbrokers
and Frat boys, I were like,
let's have heavy Yeager. And then
inevitably they'd put on, you know,
living on a prayer and everyone would
say it was the most horrifying experience
and I hate those kinds of bars and I
hate that kind of vibe for that reason.
And I feel like if I got talked
into doing a Yeager shot with Shane,
I'm trying to go along and have fun.
It would just be the thing that
put me over and to, to vomitorium.
So Yeager is not disco. It's for
people who don't know how to drink.
Well this is what it really
is though. What is it?
The people in around the world probably
drink it differently than we do. Okay.
Yeager meister is a German digestif so
this is like, you have like a big meal.
You said that that makes
sense in France. Yeah.
Made with 56 herbs and spices at a
strength of 35% alcohol by volume,
whatever the flow, whatever,
35%. I mean that's a lot.
No wonder people mainline
it like fucking white China.
But a couple of drag
references in there for you.
What's white shines that heroin think
I think, I don't know. Why are you,
um, oh, there you go. It's a
digestive so it's not supposed to. Uh,
you're not supposed to be doing what
people are doing with it. 35% alcohol too.
That it makes a lot of sense. I would
just also like to say in terms of the,
the edible does that a lot. By
the adjusted it is a lot. Um,
the edible that you ingested, it was
cut into fours as is recommended.
It's not like you ate the entire cookie.
So I want people to understand that it
wasn't like you got the whole entire
thing. Oh yeah, yeah. But still,
I mean a lightweight like me need
you. I was like fucking tripping.
He would 70 proof. That's what
Jaeger is. That's also insanely high.
Oh, this is not 70 proof. I mean it's
up there. It's a shot. We'll look,
let me just, let me just, I'm
like Jack Daniels let, let's see.
I'd like to know these old Jack. Oh my
buddy. Your Buddy Jack Daniel. My buddy.
I visited him the other night. I only,
I only talked to him once so I usually
have a long conversation that slowly
dissolves into tears. You
know what I mean? Jack,
do you like Jamison? Uh,
yeah I do. It's all right.
I don't once, once your fancy and
I want you to become a snob. Yeah.
Jamie's like,
I go when I'm in the mood yet when I
want to get fucking hammered James,
you know, if I want to have like,
you know something nice and
pretend I actually am cultured,
I'll go with more of a scotch
or something like that.
For the fact that stuff that you have
that's in that like suitcase looking
thing. That coffin. Yeah. What does that,
that blue stuff is that
Johnny Walker blue?
It's like a half gallon of Johnny Walker
blue. They don't even, a lot of it,
I don't even sell that bottle.
When I went in and bought it,
they had it in their liquor store for
10 years and [inaudible] was coming out
here. So I was like, I gotta get
this thing. I'm just laughing.
Like the label's different. The thing,
it's the sickest fucking [inaudible]
suitcase. It's like, it's so pretty.
Like it's leather and it's like, really?
What's that other one that's really fancy
when you really have dedicated to damn
damaging your liver?
What's another one you have that's really
fancy that you haven't even drank yet?
You've had it here for like three
years. Pappy van Winkle. Right.
Did you break that up and when Paul
Versey was here? No, we did what I put,
I drank, I drank pappies with him in a,
what the hell are we?
Nashville. So it's here,
but you just haven't drank a yeah,
I'm just waiting for that right time
when all everybody's over, you know,
to break it open. And uh, when
would that be? I don't know.
In other words, you want a shot?
I'll, I'll open and try like,
I want to try that shot.
When we went to the,
what was at the Polo
Lounge and we had that,
that fancy shit that you were dying to
get, which stunk. Yeah. You were like,
Eh. What was that Lou? Louis the
14th 13th or something like that.
Nine zillion dollars in. It's
stunk. I've had better, I bet.
Better cognacs and that one
comes out. That one's a,
that one's like totally like a,
that's like the boy band
of cognacs. It's which one?
Cause everybody who doesn't know
anything about it like me fucking sees.
No though the Konya, there's a lot of
snobs that say pappies is for the prices.
Fucking overrated. But uh,
it's still delicious though.
The way to get all of those
is just to buy the shine.
If you go out and buy the bottle,
you're an asshole, which I am.
You know what I mean? They're
completely overpriced.
But it's fun when you have people come
over and you break out the bottle,
it sits a nice thing to do as a
host. But if you just going to,
you shouldn't have a buy a bottle of
that just for yourself and then just sit
there. That's what I mean.
I guess you're saving money.
Sat there for like a few years now.
You gotta you gotta break it out.
You know the old me, when I, when this,
how ignorant I was with and I'm still
don't know much about this shit.
All right, so save you fucking
Cunty tweets. Can you just in a,
in a nice polite way, be like, actually
it's not 30% alcohol. How that fuck,
cause I know it's not 30% alcohol, it's
like 30% of something, Blah Blah Blah.
Some egg heads. We were Doris, you
know like just as a human being,
you're supposed to know everything, right?
You know you're into math and booze.
So you know the answer to that. You
know, I know the answer to other things.
I lovely bartender or mixologist perhaps
listening who actually really knows and
it's not going to just like,
I don't want to talk to a mixologist
cause I don't like that word. That was,
that's right up there with footie.
Right. I'm 40 which I've even said.
And then after a while it's
like, you know, I don't like E.
I don't like that at the end. Food
Lilly. I'm a foodie. I'm a mixologist.
So what about can
bartender, what about this
deal hard? It has to
be a bartender though.
Can you imagine switching
places with a bartender?
I went on a really busy
night. It's like, it looks,
I work on restaurant industry.
Yes. Were you a bartender? No.
But at one point I worked the,
I worked at grill with one of those tall
chef I was last and I was the busboy
and I washed dishes all at the same time.
It was like a fucking
Carol Burnett sketch.
The restaurant was going out of business
and initially I was just the bus boy
and a dishwasher. And then they had
this guy working the grill and a,
I remember he quit or got fired. He
used to just get hammered and dry.
He had a van and used to
just take restaurant panel,
the restaurant business
fucking nuts. Right.
And this guy used to drive this van and
he came in one day and just had this
fucking like somebody just took a belt
and diagonally smacked him across his
forehead.
And what happened was he was driving
home to his parent's house and he pulled
any was so shit faced t they hit one of
their cars or the tree and when his head
went to slam against the windshield,
the visor was down a little
bit and he like bent it.
And that was one of those old school like
metal ones. He bent it with his head,
um, which was probably traveling a good
25 miles an hour when he hit it. And,
um, so anyway, he got
fired. So then they had me,
uh, flip the burgers. Yeah. Ashley
Brochette and that type of shit. No,
I think I became a dishwasher and the
bus boy yet it was just like a bacon
wrapped shrimp that was
seasoned. And uh, so I would,
I would fucking set up the tables
and the lunch rush would come in,
which wasn't much of a rush.
We were going out of business,
but I would be sitting there
cooking shit trying to look suave.
Like this was his fancy fucking place,
which it wasn't cause I was on the
grill and I was sort of eyeballing the
lunchroom, waiting for people to finish.
And as I saw people finishing up,
I would sort of casually duct down where
they couldn't see me like below the
grill. Like I was, uh, you know,
getting more food or something.
And I would pop up in, my apron
would be off. I had the bow tie,
the whole busboy thing
on underneath the apron.
And I take the hat off and I would
run out there plus the table,
bring the dishes back, rinse them,
set them up and then I would run back,
flip the fucking burger and then go back
out and set the table in case somebody
else came out. Oh my God. And
then I would go back. Yeah.
I ended up burning a guy's
hand. Cause from this stress,
I remember I made a burger.
I've told this story before I made this
fucking Burger. Knows this kid Jason,
this Metallica Fan. Jesus Christ. Clear.
Holy Shit. Woo. She been out today. Yeah,
I let her out. This letting her out.
She doesn't shit. She just peas.
She should go for a stroll. I think she's
farting cause she's dead ass asleep.
Yeah, but she doesn't care
if she shits in the house.
She doesn't have to clean it up.
Look at her though. She's passed out.
Woo Cleo. I put a bed right by the,
by the window where the sun comes in
and that's the, I have to go soon.
So can we talk about this Jamison thing,
how much or whatever Jack Daniels you are.
And I promise everyone I'll finish the
story about burning the guy's hand. Oh,
right. Sorry. Um, what was it you were
looking up? How much proof is, uh,
okay. Uh, oh Jesus Christ.
Come on man. I just asked the
question. Oh, Jack Daniels.
I just won't inject Daniels.
I should write proof.
That helps you go to the Wikipedia page.
Can we also talk about how your social
media game needs to step it up a little
bit? It's 80 proof. That
seems like a lot too. Well,
Jameson is only 70 proof.
Like what it is about Jamison is
it is you're drinking something.
You supposed to sip something
that you're drinking,
that you're fucking slamming and
then they do a bunch of them.
And it's really the, I mean,
I would think that the, the,
the sugar is just off the
fucking charts for them.
Remember the first time I ever
had Jamieson was when we were in,
when you did a show in Dublin, our
first time in Ireland. And you know,
I fucking love Ireland and I
love the people there that go.
And then you'd be shit. Oh
my God. It was, it was the,
that was the first time because
you know, I don't drink beer.
That was when that guy gave you shit,
right? Yeah. When we were leaving,
we stand on a street corner.
This Irish guy is on a bicycle,
riders every European seems
to be, and he came up,
got a little turned around trying to
find our hotel. And I went, I'm so am I,
so let me just ask this guy. And
I said, um, excuse me, Sarah,
do you know where at such and such is?
He just pauses and he looks
at me and he goes, I do.
And he's still staring at me and
I look at you and I'm like, um,
are you gonna tell me? I'm like,
yeah, I remember you laughed.
And he laughed, won me over and you were
like, well, you're going to tell me.
And he's like, I'm like a moist.
And then he told me and it was all going
to gave me like a big smile and I was
like, are you fucking Irish? But
you know you Irish men, you like,
you like black women. So I feel
like maybe that was part of it too.
I think we like women in general.
I feel like everybody likes
black women though. Like the,
like everybody likes me. Let's
just go off on a nice ego trip.
But [inaudible] your
social immediate like,
so I seeing me do Snapshat are
you not into doing snapchat?
Not at all. Why or Instagram?
You have an Instagram.
I'm not into Twitter. I'm not
into like going on Facebook.
I don't like any social. You go there.
Can we talk about you just go there
because you I have to do it or else you,
your career just dies. And
that's where everybody's at.
So you've gotta be there. Everybody's
at snapchat now. All are there. Yeah,
they are. Oh you horse. We'll be back.
You guys see your social media whores.
You just run it around the block.
It's true. It's like, it's fun. Those
fucking club kids. They go to this spot,
the spots, the spot.
Then everybody's there and then they
run across the street to the new spot.
And it's the same fucking people.
Just a different background. Um, okay.
Isn't that what it is? I haven't
got that new clubs. Speaker.
Oh grandpa. I never had. What
else? Don't you understand?
But how come you're not doing Instagram?
You take pictures all the time.
Why don't you ever cause they're nuts
for people there for me. Oh, I see.
Although there's a couple of killer ones
from how great were the pictures from
Dean Del Rey's 50th
birthday party. Amazing.
You fucking MSD. I missed
it. I missed it. That's true.
I'm sorry, Dean. Happy Birthday.
Dean del Ray. He's an entrepreneur,
was one of s, I don't
know how you taught this.
This fucking guy turns 50 years old.
He packs out the El Rey theater.
His name is Dean del Ray. So it
was Delray at the El Ray. Right.
So he goes out there. It
was Joe Barton x hosting wearing an ACDC
fucking one at like a Hawaiian shirt.
But it's an ACDC shirt. Right.
He brings up red bed, red bed,
fucking kills it.
Then it was Dee del Ray who
fucking murdered one of the
best sets I've ever seen
a map. Then Krista, Leah, then Joe Rogan.
And then I had to follow all
those fucking monsters. Right.
And then after that he had a live band
came out and he sang the entire highway
to hell album. He's such
a great fucking, yeah,
when I tell you he fucking crushed
it. Yeah. Like first of all,
the song that they opened with was
a live wire now for ACDC maniacs.
I didn't even know this. They all
went bond. Scott was still alive.
Their original singer, they always opened
with livewire on all their live shows.
And when he died in tribute to him,
they retired the song and they didn't
even play it in concert for like fucking
30 years until recently. They
started playing it again.
So because he was playing,
um, the highway to hell album,
which was the last bond Scott album.
He also has the sickest fucking tattoo
on his side of bond Scott's face,
which I know sounds cheesy, but if
you see it, it's fucking costumer.
If it's good, it's on
funding. Believable. Okay.
Cause otherwise it's unbelievable.
I haven't people's like famous people's
spaces on you unless that is a fun, no,
it's unreal. Amazing Tattoo. I remember
when Jim Florentine was down the store,
I had to show him like, dude,
you got to see this cause Florentines
obviously you know that metal show.
I was like, you gotta see this?
And he goes again, he's got a bond.
Scott Tattoo. And I saw it in his
face like out and then he saw it.
He was just like,
next thing you know they're off in a
corner talking about eighties metal.
Did they play this song when we went
to CAC ACDC all those years ago?
I don't remember if they played. Yeah.
So anyways, so here's the funny thing.
I go on last and what's his face
dean? So when you finish your set,
just go like, ah, you guys ready
for some rock, whatever. Right?
You ready for some rocks?
You got? Oh, you rating.
And then I fought.
So right then the [inaudible]
Bam was supposed to kick in and Rudy
Sarto from fucking a quiet ride.
Ozzy Osborne was this
company. I do do, do, do, do,
do they begin the fucking
song? I didn't realize that.
They didn't know that that's
what was gonna happen.
So nobody was on the stage and I
didn't know, turn around. It looks like
you said rock and roll. I was like, you
guys ready? Put some rock and roll. No,
I, yeah, I turned around. There
was nobody there and I was like,
it's going up for a few minutes.
Longest walk ever. And
I get off. So anyways,
they start off with fucking livewire
and Delray kind of sounds like Bon Scott
and he's fine. He's fucking murders.
And then they played the
whole highway to hell album.
[inaudible] um, then they
ended, uh, they brought out,
um, uh,
hang on a second. Sorry. I
almost knocked my computer off.
Then they bring up Dave Lombardo
from a,
I'm fucking going blank here. I'm
trying to name his new fucking band.
Dead Cross. Okay. Slayer.
Obviously he goes out,
he plays a let there be rock and then
they played, um, they played Motorhead,
ace of spades and fucking
Dean like channeled Lemmy.
It was fucking unbelievable. Can I
tell you like when you missed it,
I sat in on two songs. I played
get it hot and if you will,
what is so enjoyable about being with
you amongst other things but like with
being with the money, that's really
great tip when you leave. But um,
no it's like being with someone
who is so different from you.
Like obviously we're
an interracial couple,
there's a bit of an age
difference between, oh Jesus,
she just kicked me with
rights and left here. I know,
but the thing is like I learned so much
stuff about things I wouldn't normally
know. Like, I like rock music
and stuff, but like you know,
your dedication to it and like your
childhood or your like being a teenager,
the stuff that really moves you is like
nothing I ever would have considered
before. And people always
make fun of like hair,
metal and all those bands that
you like legitimately loves.
And when you talk about the musicianship
and the like the trace of guns was
there from, from La guns. Yeah,
like all that kind of stuff that I've
seen documentaries about like oh the
English noser the composer F is for family
music and from person and from velvet
revolver. Yes. All that kind of
stuff. Like since I've been with you,
I've seen Michael, Michael, Devin
from Whitesnake, I've seen ACDC,
we saw a velvet revolver, we
saw food fighters, we've seen,
um, I'm sure there's some further
volts them crooked vultures. Um,
what's, oh what the band that Josh is
in Queen of the Stone Age. Oh yeah.
Jesus Christ.
Like all these rock shows that I never
would have seen if I was not with you.
And I think that's really fucking cool
cause I already like all different kinds
of words now. I really, I saw
Erica Badu with the roots. Yup.
We saw Bruno and for hours I
wouldn't see that. Yeah, I wouldn't,
I wouldn't even go on scene.
Uh, speaking of white music,
I want to go see a drink your
big black cow and get outta here.
Oh, steely Dan. Yeah, that's
right. I wouldn't have seen them.
And that was one of the
sickest fucking live shows.
It was so amazing at the Hollywood bowl.
And that's my dad. My Dad was into his,
into steely Dan. So uh, yeah,
no, we've gone to see some,
we got to see some live
music coming up this year.
That's one of the things we
like to do. I've seen so many.
I actually like seen
like the smaller ones.
I saw arrivals son and that was somebody
that Dean del Ray told me about.
I love them. They're great.
Really fucking great.
I saw him in his little ass club.
They gotta be in a bigger
place now cause I've heard,
I heard them on the radio recently. Um,
they'll plug in some big
show that they were doing,
but like the lead singers
just got to fucking force.
It's ridiculous in their drummers
and saying, who is the guy when we,
when you did that Rhonda as kiss
charity that Mark McGrath hosted.
Great guy by the way.
So the first time I ever had a
pickle back was with Mark McGrath,
a little shot of Jamison and a pickle
back. Disgusting. I'll never do it again.
But he swears by it, but okay. So it
was, he was there for two to somebody,
random person in the crowd. He
goes, he goes, what'd you say sir?
Sing it number one song that you wrote
in 1997. Absolutely. Then he signed that.
I just want to fly. I thought everybody
in there was singing like the,
all the lyrics to it. Um, but he
a very funny self deprecating go.
Yeah. Navarro was there.
Juliette Lewis Casha but there were other
bad deaf mckagan was there obviously,
um, guns and roses. And
then who else was there?
There was some other Gilby
cluck, I don't know who that is.
He was one of the guitars
to guns and roses.
Second generation of
guns commissioner was,
they had Billy idol showed up at
the ends. Even Billy idol. Steven,
Steve Stevens. Um, no, that
was Trump's by the way. Who?
You don't know him but you know him
cause he's played on for everything from
like devote in nine inch
nails. Oh really? Okay. Yeah,
probably with Menudo at
some point. You know,
we did some sort of fucking studio
thing with them. Like fuck it.
I'll make it sound good. He's like
one of those guys you could just,
no matter what it is. Yeah, he's
played with fucking everybody.
All right. I got to get going. Are
you getting at it going, oh Nia,
y'all gone to jail? Yeah,
I'm going to the gym now and right now
and then yoga tonight, but I won't,
I'm dedicated. I'm saying it on the
podcast now. I said on my snapchat,
I'm going to say it on my, on the Napa
chat on the podcast. I love snapchat.
I'm going to do yoga every day. This
month, 29 days. I'm kind of cheating,
but while you're kind of cheating,
well it's a full like 30 31 days.
So I feel like I'm kind of
cheating. But you know, it's a,
it's black history month. So
I mean,
I'm just saying years ago I wouldn't have
been allowed to go into a yoga studio.
You weren't alone. I wasn't allowed
so I gotta do and go back far enough.
You weren't allowed to even
read the word Yoga. Exactly.
So now I have to say this is by far and
away the widest Shit I've ever done is
to do yoga every day and talk about rock
music. Yeah. Yeah. Today is topping it.
But that's okay. I love it. I love
you. I feel so clear ethnic today,
like a loader, a Burrito or
something to try to balance it off.
I don't know if that's something that
you want to say that you're doing that,
but food, I guess it is, I guess is,
there's so much though. How is
that not ethnic food? I guess.
You know what makes something ethnic food
isn't why I'm saying can you stop with
that? You just said something fucked
up. Tone Jesus Christ, and I tell him,
you fucking say anything. I just
said I'm going to get the Burrito.
Was it God damn joke?
Will I look because say that in during
election year told me that there is so
much Mexican food that they
don't really eat in Mexico,
that they are just sort of
developed for us. Gringos.
Although I don't think I'm a Gringo.
You're definitely doing, yeah. Yeah, yeah.
The same way that if we
fucking, if we moved down there,
we'd fucking weed lighten up the steak
or something. It's just the way it goes.
All right, burrito. We, we,
we'd have to adjust our shit.
We'd have to throw more spice into the
cornflakes so they wouldn't buy our sh
bland shit down there.
Our European underseas in food land. Fuck.
Most boring ass cereal
is cornflakes. Yeah,
but you know what this saw in
corn flag, the solid, the points,
the solid and you're like, okay. And
like 30 minutes later you're hungry.
All right. I've got a question for you.
Name is cereal with a point. Oatmeal.
It's not a cereal. It is the
hot cereal. No, it isn't. Yeah,
it's considered a cereal. Look it up.
What do you want to bet? I
don't know. It's a porridge
is I like that there's enough people
out there in the war. Ended many wheats.
Is oatmeal healthy? Let me see if
I'm anybody else? Who's dumb enough?
Is oatmeal a theory? A
carb, a grain, a starch,
a whole grain complex. Car.
Alkaline. A good source of fiber.
Acidic. It's harbor a
cereal. Way down the bottom.
So someone did have this
question. See it pops up.
Do you consider oatmeal
is cereal is oatmeal?
See in cereal is same
thing. Wikipedia. Breakfast,
cereal, health benefits. Breakfast cereal,
I guess it is is oatmeal
cereal. What is oatmeal?
All right. There's a lot of people
with a lot of questions here.
I don't have time to go through
all of this. If the growths,
we're going to get tweets. We're
going to pizzas, cereal and alcohol.
That's how, that's how very old meal can
be eaten. Raw with milk like a cereal.
Okay. Or heated and
eaten as porridge. Okay.
Okay. I never said it couldn't
be considered porridge.
I would just say what you never did
say it couldn't be okay. All right.
Well can I get extra points
for knowing the word porridge?
Is that a word that people
have never heard of?
Is that something that's
new day you think?
Or you've known me for 12
years and you think Shanie yes.
When was the last time you ever
heard me use the word porridge?
I don't think I've ever heard
it. Oh my God. 12 years.
Our anniversary is coming up. Our
12 years. He is stay focused now.
I'm like you now I'm add. I still remember
the bird in the hand story. Oh good.
Go back to it. Cause I'm leaving a, no,
I've never heard you use the word
porridge. But um, you know what?
You're going to yoga and arts. Well,
our 12 year anniversary is this month.
How exciting is that? You
don't look very excited. No,
cause I just realized you're going
to yoga for Hollywood purposes.
What do you mean for Hollywood PR?
I'm going, you're not me. Purpose.
It's like when I went to go,
then I went to a fucking boxing gym and
they started calling me billary swank
cause they, I was never,
I was never getting in the ring. You were
going to that boxing gym a lot though?
I was going to Gleason's gym. Yeah.
Yeah, yeah. What happened to that?
Well we moved out here so the commute
got a little difficult. But my trainer,
my trainer does boxing. He Trans
guys all the time. Yes. Young guys,
young fellows who still got that
in. Oh come on. You can still do it.
You still do pull ups out here and I'll
skip rope and I'm not going down to some
stinky ass fucking gym but eh, pretending
like I'm going to get in the ring.
I'm not dumb enough. It is.
It is and I'm slow as shit so I know I'm
going to get knocked on my ass for yoga
purposes for Hollywood cause
I'm not trying to be like
a yoga instructor or some
kind of, what are you saying?
I think you go in there to somebody in
there like has his screenwriting class
and you want to get like a discount.
Jesus. No Gigi. No, not at all.
All right, well I'm
going to go. All right.
Did they give you like a yoga name when
you go there? No, they do not. Okay.
They call me by my actual name and then
they remember my name and they're like,
thanks Nia for coming in. Good job
today. Do they call Uri Niacin Nini?
No mistake. Yo. Oh, I
like it though. Do you?
I though you're going to laugh
like those stupid stay. Alright.
I thought I was cute. Now I'm gonna
stay here now. I'm a stay here.
Stay in bed. You go to yoga,
Nama. Stay here. Oh Jesus.
By later. See you later.
I'm going to take fucking
stinky butt outside in a minute.
Then I'm throwing her right in the
fucking tub. You hear me? Anyways,
let me read some advertising and then
the Burnham's story and then we're going
to call it a fucking day here.
Oh, fucking day. Oh, all right.
Um, where the fuck am I? Oh,
headspace. Man. New
advertiser, headspace. Man,
don't harsh the mellow.
Please talk about your
experience with the product.
I don't even know what it is.
Use the following introduction to
accompany your anecdote. Hey everybody.
I don't know what the fuck
this is. Let's be honest.
Most of your problems start with
your mind, man. Fear, anger,
stress, anxiety,
depression, sleeplessness.
Is this going to be one of these
products that like if you have suicidal
thoughts, consult your doctor. What am I
pedal in here? They begin in your head,
but they can wreck your life.
Please include all of the following
points during your read. Well,
if you send it to me, I'm
going to read it. All right?
But it doesn't have to be that way.
You can make a major difference
in just 10 minutes a day.
The change comes through through guided
meditation with the new headspace app.
Oh, I like this. Okay.
This is some hippy shit.
My apologies to everybody
at headspace, man. Um,
headspace is a mess. Is meditation
made simple? You know something?
I gotta be honest with you. I
would actually download this.
I used to meditate to the second
side of Jane's addictions, a ritual,
however the fuck you say, the rest of it
I had. Space is meditation made simple.
It's guided meditation that you listen
to whenever you want, wherever you want,
right on your phone, computer or tablet.
Meditation is rooted in thousands of
years of tradition with thousands of
scientific studies that
show its positive effects,
like improving focus and relationship
harmony, whatever that means,
and decreasing anxiety and stress. Jesus,
is there anybody in the world that
needs to meditate more than me?
Join over 5 million uses already getting
some headspace man for free right now.
Uh,
download the free headspace app and begin
their take 10 program for 10 days of
guided meditation@headspace.com slash bar
there is no man the headspace man.
Take 10 program as 100% free way to
experience the benefits of meditation in
your busy modern life. So how
do you make money? I guess I'm,
I'm so addicted to it. After
10, I start paying for it.
Train your mind for a healthy, less
stress life. Start with free trial.
Your free trial today at
headspace.com/bird that's
headspace man.com/ [inaudible]
there's no man trunk club.
All right.
Don't waste a second of the new year
in a crowded mall with trunk club.
You can make 2016 your most stylish year
yet and the best part is you won't have
to do any work yourself. 2016 is
going to be a game changer for you.
You're going to get some top shelf ass
with the clothes you're pulling out of
this trunk. Your a fresh start.
Start the year off on the right foot and
the right pants with the right jacket
over the right shirt.
Trunk Club is here to handle your
wardrobe so you can focus on what matters
sticking out and the Hawaii.
Please include a shut up trunk club.
Take the hassle me in out of shopping
by finding the best clothes for you and
your style.
You'll look like 1 million bucks or at
least a thousand and that's about $300
better than anybody else in the club.
And you'll always have the perfect
clothes for the season@trunkclub.com slash
burgers simple questions answer
simple questions about your style,
preferences and size and
you'll be assigned an expert
stylist who hasn't made a
name for themselves yet.
Your stylists will hand pick clothes
from the best premium brands.
Just approve of what you like and send
back what you don't like and just like
that a trunk arrives on your doorstep
filled with handpicked clothes that are
perfect for you. Try them on,
keep what you like and easily return them
for easily return what you don't like
in their prepaid trunk. Trunk Club
is not a subscription service.
You only pay for the clothes you keep
from your trunk. No hidden charges,
just great clothes. It's a brand
new year full of possibilities.
We and with Trunk Club,
you'll start the year off looking
great clothes pick just for you.
Get started today at Trunk Club.
A Trunk Club will style you for
free plus free shipping both ways.
You only pay for the clothes that
you keep. You just fucking said this.
This is way too long to take
advantage of trunk club.
Go to trunk club.com/burr trunk
club.com/bar trunk club.com/bar.
All right, here we go. A little. What?
Can I, can I come in and, and, and
plug something really quickly? Yes.
I want to plug, can I kick it this
Saturday at nerd melt at meltdown comics?
Nine o'clock you guys have seen me
Instagram and Facebook and tweet all about
it. But a,
I'd love for you guys to come out with
some of the whole nine o'clock. Well,
we normally have tone bell, Al Jackson and
Joey Roses. Derosa Jodi Rosa, Joe de Rosa,
the teen idol sensation
from the OPD three program.
Oh Joey row
closes. But this Saturday we just
got tone and two special guests.
So guy should come and
check it out. Can I kick it?
9:00 PM meltdown comics. Who was
I supposed to yell? Yes you can.
Can I kick it? Yes you can. Thank you.
It's even, I know that one. You said
Dale Soul. What is that tribe called?
Quest. Oh, let's try calling. I only,
whenever I want those groups sound
the same to me. That's how white I am.
I know she need to just
go say, ah. All right.
Well you tell me when you can tell the
difference between fucking white snake
and white lion and great white.
Can you yeah, I can't.
Great White and gray and a lion head.
Whatever the fuck I just said.
White Lion White Lion had the guy
who sounded like Eddie van Halen,
a great white.
Had the guy with the raspy voice and
Whitesnake is fucking Whitesnake. Okay.
If you don't know them
and it's still today,
Daddy, he happy.
Um, she's laughing at me. All right.
Oh, look at who's here about,
oh boop, boop me undies.
Me undies. Take 'em off in a stall.
Boudou do to me on these me
undies dry him on a fucking towel.
I'm trying to make a run with that.
I don't know why you taking
them off in a truck stop.
Maybe you want to get banged in the ass.
The truck all appreciate how dry your
undercarriages as you're reading all the
fucking graffiti. That's gross. All
right. Mandy's everybody this year,
don't be predictable and show
up at your Valentine's date,
date dinner with some last minute box
of chocolates or a bouquet of roses.
Oh, shots fired.
Shots fired by me undies. Oh,
I'll tell you right now. I am.
I'm waiting for the [inaudible]
for speaking of rap music.
I think that they need an answer at
just like a, this is like when a,
that guy said the bridge was
over and the other guy said,
no it isn't right.
This is fucking Sherry's
berries and fucking, uh,
a flowers.com.
Wow saying they're saying that
the flowers are going to die.
The Roosevelt die in a week.
Anyways. I like me on these, man.
I like this 2016 they got a
little bit of an attitude.
Give the gift everyone is talking
about. Show you a special someone.
Just how much you care with a present.
You'll both love a gift that looks great.
It feels great. Something that
says you deserve the best.
Treat yourself and your bu to
a magic pair of [inaudible],
the world's most comfortable
underwear. You know, it's hilarious.
I thought you were just going to get
them for yourself and be like t your
Valentine. A.
Treat yourself to a nice set of
dry balls with a swinging dick.
Happy Valentine's Day.
I think Mandy should send us a pair of
matching undies for Valentine's Day.
I don't think they should.
Well I do me on these.
All right.
I'm not going to be able to walk around
wearing underwear that matches yours
cause you know they're going to
make it more a feminine. You know,
they're going to have to
lean your fucking way. Uh,
I don't need any guy
underwear with lace on it.
Yeah.
Oh, there's a visual Jesus that
even disturb me. All right.
Please include all of the following
points during your read note.
Modal is pronounced modal, modal.
This underwear is as comfy as it gets
for whoever fucking keeps writing MOH.
Dash D a. L you don't have any sort of
where I'm supposed to accent it, so,
so I know it's okay.
Modal, is it modal? Modal.
This underwear is the company as it
gets me undies are made of micro modal
mallow fabric meaning they're
twice as soft as cotton. You know,
someday I'm going to look that up to see
if to just not making that shit up and
they just don't feel great.
They look great to me on East Dot coms
com Mandy Mandy's comes in tuck tons of
cool prints and styles and new
designs come out every month.
You won't want to miss February's
limited edition design from the legendary
artists Keith Herring.
The retro design is inspired
by love making it the
perfect Valentine's Day gift.
This is when like the way black people
wear fucking pants with the the hanging
down off their,
their ass like this is the underwear for
them so they can be all you got them.
Limited edition joints. Say
sorry. That was, you know,
that was my idea of a black
guy, but it was all white guy.
Well you haven't pulled up.
Just study a fucking navel.
You just going to sit there sad and a
club knowing that nobody knows that you
have on this limited edition underwear.
And I think that that's why black people's
music is more uplifting than white
people.
That's why we have like the cure and all
that sad stuff is because nobody knows
that we're wearing
limited edition underwear,
but black people getting their prompts,
right? Oh, Devin, them June joints,
right? I remember them from
fucking 2014 all right,
grab yourself a pair and celebrate the
holiday sporty matching underwear with
your sweetheart. Emmy on d says,
this is just too fucking long.
You know what they are,
you know where to get them.
Go to [inaudible] dot com slash burb
Mandy's dot com slash [inaudible] for free
shipping at 20% off your first order of
the world's most comfortable underwear.
And lastly, well certainly not lately sip,
but growing up as a business owner,
your company is only as
good as the people you hire.
Posting jobs in one place is not
enough to find quality candidates.
Short staffing leads little time
to post a dozens of job sites.
So what can you do? Well,
you could go to zip,
but Croda you can post to a hundred
plus job sites with one click.
Be instantly matched to candidates
from over 6 million resumes.
Plus Watch brand new candidates
roll into ZipRecruiter's.
Easy to use interface within 24 hours.
ZipRecruiter has been used
by over 400,000 businesses.
Um, today you can try zip
recruiter for free. Go to
ziprecruiter.com/bar that's
ziprecruiter.com/bar one more time. Hey,
ziprecruiter.com/berm. See they
know how long to write an ad.
These other guys with their fucking
stories that make me go into a soliloquy
there. Um, oh, by the
way. So as I was stating,
uh, I've told this story
before, but I already started.
If you new to the podcast,
I'll tell it. You see. Anyways,
I'm working the sable cafe
in Cary, North Carolina.
It's 1987 going into 88. Alright.
I probably just got done
seeing Tesla opening up for a,
it was either Eric Smith on the permanent
vacation tour or it was def leopard on
the hysteria tour.
Remember Joe Elliot or those acid watch
rip pants the entire tour and through
all of the videos, you know,
he went, Jim Morrison, what?
Jim Morrison wore the same leather
pants. He wore the same acid washed,
ripped fucking jeans. You know,
and I'll tell you this right now,
the man knows how to pack.
All right. Plowing ahead.
By the way, I always heard Jim
Florentine really knows how to pack,
drop it his name twice in this podcast.
I always heard he's one of those
guys goes away for three weeks.
It'll show up with like a fucking a
knapsack and like a cheese sandwich and a
brown paper bag and he's just fucking
good. I'd like to be more like that there.
I can admit that I'm old enough now to
say I'd like to be more like Jim Flora.
Um, anyways, so I work in
the sable cafe. So, uh,
how it works is I'm glassed in, right?
And right behind me is that little window
and behind the window is the kitchen,
right? And there's the line. So
this order comes in, they're like,
you know this guy, Jason's like, oh,
we're up for a burger. Right? So my guy,
what Barbara coming up, you know,
so I'm supposed to look at the order and
if there's a lot of shit on the line,
you know, if they've got a bump,
basically a bunch of entrees to make,
I hold off on the Burger so we can
time it all out. So it's already,
I wasn't thinking because
I'm busing tables and washing
dishes while not washing
my hand. Total health code violation.
Right. I shouldn't have said that.
Now that I said the name, the restaurant,
but it's all gone anyways. Um,
so I just start making
this burger. So, you know,
I'm cause I'm watching the tables,
like I gotta finish this Burger Cause
I got to go bust that fucking table and
throw some dishes into the
fucking dishwasher a, by the way,
I also mopped the whole fucking oyster
bar and clean out both bathrooms before I
fucking start. Brutal. Right. And, uh,
so I just start making the burger.
I put it on a plate and I'm like,
Jason Burger up.
And he turns around and looks at me and
he's got his heavy metal hair shoved up
into a chef hat and he use one of those
guys that grew a mustache before he
could grow one. And he just looks at
me, he's like, dude, what the fuck?
And I like seven on trace
here. I'm like, God, I'm sorry.
So just fucking put it on the grill
to put it to the side of the grill.
So I grabbed it with tongs, it was a
glass plate and I just set it on the,
on basically on the grill, but underneath
the burner that was off, you know,
but just basically, you know, it's
a mesquite grill, so you know,
it's hot because the one, the burner
two three over is hot, you know,
it's all the same piece of metal. So
it's basically hot, but not piping hot.
Okay. But it's still
fucking pretty hot. Uh,
so I go out and I bus a
fucking table, right. And I,
I wash them dishes and I come in and
all of a sudden I've got all these other
orders for chicken sandwiches
and [inaudible] and I
leave the burger in there.
I'm not even fucking thinking.
So Jason finally finishes two fucking
entrees and he looks, he goes,
he just goes, Bro, what's
up with that Burger?
And I just grabbed it with the tongs
and he has both his hands out to receive
this thing and I just set it right down
on his hands and he just goes, hey.
And fucking spun around
and like basically threw
it down on the, on the,
on like the wood fucking shelf that he
had there and was immediately not in the
window.
So the whole fucking like dining room
heard this muffled screen and looked just
and then looked my way.
And by the time they look,
I was just standing there and I
tried to keep a straight face.
I fucking, I mean I
didn't really burn it bad.
He just made this face before he yelled.
It was like his brain was registering
what the fuck was happening and with his
fucking hair pushed up in his hat and
that stupid mustache that really wasn't a
mustache dude.
I fucking ducked down and for like
seven straight minutes was like crying,
laughing. I was laughing so hard.
I remember he wasn't even mad at
me cause he was trying to be mad,
but I was laughing so hard. He
started laughing and uh, you know,
then I had to run out and go
bus. All that stuff's there. Hey,
how about a pat on the
back for myself? Rex,
you remembering to finish that story?
Cause I know that, uh, that I didn't.
Oh and by the way,
I got a lot of backlash from my
given Australia Shit for saying that.
You know, you only had one one attack
and we had three people like, oh,
why don't you look at the population and
there's only like 23 million people or
some shit and fucking Australia,
there's like 400 million here. Well,
I will counter that point with the fact
that the top 10 fucking most poisonous
snakes,
like nine of them all
reside in fucking Australia.
You know,
like rock stars living in Jamaica to
avoid the fucking taxes in England, right?
They're all fucking in Australia. All we
got is a couple of rattlers over here.
Okay. We're so dedicated to getting
killed by snakes. We fucking,
we had a guy die with by a Cobra
last year. They don't even live here.
The thing was just visiting
bit them in a car. Um,
they think it was suicide. Anyways,
that's the a podcast, 45 fucking minutes.
It's not bad for just checking in
on you. It starts to everybody.
All you've got is one more day
to go and then it's fucking,
it's shit time at the fuck party,
right? Isn't that what Joi de Rosa says?
All right, I'll talk to
you later. See on Monday
[inaudible] [inaudible]
awesome.
I need you guys to come up with
a name for this phenomenon.
You have a man standing in a,
in an airport terminal in this,
some douche talking really loud on
his cell phone. Of course you have.
We all have, right? She
big just giant dude.
There's a fat black dude from England,
so he sounds like he's in, you know,
lock stock in a smoking barrels,
whatever the fuck it's called.
And he's a tub of Shit,
which is making me laugh cause
everybody in Europe acts like that.
Fucking smart and in shape. You
know, he looked like the fucking
dude on a, you know, you
know, what do you look like?
You know that show? The Cleveland
browns show, you know his son.
That's exactly what he looked
like. He didn't talk like him,
but he had the fucking round
glasses, the whole God damn thing.
That's what the fuck he looked like.
And he's talk and he's fucking,
he's Fi's American fat. He Chicago fat.
All right. But he's European, so he still
has to wear those tight fucking Janes.
I don't know why.
I don't know what it is about Europe
and fucking suffocate and your balls,
but Europeans just did. Jeans
cannot be fucking tight.
They just cannot be fucking
tight enough. They have,
they have to fucking frame their package.
That goddamn units look like fucking
hand Solo's face when he gets frozen in
that little piece of fucking
carbon or whatever the fuck it was.
Um, anyways, so he's running
his stupid yet. Yeah.
Mike going over to Melbourne after they're
going to go back over to fucking who
gives a fuck, right. Just
talk and talk and talk.
Talking big stupid Chicago
bare fucking gut, you know,
you know when you get the creases on
the side, you could stick mail in there.
He's got those on the side,
right. Or Offensive Lineman, fat.
You know, he's got great footwork though,
but look at his fucking belly and he's
just running his Goddamn Yap. You know,
so I walk away from the guy,
but he's one of these guys that
takes a little stroll when he walked.
So he keeps fucking walking over into
my little area. Right. So my guy,
you know, Bill, come on,
just fucking, don't be this.
Don't be fucking screaming and
yelling. Just fucking relax. And uh,
what is the name of this phenomenon?
They start loading the fucking plane.
I get on the plane, here
comes that fucking Douche,
right? Still talking. Yeah,
my, yeah. Yeah. Good Day mate. Yeah.
Yeah, I'll fucking bullshit. I know.
Good day mates from fucking Australia
before I get shit from fucking people from
England. Y'all sound
the same to me. Right?
So he comes walking up the alley.
He's still running his fucking yep.
And I'm just going out. Jesus
Christ. All right. Only off,
listen to this guy for
another five, four, three,
til he goes by and the motherfuckers
in my row. What are the odds?
You know, what are the fucking
odds? God Damn 70 fucking rose.
Not only is he in my row,
he's sitting right next to me and he
stays on the phone the whole fucking time.
Yeah, my, yeah. Now, now
JD bess watch intellij.
Is this Stan right?
The whole fucking time.
Why you swearing?
I'm not swearing the whole fucking time
sitting next to me running his God damn.
Yeah. But this fat fucking stomach
and the crease in the side and um,
is he only, this is the only a, the
only props I will give this guys is,
you know, he never seen ever said
hello. We didn't speak the whole flight.
I loved it.
I loved that he was as
self-involved as I am. And uh,
the last thing I wanted to hear,
the last thing I want to do,
we started talking to him cause he
already annoyed the shit out of me.
And I know from experience that if I'm
going to talk to somebody from another
country,
at some point they're going to shit on
the United States as something that they
like to do while calling us the ignorant
Americans traveling around the world.
You know, all knees and elbows,
those motherfuckers come
over here and it's just,
you can't talk to them for more than
fucking five minutes before they, they,
they shit on America. I don't
want to fucking understand it.
Okay.
[inaudible] you know, I would
never do that. The only,
the only way I would do that is if
I was on stage in another country.
Just just for the fucking ridiculousness
of it to start making fun of their
fucking country. But if I was sitting
on a plane, I would just be telling her,
you have a beautiful country, blah,
blah, blah. I be a decent fucking guy.
I don't fucking, AH, Jesus Christ
the was I just going to tigers?
You remembered something
in the middle of that,
the hell was it talking about, hang
on a second. Let me think about this.
Oh yeah, I remember what it was.
Did I tell this story like
fucking four months ago,
I pulled my big ass truck
into this small spot,
but there was nobody on the
other side of me and I was fine.
Right when I came out,
somebody had pulled in and it was really
tight as far as like on either side of
my truck. And then I didn't
have a lot of space to back out.
So it was this fucking problem. I keep
trying to back, you know, back out,
come back in, back out,
like inching my way in.
So this fucking guy starts helping me out.
I think he was from England and
he's like, uh, you know, next time,
why didn't you do the UNAMERICAN
thing and back in and I, I,
I fucking, I,
it's like you can't even help me out of
this spot without fucking nitpicking you
fucking cunt. You know what?
I'll listen to it from Australia.
But England though,
the amount of shit that is going on in
the world still because of those cons,
the fact that they actually fucking give
you have the balls to give the United
States shit the very least be
like, hey, welcome to the party.
Yeah,
welcome.
You guys just slowly catching up to
us historically as the biggest fucking
oppressive douchebags on the planet.
You want to come at me like that?
Absolutely.
But if you're going to fucking come at
me like you didn't do all this other
bullshit out there, the fucking caste
system in India and all that fucking crap,
the shit that happened
in Rwanda, you know?
Yeah.
That's all. I got. Two examples.
I don't know anything else.
The Falkland Islands at JCC
Igert, American strikes again,
but you know what I'm
saying? If I actually read,
I could fucking bury you guys
in this argument. All right.
With your jolly rancher flag,
whatever the fuck you call it. Um,
all right.
Thank God I don't have a gig coming
up in England after that little thing,
you know.
[inaudible]
a dilemma. A bill, what
would you choose? Um,
to either have sex with any woman
in the world? Nia wouldn't mind.
I wouldn't care if she gave a shit if I,
my choice of any fucking woman in the
world just to do it one time. Yeah.
Uh, that wouldn't be worth it. It
wouldn't be worth it to lose Nia, but eh,
but my Dick would override
that wisdom in the moment.
Um, or to have access to the truth
about any government secret in history.
What would you do?
Okay.
All right. Well, how would I know
any government's secret in history?
What would they know that I knew it and
then they'd start tracking me down and
then I'd have to be like fucking
Jason Borne for the rest of my life.
Never getting to sleep more than
five seconds between concussions. Um,
all right. First of all, if I could
have sex with any woman in the world,
who would it be?
Okay.
Ah, let's see here. Well, you got UK,
you got, you got your major groups.
I think you've got four major groups.
You have famous, you have celebrity women.
Um, you have a young
celebrities like movie stars.
Then you have, you have a rock star,
chicks, sports checks,
and then you got chicks
from your past. You know,
some teacher you always wanted
to bang any woman in the world,
you're going to go back. But she
has to be as hot as she was. Oh,
this is a dilemma. Oh, by the way,
the other day I was at a comedy club
in that, that, uh, pink was down,
was actually in the crowd. And
uh, I didn't go up around anybody.
She walked by fucking absolutely
like slump against the wall.
Beautiful. Absolutely fucking gorgeous.
Um, I'm telling you some of the, like
those fucking like super famous people,
like they don't even look real when
they walk by you. They just liked it.
That genetics, like, I don't know
what happened, but I'm just like,
Jesus fucking Christ. You know? I mean,
I knew she was good looking right.
I've seen the videos, but everybody
looks good in videos, you know,
and then half the time you
see him in fucking real life.
I'll tell you this right now. If you
ever see pink, she does not disappoint.
Fucking just write down the checklist.
Absolutely fucking gorgeous.
You know, beautiful fucking dress.
That was sexy but not slutty.
She had the fucking tattoos, but
not too many of them. Fucking,
just absolutely a fucking gorgeous.
I felt like I was in second grade.
Um, you know, like when a beautiful girl
walks by you like a big [inaudible],
you don't even know what to say. Um,
all right, so let's get back to it.
So if I could beg any
woman in the fucking world,
well, there's two kinds of women.
There's the woman that you,
you're fucking is absolutely gorgeous
and makes you believe in an afterlife.
And then there's the other girl you
want to bang just to shutter the fuck.
Gotcha.
You know what I mean? Like,
I bet there's a lot of liberals out
there that want to just bang and culture,
just stick their dick right in her
fucking mouth. You know what I mean?
But not like a totally malicious way.
Just really put one on her where she's
just fucking losing it and you know,
making noises in bed that she didn't
even know she could make and uh,
you know,
and make her be able to make those noises
even though she knows that you voted
for Obama. You know, there's
that kind of fucking right.
And then there's the other one
where you just wanna fuck in a,
you know, run down the beach,
hand in hand with something girl,
at least in my world, that's the only,
those are the only two. What would I do?
You know what? I would choose a,
I would choose sex with any woman in
the world because I'm that government
learning a government secret.
I've actually done that on
a certain level and it just,
it's like being in show
business is when you're like,
wouldn't it be cool to meet this person?
And then you meet them and they're
like the biggest fucking asshole ever.
Or they, uh, I don't know. They just
like, they just do something that
just, it just blows your whole
fucking image. It's, it's,
it's the wizard of Oz thing.
We, you, you don't want it.
You don't want to peek around
the corner. You don't want it.
You don't want to peek around the
corners. So what I would do is, uh,
I would definitely, I
would, I would, I would,
I would have sex with some
[inaudible] and you know what?
I'm [inaudible] it would have
to be somebody famous. And, uh,
Dan, out of respect for
Nia, I would have to be a,
just to shut them the
fuck up kind of woman.
Although I would love to run down the
beach. You know, why can't I have that?
Why can't I have happiness?
All right, let's,
let's pick one. One of each. Alright.
Okay.
Is there any girl I just want
to lose, shut the fuck up.
I would say back in the day it would've
been Madonna, but like, she would just,
she was like beyond the noise. She
was so fucking annoying. She was like,
I would just want to get out of the room.
Okay.
You know what I mean?
They always watches that blonde ambition
tour and there's nothing more nauseated
than watching somebody who's surrounded
by yes men. You know what I mean?
That just completely fucking
up noxious everything they say.
Everyone's hanging all over every word
and they just laughing at everything.
Like that's, you know something.
That's one thing that I have
learned in this business is, uh,
a major red flag is somebody who has
an entourage. If you have an entourage,
like a, I dunno, I've already, I,
I automatically judge you as
like, all right, this person is a,
is not somebody I'm going to
want to fucking be around.
Cause the only way I'm going
to be able to exist is this.
I assimilate into your entourage and
when you tell the joke that isn't funny,
I can't be like, I can't look
at you like that joke sucks.
I have to fucking do like
what they are doing, you know,
laugh my ass off cause paying for my
hotel room the fuck out of here. Right.
That and, and people who don't
hang out with peers, you know,
maybe they don't have an entourage,
but everybody they hang out with is
fucking like 10 years behind them in this
business. Then that's another,
that's another red flag because then
nobody's calling you out on your shit.
Right. That's, that's how I look at it.
How did I get to that with this shit?
You know what, I'm going to have to
get back to you on this one. You know,
I'm a fucking 44 year old guy,
so I don't really set, you know,
when I was younger I had my, my, I'll
go back in the day, my list. Okay.
When I was a kid, uh, the bionic woman,
all three Charlie's angels, um,
Farah, I wanted to bang, I
had lust for her. Kay Jackson.
I would marry and Jaclyn Smith get out,
which your fault for stand
in between the two of them
you're going down to. But you know,
I didn't need Jacqueline Smith cause
I already had the Brunette with,
with fucking, uh, Kate Jackson. Um,
then who else? Who else in the 80s?
I like what's her face? The
replacement for Shelley long.
Uh, who's in the look who's talking?
She came on at that horse smokey
foresee fucking smokey voice,
whatever the fuck you supposed to say.
It's supposed to sound way
more sexier than that. Uh,
she had nice fucking curves. Got a little
out of control there after a while,
but uh, you know, um,
she still has nice apps.
I got to tell you, uh,
who else?
You know, it's weird. Florence Henderson,
when she had the worst mullet haircut,
always turned me on more than
when she had that awful fucking,
oh, Marsha, Marsha Brady, when she
fucking had the little short skirts on
fucking a Janet Jackson when
she was on a different strokes.
Who else?
I just, it goes on for fucking
ever. I just can't remember anymore.
He's never Cyndi Lauper,
I could tell you that.
Okay.
She just seemed like some
spares. Little fucking boy to me.
Yeah. Then that fucking
haircut that she had was,
she fucking had like a tic Tac
toe board on the side of her head.
That just really freaked me out.
Um,
not that I was totally against that here
cook cause I thought that chicken bow
wow. I thought she was hot.
Um,
okay.
Who the fuck else did I like lead
a Ford. Oh my God. That I like her.
I think I might've somebody back then.
I can't fucking remember. [inaudible]
I'm lonely.
I was just watching television by myself
speaking to it as if it was another
life human being. And I saw
this commercial for this, this,
this new website called
farmers only. Dot Com.
This is not a commercial people.
This is actually an observation. Um,
it was basically showing a, you
know, some, a couple of ranchers,
a couple of farm girls and they just walk
in the fields by themselves, you know,
playing with their face finger,
playing with each other. You know,
you do that when you were a little kid.
You'd do that little thing where you
put your thumb and index finger together
and both hands you need
kind of do the little,
almost like there's an
invisible tiny screw.
You know there's some poor woman walking
through like these a bunch of corn,
you know when the cows are all concerned
to the point directionally speaking
English to one one another, you
know about each of them going,
how the hell are they
going to meet each other?
And then all of a sudden this Whalen
whore comes over the top and just start
singing young. Never be
lonely. Add Pharma Zone,
lit.com so it's basically their Facebook
and you should go and look at it on
Youtube. That's what you should
do. You shouldn't work, you know,
where do you work? What are you doing?
Is it your dream or somebody else's?
You just a cog in the wheel. You know,
are they really going to notice if you
stop working, everybody else is working.
Why don't you just fucking, you know,
Tour de France just sort of draft behind
a couple of people's today. You know,
take a fucking Monday off, 20
weeks, check out this video.
And you know,
it's the funniest thing about it is the
comments underneath it is the amount of
people who shit on, you know, just
immediately thinking how dumb people are.
It's like these people grow our
fucking food. Do you understand that?
I'm sure they don't know where
the rave is. You know well,
who the most popular bands are or how
to get from fucking Brooklyn over to
Staten Island. Oh right. They
don't know how to do that shit.
They don't know how to put on
a fucking shiny shirt. Right.
And go jump on the subway and go down
to Wall Street and make sure old people
eat dog for the rest of their fucking
lives. Yet they don't know how to do that.
But you know, they know how to do, they
ought to make them, I make corn right,
or planets or grows. They
don't make it. God makes it,
and he makes that fertile
fucking country. You know?
It's got to be really hard to catch
herpes out there. You know what I mean?
I mean in much spread.
Really fucking slowly.
Jesus Christ. I mean,
you wonder why you must fucking
rub them at least two loads out.
By the time you get to her house to sit
in there driving and driving fucking
tornado, man, pull over.
Rub another one out by then you add or
you know what the fuck I'm going over
there. Foreign ways. Shit. I got more
teeth in her. That's a deal breaker. Look,
now I'll make fun of him
at farmer's only.com.
That's going to be embarrassing.
You and your fucking
neighbor are going to join.
You can be the only ones on the site.
Hey, I thought you wanted to fuck me.
I just was too long of a walk.
You know what I'm saying?
Plus it's tornado season. You
never know what's going to happen.
I lived there called the fly overstates
and no reason to go there. Yeah,
no reason to check in
on the food supply. Uh,
like you're gonna. That'd be a good
thing to fucking freak them out with.
Just show up with like a clipboard.
The fuck are you doing sit up boy.
Or they actually, you know, something,
they make themselves kind of separatists.
Cause at the end of, is
that even a word? Um,
they actually say the city
folks don't understand.
What don't we understand?
Loneliness. Is that what it is?
Come to New York and be alone
with everybody. You never
heard that. You fucking,
you know what? Fuck them. Goddamn
farmers. Jesus Christ. What?
You don't have your cousin's
phone number. He said, well,
you're sick of fucking your sisters and
now you gotta get your own Facebook and
see the jokes that just too
easy here, people, you know.
That's good.
[inaudible].