Hey, what's going on? It's bill burr and
it is time for the Thursday afternoon,
just before Friday,
Monday morning podcast and Ah,
just checking in on
motherfucker.
Um, how are you, how was your
week going? Oh, that's love.
Don't let it get you down,
you know?
Um,
yeah,
I'm recording this fucking Wednesday
night. I got so much shit to do tomorrow.
I didn't even realize it. You know,
it's the usual shit. You know how many,
um, I'm just gonna do a bunch
of stuff. I was wondering,
is there any way that you
could handle the other stuff?
Okay.
Oh, good to, to do this job. Could
you do that stuff? Well, you know,
I was already had some stuff.
Honey would be a big help if you
could just do the stuff to easy to do.
Put the stuff that you were already
going to jail. That bullshit.
It happens
to one of those things that happens.
Um, you know, I don't, I don't know
what the fuck to tell you guys. Hey,
I'm starting a Patrion page, by the
way. I don't know when it's coming out,
but it's going to be all this extra shit.
Um,
a bunch of extra shit,
a whole bunch of extra shit and uh,
you know,
get some helicopter videos and
whatnot and some other shit.
This is sort of a pre promotional
promotional thing here or you know,
if I was supposed to bring it up,
I think I'm supposed to wait until I
had more shit on the sat. You know what,
I might still be worth it
worth the two year, uh,
basically just trying to
become this little fucking,
you know, you have a go. Yeah.
A little town. This little place that
makes a little candies, you know,
and it just fucking,
they hang in there despite the fact across
the street there's a Mcdonald's are,
you know,
there's a fucking Walmart Assam Shit.
There's just this fucking guy
down the Hebrew payers shoes,
whatever the fuck he does. That's all
I'm trying to do in this business.
Just trying to have my little fucking shop
be bringing in enough fucking money on
my own. So these Steven cons out here,
you know,
I can't even tell you some of this
shit that I've done like I've really,
like a long time ago I saw
this documentary and this
fucking musician said you
are better to own something 100% and
sell 20,000 copies then did not own it at
all and sell 20 million.
You actually going to make more if
you just sell 20,000 if it's your own,
if you own it and a,
it's one of the truest fuck it things
I've ever,
ever heard other than
don't stay friends with your
ex girlfriend. You know,
you break up with a girl,
you've got gotta get the fuck
away from her cause uh, you know,
it's just, it's, you know what, I
don't listen to me. Generally speaking,
some of them are cool, some of them
get it, some are happy for you.
The rest of them, Jay, you got to get
away from him. You know what I mean?
It's like when there's mold in the house,
you got to go, are you going to die?
Okay. Does that make sense? Do
I need to sing a song about it?
I don't know what the fuck to tell you.
All I know is that I am sitting here
alone in this God damn room and my fucking
chest hurts. I think I have a
bruised sternum. This fucking guy,
like the end of last year,
he was trying to show me what the fuck
happened on this football play and I as
he was coming towards me, I should
have been like, dude, I saw it.
I saw the play and he went to pick me
up any fucking compacted my fucking ribs
and I think it fucked up my sternum.
Either that or I have a to,
I don't know what it is,
but you know I'm going to
go see a doctor about it.
See what the deal is now that
I've fucking been here for like a,
why does this fucking couch scratch ups?
Do they make anything nice anymore?
But these fucking leather couches,
you stick anything on it and everything
gets all fuck that fucking hacked up.
Look at this shit.
Jesus Christ.
Oh, it gives a fuck. Right?
I guess that adds character,
but will say a bunch of hack marks on it
anyways. Um, college
football starts this weekend.
A wrong song.
Yeah.
Blah, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah,
blah, blah, blah, blah, blah. Papa, Papa,
Papa, Papa, Papa, Papa, Papa.
But they're all the same fucking song.
[inaudible]
you know, people or some sort of hand
gesture that they fucking throw up. Right.
Um, anyways, Mike, most beginnings
of most college football seasons,
there's not a lot of good games. Okay. So
the ones you want to look out here, uh,
speaking of, of, of his
University of Michigan, Yay.
Yale to the, there is value
yet right against a Notre Dame.
Uh, he was in a fucking hospital.
He was dying and he said,
where in one for it may cause I'm a
selfish cunt and I'm still thinking about
me. I don't even know if that even
happened when one for the gipper was that
Hollywood adding a dialogue,
some shit that was never said,
you know,
like you complete me.
MMM.
Anyways. Now the good ones, I LSU first
Miami. That could be a decent one.
Just as far as rank teams
actually each other.
Other than than that.
Virginia Tech,
Florida State 20 Verse 19 I love it.
How the fuck did they do the rankings
at the, so many people leave.
How do they figure out who's what?
You know you can watch number for
Wisconsin against Western Kentucky.
I think the spread is on that. Look
at Tcu is not ranked against southern.
You come off frogs.
What happened?
I don't know why I fucking,
you know, I know why because I,
they came to the rose bowl that one
time and everybody was dressed like a
fucking douche bag.
Everybody all living,
all the guys were all
dressed like jr Ewing.
You know that there's like
dress and classy. Right?
And then there's just like you just a
privileged cut and it's neither one of
those is probably true. Well actually
dressing classes too. But the second part,
they probably won't even privileged cons.
I probably just looked at them and
just judge the shit out of them.
There's probably what really happened.
I bet there's nothing wrong with tasty.
You come off frogs.
MMM.
I Dunno what they just, they just, they
just look like assholes. Not the women.
Just the guys sit there. You know
what I mean? He's sitting there,
this stupid fucking loafers
in a fucking blue blazer.
Who wears that to a football game?
Right?
Why are you dressed like an usher?
I Dunno.
It's amazing how long ago I saw that
in the fact that it's still bugs me.
It doesn't bug me as much as how easily
these chairs fucking scratch evidently.
Oh well what are you going
to do? You know what I mean?
You know was funny is I got these chairs,
not for a lot of money
because they're like, hey,
here's some vintage fucking chairs. Right?
So you don't want these old as fuck.
First one is zillion dollars for
these vintage leather chairs, right?
So I've got just buy some new ones and
I'll put the fucking hack marks in them.
And now every hack mark that's
getting goes in and now mellow.
What happened, Bill was exactly what
you said you wanted in your couches.
And now that's happening. And now
you're upset about, all right.
Fair enough. Fair enough. How
about those red socks? Huh?
Pouring it on the offense. The
bats, the bats hanging in there,
hanging in there while our pitching
staff all goes on the fucking deal.
Chris sale once again is on
the 10 day disabled list.
David Price got hit by a line drive.
Oh,
come back or write to the mound.
X Rays were negative,
but they're going to take more
fucking, more x rays, you know,
so we shall see. That's why I ESPN. Oh,
it's all over. Or beginning of August.
You never know what can happen
with all the fucking injuries.
MMM.
So anyways, I was watching that. Uh, I'll
tell you what my daughter does. You know,
it's fucking hilarious. Did I tell
you she imitates the old noises,
old man noises I make when I pick her
up. All right, come on sweetie. Let's go.
And I pick up,
she looks at me and she goes,
I don't, you know, I, maybe I already told
you that story. I'm old. I don't remember.
Speaking of all that went to the gym
today and after bragging about my perfect
form,
I somehow threw out my back trying to
make sure I was doing the middle of my
back chip Pz exercises.
So my fucking chest and shoulders
wouldn't pull my fucking know my chest,
wouldn't pull my shoulders
forward against, I wouldn't
fuck up my rotator cuffs,
my rotator cuffs, doing great. And then
I end up fucking up my back. I can't,
when I think I'm at that
age where I got it was, Nah,
I just gotta I gotta you know,
somebody finally said, I said,
why don't you get a fucking personal
trainer and just have them go over there?
All the exercises you're going to do.
They'll put together a workout plan that
tell you how to do the, the, the, the,
the exercise correctly. And I've always
said, Nah, Nah, Nah, fuck that. Fuck that.
I know what I'm doing. I know what I'm
doing. You know, I know what I'm doing.
Because in the eighties I went,
I went over to a friend's house and
he's going to, come on, let's work out,
make a friend of mine, just get your
bench to this. Nothing about grip,
nothing about form, nothing. Do
some curls. This is good for you.
Didn't fucking know. And then you'd
go to the 10, you joined a gym, right?
You joined Gold's or world gym or
whatever the fuck it was right back in the
day. And then you just see somebody
doing an exercise, you know,
they seemed approachable. You'd be like,
Hey, what's that? What does that do?
And if they seemed intimidating,
you just sort of watch it out of the
corner of your eye and then you just start
doing it. You had no idea what are you
are doing, what the fuck it was working.
You would basically guess what it was
doing and then you didn't work the
opposite muscle and you fuck yourself up.
It had I just gone out and got
a personal trainer from day one.
If they even fucking existed back
in the 80s, I don't think they did.
You just went to the gym.
Um,
I wouldn't have all of these problems
today. So there you go. There you go.
Everybody, if you're learning how to
play drums, wear ear plugs from day one,
if you're going to go to the gym,
get a fucking trainer from day one,
learn what the fuck the correct way to
do shit. So you don't end up like me.
End Up hurting yourself
trying to fix something else.
My fucking shoulder is doing great.
Yeah.
There's nothing worse than
thrown out the top of your back.
I don't know what it is. Lower
back up, just so used to that pain.
It's like acceptable at the
top of your back is fucking,
and I explain it.
Yeah.
Takes your breath away. So in dealing with
that off all day, you know what I mean?
And my Kiddo, you know, she likes
getting picked up all the time,
so I was making extra or band noises,
uh, anyways, but it's still worth
it back. Pain for a kid is the best.
It's no worries. You know,
I'll take any day of the week.
The kids are fucking right.
She's got a great sense of humor and
she likes to rough house. It's perfect.
It's perfect. You know? Oh, she
loves vamp arena, man. I got 10.
I'm getting sick of that show.
You know,
the fucking little blue
chick. She's always having
problems fitting in. I get it.
She's different.
Every fucking goddamn episode.
And then the other two people
have to fucking help her out.
You know what she reminds me of?
She reminds me of an addict.
You know where it's always about them
and you've got to fail. Oh No, no.
You're doing great. What's the
matter? What's the matter now?
You know,
I don't really mind it.
Fancy.
Nancy's the one I don't like that
one fucking chicken all. She,
she's just sitting there, y'all.
She's about as material things.
She always trying to have the nicest shit.
She somehow gets status and then
give friends or whatever is like,
what the fuck are we watch? I don't
want to watch this shit. You know?
So instead I was watching a little bit
of the red sox with my daughter before
she went to bed. And then, um,
afterwards,
uh,
it was funny, actually nodded off
when I was watching vamp arena.
And you have like that
panic when you fall asleep,
flight three seconds that you kids like
walking up to an alligator or some shit.
And I just opened my eyes and she
was just looking right at me and she,
and I opened my eyes. She just looks
at me and she just goes, hi. Like,
what's up buddy? Sorry. Oh,
fucking all freckles nodded off there.
So anyways,
I put her to bed and I went on Instagram
and I saw Joe Rogan was promoting a,
or just talking about,
well,
we just watched this documentary
about Leonard Skinner,
sorry for the onyx. I was like,
God, I got to check this shit out.
And I just watched, it's on showtime.
It's called if I leave here tomorrow,
um, and I gotta tell you, man,
these fucking old southern guys
that is still around. I mean,
I literally had to put on the, the, uh,
the closed caption so I can understand
what the fuck they were saying.
And Jesus Christ,
incredible documentary.
But it's also amazing at how similar,
you know,
so many of these bands stories are,
and it's just because they get into that,
they get into the music business where
they getting fucking ripped off and they
just put them on the wheel and the
business just gives a shit about money and
they don't give a fuck if they run a
band into the fucking ground because
there's always another band that
they can sign. And plus who,
why would you want to wrap an old band?
They know all the tricks and how
you're going to try to steal from them.
They'll probably try to get the rights
to their music pack, so fuck them,
you know?
Then he lucked,
they'll blame each other and break up
and then we'll move onto the next band.
Like that's literally how the
music fucking business worked. Um,
so I'm sitting there
watching this shit and um,
just,
you know,
that whole,
just the work ethic and just keeping it
simple in the beginning and then they
just get stuck in the,
uh,
the craziness of touring. I don't want
to ruin any of it, but definitely, uh,
definitely check it out and just also
how great the band sounds in the night.
Just seeing people singing live and
playing live with other human beings is
incredible. I don't know, man. I'm kind of
going off the rails here, dude. I'm just,
I'm just,
I can't remember the last time I
watched something from this century.
Yeah.
By the way, I've been watching that.
Peter Gunn on a me TV bed at it,
dude. Dude, dude. Wow. That's
where that song came from, right?
That is the worst lit show in the history
of anything that was ever fucking lit.
At first I thought it was like
a style thing. Like for you,
if you guys have in the business, they're
like, when they go to light a scene,
I never understood why this shadow
was like a big full gives a fuck up.
There's a shadow. Right? But it's just
like if you know, if you're in a room,
okay.
Like if,
I dunno, I don't even know how
to explain this because this,
this is really beyond my ability.
All I know is that's what's so fucked
up is they'll be in a dimly lit room and
one person's talking and then there's
a shadow behind him and then somebody
right behind them, like wrecked directly
cross talking for them. So if anything,
the shadow, that person should
be on the person talking.
But whenever they turn
around to go to that person,
then that person has a shadow behind them.
They literally had like one light and
they just would stick it in front of
people.
So this episode ends,
I'm not saying it's a bad show, it's
just a badly, poorly lit lit show.
This woman standing there and
because she's standing in like, uh,
the opening to this,
this apartment building where it,
uh,
it's not straight on the walls,
they sort of angle in towards the door.
Her shadow was on both sides
when she standing there.
And that would just say,
okay,
maybe that's how they lit the building
in which she standing. All right.
Then she walks, it's the end of the
episode. She goes down the street.
Now we're behind her and as she's
walking away, as the camera rises up,
you literally see the shadow of
the camera and the fucking guy,
the guy's head and body
hanging off the side,
off going off the building in the
background that she's walking towards.
And it's like, how to fuck
that? Somebody missed that.
So,
um,
but you got to watch Peter
Gunn. All right, it's on me TV.
I still highly recommend it.
It's fucking hilarious. You,
you will never see a character die faster.
They only had fucking 22 minutes
to have somebody get killed,
to have Peter Gunn to
try to figure out what,
what the fuck happened to have Peter
get the living shit kicked out of him.
And then for him to
solve the fucking murder,
they had to do all of that in 22 fucking
minutes. So it always just starts.
One of them started at like,
Ladies and gentlemen on piano,
please welcome 88 keys,
kitty or whatever the fuck his name is.
And the curtain comes up and the guy's
just sitting there with this weird look
on his face and they just keels over
with a knife in his back and then it just
goes, yeah, no, no, no, no,
no, no. [inaudible] Bam.
So another one, a guy gets on a fucking
elevator and the elevator stops.
He's pushing the button. He's
like, what the fuck's going on?
And all of a sudden the trapdoor above
it opens up and a gun with a silencer
come sue. Yeah. Fucking guy drops down.
Debt goes down to the first floor, opens
up, the guy reacts to the dead body.
Yay.
That was it. Then they're right
in there. And I gotta Tell You,
Peter Gunn,
it's sort of the precursor to that.
David do cover the
minimalist style of acting.
MMM.
Guy Crushes it.
And then also 77 sunset strip,
they would do foreshadowing to the
middle of the episode like you saw at the
beginning of Goodfellas in a
lot of Martin Scorsese movies.
Everybody always said, I always think,
oh, they're ripping off Martin Scorsese.
I'm like, [inaudible], well wait a
minute. 77 sunset strip. Did this shit.
Maybe he watched a few
episodes. I don't know. This is,
let's see what we see,
what this podcast is becoming.
This is becoming an old fucking man.
I gotta what are you guys watching that's
worth watching? I Dunno what it is.
Cause my wife dominates the TV. I love
it at death. What am I going to say? No.
And she's literally sitting there,
she's watching that Andy
Cohen show where all the,
the little old ladies get together with
their fucking 20 pounds of makeup and
they just start fucking saying means
shit to each other. I liked one of them.
One of them was a drunk,
clearly was a drunk and they would tell
her that she needed to go into Rehab.
She goes, I don't need to go in
and Rehab. And I'd probably say no.
I went into Rehab was was my cousin. And
that was because you know they, you know,
she didn't, she go to jail was saying
like, that's why you go to Rehab.
And they were like,
yes,
but sometimes you have to go to rehab
because you have a problem. Well,
I don't have a prominent guy. Am I going
to prop? That's what she does. She,
she did the fucking
Archie bunker fuel like fuck you guys.
And you could just hear in a voice,
even if she wasn't drunk,
just like she,
she's at that level of booze with
a bottle has like a fucking handle.
You know,
it's like a jug.
You buying that cheap shit with
like a carton of cigarettes.
There is something to be said
for going out like that,
you know,
to just give in to all of it.
Scherger's saw liquor,
fucking smoke.
I Dunno.
I think it's all good right up
until you get sick and then you die.
Then you're like, ah, you know,
I could have been fucking,
I should have jogged in aid apricots,
you know, Dan, what
I mean if it really is just a
blink of the eye, well, you know,
as far as how long the universe has been
here, oh Jeez. I'm going deep now. Right.
Deep. For me anyways, if it
really is a blink of the eye,
just the amount of time that human
beings have walked the earth, you know,
who gives a fuck
if you live to be 30?
Oh fucking a hundred.
Right?
Yeah.
Well you know, who gives a
fuck the, I guess the person
because for you that's a long fucking
time or really short time, right.
Not Saying, you know, I wouldn't
give a fuck if I was dying.
I'm just saying, you know
what I mean? You know,
I'm really saying is that I've been
eating like an angel and I barely been
drinking and uh,
trying to get my abs back here and uh,
this is one of these nights where,
uh, you know, I dunno,
it's kind knowing at me
where I used to drink booze,
like my late night snack now is,
is heirloom tomatoes.
I just cut a few of them up and I
actually fucking look forward to it.
I like drinking smoothies in the morning.
I fucking loved that for
breakfast with Kale and spinach,
bananas and fucking Chia
seeds and all of that shit.
But every fucking once in awhile,
you know.
Well, every buy once in a while,
I've kind of mean like every night.
This week I just feel like,
just like fuck, you know,
so I don't know. What do you do
about that? You know, I just go,
I'm just not gonna do it right now.
I'll go do a fucking podcast.
Um,
I dunno.
I don't know what the fuck that means.
Probably means I have issues. Right.
It's weird because I
haven't eaten any fucking,
I haven't eaten any fucking ice cream
cookies, any of that fucking shit.
And I'm not thinking
about any of that at all.
But booze is the one that always, it
always comes back knocking, you know,
like didn't Elizabeth,
Elizabeth Taylor, Mary,
like the same guy like twice or you
always hear these fuck one I one with the
fucking record is for that.
Most Times two people got married.
Most Times two people
got remarried. What's going
on in the world by the way
of what happened this week?
Tennessee couple gets married a record,
110, nine times. Go Fuck Yourself.
I didn't want to hear that.
That's bullshit.
World records from marriages and divorces
after knocking for 21 how many people
in America get remarried?
She got title one swimming
tied the knot 23 fucking times.
Yeah.
Jesus Christ. Talk about a codependent
psychopathic. He can't fucking be alone.
Grandmother is most married woman
after tying the knot 23 times.
Cheese can imagine the fucking check
she was collected. Well, actually no,
that's not true, right? Because once
you're married, the next person,
Jesus Christ, how? How easy would
it be to fucking divorce her?
I'll make payments for eight months.
She'll fucking find somebody else.
Get married again.
American grandmother,
Linda Wolf has become the most
married woman in the world.
I'm surprised she's not a great
grandmother. All that cock going into her,
Huh?
After walking down the aisle 23 times
and is now on the lookout for number 24
Mrs. Wolf 68
is included in the Guinness Book of World
Records for the dubious honor of being
wed more times than anyone else.
Alive chew.
She must be the first time you're like,
hey, could you not put your shoes here?
I, you know what? Go Fuck Yourself.
Okay.
Linda,
she has said she's addicted to romance
to the romance of getting married.
Oh, she likes it. In the
beginning, born Linda Lou Taylor,
the American or the American first
married in 1957 at the age six,
eight to a 31 year old
called George Scott,
former first baseman of the
Boston red sox. I'm the union.
Lasted for seven years,
the longest and happiest if any
of her marriages since then,
things have tended to go
downhill. Oh, that's funny.
She got divorced at 23 for the first
time and she went on to marry 23 times.
Um, over the subsequent decades,
she'd married a one eyed convict,
a preacher, a bar. Man, it
sounds like an Irish song.
They're green alligators
and a one eyed conduct.
A fucking preacher ran a bar
man and a plumber. Uh, and uh,
and musicians, plural. Ah, Jesus.
Two turned out to be homosexuals
to are homeless and one beat her.
I mean, that's pretty good, man. You only
got beaten. You get married 23 times.
You only get beat once a month.
It's pretty good.
You figured somebody got married 23 times.
They just had bad choices in men.
Another put a padlock on her fridge.
Oh,
there's a guy that's
called marrying for looks
getting fat.
They're hunting.
I swear to God you have another fucking
fescue and I'm putting a padlock on that
fucking fridge.
Yeah,
watch me.
Watch me.
And then he fucking does it and then she
has to go fuck yourself. I'm Outta here.
He's too controlling.
He was counting the level,
the amount of pop tarts
I was eating. Um, okay.
One marriage lasted just 36 hours
because the love just wasn't there.
But Linda from Indiana once
married the same man, Jack girly,
three times she's had seven children
by or different husbands and has been a
stepmother too many more.
Her last marriage a decade
ago was a publicity stunt.
It was to
Glenn Wolf,
who in taking Linda as his bride meant
he was the world's most married man at 29
times,
29 times on Jesus.
He died a year later at 88 I bet God's
first fucking statement to him was,
what the fuck are you? Fuck
are you doing? What was that?
You are an asshole
after 17 times. Did you really think the
last 12 times are going to be different?
You fucking moron.
Okay,
no sense sending you to hell,
buddy. You've already been
there. Come on in. Alright,
consequentially,
consequently she said she was,
that she was on the lookout
for number 24 she told the son,
it's been years since I walked
down the aisle. I miss it.
Yeah.
Jesus Christ.
She's like fucking,
she's like an athlete that
doesn't know how to retire.
The serial bride who now
lives in a retirement home,
said she had never cheated on her husband.
You didn't have fucking time to.
She said if she had her life over again,
she would never ever marry so many men.
Well, let it ended. Kind of
sad. Right? So of course,
this is all of these clickbait sites.
What should every architect
demand from a cloud,
the most dangerous species alive?
Donald Trump and his younger days.
This mom never fed or daughter carbs.
Which one did you guys want here?
This is like jeopardy for dumb people.
Volkswagen CC tests.
Wild old age.
Stop US seeing.
Oh wild will.
My eyes are going here. We'll old
age. Stop us seeing our grandkids.
60 candid photos from the past.
A coolest new cars.
Final moments they never expected.
I got to go with that.
Oh, clickbait. Here we go. This is news.
This is a new segment is a new
segment called clickbait. All right.
This is the last known picture of the
RMS RMS titanic on the surface of the
ocean.
Yeah,
cause we found the fucker was taken
during her maiden voyage at crosshaven
Ireland
just after the vessel departed Queenstown
where it stopped before heading
westward towards New York.
Three days after this photo was taking
1,514 people would be dead and the
titanic would be titanic would be at
the bottom of the North Atlantic after
colliding with an iceberg and one of the
deadliest peacetime maritime disasters
in history.
How the fuck did you hit
one of those goddamn things?
I guess it was nighttime guy didn't
have the lights on. You know,
sometimes you're driving down the street.
You had no idea. Okay, next page. Okay.
And they got three advertising.
It's in there.
Fur Jacket. Fucking microchip.
Alright. Andrew Mccauley, 2007 well,
this doesn't look good. This is the
last known photo of animal calling
Australians Sea Kayaker who
is now presumed dead Mccauley
attempted to Kayak 994
miles across the Tasman sea in February,
2007 was never found. And how the
fuck did they get that picture?
Is that between, uh, where's the Tasman?
Is that between Tasmania in Australia?
Fuck all the Australians direction.
Like I'm dumb right now. Okay.
You're at the bottom of the fucking world.
I don't know.
I don't know what goes on down there.
Tez Man. See maybe, I guess
correctly the Tasman Sea.
The Tasman Sea.
Yeah.
Oh, was he trying to get all
the way over to New Zealand?
Jesus Christ in a fucking boat
that's like designed to tip over.
Yeah, I mean, you know.
Okay. All right. Well,
he definitely was trying to
protect his skin. All right.
Freddie Mercury 1991 oh Jesus.
Looks like an old peewee Herman. Freddie
Mercury was the lead singer of Queens.
He died of complications of AIDS,
really a related to AIDS.
He was key confirmed the day before he
died that he had contracted the disease.
This is the last known photo. All right.
Why the fuck would I want to see that?
That's arguably the greatest
front man of all time, Amelia.
Okay.
45 days before she embarked on our
infamous flight that would render her both
missing and eternally famous Amelia
Earhart pose for a photo shoot here.
She seen standing in front of the model
10 electra that would carry her to her
mysterious destiny.
Korean Airlines flight triple o seven 1983
it's plane took off from New York
because there's was shutdown is Soviet
airspace out. Jesus Christ. This is just
getting worse. The Ara, San Watteau.
This will be a bunch of people taking
selfies on bridges. Steve Irwin,
another Australian.
Yeah,
the USS Maine.
okay.
What did it fucking
collide with Paul Revere.
This is the wreckage of the
American battleship Maine,
which was destroyed along with 260
members of the blah, blah, blah,
likely by a mine.
They had minds even back then,
fucking lit lit a bale of Hay on fire,
sent it out there and take out a
wooden ship. Right? All right. Uh,
this is too creepy. Let's
lighten it up with, uh,
last selfies
before death. Half of
these are fake, by the way.
Yeah,
yeah. There you go. 19 selfies
taken moments before disaster.
There's one with the
fucking shark coming up.
10 selfies. Those, yeah. These are all
fucking bullshit. I like these things.
I want images.
I'll come on.
Couple people up on
climbing up on buildings.
Oh. Then there's the two beautiful
girls in the fucking car. Oh, Jesus.
There's a lot of them up. These fucking
kids that like the free climbers,
they climb up the top of buildings.
There's a lot of bullshit ones.
That guy's in pools with bad
pictures of great white sharks.
All right. What am I doing here?
Talking a lot about death here. Huh?
Um, anyways, let's get
back. Let's talk about, uh,
I don't know what the fuck else to talk
about if I'd done a fucking half hour at
this point. You know, I think every once
in a while you should have, oh shit.
34 minutes,
34 minutes of,
I don't know what the fuck
that was. Sorry guys. I had to,
I had to get this thing done because I've
got all this other bullshit I have to
end up doing tomorrow.
Do you know I,
I would like to think that
the woman getting married
nine Zillion fucking times.
Maybe there was a little bit of humor
in there. I have no idea. I'm sorry.
Did the fucking news. Nowadays, it's
just too goddamn depressing and I just,
I don't know how you guys do it.
How do you stay informed? Oh,
congratulations to Dean del Rey.
Everybody who got his first,
first Conan O'brien went over there
for the taping. He fucking killed it.
It was Burke. It was Mark Marin
who fucking ripped on guitar.
He got to find that clip after
he killed it on the couch.
He then went over and Jan with the band
and fucking play guitar at a whole other
level. Um, then Bert Kreischer killed it.
And then Dean del Ray was fucking
unbelievable. A former officer,
Roy Oliver sentenced to 15 years in
fatal shooting of teen. Holy Shit.
A cop went to jail. You don't
see that often, do you? Okay.
Code of silence. The Blue Code. All right.
What happened to your former Texas
police officer role in, in Texas?
Roy Oliver was sentenced to 15 years in
prison on Wednesday for the Burger of
murder of a 15 year old boy who was
shot while riding in a car full of teens
leaving a house party.
Uh,
all Oliver 38 was convicted on Tuesday
in the fatal of the high school. Fresh
freshmen, Jordan Edwards. All
right, hang on one second.
Let me see something.
Jordan Edwards,
teen shot.
Oh,
hey.
I thought it was going to be a white kid.
So they actually sent a cop to jail
for fucking killing a black kid.
Although you go miracles never cease. Not
shitting on the cops. I'm just saying,
you know, there's bad comedians.
There's bad cops, you know. Um,
anyways, I love Jesus. They
probably just got myself,
I should probably just got myself a ticket
right then and there. I swear to God,
I'll tell you right now,
that bald record motherfucker drives a
half fucking mile over the speed limit in
my county.
How dare you suggest that, uh,
even know human beings are flawed.
That may be some of them
are in my own profession.
Why am I picking on southern people there?
I don't know cause I'm limited.
Um, all right, I'm going to
read some advertising here.
Whenever the fuck I get it.
I'll probably read it tomorrow morning.
Um,
if I leave here tomorrow,
you,
um,
that's another thing too.
I watch all these old shows on me TV
and everybody's drinking and smoking and
then I'm watching this whole thing on
Leonard Skinner and everybody's drinking
smoke or do it. Oh, this fucking shit.
And uh, yeah, it starts giving you ideas.
Maybe if I got to start watching a
workout shows, maybe I should do that.
Are their workouts shows whatever
happened in the biggest loser? You know,
what happened is the fucking guy on there
had a goddamn heart attack figure that
one out. And the other woman, I don't
know where she went, she broke off.
She went solo and she started
doing her own exercise videos,
if I remember correctly.
All right,
I'm going to read some
advertising here for Y'all.
Just going to read a couple advertisements
here for y'all and then I'm gonna, uh,
you're going to listen to some music
and then we're going to play a,
some greatest hits from a
Thursday afternoon podcast
from, I dunno, some fucking,
I dunno when earlier this year,
maybe last year, two years ago.
I don't fucking know. Um, but uh,
I'll have more information on our,
uh, the Patrion page. Got a bunch
of things that, about all things,
comedy coming up,
a bunch of things that I would love to
announce now that I'm not allowed to
announce due to contractual
agreements and a,
um, some f is for family shit.
I got all his shit coming up.
I know when it's coming out.
The ink isn't dry yet,
so I can't fucking announce it.
I really want to tell you when
f is for families coming out,
but I'm not allowed to do so yet. I would
like to, uh, tell you about some, uh,
other shit we got going on, but
I'm not allowed to. All right,
I'm talking in circles. Here's the
advertising at, uh, have a great weekend.
You can sit. I'll see you on Monday.
I'll be in there in a minute.
Okay. Uh, alright, borrow. Go ahead.
You can get out. You can get on.
I'll just sit here. Uh, only
a couch from hell is a right
or a passage. I, he too
expensive. Too heavy,
too cheap to warn. I'm going to get out.
So don't dive without the frog and AC. Oh,
you got to pull away from the curb.
I just destroyed your door.
Please use one of your
negative couch experiences.
I used to live at Bobby Kelly and he
used to fight fucking find them on the
sidewalk in New York City. See,
had no idea what sort of crack head
slapped and fucked on the thing.
But then after he had a bowl of
cereal on it somehow. What was yours?
Was that a personal enough?
After all these years of suffering,
you owe it to yourself to experience the
comfort and quality of borough couch.
Burl.
Bring Style and comfort to a whole new
level and ships to your door fast and
free. Your relationship with your
couch will never be the same.
Borough selfers our air ergonomically
designed so I'm comfortable while I don't
know what 77 sunset strip.
Um,
Customize Your Birth Sofa Sofa to match
your style by selecting the colors, size,
armrest, height and leg color.
A shipping is fast and free,
unlike the rest of the furniture industry.
I can attest to that.
Those fucking slow bastards.
And did I mentioned it has a built
in USB charger in your couch.
That's amazing.
Enjoy 30 days of cozy on your comfortable
borough risk-free or try out borough
at one of their partners show rooms today.
Customize your own borough and
get $75 off your order by going to
borrow.com/burr B u r r a.
That's borough.com B u r r.
O w slash [inaudible] dot com for $75 off
your purchase borough makes the luxury
couch for real life. And
lastly, but certainly not least,
the Oh butcher box.
I love these guys.
Butcher box delivers healthy 100% grass
fed, grass finished beef free range,
organic chicken, chicken and the
game changer. Heritage bread, pork,
the best pork chop I've ever made at home.
It's incredible.
Incredible quality of butcher box meat
starts with a commitment to raising
animals humanely and free of antibiotics
and hormones before they kill them.
Each box comes with at least
nine to 11 pounds of meat,
which is enough for 24 individual sizes,
sized meals or a couple
of lunches for a fat fuck.
You can choose five different
boxes. All beef, beef and chicken,
beef and pork mixed box and custom
box lets you, uh, the custom box.
Let you choose your own cuts. Um, uh,
in order to receive free bacon for life
of subscription plus $10 off your order,
go to butcher box.com.
Click on the big bacon banner on the
homepage and use the burpee you are at
checkout. Go now, limited time offer. Um,
it's the best pork chop I
ever had. Definitely recommend
the heritage bread. Pork.
I'm sure the chicken and beef are great
too, but I'm loving the pork. All right,
there you go. Oh, look who's back.
Just in time for football
season, draft kings, everybody.
Football's about to make its long
anticipated return to the living rooms all
across America.
That means bragging rights and huge cash
prizes are up for grabs@draftkings.com
the leader in one week, fantasy sports
with one week fantasy draft kings.
You choose when to play.
Draft a new team every week with no
season long commitment. At draft kings,
you are the GM.
Just choose your players.
Stay under the salary cap and see
how your team stacks up against the
competition.
No matter what your skill level is,
there's a contest winning
for you are drafting.
So if you've been thinking about
trying one week fantasy football,
now is the time to play because
nothing makes football Sunday.
More exciting than when you have draft
kings lineup on the line to celebrate.
Week one. Drafting is hosting
a free team. Pick them promo,
download the APP and go to draft kings.com
now and use Promo code [inaudible].
All you have to do is pick at least
half of the winning teams correctly and
you'll win a share of 1 million bucks.
That's Code Berbee.
You are our only a draft kings.
The game inside the game.
Eligibility restrictions apply.
See draft
kings.com/pick them for details.
All right,
this is not a bomb test or anything.
I'm doing the reads in the car here.
I am not driving, I'm being safe.
All right, hymns, everybody.
Sexual performance issues
more common than you think.
Uh,
your 25% over 25% of new ed cases are
guys under 40 40% of men by the age of 40.
Struggle from not being able to
get and maintain an erection.
Even the world's greatest
actor can't fake one.
Why the guys turned to weird solutions
or do nothing when they can turn instead
to medicine and science or lay off
Internet porn for a couple of weeks for
hims.com a one stop shot for hair loss,
skincare,
sexual wellness from men.
Jesus.
Thanks to science ed can be optional.
No waiting room,
no awkward in personal doctor visits.
So what's wrong with you?
Schmeck no lines save hours by going to
four hymns.com hims connects with you
with real doctors and medical
grade solutions to treat Ed.
Products are shipped directly to your
door with ED products stamped on the side
of the box.
Kidding well known generic equivalents
to name brand prescription to help you
combat Ed.
Try Hymns for a month today for just
five bucks will get you started for just
five bucks while supplies last.
See website for full details.
This would cost hundreds if you
went to the doctor or a pharmacy.
Go to hims.com h I m
s.com/b u r r capital Ed.
That's for hymns.com for h I m
s.com/burr ed for hims.com/bird Ed.
All right, the next one. Who Do we
got here? Who's up next? Oh honey.
Millions of people are using honey
to save money shopping online and why
wouldn't they? It's free. Takes two,
just two clicks to add to your
browser and saves you tons of money.
It's ingenious or one of my absolute
favorite things about honey is how much
better it makes shopping on
Amazon. Um, yeah, turn right here.
Uh, please personalize
this to make it your own.
I am making it my own honey magically
adds all sorts of useful information right
on your Amazon page of
whatever you're looking for.
Just shop like you normally do.
Honey automatically searches the 2
million sellers on Amazon to find you the
lowest price. It even shows
you the item's prices, uh,
changes. So you can decide if you want to
buy or wait for the price to come down.
If you decide to wait,
just add it to your honey drop list and
it will notify you if the price drops
when honey guts,
when honeys got your back.
You'll never overpay for
anything on Amazon again.
What's the last purchase you made with
honey on Amazon? How much did it save you?
I haven't used it yet, but I'm sure
it's great. Was that personal enough?
There's no reason to add honey to
your browser today. It's free. Uh,
just takes two clicks to install.
We'll make sure you always get
the lowest price on Amazon.
Add honey to your browser for free right
now@jointhoney.com slash bird
that's join honey.com/burr
do
pappa
[inaudible]
balls.
We ended up watching something on TV,
one of the sickest stories ever.
And we're like, dude, this
has to be a fucking movie.
The mega star who was Benjamin
button than muddy balls.
Billy Bean is now interested in
playing none other than Jimmy Keane.
And uh, of course in the end they, they,
they said that they were turned into a
movie was basically about this guy, right?
It was this fucking show
about serial killers.
So of course we're going to watch it.
In 1983,
Jesse was a high school sophomore
devoted to home and family.
Jessia was really very much of a homebody.
So one bike right up the road
and back she was done. Um,
so we're watching this thing about
fucking serial killers and the whole time
they're talking about this,
this drug dealer kid and well,
I kind of fucked is this. And they
keep showing this serial killer guy.
It's like does in the show
in the drug dealer, older,
you know, and not in jail and all that
shit going, what the fuck happened?
You know, just the way they
put it together, you was
you ribbon and you're like,
what the fuck is going on here?
So basically what happened was there
was this kid, right? He played football,
they called them the assassin
because every game he ever played,
he took somebody out,
right? Was it the assassin?
I heard they called you the assassin
in football. That was a good thing.
I take it.
Yes.
Was that Jack Tatum? Check
Tatum. Now I forget what it was.
Something like assassin.
So
he fucking, uh, interests movie
star good looks all right.
And he's The star of the football
team. All the women loved him. I mean,
this guy was just like,
it was,
he looked like a movie star
in his life was a movie.
So his big Achilles heel was,
he didn't have money and he wanted
to keep up with the rich kids.
So we started dealing drugs and he ended
up being really good at it and by the
time he was like 20 years old,
this fucking guy was making
like $1 million a year
expanded to cocaine and
at the tender age of 17,
he moved to Chicago where the
business and profits exploded.
He was now a big fish in a bigger pond,
Lake Michigan to be exact.
He was his own in crowd fast cars,
faster women and souped up living
all the hot spots, all the big nightclubs,
all the owners I was in tight with.
Um, I would come in there and have carte
blanche in every place that I went to.
Where you're feeling invincible.
Yeah,
there was a certain point where I would
say there was an invincible feeling.
It almost seemed like this American greed
type story as opposed to this serial
killer thing and they keep going back
to this serial killer fucking piece of
shit. Who's killing these
girls? These teenage girls.
So long story short, he's laying in
bed one night and he's just thinking,
I got to get out of this life.
I'm so sick of looking over my shoulder,
I can't do this anymore.
How am I going to get out of his?
But he's addicted to the money.
He's addicted to the life and
all of that type of stuff.
And he has this rattling on the
door and I'm thinking, oh fuck,
it's the serial killer.
And he obviously fought the guy in one.
What the fuck happens, right?
All of a sudden the door fucking
boom, the whole door blew off the
hinges and come flying into the house.
And all of these DEA,
FBI and locals all came in and
single file line with their law.
Automatic weapons.
Yeah. Was that alcohol? Tobacco farming?
I don't know. What the fuck are you?
So anyways, they fucking come from
FDA food, Drug Administration,
the uh, transit Chicago Transit
Authority. I don't what the fuck it is.
Whatever the fuck that thing is.
They come fucking blast
and through the door run,
you know a bunch of guys with the fucking
minor helmets on with the fucking Uzis
from a Steven Seagal movie.
Don't get on a graph. You fucking look
at me. I'll blow your fucking head off.
And the whole thing was over and
he just scraped his family name.
Did your pop know what you're doing?
Do they suspect?
He didn't suspect it until much,
much later.
Jimmy grew up in the shadow of his father,
big gym,
a giant of a man who was a cop,
fireman and hero to his son.
He's my best friend. He was my backbone
and pretty much everything I did.
And they never said it,
but I imagine they probably took his
fucking pictures down off of the high
school and all of that type of shit,
you know, did some Oj Shit, right?
Take all his trophies and all that
fucking shit. So it's over. Right?
So then he's sitting in jail,
um,
and they tried to get him
to flip and this is kids,
just some fucking kid from the suburbs,
right? So I'm thinking, well, he's out.
He must've ratted somebody out
so he doesn't rat anybody out.
He's like, I'm not telling on anybody.
So then they're like, all right,
well fuck you. So now we're going to help
us out. We're going to fucking give you,
you know, the full extent of the
law, we're going to prosecute you.
So they gave him 10 years.
The guy gets 10 years
and in court, Beaumont
showed keen, no mercy,
he was coming at you on all fours. I
wasn't like, Oh God, here. I mean he was,
he was a bulldog. Jimmy was convicted
and slapped it with a 10 year sentence.
He's in like a minimum
security cause you know,
he didn't really have any
violent past or anything.
He was just getting people addicted
to drugs. That's all he was doing.
So his dad is devastated and all
that shit and he goes to jail.
And um, meanwhile this serial killer
guys out there killing these girls.
So I'm thinking, what the fuck? Wait.
And they keep going and commercial mean
versus you're looking at each other
going, how the fuck are they going
to tie this fucking thing together?
But baseball kid comes with bad
in six balls. Assembly required,
new from Ohio are.
Long Story Short, um, they ended
up catching the serial killer guy.
Uh,
I forget how we fucked up,
but they ended up catching him in one
of those things where you seem like
relieved and all of that type of shit.
And a,
but he had this thing where he
wouldn't admit to all of them.
And if he came at him, he would
just clam up. It wouldn't say shit.
He denied confessing the any killing,
including Jessie's and Trisha's.
What's more,
he claimed it was all a misunderstanding
about disturbing dreams he had.
So he ends up going to jail for like
either one or two murders for life.
He's never fucking getting out.
So meanwhile there's all these parents
whose daughters were killed by this guy
and they don't know where they are
and all they just want as the body,
they want fucking closure.
And these parents had just tortured
by this fucking thing. All right,
so they're trying to figure out,
because he won't talk to them,
you won't tell him anything. And he's
also in denial and he keeps going like,
actually I didn't kill him
and blah blah blah blah blah.
And then one day and be like,
oh I did and I blacked out.
I don't remember like the was, he's
a fucking creepy goddamn mess. Right.
So they ended up coming up with this idea
that they need a charismatic person to
talk to this to prefer friend.
This syrah killer gained the guys trust.
And maybe he'll tell him where like
the bodies are in that type of shit.
So they go to this fucking dude,
Captain America,
you know the football player,
the movie star looking guy who fucked his
whole life up cause he got involved in
drugs.
Right.
And they approach him to go from his
minimum security to go into a maximum
security prison with his murderers,
rapists, animals, fucking maniac.
That's right. And um, you know,
to go in there and they said,
if you,
if you get this information out,
we'll take your sentence
and we'll just wipe out.
The rest of it will set you free. He'd
already done like three, four years.
And he came up with an outside
the box game to get hall,
which would risk the life of that
charismatic convict via just put away for
dealing drugs.
Jimmy Kim,
what happens when I've gotta deal with
all these crazy killers and stuff?
You know what if I get shanked,
what if I get killed? I mean,
am I gonna survive this?
So
meanwhile, Captain America's Dad
had a series of strokes, you know,
and was basically gonna die and
he had to go see him. I mean,
it's like a fucking movie. So he goes,
all right, fuck it. I'll, I'll do it.
We cried through the window to each
other and we talked for awhile and uh,
he didn't even know about the offer.
Nobody know about it.
Jimmy now realize Betty had a one time
only opportunity to fix the mess he made
for himself and get out while
his dad was still alive.
But I want it in writing
it. You're definitely going
to let me go. So they say,
yeah. So they go out, right?
Egos. They go, here's the deal.
We don't want you to approach
him for at least six months
because he's very cagey in if she fucking,
you know, come at to guy the wrong way,
he just fucking walls himself
off and that's it. All right,
so this kid comes walking, he
goes in, he goes, fine, cool.
And he walks in and he's like, I don't
have six months. My Dad's gonna die.
All he wanted was to get in and out
with Trisha's location and as fast as
possible
within the first two
months, two, I'm sorry,
first two hours he goes into
the fucking jail. Any fucking,
uh, on purpose, accidentally
bumps into the guy.
I was waiting with my tray and
I look over and there he is, 20,
25 feet away from me sitting
there all by himself.
It felt like a magnet was compelling
me to come to him and finally act bump
shoulders with them on purpose.
And then he immediately apologizes.
He goes, I'm sorry about that buddy.
I didn't see a standing there.
Hey, he goes, I'm new here.
Do you know where the library is? And
the guy tells him where the library is.
And he goes, thanks man. Uh, you know,
and he said something to the effect of a,
yeah, you're a good guy and gives him a
little slap on the shoulder. That's it.
It goes to the fucking library.
And they set it up where his fucking,
his cell was right across
the hall from the other guy.
And he says to him, he goes, hey man,
he runs into him again. Hey, wait,
you stay and blah blah. He
goes, oh, that's crazy man.
You want him running across?
And he said, it's good to be with a
good guy like you, blah, blah, blah,
right across from each
other. And he goes, uh,
so then fucking the serial
killer guy one day he goes, hey,
you want to get lunch
with me and my friends?
And at this point me and [inaudible]
were fucking laughing our balls off going
like this kind of social
shit happens in prison. Okay,
y'all are some friends of mine,
uh,
going to have some other murderers and
serial killers. We're going to get some,
uh, maybe get some, but you know,
frapin a fucking rap or something.
You want to come down, just kinda hang
out, I'll meet you down the coma, Sarah.
You always think it's all just getting
shanked and trying not to get raped.
Right. So he goes, yeah, cool.
So long story, he gains this
guy's fucking confidence.
And one time he actually
goes in and he sees the guy,
he's got a map with all these
red dots on it and all that shit.
And as I came up from behind him,
he had all these little
different statues lined up,
10 15 of them maybe. And I couldn't
tell what they were at first.
And as I got closer,
I noticed he had a big map laid out
and he dove on that map and folded that
thing up really fast and slid it off
to the side of the table. And I go,
what are these things? Anyway, he
says, there are these little falcons,
he's trying to get to it and blah,
blah blah.
So the guy starts opening up any
finally ends up telling him this fucking
stories, um, of all the women that
he killed and all of that shit.
And,
uh,
in sort of kind of mentioned it gave him
like sort of enough information about
where the bodies were and the captain
America guy kind of fucked up because once
he got the information he thought he
had enough information to find all the
bodies and get himself out of prison
and he just couldn't have, oh wait,
I forgot the best part. I'm sorry.
It's gonna be like a Terantin a movie.
Now we're going to jump backwards.
Another way he gained the guy's confidence
was one day they was sitting in the
TV room watching TV.
He sit next to this guy and this big
fucking giant dude just gets up and turns
the channel
without talking to anybody.
And as he turns to channel the serial
killer who was unlike a meek little guy
and he just kind of went, he just sorta
said out loud to nobody who's like, Hey,
I was watching that.
That's not right.
I was watching that
like powerlessly really
fucking weird psycho thing.
And the fucking captain America Dude
walked up to the big dude and knocked him
out.
Just beat the guy's ass,
hit him with an upper cut fucking forearm
shiver and just sent this guy flying
through some chairs and then they stuck
them in the hall. That's what happened.
And then when he fucking comes out,
tell me he doesn't sound like a fuck.
I almost don't even believe it. So that's
when he gained the guy's conference.
That's when the dude told him and
his second, he tells him this dude,
Captain America couldn't hold it in
anymore. And he goes to, do you know what?
You're a sick fucking piece of shit,
Blah Blah Blah. And flipped out on him
full of yourself then. Yeah, I did that.
I thought it was good for me to unload
on him and tell him what I really thought
of him and who he really
was. I said, you know,
so I'm gonna be going home tomorrow
there. I said, you're a crazy killer.
And I started calling them
everything you can think of.
And then the guy, the CEO kill just backed
up and he goes, he goes, who sent you?
And he goes, so and so sent you
writing any named the prosecutor.
And then he just fucking disappeared
and the map disappeared too.
So then it's like they didn't get the map.
So there was a thing,
we don't know where the fucking bodies
still are, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
But you got him to admit
to these fucking murderers.
So we know that the women are least dead.
The blobby basically.
Then he did enough where he got out.
Um,
and the whole time we were watching this
fucking thing, we would just go on like,
this is a,
this is a fucking movie.
And I guarantee you when
they do the fucking movie,
they don't even need to add any mustard
to it. But I guarantee you in the movie,
he won't flip out in the end, you know,
or free flips out. But then he somehow,
and then that'll be the last
little leg kick up. Like, oh no,
they didn't find the map and the movie,
he'll find the map and then
parents will actually get closure
button. Real life, you know.
[inaudible]
do we change
this
going on? It's built bar and it's the
Monday morning podcast for Monday,
uh, August 30th, 2010. I'll look at that.
There's 31 days in August this year.
I didn't realize that. I thought, uh,
all the,
the rent and everything like that
was going to be due on Tuesday,
but this year I think it's every,
every nine years.
There's 31 days in August and you can
look that up to people. That's um, a,
you know, 40 days has
November, April, September,
and remember all the rest
got 28 [inaudible] so I don't
know what you're talking
about. Isn't that how
it goes? Um, anyways.
Fuck is 29th. I'm recording
this. Tomorrow is August 30th.
And you're listening to it right
now on August 30th. All right.
What happened to the thumber? Where
did it go? It's, it's over, man.
I hope you enjoyed it. Didn't I tell
you guys do enjoy it back in May.
Did you listen to me? You didn't digit.
You thought, ah, we got plenty of time.
There's plenty of fucking time. Then
what happened? Next thing you know,
it's August 29th.
You know,
you're looking down at you pasty
legs go and Jesus Christ. Yeah.
Your farmer's Tan from all on the
fucking long. You didn't do shit.
I warned you. I told you in May was
going to fly by. And what'd you do?
Did you spend one night roasting
marshmallows as they say in Boston?
Um, I'm doing this on the 29th, so
it will be ready early on the 30th.
And also because, uh, this week, as of
right now, when you're listening to this,
I will be onset.
Isn't that exciting?
This whole week I'm shooting my
pilot for comedy central Monday,
Tuesday, Wednesday,
Thursday, Friday. And uh,
unless we make a horrific piece of
shit, um, according to the deal,
it's definitely going to air. So
a, I better make sure that, uh,
my acting game is where it needs to be.
Um,
because we start shooting tomorrow.
I'm actually really excited about this
show and as always, I don't name names,
so, uh, you know,
you don't even need to know names because
if it's going to be worth anything,
you're going to know who the fuck's in it.
But I think it's going to be great and
I'm really excited about it and maybe
this'll be the one that
actually gets me to be on TV.
Right?
Then all of a sudden it goes to a second
season and then you notice I'm getting
a little bloated.
You know,
I come to your town to do stand up and
I'm just not as sharp as I used to be
when I was hungry,
when I wanted to have a show and
all of a sudden you guys like,
you know he's not as fun as he used to be.
I like the old Bill Burr,
the pre TV show bill burr.
Why is he wearing a bathrobe and
slippers on stage as he working out of
character for his new hit show or did
he just roll out of fucking bed to come
down here, drink a little scotch
and collect his fucking check?
That's exactly what I'm going
to be doing. Okay. People,
when I get on television, I, if I
get my own that this TV show goes,
my standup is going to
go do fucking south.
I'm telling you right now.
I never liked stand up.
It was all just a tool to get me.
I'm fucking with you.
I'm Archie already paranoid about that.
I'm already sitting there and I'm
thinking in my head, typical me,
typical east coast negative guy,
just looking for the next shoe to
drop rather than being like, oh fuck,
I can be on a hit TV show and uh,
you know,
my life could be awesome. I'm
already thinking, Oh fuck.
What's going to happen in my stand up?
How can I work in guest spots during the
week so I can stay so I can stay sharp?
You know, I don't trust these
fuckers. Yeah, it's a hit. Oh,
is it? Yeah. I, I'm believing you.
You guys are fucking pulled that Charlie
Brown pull the football fucking thing
or Lucy, whatever that costs
name is from the peanuts gang.
Um, too many times. So I'm not buying it.
I won't buy it until it goes into
syndication. What's your show about?
What is it? Is that, is that
a comedy? Is that a drama?
It's on comedy central.
Just you and anybody who has a Nielsen
box. Whenever the fuck it comes out,
please sit there.
Find the oldest person on your
block cause God knows they have it.
Whoever is the oldest person on your
block or whoever's the most indeed Jesus,
they are old g,
they're going to be the ones
who have the Nielsen box.
Those are the people that
determine, I guess, you know why?
Cause they actually have
time to write letters. Um,
anyways,
so that's the deal.
I'm shooting a show this week that is
going to air on comedy central at some
point. And uh, speaking of
something, airing on comedy central,
just to let you know, my
standup special, let it go,
was finally airing September
18th on comedy central and die.
I believe it's going to be uncut.
Hopefully it'll show up late at night
when my crowd is just stumbling in from
whatever fucking for the lab for the last
four hours of mistakes that they made
on of night of drinking.
Okay.
And after you have it out with your
significant other and she doesn't let you
sleep in the room or whatever,
he doesn't let you whatever
sloppy mess you are, just go,
you know,
sit down and you're fucking lazy boy.
And watch my special September
18th. All right, there we go.
I got all the hype out of the way and um,
I had a bunch of shit to
talk about this weekend. Um,
I know the NFL season starts on Thursday
night because the NFL is basically,
I think slowly trying to be seven
days a week, which I am against.
You know, I always thought it
was really unique how it just,
it all happened on fucking Sunday and
everybody was just fucking getting geared
up at sea anticipation.
Leave them wanting more classic show
business theory and the NFL had it like
nobody else and now they're talking
half, fuck, let's add more games.
18 weeks schedule 18 games, right?
Is that what they were trying to do?
They already got the bye week so
they got an extra fucking weekend.
They're right for more advertising now
they're trying to add two more days.
Now this shits, you got kicking
it off on a fucking Thursday.
They're playing in Europe. You know, I
really sound like a crabby old man. Whoa.
Don't worry. Priorities, Sean, Derek,
everybody gathered around a TV.
Um, I liked it better that way. What
the fuck is wrong with Sunday? You know,
you go to church. Oh Gee, you and
then you fucking, you sit down,
you get drunk and you watch the football
games. Nobody gets hurt. Show up Monday,
all hung over. Go and do, what the
fuck did they run it for there?
Oh, they should have passed it.
That's what I would've done.
That's what I would've done
seeing is now that I know that,
that they shouldn't have fucking
run it in that moment. So anyways,
I was trying to figure out
what the schedules were and um,
I ended up going on to see
what the Patriots have.
We got the Bengals the first
week with Batman and Robin.
I'm really gay anyways. Uh, so
it's checking out the schedule.
And one of the stories,
if you can fucking believe this,
the story is Tom Brady,
how he can swing the Peyton manning
debate in 2010 and this is what it says,
the Tom Brady,
Peyton manning debate has raged for the
past decade and will probably continue
to do so until the to retire every
time one seems to make their case.
The other offers a rebuttal the next year.
All right.
All of that's fair enough. I'll even give
you that, but this is what they say, man.
He made his case in 2009 by carrying his
team to a Superbowl birth with an MVP
season.
That's what they said.
Completely ignoring the fact that the
guy had the game in his fingertips.
Just like Tom Brady has four
fucking Superbowls and Tom
Brady has delivered four
fucking times.
Giant fans shut the fuck up.
The last time he got the ball,
he drove.
Actually he got the ball
with like eight seconds left.
You're going to be cuts and
call them that, you know,
and count them on that one.
But even when we lost to the giants,
when he had time to drive down the field,
that's exactly what the fuck
he did for the go ahead.
Score for the unprecedented for time,
fourth time and the biggest fucking
game in professional football.
He's done it for fucking times.
He's got three rings.
Peyton manning has one fucking ring
and he had the Superbowl on his fucking
fingertips. And not only does he
not drive them for a, for a fee,
and I know I'm going through this again,
but I have to because people
keep forgetting this shit he had,
he had the game winning drive
right there to go. You go ahead,
Peyton drive down the fucking field.
Not only does he not score that touchdown,
not only do they anemic,
not get a field goal,
he throws a pick fucking six to
lose the game for his fucking team.
And somehow I want to
know where the debate is.
Where is the debate?
Indianapolis Colts fans.
Which would you rather
have as a quarterback?
A guy who acts absolutely annihilates
the competition in the regular season.
Okay.
And can only get you one championship or
would you rather have the other guy who
wins three out of four fucking bowls?
What would you rather have?
You want three rings. You want
one? The debate is fucking over.
There is no debate
as far as I'm concerned.
Peyton manning is still chasing old
date rape there in fucking Pittsburgh
because as much as you wouldn't want
that son of a bitch around your daughter,
God dammit. You got to want
them under center. Right.
This is bullshit that just,
they just put this out here
to get people all pissed off.
Just like that mosque at Ground Zero
that had me pissed for 48 fucking hours
before I found out.
It's not at ground zero.
It's fucking two three blocks up
the street and it's not a mosque.
It's like a fucking wreck. Rump.
All right. I don't give a fuck.
You want to go in there and play
Ping Pong? It talk about Mohammed.
I don't give a shit, but what did they say
it? It's a mosque. It's at ground zero.
The building a brunch statute.
Who is some had been London.
You should have seen me frothing at
the mouth, like a dog that had gone,
Matt actually got into a fucking
debate about it with somebody you know,
went out when I,
when I thought it was an actual mosque,
when I thought it was
being built at ground zero,
like I was told they're building
a mosque at ground zero,
you know, so I was like, you
gotta be fucking kidding me.
Not only did they not rebuild the towers,
not only their architects still acting
like they give a fuck when the reality is
that they want the contract so they can
put their fucking name on the building.
Not only is that bull shit
been going on for what,
nine fucking years now they're
going to put a mosque down there.
I was literally beside myself and uh,
I was getting into tons of arguments out
here in Hollywood about it during the
48 hours when I actually thought they
were building a mosque at ground zero. Um,
and they fucking, you know,
these Douche bags out here,
they will usually do reteaching you
thinking like, I don't realize that.
Like, I realize that it was not
the religion. I realized that Shit,
but you know, you know, how about, how
about just having a little bit of tact,
you know, you know what I
mean? That's all I'm saying.
That's all I'm saying. I know it's not
the fucking religion. Okay. But you know,
look, look at my religion.
Look at the Jesus freaks.
Go out there and kill fucking
abortion doctors now with 18 of them,
flew a fucking a, you know,
assessment into an abortion clinic.
Fucking blew the God damn place up.
And then the next day they wanted to put
a big bronze statue of Jesus across the
street.
And people,
the sons and daughters of the abortion
doctors had a fucking problem with that.
I will be like, yeah, you know, do we, do
we really have to put it there? I mean,
it's not us, right? We didn't do it.
It's not the whole fucking religion,
but really all the fucking places you
could put a big bronze statues of fucking
hey Seuss there. Oh, Jesus. Right?
We can't just fucking, you know,
maybe go like quarter mile, half mile
up the fucking street. That's all.
That's all I'm saying. Right?
That was my fucking argument.
And we were going back and forth and I
realized that's not even a Goddamn mosque
. It's not at ground zero. Okay.
Three blocks up the street,
the building like a lemonade
stand or some shit. And as always,
I didn't really quite fucking read
up on that part of it. But um,
yeah, so whatever. So that's the
same thing with this Tom Brady,
Peyton manning debate. There is no
fucking debate. This is ESPN guys,
all these sports guys, they
have this nothing left to
fucking debate. So they did,
they learned that with that Yankees,
red sox keep pitting
them against each other.
Even when everybody's kind of over it.
You know,
it's like once the curse of the
babe was broken, it's fucking over.
Who gives a fuck? Yes. We're
going to play each other. Yes.
The Yankees will win it again. Oh look,
the red sox won it again too. It's over.
And they keep trying to sell it to you.
And what are the greatest rivalries?
No one gives a fuck. And by no one,
I mean I don't give a fuck anymore.
Therefore, nobody gives a fuck in
this Tom Brady, Peyton manning debate,
there is no fucking debate.
Peyton manning cannot care. He can't
hold fucking Tom Brady's jockstrap.
He can't
look.
Anybody can kick the shit out of people
during the fucking regular season,
but when it counts, when
it counts, what do you do?
What do you do these stand out like a man.
I'll fucking relax like Joe Montana and
drive your team down the fucking field
or do you get that little bitchy tone
in your fucking voice? Okay guys,
how it's going to be on tour
and you get under center. Well,
whatever you do gotta beat. Marsha, got
to get closer than a quarter of an inch.
Remember that one Greg Brady striving
that fucking caprice classic or whatever
the fuck they had whipping
it around the parking lot,
making fun of how broad can't drive.
One of my favorite fucking
episodes of the Brady bond.
My two favorite episodes was the first
half of that Brady Bunch episode when
Greg Brady was bringing the fucking
hammered down and was going,
let me tell you three fucking
stepsister bitches, something.
None of you broads know how to drive.
And that includes your mother
who I'm banging by the way,
who are banking by the way.
All right.
With their weird ass haircut,
whenever the fucked, you know,
did anybody ever have that fucking
haircut at other than her? I mean,
that is like,
I don't know what it was.
She took like Mo from the three stooges
haircut and then she put a fucking sort
of mullet that she did a little
flipped to on the back. Anyways,
let's get back to you broads,
you know, not to fucking drive.
That goes for you with the
fucking speech impediment.
You don't know how to fucking drive
Jan with your awful fucking Hasidic Jew
fucking curls. I don't know what you're
trying to do, you know, and, and,
and Marcia who,
I don't know why I'm not banging you some
reason I skipped over you and started
banging your mother, right? None
of you bitches can fucking drive.
And I'm watching this episode going
this, see Greg Brady says, Shit,
Greg [inaudible] Fuck Fonzie. You know,
with his stupid fucking, you know,
spinning around and punching a jukebox
so plays Shaboom Shaboom I don't give a
fuck about that. I like
Greg Brady, you know,
for as much as Fonzie was talking shit,
he was always nice to the ladies and he,
that's, that's seventh grade game
with the woman Greg Brady. That's,
that's how Greg ended up fucking their
mom because he didn't give a shit.
He didn't give a fuck Greg. Fuck
you Carol. You're not my mother.
You know how to drive either.
Oh my God.
Took him in that fucking Groovy
Adic they had started blowing up
twice here.
Got All curly.
So anyways,
that episode,
he's telling these fucking broads
that they don't know how to drive.
And then in the end of course,
cause they always have to cater to women,
these nerdy fucking writers, you know,
and then the end they fucking, you know,
Marsha goes around this stupid fucking
track and they had a cone with a little
egg on it. You guys have seen
this and she fucking, you know,
I forget whatever Marsha chokes in the
beginning and then in the end just to
fucking even it out so everybody's happy
and they could sell tide during the
commercials. They have Greg fuck
up and knock the egg off. That's,
that's what I was trying to get to.
Wasn't that what I was trying to
get to that one on so fucking long.
I can't even remember.
All I'm saying is
that the guy you want,
you don't,
it doesn't fucking matter
how many yards you throw
in the regular season.
It doesn't fucking matter unless you're,
you got 'em on your fantasy fucking team,
whatever that means.
Evidently that makes you sit up a little
bit straighter in your Ikea Office
chair on Monday. I don't know what the
fuck it means, but at the end of the day,
how you judge a quarterback is in
those fucking moments. Okay. All right.
And I understand the Barry Sanders
out there played on the lines.
It's a horrific franchise.
I can't judge him like that.
He never had the opportunity.
So I don't,
but when I see a guy like Peyton manning
who is had the opportunities and he has
not delivered for them to sit
there and try to act like this,
fucking debate is still going on.
It isn't.
There is no Peyton Manning, Tom Brady
debate Peyton. Manny has to redeem.
He has to redeem himself.
You don't think the players on his
team of fucking questioning them.
This is the guy,
this is the guy leading us to battle.
Who's great during bootcamp,
who's great during the war games.
We play during fucking regular season,
but when it really comes down to live
ammunition in the fucking playoffs,
this fucking guy's curling up in a Fox
hole blaming the fucking radar guy.
We had communication issues.
Fuck you.
There is no debate as far as I'm
concerned. You guys can chime in.
You guys can chime in. Go ahead.
Indianapolis. Huh? With the ISTEP team.
They're the fucking
Baltimore colts by the way.
That would be great if it and started,
I said the Baltimore Colts. Um.
Anyways. All right. I enjoyed that.
I'm sure a lot of other people didn't.
A lot of people probably
turn that off going. I'm,
so let's take a hint talking
about Peyton manning. Well,
I'm going to react to everything that
they write on the news and I guarantee
you're going to watch Peyton manning
again this fucking year. Just light it up.
Light it up. Absolutely. Five,
6,000 fucking yards.
Right.
And always got is that little fucking,
you know,
he's got one little Superbowl
ring, you know, like,
like that fucking professional gambler
who one time took the big pot and went
down to the gift shop.
Got himself something fucking shiny.
You know what about the other nine digits?
They got nothing sitting there naked.
Losing every fucking night. Coming
home to a sparsely furnished apartment.
You know, don't you have a flat screen TV
anymore? You still get that big fucking,
you know,
zenith color TV
that's been around since before the
world series of poker. That's, that's,
that's where Peyton manning is right now.
All right.
Okay. I think I fucking pretty
much poured salt in the field.
Burned down the village.
Right. That's over. Okay.
For those of you had to
sit there and endure that.
Let's give you some pleasurable viewing.
Why don't you guys do yourself
a favor and go over to the Mlm,
podcast.com where you can watch
all of these funny youtube videos.
Um, here are the youtube videos
for the week. Everyone. Um,
first one, number one search.
This one crazy guy sings karaoke.
Um,
this is a fucking great one.
I don't know if you guys want to write
a psychological breakdown to this guy.
I would really appreciate it cause I was
trying to figure out this guy's energy
if,
if it's like he's so fucking amped up
cause he's always wanting to perform that
it somehow manifested itself in this
spastic fucking look on his face.
I'll tell you right now he's an Asian guy.
And the second I saw this stuff,
fucking look on his face that he
makes right before we start singing.
And when he sings the chorus,
it really reminded me a killer Khan
and he wrestling fans out there.
Do you remember how killer Khan used
to when he used to come on the mic?
They acted like he couldn't speak
fucking English for God knows.
He probably taught at Princeton
during the fucking week.
He would just sit there going,
guys, no Virgilio guys him
and having this crazy
fucking look at his face.
And then Freddie Blassie
order the fucking manage them.
The grand wizard or wrestling would
step in acting like they knew how to
translate his shit.
That's who I was thinking of when you
watch this guy or he really went through a
breakup cause he's singing a breakup song
and he's mad at some bitch. I have no,
no idea, but it's a crazy guy. Sings
Karaoke. Please check that out.
A youtube video number two,
Hay bailing fun.
Now if you're sitting there
right now writing down,
all of these are trying to remember them,
just go to the [inaudible] podcast.com
we're going to have them all lined up for
your nice and fucking easy. Uh, here's
another one. Pole dance. It ruins wedding.
This one was so fucked up. I thought
it was fake, but evidently not a,
here's another one. Prank phone
call. Our calling in sick to Walmart.
And, uh, the last one. This is one
for after you've gone to lunch.
Look up fat wrapper.
Uh,
this one? Yeah, this one.
You'll have your jaw on your desk
looking at this one. Um, anyway,
so let's go back to this way.
I always wait till the youtube videos in
the end because I just stopped riffing
and I just thought of just,
you know,
and then go check this and then
I go into fucking robot mode. Um,
anyways, let's, let's plow ahead
here. Let's get me going again.
Let's get the funny going
again on this podcast. I'm, oh,
I know I always trash women on this,
on this podcast and um,
you know, so I'm always telling them the,
the, the bride's over there to fucking,
you know,
write some shit here,
talk some shit back so we can be nice
so we can be fair and balanced like all
those, uh, those, those are new shows,
those news programs that they have
that gave you screaming about mosques.
Do you know,
they're making a bakery where they will,
they have the fucking
biggest loser. Um, anyway.
All right. Uh, the empire strikes back
is the name of this one. Um, this is,
this is women. This is this
one, a female listener.
I have who just really just in a,
just an absolutely beautiful way.
Just dissects guys here.
So we're going to read this here,
our bill.
I've been listening to your podcast
every week for a while now. Um,
I'd like you to start off giving me
actually a really concise form of time and
then you get real vague nebulous of your
podcasts every week for a while now,
every week since 2009 everywhere for,
well,
I will see you at five minutes
past some hour today. Okay.
So be there. I've noticed you rag on
females, but I haven't been offended.
It's funny and I know it's all in good
fun. Hey, here's a cool girl. All right.
I heard the emails of the guys
who wrote in trashing women.
So I am answering the call to write
in and trash guys. God bless you.
Uh, let me give you a little context
about who I am. I'm an industrial,
seems seamstress, can't even say
it. I am an industrial seamstress.
Does that job still exist in
this country? That's great. Um,
who gets to listen to podcasts?
Podcasts while I work?
I'm 25 and had been married to my
husband for six years together for eight.
Okay. Let's try to dissect this woman.
All right. So she met her husband at 17,
got married at 19,
and she's an industrial seamstress.
You guys want to guess
what state she's in?
Um,
do you work at the last factory that
hasn't been turned into a Condo in Ohio?
This is just as like a character
on little house on the prairie.
Does your husband have polio? Um, anyways,
he is also a fan of you and your
comedy. Uh, we have no kids,
but we do have a three year old male
am staff. I don't know what that is.
Terrier and an hopefully we'll have a
picture of that on the [inaudible] podcast
am staff a m s t,
a f f terrier and a nine month
old blue nose American pit bull.
God bless you.
My mother raised me on her own and I am
the youngest of four kids because I grew
up without a father in my life.
I am sure that a huge part of my dislike,
that's a huge part of my disliking of men.
Is there anything better than someone
who could just address the fact that they
fucking hate something and actually
put a little bit of little bit of it on
themselves? I hope I've done
that. Why do I hate women?
Uh, I think it's because I'm a control
freak. I think that's what it is. And um,
I don't like people running my
life or attempting to run my life.
I don't like people budding into my life.
And that's how I view women.
And it's how I view the marital laws,
which I understand were
put together by men.
But I think that it was put together
by the Illuminati to keep people like
myself, regular guys, salt
of the earth guys, you know,
oh fucking just chip off the old
block kind of guys. You know,
the kind of guys you could pal around and
say, Gee Whiz, Gee whiz with, you know,
they prevent us from becoming rich
by,
let me look at tiger woods.
They cut that man and half
of vagina came in like a fucking radial
arm saw that flew off it's fucking
hinges
and just sliced that fucking
once in a lifetime talent,
right. And fucking half because why? Why?
Cause he cause he blew out
his knee because he rested
on his laurels now because
he got legally bound to
something that had a vagina.
That right there. And as you can
see, you know what it really is?
Is I always look at worst case
scenario shit. Like, look at me. I'm,
I'm taping a show that could go on to
become a hit show. And what do I do first?
I immediately worry that my standup is
gonna suffer rather than being like, hey,
this could be awesome.
All right, why don't,
why don't you just Smithville you're
a fucking psycho and you're a paranoid
maniac and you really don't know what
the fuck you're talking about. All right.
Guilty as charged, guilty as charged. Uh,
but I do know a lot about Greg Brady.
You've got to give me that. All right,
so here we go. Please let me share
with you the reasons why some men suck.
Look at this. She even said some men
and what have you got married so long?
So young. This girl is a catch here.
All right, number one. She says,
I don't like diesel guys. You know the
guys who drive, they're extremely lifted,
tricked out diesel trucks and
think that they are so fast.
I don't know what that
means. So cool. We mean,
they are always trying to get
me to race them in my evo.
I don't know what that is
either. And when I don't, uh,
because they're gay,
they blow black smoke out out
their exhaust and peel away.
Do you worry?
Do you live in Texas?
That just sounded like the beginning
of like urban cowboy. Anyway,
something about their huge truck makes
them think they have a huge dick. Ah,
I gotta go. I gotta go with you on
that one. Yes. I don't like those guys.
I don't like people who feel like because
of the car that they have, you know,
especially in myself
because I drive a hybrid.
I always get people giving me shit and
then they start talking about their car.
Like they fucking invented
it. Like they built it. It's
like, no, no, no. I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. Somebody, some other
man had to build that for you.
Do you understand that sweetheart?
So why don't you come on,
climb behind you a little shiny toy
that you don't even understand how it
fucking works. All right.
You can't. All right,
can I kind of plow ahead here and
actually stay with, uh, with, with,
with rather than interjecting my thoughts,
let's,
let's let the females talk here.
A number two,
my mother always taught me
that it is rude to stare.
I guess 50% of men either weren't
taught that or they don't care.
It is super fucking
annoying when men stare.
I totally understand seeing
an attractive person and,
and them getting your attention,
but it should end there.
There are too many guys
who just keep looking.
Ah, yeah. I, I'm only guilty of that when
I get drunk. Then I don't give a fuck.
I'm like, yeah, look at that and
they'll fucking titties on her. Um,
excuse me quite down, sweetheart. I'm
looking at you cleavage. Uh, anyway,
she says, get a grip
fag. Uh, like clockwork.
If I am walking up an accident
and accidentally make eye contact,
um, this guy might look away for now, but
the second I pass him and turn around,
turn around to bust him. Lo and
behold, he is fucking staring.
All right. I gotta tell you
something. Staring at a woman,
making her feel uncomfortable
is, is definitely not cool. Uh,
I totally agree with you on that, but
you know, if you fucking walk by me,
I can turn around and check
out your ass. All right. Yes.
If you have a problem with that,
um,
I feel bad for you because one
day you're going to turn around.
I Dunno. Could be when you're
27, it could be when you're 47,
I don't know when, but one day you're
going to turn around and low and behold,
the dude is not going to be staring.
And let me tell you something.
That is not a fun fucking day.
So enjoy those day.
As long as he's not running back at you,
grabbing your ass. If he's turn around,
checking you out, there's nothing
wrong. He's not fucking staring.
Staring is looking at when you're
facing him, that's staring,
staring in your eyes, looking at
your titties, checking out your box.
I'm really being disrespectful.
That's staring.
But when you walk by looking over your
shoulder, I mean that's a fucking,
you know, it's a compliment. If he
continues to walk and turns around,
checks you out,
that's actually a compliment.
If he stops and he's got one hand in his
pocket and it appears that he's doing
half the mash potato dance like that,
that is offensive.
Without a doubt. Cheeses, where did I pull
that out of? Um, that would be offensive.
All right,
but he's around fucking staring at you.
That means that you're an attractive
woman and stop being so conti and take it
as a compliment.
All right,
I understand you walk by a
construction site and they go, Hey,
let me see your fucking Panties,
or whatever the hell they yell,
you know, whistling at you and all
that type of shit. I understand that.
Yeah, I totally get that. You know,
you treating you the same way I would
be treated as when I first walked into a
prison facility holding my blanket.
I totally understand that.
But you know,
if he continues walking in the other
direction, it turns around and checks out.
Your ass is not wrong with that. This not
wrong. That means he liked what he saw.
That means you'll look and good.
That's all that that means.
He's not fucking staring. All right. Um,
anyway, she goes on to say everyone
notices hot girls and guys too,
but it is rude to stare. Okay, I'll
go with you halfway on that. You know,
when you're looking at me, I shouldn't
be staring at you fucking chest. Oh,
your hips or you,
so you fucking who are
now your legs or whatever.
Um, but on the other side, you know,
if you're really hot and you
wear something really sexy,
I mean guys are only so like,
I dunno,
we're only so, we only have
so much control over that.
You fucking with nature,
they're all right. Yeah. So I kind of
blamed you in a way. So you're right now,
somewhere in the middle
of that I agreed with you.
Just take that take you take that
home with you. All right there taught.
All right. Number three,
uh, what is the nasty, uh,
what is with the nasty bathroom habits?
Um,
I don't know if some men just don't
notice or don't care that the outer rim of
their toilets are fucking disgusting.
Is that hard to wipe off?
What?
Missed the target?
A house with only single guys or a
men's bar bathroom is proof that some
me have horrendous.
Some men have horrendous bathroom habits.
Okay?
I'm absolutely 100% agree with you
other than the public bathrooms.
There's nothing more disgusting.
The female's bathroom is actually more
disgusting because you guys hover and you
can't see what the fuck you're aiming at.
All right.
I used to work in a restaurant and one
of my jobs was I had to clean the fucking
bathrooms and I don't know what
the fuck you guys are using all,
all that fucking toilet.
It's like a ticket.
It's like somebody want
to fucking championship in
there. You know the canyon,
a heroes like this all ticker tape and
all kinds of shit all over the floor.
It's fucking horrific. And you
guys piss all over the place. Uh,
you know. Exactly. You know
what I mean? US urinating.
At least we're looking at
what were urinating you guys,
it's like a fucking trick shot and
your shit faced in high heels. Okay.
And you're hovering. Need
I say more? All right.
But everything else that you
said is, is 100% true. Um,
I lived with guys when a,
obviously when I was fucking single
and all that type of shit and I never
understood that.
I never understood the fucking dirty
dishes piled up to the ceiling or,
or the food that you fucking ordered nine
months ago and it has like disgusting
mold on the side of it and
thinking all that shit was funny,
not mopping up the floor,
live in like a fucking animal slice of
pizza in the cushion or however they
always try to make gut single guys,
you know, you're like whenever they,
whenever they do in a Hollywood movie,
please say you used to do
it like back in the day,
like whenever a single guy would get up,
uh,
just to demonstrate that he needs
a woman in life. It was actually,
it was actually insulting to both sexes.
Uh,
it was basically saying that this guy
needs a woman in his kitchen to start
fucking making some food or something.
And it was insulting to the guy basically
saying that guys didn't know how to
take care of themselves.
You know?
And I know that there are a lot of guys
out there. I know it's just comedy,
whatever it, every fucking
movie would always start off.
The guy would have like chocolate milk,
a half a beer left and he poured on
some fruit loops and then mix the whole
thing together in a blender, suck it down,
and then do a spit take into the sink.
And then that was the deal to show that
he needs a woman in his fucking life.
But I, I totally understand
you. It's fucking gross.
And there's nothing worse than,
uh,
when I would be on the road when I was
younger and I would crash at Buddy's
places and you'd go to get
up, hey, can I, you know,
can I take a shower before I go?
They'd be like, yeah, right. And you,
and they'd go to give you this
fucking towel that, you know, they,
you know, check their oil on,
wash their dog with and fucking,
I don't know what drove the car over it.
It felt like a fucking
stiff piece of cardboard.
And then you go into their shower and it
was just, you couldn't touch anything.
Hair all over the place, fucking desk.
I never, never fucking understood that.
And I want to tell you, sweetheart,
I never lived like that.
I've never fucking lived like that.
And one of my biggest fucking
turnoffs ever are messy women.
There's nothing worse than a messy woman.
Cause as much as I just stuck up
for guys that were not all slobs,
it's like you're supposed to teach us
how not to be fucking animals, you know,
the same way I'm supposed to,
you know, teach you ditzy broads,
how to fucking change a light bulb,
you know,
cause you don't want to get your nails
to have your nails melted away. Right.
You was supposed to teach me how not to,
you know,
drink milk from nine months ago.
So I'm actually the first girl I dated,
she had a bedroom where she wouldn't
let me in her bedroom for like the first
three months we dated, you
know, so I just, you know,
we just sort of hook up
out in the living room,
had to make sure her roommate wasn't
home. And I was like, no, honestly I'm, I,
I don't, you know, three months,
I know you let me in. And I,
and I went in there and,
uh,
it was a combination storage bin.
You don't look like you ever
see those guys in New York City.
Like when they're selling shit illegally
on the sidewalk and all of a sudden the
cop comes and they just grab
it and they run like hell.
Just imagine if after they ran like hell,
they just threw it into
somebody's bedroom. That's
what the fuck it looked like.
And you had to like, it was like a
hoarder. She was like a fucking hoarder,
but her roommate didn't tolerate it.
So it was all on her God damn bedroom.
And I just immediately member looking at
this woman going like, yeah, this is, no,
I'm not going to live
with this girl someday.
And then I continue to bang
her for another six months
because I was young and I
was like,
but what if I never get another one
stupid. Um, anyways, let's plow
ahead a number four, trashing men.
The empire strikes back here.
I absolutely hate when men honked
their horn at women on the street.
I have lived, you must be pretty
hot if this. They're like,
most of this has to do with you trying
to get down the street without getting
leered at uh, getting
your butt pinched. Uh,
what's your next one going to be? I hate
when I become a secretary in the boss.
Thinks I'm going to blow
him. Um, number four,
I absolutely hate when men honk
their horn at women on the street.
I've lived on my,
uh,
I lived a lot of my life in
an urban setting and I have
walked busy side streets
a shit ton. A shit ton. Okay. What
good does it do to honk your horn?
Like a faggy coward?
You sound like one of those women
who like throw shit when you get mad.
Like you just,
I don't know what your energy,
I don't know what the fuck it is
about the way you write stuff. Um,
you don't write stuff like typically
female where it's like God,
it's like throw stupid. It's
like, like a fucking fag. Um,
you do throw shit. Um, anyways.
Is it satisfying to them?
Do they think they are
paying a compliment? Ooh,
that capital letters really
makes me feel capitol.
There is so special to have a dirt bag,
honk his fucking horn beep,
usually follow his gesture up with
the bird and allowed fuck off.
Oh, that's what you do back.
That usually makes us laugh.
I guess that what I guess that cat calls
whistles and smoochy sounds or
even I guess that, oh, cat calls,
whistles and smoochy
sounds are even worst.
What the fuck decade are you living in?
People still do that.
I just do not understand what the
benefit of these actions are. Um,
oh, ah, from my side of the street. Um,
all right. There's a lot of more on guys
out there. Okay. Who's getting hope?
One of them plays quarterback for the
Pittsburgh Steelers and has one more ring
than fucking Peyton manning.
All right. But I digress. Um,
but then there's another
thing, there's a, I don't know,
for guys to get laid,
you have to understand we have to get
over the fear of approaching women and
getting rejected. Like, I
know you guys have your level
of rejection, but like, um,
I dunno, it was far other than
humiliating yourself in front of a,
an audience just for every regular guy.
I would think the most
humiliating thing is,
is to walk up to a female and,
um,
have her shut you down just because that
whole bullshit of being a guy you're
just supposed to,
it's just like from day one,
you're supposed to know how to
do it. You're supposed to, uh,
know how to talk to women. You supposed
to, you know, know all about sex.
He supposed to be like worldly before
you've even seen the outskirts of your
fucking town. And uh, you know,
I don't know now with the whole
fucking emo generation, I'm sure it's,
it's okay to now it's just say,
hey, I don't know how to do this.
Can you give me some advice and
reach out for help? You know,
that Shit didn't exist
when I was growing up.
Like they actually have
reality shows about that.
Remember that guy who had that,
that the lamp shade from True
Romance on his fucking head.
Remember that reality show, that guy,
that guy was remember, okay, true romance.
When Christian Slater's,
he's going in there,
he's talking to Gary Oldman and he's,
he's pushing that lamp shade
at the his fucking head.
And uh,
this was a reality show on VH one teaching
these nerdy guys how to pick up women
and that guy that literally had that
lampshade on his fucking head and is dumb
as it was. If you have the balls
to wear something like that,
some woman is going to come up to you.
I'm not saying a good looking one,
but some woman is going to be
intrigued with the fact that you,
so don't give a fuck what people think,
that you would actually wear
that thing on your fucking head.
That she would somehow perceive it
as some level of confidence, I guess.
And that you're going to do
what the fuck you want in life,
which might translate to them
on, this is all speculation. Um,
you guys can all correct me next week,
but under all that I don't give a fuck.
I do what the fuck I wanted to.
I think females read that as in this guy
is going to take what he wants in life.
This guy's not a scared little bitch.
Therefore he's going to get what he
wants and if he gets what he wants,
he's going to be able to provide, which
is what I need. Because when he not,
when I get knocked up, I'm out of
the game. I'm on injured, reserved,
just sitting there, you know,
with a swollen fucking belly.
Can you go this Sunday?
No, no sir. I cannot,
I cannot write who the fuck's
gonna team. Do you realize
how fucking scare of that is?
I just realized that like, uh,
just as a, you know, being a guy,
like you never think about
that shit as far as, you know,
being able to pay your rent,
how fucking bad women have it that you,
you gotta go out there and try
it not to get a fucking loser.
Like really just sit there and be like,
we're going in there and trying to pick
out the person who's going to be able to
have your back for financially, I
guess. You know, women can, you know,
tough it out for the first two trimesters
that you know, yeah. Mean Jesus Christ.
Some of them right up until like now
I've given birth next week. Right.
Isn't that how it goes? Did
they just fucking, I don't know.
They're like hockey players just get
stitched right up on the fucking bench and
they're right back in there.
Right. I didn't mean it like that.
If you thought I meant like, you
know, oh, that was really disgusting.
I didn't mean it that way. I was
trying to compare it to hockey. Oof.
Really in a pit right now.
See if I can crawl out. Um,
yeah, that must be an a, uh,
like if I like walking into a bar,
I used to just,
I would walk in there and I would be
thinking like a guy like a, all right,
who's the hottest girl in here that
would actually still consider fucking me.
So it was never the best looking chicks.
That's, if I could go back in time.
That was the one thing that I
really don't like about myself is I,
whenever I saw the
hottest girls in the bar,
I immediately just said that Jesus Christ,
you know,
I'll leave that to the
fucking quarterbacks.
I was so conditioned in my head to where
I was in the fucking pecking order that
I didn't even, I didn't even
try it. So I went with the a,
I went after like sevens and eights.
You know,
it wasn't until I got into show business
and danced around like a fucking God
damn monkey on stage.
And even then the good looking ones who
came up to you are fucking crazy. Um,
Jesus Christ, almost 45 minutes in here,
she's quit babbling. Let's a solid,
they'll actually right there. That was
one of the rare times on this podcast.
I actually tried to look at it from a
female's perspective and actually gave you
props that has to be really
difficult and fucking scary. And um,
I think we've had plenty of stories of
guys talking about nightmare chicks who
come in and take them for
everything they're fucking worth.
How about all these women out there
with who you, you, you looked at a guy,
he looked like a fucking winner.
All right. And then he just,
he just ended up being this fucking
loser sitting on a god damn couch playing
video games, eating donuts. As you're
sitting there pregnant going like, really?
This is, this is this guy, this is
the dude. This is how you provide.
You know what I mean?
And if there's any females out there who
have any sort of inside information on
how to read guys, so you don't end up with
that dude, by all means, by all means,
write in and I will read the shit or at
least attempt to and stutter over the
goddamn words. All right, number five.
It's not over yet. All right, number five.
And I do not like when some guys cannot
control themselves in stare at tits and
ass. Did you already say this?
Doesn't this go under staring?
Is this an offshoot?
Is this like a spinoff?
When flow got her own show off of Alice.
Um,
instead of respecting the
women by speaking to her
face while making eye contact
and just using their peripheral vision
to get a good idea of her tits and ass.
You know what? Go Fuck yourself on this
one. Once you put your fucking tits away,
sweetheart. Okay? You don't want
people staring at your tits and ass.
Stop wearing those fucking hip hugging
jeans with your little booty crack coming
out. Stop wearing the shit
with the cleavage. All right?
Jesus Christ. Why don't you
just fucking walk in their top?
That's the thing I've always hated.
You know, hello, I'm up here. Well,
you know what? You're not as good
looking as you tit sweethearts,
so why don't you fucking
put him away and he's back.
The chauvinist to con is back. All
right, let's finish reading this. Um,
I have one friend in particular
who was terrible at this.
He even will walk 20 feet out of his way
to be at a good angle to see down his
shirt or indoor skirt. All right?
That guy is a pervert and a,
I got to admit I'm a pervert too.
I swear to God,
if you have a fucking skirt on that's
really short and you're about ready to
walk up some stairs, uh,
you know I'm going to do,
I'm going to do a little march in place.
Let you get a good fucking 10 stairs
in front of me. I don't give a fuck.
I'm not gonna look,
I am going to look where's some pants if
you don't want it to happen or take the
fucking elevator.
I'm looking,
I'm looking. You know what? You know what
the thing is too. You know what it is.
They want you to look. Oh yeah, they
want it. I'm fucking with you. Um,
what is going to anyways,
what does that gonna do for him?
I wonder if he has heard of the Internet.
There is way better shit on there.
There isn't sweetheart. There's nothing
better than seeing live titties.
Okay.
And you can never see enough of them.
So he's probably on the Internet
too and whenever he can,
he's just checking out titties.
Um, anyways, continuing. Um,
it is the 21st century.
You can see millions of bare tits
and ass in the comfort of your home.
I don't get to distraction.
That's a classic fucking argument that
if you put it in the, in the right, uh,
in a different situation,
you would argue the other side.
What if you were in a relationship with
some guy and he's looking at tits and
ass on the Internet? You'd be
standing there like, really?
You'd rather look at this shit that you
can't really even interact with than I
got live, titties and ass right here.
Why don't you come over here, see,
see what I did there. Um, anyways,
initially I thought that I could
compile a huge list trashing men,
but I've realized that as I'm
growing up, I've calmed down. Um,
some with my auntie men attitude. I have
many male friends who I care for dearly.
Uh, this is all nice. I am a
fan of many male comedians,
musicians and artists and
no way do I all men. Now,
why are you taking it all away? I
liked what you wrote. All right.
Here's someone who just
straight up fucking hates guys.
Let's read this real quick and if
you're bitching about it as a guy,
we fucking deserve it because I got
three years of podcasts, trash and women.
Here we go.
Uh,
number one guys who think one good
conversation means they're in.
I can't tell you how
many guys I've spoken to,
a grand total of ones who think that
just because they made me laugh during
light conversation that I will
automatically bed them. I'm sorry. No,
the world doesn't work like
a porno said to tell you.
All right. Wire to wire. That's
perfect. Can't fuck with that.
Number two guys who use acts
as a replacement for showering.
I hope I said that right. I'm seriously
stop it. Yeah, you smell good now.
But as soon as you walk away,
that second cloud of ball smell is going
to be waiting after you and no girl is
dying to get with that two for two.
Um,
due to can't flirt needn't try.
Uh, this is an actual conversation.
I had him. What are you doing?
Me Watching Jersey shore.
You him wondering if you'd suck Dick,
uh, wondering if you sucked Dick. Wow.
And then her response was, wow, just,
oh my God. All right. Number four,
learn to kiss fellas.
I know that when you practice on your
hand and think you've got skills and think
you've got skill,
but when you attempt to French kiss and
you end up basically eating my mouth,
that's not good. A sweetheart
that works both ways. Um,
female,
stop thinking just because you're female,
you're automatically sensual and you have
a nice touch and you know how to kiss
it is a fucking skill.
Some people are born with it,
but not everybody that kissing things
you don't want to fuck with you on.
All right. I believe I've told this story
before, but I'm going to tell it again.
All right, I'm in this, I'm
in a bar, right? I'm chatting
up this broad. Okay. Short.
Okay. For armed to something
fucked up with their arms.
I can't really tell like that chick
who makes the Italian food on the food
network. If you ever really start looking
at our arms, she's cute as a button,
but the son with their fucking arms,
she's just not a dwarf.
Um, anyways, so it was one of those deals.
But anyway, she was cute though, right? So
aside from our Jack in the box arms,
he was fucking cute. All right.
So I go lean in, right? We're going
to make out or whatever it was.
I was fucking in there. Right now when
you go to kiss somebody for those,
you don't, not a kiss, you pick
a lip. Either you're going high,
they're going low or vice versa. But
with this girl would do, when I went, hi,
she went high, or if I went picked
the lower lip, she went lower lip.
She would basically do upper lip,
the upper lip, lower lip to low, low.
That's what she kept trying to do.
And I got so frustrated. At one point,
I literally grabbed two handfuls of hair.
I was a little drunk on both
sides of her head and tried to,
tried to help her. Needless to say, after
she kissed me at my Dick was just like,
all right dude, you're on your own.
You're on your own on this one.
I don't know what you want to do, but
uh, I'm good. I'm going to bed now.
See in the morning, you know, I
think I told that other story,
that girl a doggy style,
you know,
when I move forward, you move
back. Sounds like a rap song. Uh,
is that a ludicrous sung?
Um,
when I move forward,
you move back and then we both separate
and then we come together again,
like fucking magnets. That's how you
do it. This girl would basically,
when I went forward, she went forward
and when I went back, she went back.
So we just sort of rocking
together. So I was, uh,
I was inside the building,
but uh,
there was no friction to once again,
my dick started being like, you know,
if this is how it's going to
be, I think, uh, you know,
I've got work in the morning.
So once again,
I had to fucking grab her
by the back of the neck,
like some fucking
insubordinate Hell Hound.
Now the hand on her hip and I had to hold
her still for a second as I went back
and then I brought her to me
and then see that. There you go.
There you go. All right. But I
understand this woman. You don't,
you don't kiss other women's. So there
you go. All right, number five guys.
Who by the way,
this is fucking killer lists here.
Number five guys who insist
on a girl who's hairless.
I don't think guys realize how much work
it takes for a woman to maintain silky
smooth skin all the time.
But it is a pain.
It wouldn't be so bad to keep
it up if the guys did the same.
But sadly a lot of furry little men
stick their noses up at the ideas.
Um, how can we be forced to do it
when you're Chinchilla asked? Doesn't.
Um, someone else made a list and was just
talking about the pedophile tendency of
that. And I could not agree
more. I think it's creepy.
100% hairless is fucking creepy.
All right.
I'd like a nice manicured lawn please.
That's all I'm asking for. Yeah.
That other thing.
Yeah.
That's just know the Calvin Klein ad is,
I call it,
remember those creepy ads he had with
the fucking people kids down in the
goddamn basement.
I'd still think that's truly one of the
few times in life when I actually get
offended. I really, it really
bothers me when, uh, they,
that ad campaign and when they
have like 14 year old models,
you know,
sitting on a swing dress like they're
22 and they look like they just got roof
EAD. That's really, um, I don't get it.
I really don't get that at all.
Uh,
I don't know if it's cause there's a lot
of gay guys in fashion and they don't
realize how street p
straight guys view that.
I don't know what, but whoever's your,
they're really missing the mark on that.
There's just,
it's fucking unbelievably creepy.
And it actually makes me
angry when I see it and I,
and I want to find the guy
who came up with it and uh,
and fucking punched him in
the face because it's, it's,
it's wrong fucking road.
It's just, you know, and believe me,
for me to be saying something's wrong,
it has to be fucking wrong
because I really don't give
a shit about most things.
All right.
But yeah,
enough with the fucking sexy 14 year old
who looks like she just got drugged and
can't stand up on her fucking Bambi legs.
I really, that's fucked. It's fucked up.
Okay, number six. And lastly,
a man who assume oral
is always on the table.
You are boring. A bad driver
didn't pay for my movie ticket,
made me listen to speed metal
while we were in traffic.
But you think that you deserve
to be blown. You have dirty hair.
I can only imagine what state your
Dick is in. Ah, that she writes.
What's that in your eye? Oh, it's
just a sparkle that, you know what?
That was phenomenal. Phenomenal
points. Phenomenally written. Um,
I'm liking this. The empire strikes
back, the women coming back at us.
We fucking deserve it. Uh, let's
see if I think I got it. Okay.
Let's get to overrated.
Underrated for the week.
This podcast is getting a little
old here. 56, uh, overrated.
I like this one here.
This guy writes and he says the use of
the word epic to describe everything.
And you know, it's funny, after I
was just like, all that's a classic,
I've got to put that on the podcast.
And then I was driving down the
street and there's some, um,
new show coming out in the
advertising billboard says,
um, something about the
epic of epicness, you know,
just classic people in the motion
picture or whatever. TV industry.
They liked that.
We keep finding the word epic on Youtube.
Let's use it in our advertising.
Um,
kind of like,
remember when they were trying to
figure out grunge and they just couldn't
figure it out. How to advertise
to the, I don't give a fuck man.
I'm gonna shoot myself in the face
generation, right. That I semi came up in.
I'm like half in grunge,
half in hair metal. Right.
So they actually came up with that
movie called feeling Minnesota.
I believe Keanu Reeves was in it. I think
it was a, uh, uh, Soundgarden lyric.
Um, I dunno what I'm
anyways, overrated. Uh,
working in a job you hate
and don't want to do anymore.
I feel like my job is slowly killing
me and I need to find something else,
but I'm dragging my feet thanks
to this economy. Yeah, Dude.
Well the great thing is
you've expressed it out loud.
You've written it and now I've said it
out loud. So you'll get out of that. Yeah.
You don't like it? Just get out, get out.
Just find something else. Anything
fucking it. Not Anything, but you know,
just every, you just take another
swing at the fucking tree.
Eventually a chop it down,
uh,
and get the fuck out of there because
it's your life. All right. Um,
what is this? Oh, this is
some more mentoring, trashing
a men with huge muscles.
I think we already do. I'm not just
talking about the steroid freaks.
I'm including those guys whose necks are
hidden by their overdeveloped shoulder
muscles and who's pecs could fill
a C Cup Bra. And for Christ's sake,
stop talking about your workout routines.
I don't care how many reps you did while
exercising your idiot toys or how much
you can bench press.
Just mentioned the fact that the bar
you use to bench press ways by itself.
40 pounds. Uh, wait a minute, I just lost
the sentence here. I'm so fucking dumb.
Just mentioned the fact that the bar you
used to bench press ways by itself, 45,
45 pounds and that you
added some heavy crap on,
on that heavy crap on that alone
impresses me and doesn't bore me to death.
And that was actually a great point and
I butchered it. Number two, a shaving.
I'm not talking about
men's shaving their faces.
Please do it because we women hate
stubble. Okay. Honestly, we love it.
Movies and on TV. But the beard burn
in real life is just not pleasant.
Uh, it's not shaving. It's
not women's shaving. Their
pubic hair that is overrated.
Naked pussies are, oh,
here's a woman. Naked.
Pussies are another product of our
culture's obsession with super thin models
and actresses in it is sick.
Think about it this way.
Keira Knightley naked.
I don't know who that is.
Naked looks more like a 10 year old boy
than a 25 year old woman in ladies who
actually have sizable
breasts and shave crutches.
Look like women on top of
little girls on the bottom. Yes.
See that's just fucking gross.
This is the woman.
This trend makes me think that all men
are secretly pedophiles and like to
imagine raping children.
All right? You know. Okay.
I think pedophiles work.
You really took it the whole nine yards.
So she said you're pretty predictable.
Rent defending men goes here.
Now Sweetheart,
I'm not fucking defending your,
I'm so I understand your side on that one.
Um,
I can already hear you accusing
me of being a fat, bitter broad.
This is how bad I am. They're
anticipating these saying this shit.
This is why I'm doing this segment because
I've completely lost credibility with
the female audience here.
Uh, she says I'm not.
I'm 26 and while my bathroom scale,
if I had one,
wouldn't would be over one 30.
Um,
I've been in a relationship for seven
years and dated other people before that.
So it's not like a few fluke that a
guy is interested in me. Ah, yeah.
You don't need to justify yourself. You
made great points. All right. Underrated.
Oh,
these are from me here.
I'm actually gonna contribute here so
you guys don't have to work all the
fucking time. He can kick back and your
cubicles and relax. Underrated drinking.
This is from, this is from me. This
is from my heart to you people. Uh,
drinking a beer on your porch or
balcony at the end of the day.
I did it the other day.
I got a little fucking balcony,
one of those one bedroom apartment
balconies and I just sat out there.
It's impossible.
I don't give a fuck what is going on
in your life as a man to sit on a porch
with a little breeze going at dusk,
right?
Drinking a beer with the,
it's impossible to not feel successful.
You feel like he just fucking completed
the transcontinental railroad near the
Gout, drove in the golden spike. Um,
all right. Um, here's
my next one. Underrated.
Actually using your car as
a place to park your car.
Um, I just feel it's a good sign that
you're a well adjusted human being if you
actually put your car in the garage
and if you have a bunch of clutter in
garbage in your fucking,
uh,
if you use your garage as storage also,
you know,
and then I think that's, you
know, that's like the Bronx tale.
That's just the tip of the iceberg and
you really just need to get out of that
fucking relationship. Um, all right. Uh,
we're well over an hour.
Should I keep going?
Do you guys have something better to do?
I don't think you'd do.
I'm going to keep going here.
Underrated professional courtesy.
I work for a cell cellular
provider in a call center.
And the sheer amount of ignorant assholes
that call me and curse at me for no
reason is astounding.
Now,
what does that go back
to podcast listeners?
This guy's getting cursed at because
people don't listen to my podcast and they
don't realize that you don't curse
it. That guy, after he says what he's,
what he's supposed to say, you
just tell him, that's unacceptable.
I need to talk to somebody above you.
That's what you do.
This guy's getting cursed out because
people just lacked the ability or they
don't have, they don't have the knowledge
to just say it's unacceptable. Um,
all right. Number one,
underrated a sobriety. Um,
I don't have time to read all these
fucking things. Sobriety, I started,
I got to finish it. See,
even the word makes,
uh, is this underrated sobriety. See,
even the word makes being not fucked up.
Sound boring. Uh, to these people,
to people these days lack the intelligence
and imagination to have fun without
being stoned or drunk off their asses.
I'd never seen the appeal in having random
words come out of my mouth rubbing up
against a stranger then falling down and
passing out amongst people. I wouldn't,
I wouldn't trust to walk my dog.
If your life sucks so much that you
would rather be silly sitting at a dirty,
dim lit bar or smoking pot with strange
people living in their parents' basement
than do something to change it.
Don't become numb to your life. Rage,
rage against the routine, and if your
life isn't that bad, why risk your health,
money and sanity on recreational poisons,
you know at that might be one of the
greatest arguments I've ever had for being
sober. It has an override. Righted my
sitting on the porch drinking a beer,
which I'm going to do right up to this
fucking podcast on number two girl geeks.
Why are men so obsessed with the size
to party girls at fashion and fashion?
Niesters can we just stop
here for a second? Amen.
Aren't you?
Don't you know why?
I know what a fashion Nissa
is because of my girlfriend.
She loves all of those blogs.
She goes on all of those things and she
constantly bitches about those size to
fucking women. And she always
says that guys are into them.
You guys are the one who read vogue.
You're the ones who read cosmo.
You're the one, they don't have those
women in sports illustrated. They don't.
And when they do the swimsuit
issue, they're not sized
to, okay, go fuck yourself.
They're not granted. I don't know what
a fucking size two is, but size two,
that's that little, uh, those lollipop
looking girls, the big fucking heads,
you know,
they look like raggedy Ann dolls,
but you grabbed it by the
neck like you were gonna.
You just run out this stuffing through
the doll feet. That's what they look like.
Um, so yeah, blame the people in the
fashion industry. I mean, the, the,
the hacky theory is that there's
a bunch of gay guys in, uh,
in fashion and they're more
attractive to two guys.
I don't know.
I've just always heard that.
So they're trying to make them
have no curves. I don't know what,
but yeah, no, I'm not into that.
I'm not into that looking like
you can barely fucking stand up.
I'm not into that. Um, I'll tell
you what I like. Go, go, go, go,
look up. Cool Hand Luke and look at the
CIC wash in the fucking car. All right,
go look up that on youtube. We'll
actually have the clip on the MM podcasts.
Look that up.
Um,
if you want to be in a relationship
where you can relax and not be nagged to
dress well and go do something,
you want a girl who is more
interested in surfing attended.
I don't know where the
fuck to go with this.
I don't even know where to pick
that up. All right, I'm done.
I'm done with the podcast. I'm well
over an hour. Um, and that's it.
That's the podcast for this
week. Lot of reading, by the way,
that's why it was an hour and five
minutes because I'm not the best reader if
you, as you've noticed. So that's a
podcast for this week. Um, this week,
football season starts.
Let the shit talk and begin a patriots.
Have the Bengals next week.
My prediction is the patriots
come out with a big victory. Um,
I just think, uh, I dunno. It's been
real quiet up in New England. I like it.
Rex Ryan in the jets.
I talking all this fucking
shit and I think it's great.
Everybody's going to be looking at them.
I feel like the Patriots are like the,
what the cults get every year when
nobody really focuses on them.
And everybody was looking
at bill Belichick and who
the fuck he was filming and
all the crap that was going on there.
Tom Brady's fucking knee or are
they going to be undefeated?
It's nice that Rex Ryan,
that insecure fat fuck is running his God
damn mouth with his chronic need to be
liked. Um, I, I cannot wait for
week two and I just want us to fucking
killed the jets to the point that Rex
Ryan just like literally snaps that
lap band in his fucking stomach.
Just eaten Lasagna.
If four in the fucking morning crying.
I knew I wasn't good enough.
That's the podcast for this week.
God bless all of you. Have a great
week. Uh, I'll talk to you next Monday.
I'll let you know how to pilot chute when.
Yeah.
Okay.
[inaudible] just stay with
me.
[inaudible] this will be the last thing.
Yeah.