Hey, what's going on? It's Bill Burr.
It's time for the Monday
morning podcast for Monday,
July 3rd,
2017 a day before July 4th
when you guys do own it. Jesus Christ.
When are you guys doing it? Yup.
Partying tonight. You got to go tonight,
right? You got to go tonight and tomorrow.
You like a fat fuck. But tonight
is tonight to night to night.
Tonight's tonight. If you want to
go out and get fucking hammered,
you know tomorrow's for the kids.
You know today you scare your children
tomorrow you wake up with them.
That's how it works.
When July 4th is on a Tuesday,
you know your wife will give you dirty
looks, but you know by the weekend,
as long as you're mulching up the
fucking Yad, she'll be happy. So what do,
what do you want from me?
I was celebrating the birth of the nation.
They're not the movie.
You're fucking racist. Dot.
Well, you made me curse. You know, you
get involved in those stupid things. Um,
anyways. Uh Oh man. Oh Billy.
No Fund was Billy bad boy this week.
I completely just fucking,
I just, I don't know what happened. I
went off the rails, I went off the rails.
I was flying out. I was doing the
Capitol Theater in Port Chester,
which is one of most amazing venues.
I don't know what it is about it.
It's just one of those places. It's got
the fucking magic in it, you know, and uh,
it's been around forever and according
to the people that ran it, um,
yeah,
he was saying that Janis Joplin played
there and in a bar nearby or something,
she wrote that song.
Mercedes Benz tried it out for the first
time at that venue than went out to la,
recorded it, and then overdosed.
That was it. And I was like,
that's great. Well, you know what,
I'm not going to be trying
any new material this weekend.
Bill Bird tried out a new Dick joke,
uh, recorded it onto his iPhone.
Um, went back into the city, had two
slices of pizza in three in the morning,
followed by four shots of fucking whiskey,
and then went to bed and died on
a futon. Yes, he was alone. Um,
oh my God, I just don't happen.
I was flying out there. Um,
I think I was stressed. I don't know
what it was. And then the guy, you know,
asked me if I wanted to drink,
you know, I wasn't on a plane,
it was just this die came up to me. He
says, excuse me, can I buy you a drink?
I was like, well, certainly you can
know that was on a plane in the steward.
The male stewardess came up to
me. He said, do you want it?
You want anything to drink? Right.
And the devil in me went, oh.
And I went, um, quivering
voice maybe later.
Yeah.
So, you know, I've been eating great edge
salads and all that shit and I'd done,
you know, I'll just have
one, I'll just have one.
He comes over with some Jack on the
rocks, you know. Nice fucking poor, right.
Gave me the old mile high
pulse, you know what I mean? If
he fucking give me like gave me like
three fingers and fucking booze. So,
um,
that's with a little bit of pepper and
some cheese and I fucking drank the thing
and I was like, all right,
that's it. I gotta I gotta uh,
I gotta get waters after this
cause that's the big thing.
After I have the first one, I just
switched the waters and then, then I,
I get my bearings again
of like, oh yeah, okay,
cool. Okay, cool. We had a buzz. Now
we're coming back. We'll come back.
This is a good thing.
But if I go to that second
drink for get it and um,
he just fucking, what
did he say? Do you want?
And I think he just brought me the next
one and then I was just like, well,
I'm not going to be rude. And then
I drank that one and then, uh,
then we landed and that just set me off
on the wrong, the wrong fucking way,
the wrong fucking road.
Then I got into the city and then
I got two slices of fucking pizza.
Not even from a place that I liked place
that I wanted closed because they have
great pizza and they already
made their money. So like,
well we don't need to be open all
night. Go Fuck Yourself. See Ya.
So then I walked down the street
to these other guys, you know,
the one that all the drunks
is stumbling into and uh,
I got not one,
but two slices of pizza went back fucking
shoved them down my throat the whole
time. Go, you know, this is way better
than anything that I'd get in La.
But this is not a good example of how the
east coast became legendary with their
pizza making. No disrespect
to Chicago, by the way,
okay?
I'm not saying you guys don't make you
make a different type of Lasagna pizza
out there and most New Yorkers,
people from Boston, Philly,
we go out there and we don't know where
to go and we just get some average slop
and we'll like this fucking pizza
stinks. Right? The same way you guys,
I know so many fucking people should
categorize. Do I want to know gay?
You'll get pizza and good. Did you
even look to see where to go? You Dope.
New York has a great reputation for,
for making great pizza.
That's why there's so many shitty once.
You know what I mean?
Because everybody's living off
of that fucking reputation.
There's like a half dozen,
probably,
maybe eight in the fucking all
the boroughs. How many boroughs?
I was at Queens, Bronx, Brooklyn, Staten
Island, man of five fucking boroughs.
There's probably probably eight.
Okay.
Brooklyn's got a couple.
New York has a couple and everybody
else has like fucking one may be too.
I don't know enough about it, but I'm
just telling you there's only a few.
However, in New York City you can buy
pizza every fucking 10 feet down the road.
Same way in Chicago.
Some fucking cunt is out there waiting
for someone like me to walk down the
street with my fucking Chicago,
the windy city windbreaker that
I just bought at the airport,
a genuine,
authentic fucking Chicago deep dish pizza.
Then they're going to bring me in there,
so can we end the fucking pizza debate?
Everybody, you know, has
their own way to do it.
Up in Boston, they had the little bar
style pizzas, which are fucking amazing.
And every New York content
goes, oh, I went up day, folk
with tastes like fucking,
we'll ghoulies over the again,
folk in feet days, you know,
those fucking morons when you travel.
Okay.
You got to fucking hang with local people
and they'll tell you where to go to
fucking walk into a place
and think that everything,
there's sucks and people there just
accept it is probably one of the dumbest
ways to travel. However,
that's how most people do it.
Okay.
Or you go there and you try to get what
you can get down the street from where
you live and when, then when you
can't, you say, this place sucks.
Yeah.
And was just, I can't, you know,
fuck it. I was in The Bahamas that
[inaudible]. Um, anyways,
I don't know why I'm making
everybody Italian, but I'm a joiner.
I am a joint it. So, uh,
so I hit the Shitty fucking pizza and I
was taught to finish my food as a kid.
So I'm fucking even just non
my way through the crust.
I mean I could have whittled something
like fuck piece of wood with this crust.
Tough like fucking shoe
leather over there. Um,
that's was the first night. And then
I did well during the day, you know,
I did really well.
But then just at night,
the next night I ended up staying up.
We went to a fucking oh,
right down the street from the
port Chester capital theater.
It was this great Italian
restaurant and uh,
it was all part of partly
owned by Mario Batali.
Um, who's the best. All this fucking
restaurants are awesome, right?
So I go down there and I know I
should order the fish, but I can't,
can't go to Italian out here. So I
ordered, I ordered some pasta. Right?
I get the fucking go fuck yourself.
Bolin h right. So I get that.
And then we say we don't want dessert.
They still brought some stuff over cause
they're Italian. I mean, just, you know,
if you say, I don't want
any of this, still going to
bring you over a half order.
That's how it fucking works.
So they brought over the oldies
canolas and all of this shit
and then
didn't drink too much that
night, but definitely, you know,
not trigger that much to
me. It was like, you know,
five or six over a fucking nine hour
peer stayed out till like four in the
fucking morning.
Smoked a cigar.
Fucking stupid. I had all this shit
to do the next day. Right. If fucking
get out of the fucking Uber.
Right.
I get out of the Ober and um,
I know I told you guys I Uber,
I had somebody call
it for me
cause I couldn't get a cab
and uh,
I get out of the,
and the second I get out of it I walk
over to the door and go, well wait,
where's my phone?
Where's my phone?
And I left it in the fucking Uber
and then I didn't have, I had no,
no way to call.
And I was like,
you gotta be fucking kidding me
cause I had my bag of shit with me.
So I grabbed my bag and I got this thing.
Once I grabbed something,
I never look for anything
else. And also, you know,
I had like fucking four or five drinks,
so I left my fucking phone there.
So I was just like, all right, extend
a mental check. Everything's backed up,
everything's on the computer. Who gives
a fuck? I'll just buy a phone tomorrow.
Fucking moron. Right? So
I get up the next day,
I go over to the fucking Verizon store
and they go, okay, what's your apple id?
I'm like, I dunno, you got
my phone number, here's my
license. And they're like, oh,
that's not good enough. You
need your Apple Id. I go,
well, I don't have it. He goes,
can you guess a Zodiac and fucking
standing all day? I don't know what it is.
And he basically tells
me that he can't get,
he can't get into my account
without my apple id. I go,
you're telling me if the FBI came in
here right now, that's what you'd say.
And he was like, absolutely. And I was
like, dude, I don't know what it is.
Are you telling, she's telling
me I can never get a phone again.
This feels like a Tom cruise movie.
Did you just shut off the microchip in me?
Can I you can I get a phone please?
I business to do. The guy says, no,
I haven't been meditating.
My temper starts going up
and up and up and up and up.
I didn't curse at him. I
started, you know, okay.
He goes,
well,
you're gonna have to go to our main store
and that's going to take like fucking
two to three hours. So it's like,
you've gotta be fucking kidding me.
So I walk out into the streets
in New York and I said,
I fucking hate technology.
But I said,
I really quietly in technology
really quietly, but fuck.
I said at the top of my
lungs, fucking, I just went,
I fucking hate technology.
This lady fucking whipped
her head around. I was like,
oh my God. I'm like, I like,
I'm literally the Guy Walking
in the street in New York,
making people nervous right now.
So I walk up to try to find
where this fucking places,
I don't know what you said. It's on like
fucking 50 [inaudible] and sixth avenue.
I'm looking for the thing and I'm like,
wait,
is it on sixth avenue
and 57th I have no idea.
This took me back to the nineties when
I was in New York when you didn't have a
map and you just fucking walked
around head on a swivel, right.
Finally find the place.
And I walked in there and I got
an absolute angel at the store,
old school customer service,
completely fucking hooked me up and she
was like in her mid twenties it halfway
through I just finally was just saying
like, you know, I forgot what I said.
I said something you basically see effect
that you know you don't get customer
service like this anymore.
Your parents raised you right?
She said, thank you. I go,
did you come from a big family? And she
was like, I was like said something like,
um, like one of seven. I was like,
I know it, I know it, I know it.
I don't know what it is. Kids would come
from like fucking with a bunch of kids,
families with a bunch of kids there.
They, they, I dunno, they learned that.
I don't know what to do. I know what
you learned, but you're, you're, uh,
I dunno. Everything is about you when
you keeping all the fucking toys.
So she totally hooked me up. And then, uh,
then I was able to call my
buddy who called the Uber,
who called the Uber Guy and then
the Uber Guy still had my phone.
He brought it back to me the next night.
You know,
I gave him a nice tip for doing
that and I got two phones.
I guess I can bring the other phone back,
but I just don't want to go back into a
story. I'm not rolling the dice again.
Then I'm going to get a good customer
service person. I know I'm not. Um,
so I'll just fucking eat.
It was my own fucking fault.
If I didn't go out till fucking four
in the morning, like an asshole,
none of that shit would have happened.
I apologize to the lady that I made her
fucking probably fucked up her neck when
I screamed fucking when I was
out in the street and a buddy,
you know,
I don't apologize to the guy at the bank,
I owe taxes, right? I owe
taxes up in fucking Canada.
Okay?
So they may count goes,
you have to go to the bank,
I'm going to send you an email with
all the fucking account information.
They can wire it up. They have bing,
Bang, boom, done. So I say fine.
So I go up to, I download
the thing, I bring my laptop,
I fucking get this David
Blaine looking dude, you know,
at the bank to help me out. Right? So he
walked into his cubicle area. We sit down,
I have all the information on the
computer screen. He's such go, I read,
read me the Vin number. I know it's
not that, but you know what I mean?
And I'm like, what? What? He's like
that number there. Read that to me.
So I read it to me. He goes, all right,
read me. The next time I go watch them.
He goes was me that number and then I
just find looking at my, Whoa, I go,
what do I work here? He's
like, excuse me? I go,
I go, I feel like I work here
right now. I'm like, I look, just,
just turn it around here, here's all
the information, type it in and he goes,
what's going to go quicker or something
like then they just kind of got quiet,
right?
I'm just fucking sitting there
and then after a couple minutes he
just kind of goes like, you know,
I don't understand like why you got
upset there? I go out. I'm not upset.
I'm just calling you out on the fact he
started treating me like your secretary.
I don't work here. He goes,
I'm not treating you like
get sick. Tick. Yeah, you,
why are you going to be like reading
off numbers and stuff? He goes,
I'm just doing that cause it'll be
faster. And I go, well I disagree.
Well what the fuck am I you you,
you want to stay and you work at the bank.
You're at the bank,
you work at the bank,
you get paid to work at the fucking bank.
I'm the customer.
This is what I need you to do.
Do the fucking transaction.
Jesus fucking Christ. Fucking God the,
I'm going to say it these kids today,
everything about them is, it's
interactive. Hey man, like, hey, you know,
fucking reach out through the fucking
innerweb man. Fuck off and do your job.
But I'd say to that, I just said, I
disagree. That's the best I could do,
but I just couldn't.
He was like the cues.
What kills me is he's walking around
and saying that I'm a Dick, which I am.
I admit to that,
but I'm fucking right.
I got to sit there and read off
fucking numbers to you. He goes,
can you read the CT? We say, please,
you such talking to me like I'm like,
and I was like, I'm done. I just get
hired as your assistant. You fucking cunt.
Okay.
I don't even know what he was
talking about. All of those numbers.
I'm not a fucking banker. Okay. Every
time he told me to read off a number,
he had explained what the number is
like. How was that, how has that quicker?
Oh Jesus.
So I meditated for the first
time in about six weeks.
Um, I'm just trying. Yeah, I
know. I know. I know. I just,
uh, I'm back, we're back in the writers'
room. I got all of that shit to do.
I'm building my new fucking act right.
My,
my daughter is finally sleeping
through the night. You know,
she still wakes up once or twice,
but it's just something,
just a quick little one. Um, maybe needs
a diaper change or something like that.
And I'm just feeling like it's just,
it's building up again, you know?
So for me now to like stop
drinking, you know, to add that,
that extra stress of like,
you know,
okay,
to not have the fucking thing to take
the edge off at the end of the God damn
day like that, it just starts building
up. So up to the guy at the bank,
maybe I could have
explained it a little nicer.
Maybe I couldn't just flipped out
here. But you know, know this, uh,
that's what I wanted to say in
the bank, but I didn't, okay.
I just fucking kept my cool. But
like you work at the bank, I don't,
I need you to do this transaction. I
have money in your bank. Back in the day,
you guys used to give like 10%
8% on fucking money in the bank.
You now give like 0.0001%.
Okay?
So now you don't give me any money on it.
You've alone 10 times out on what I
fucking have there. You guys invent money.
You're literally counterfeiters.
And now I have to go in there.
You guys nuke the fucking economy every
eight fucking years building housing
bubbles at whatever and you
don't go to jail for it.
And you leave Americans upside down in
their houses. You don't give a fuck.
And then on top of that, I got to go in
and read the fucking numbers off to you.
Fuck off.
I know this is childish for me to be
sitting here alone, losing my mind. But I,
I cannot lie to you and not tell you how
fucking good this feels to get this out
of me.
You know,
part of my meditation today is I'm
actually doing this series on patients
swear to God.
And the guy said,
um, Oh God, what the fuck did he say?
It almost made me mad when I was like,
I wanted to debate with the guy,
but I can't cause it's just a recording.
He basically said that when
you lose your patients,
it's because you have expectations
of other people. Okay.
And then when you react to that,
it's like your fault for reacting to it,
for having your,
you're wrong to have these
expectations of people.
MMM.
And I'm thinking in my head like,
like does that doesn't make
it, I like, I'm at this point,
I'm wrong that I expect people to put in
an effort at the job the way that I do
and the way that I did.
And I'm not patting myself on the back,
but when I fucking, I
always, any job I had,
I fucking killed it unless I just
literally didn't have the talent.
Like construction. I just, I
mean I could bring you the shit.
I just didn't have that gift.
Well I tried to sell health insurance.
I just wasn't good at it.
And you know what I did?
I had the decency with both of those
jobs to quit within a week and a half.
I didn't fucking sit there and torture
people and just suck at my job as they
came walking in or worse,
try to make them do part of my job.
So I'm listening to this guy and he's
Casey's talking in a very soothing voice
like this, some sort of British
accent. When we walk in there,
we have ted space. Hello
again. Welcome to headspace.
When we have expectations of other people,
gives us a tendency to, he tries to
like let loose, these are patient.
I get it. Don't get all
fucking jolly cause you know
that. You know what he does?
He's doing that because he knows is an
angry cunt like me laying on the ground
going like, okay, so now you're,
you're defending this guy at the bank.
You weren't even fucking there.
You know?
So now basically what you're saying is,
in order for me to have patients,
I have to basically treat people
the way I treat my daughter,
which is I understand that she's a
baby and doesn't know anything yet,
you know,
so I have to have
100% patients with her,
which I do,
but that's because she's a baby.
So now I'm supposed to walk in and sit
across from a 27 year old guy and his,
you're gonna like the way you look.
I guarantee it fucking suit.
And as he tells me to do what, uh, how,
how could I have done that better?
I guess what I should've said is,
sir, I don't mean any disrespect,
but I'm not going to read
those numbers to you.
I feel that you work at the bank and
I am the customer and I feel that that
crosses a boundary that I'm,
I'm not comfortable with.
Well, I guess I could
have said that. Right.
And like when he exhales, I probably
shouldn't, like when he exhaled, like I,
it was like someone's fucking twisted the
knife in my back. I wanted to fucking,
she's like, did you just fucking
exhale? Yeah. Once again,
I guess I had expectations that this guy,
you know,
I had the ability to fucking look at a
paper with all the answers to the test on
it while typing at the same
time. I mean, I can do that.
I could do that for half a page and I
only make a couple of mistakes and I
taught myself how to do it.
What the fuck,
how much more easier does life have
to be? And then not, well, you know,
I was also thinking when I left,
it was like, you know something,
my wife would have just read
the numbers off to them.
She would have read the numbers off to
them and then afterwards I would have
said like, why did you just do that? You
did your job. She goes, well, you know,
you're right. You're right. You know,
I probably shouldn't have done that.
But you know, it got it
done quick. You know,
I just didn't wanna have the argument
blow bunch continues on, you know,
and she's a way,
way happier person on paper.
I think on paper,
I know,
did you know something to
think about women is the, the,
the big red flag is the level of,
of shopping that they do and the amount
of shit that they buy. Like that's,
I dunno, yeah. Does this,
there's a fucking unhappiness there.
There's something psychotic
going on with just the amount,
the sheer amount of clothes and shit
that they buy and just stuff that they
fucking by.
Um,
I don't see tranquility in it.
I just feel like that's like eating
fucking, you know, see's candies. Just,
they just love having that
ups drivers showing up in, Oh,
it's a little package for me.
You know,
I actually judge how well
my relationship's going by
how often the fucking ups
driver comes through the door.
If he's coming a lot,
then I need to take her out to
dinner or something. If, you know,
if he's coming every once in awhile,
they're not just her doing the woman
thing of basically a, you know,
fucking kicking our retirement right in
the seats. All right. I didn't need to go.
I'm okay. Whatever. I
apologize to everybody.
I apologize that first guy to
fucking Verizon store. I, uh,
I apologize for the way I conveyed
what I was trying to say to the,
to the David Blaine looking
dude at the bank. You know,
I don't know. Maybe it's a new world.
Maybe I'm just a fucking old guy.
Maybe that's why I don't fucking
know. I don't, I don't know.
I still think I'm right,
but I'm going to learn in the future and
our tab expectations of people and just
sit there is that sense of my life.
Slip away waiting for somebody to do their
fucking job that they get paid to do.
Um, anyways, anybody wants some moto
GP fucking motorcycle race yesterday.
Another great one. Back to back. Fucking
great races. Congratulations to them.
Ah,
Marcus. Oh my God. Did you hear his
fucking interview afterwards? Oh,
it was fucking hilarious. First of all,
it's all these guys can speak English,
but he searches for the English
words while go in the air.
He did two fucking one's so
fucking long. They go, mark,
congratulations. Great victory,
blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
I didn't fill out dead today is I uh,
it was that,
uh,
[inaudible] minded me. Taylor Negron.
Greg rested piece is great joke when he's,
you don't want carpets.
You want an og. Remember
the area rug joke?
Um, anyways, bought a fucking race and
a, I got to look at the standings here.
I think that that put mark mark has,
she sees on top.
He's on top of the leader board.
I'm the lead of Ford Board.
Sorry. Um, Mark Marquez.
Fucking, oh, come on.
You don't have expectations.
Don't have expectations of the Internet
that it's actually going to work.
Why would it work? Why would it
work when you would need it to work?
Just laugh.
Make a note of it.
Make a note of a difficult
time in your life.
Put it on the clothes line and send
it on down and stay. Just remember,
you're not reacting. You're
observing. You're just
take you sitting on a park bench watching
traffic go by except the trafficker or
your thoughts.
Oh look,
the requested URL cannot be retrieved.
I'm going to have no reaction to this.
I'm just going to sit here and let
my podcast slowly sink into the abyss
if something completely not even
remotely funny. Alright, here we go.
Where the fuck are we by the way?
You know
this fucking website stinks.
Can you think of these guys are fucking
putting their lives on the line.
It'd be a little easier to navigate.
Weighted wait,
does that mean having fucking ex
expectations again? All right.
Mark Marquez is in the league.
Hundred 29 points.
Was this what the points that
they got from yesterday? Oh,
this looks like from what
they got yesterday. Um,
congratulations to that kid. Maverick.
Venal Bill Nez. Is that the guy though?
I thought he was German.
I don't think I have the wrong guy.
This might be the wrong list.
It says GP world standing.
There was some guy that
came in second place.
It was the first time he's ever been on
a podium this year. Hold on a second.
This is so fucking irritating.
Where is it?
Oh, they haven't done that one yet. I
bought this one every day is Deutschland.
There we go.
See I had the wrong one.
I add the word now where the fuck is,
he thought there was some German guy
that came in second yesterday says Danny
Pedrosa from Spain came in.
So wherever the fuck the guy was that
came in second congratulations and
actually learned something when I
was watching the race as far as,
mmm.
Just how amazing that these guys come
flying down the straightaway there in the
Tuck and I love when they all,
they fucking pop up and they stick
that God damn leg out. Right.
I always feel like they're going
to fall off the bike at that point.
And then it's all when you
break how you take the turn.
And this kid who was in
second place came into the,
I think it was turn one and
he just came in too hot,
which caused him to go wide and Mark
Marquez did it perfectly and he just went
right underneath them.
And uh,
but I guess you guys said something to
the effect that he heated up his tires
when you break that heart or something
and then you don't get as good a grip.
And that was basically,
what did they say something he,
I'm not create space or something
but broke away from her.
He broke them or something.
I don't know.
I'm still learning the terminology
but they're fucking amazing.
You guys got to get into this moto GP
consisting is literally it's 28 fucking
laps and you watching people
on motorcycles driving
200 miles an hour or 320
kilometers, which I've learned every 50
miles an hour is about 80 kilometers.
So always I always have to do the fucking
math but it's easy because they're
basically doing what like like I dunno
like a 240 to 320 kilometers except when
they're in the turns obviously. So they
basically go on about 150 miles an hour,
140 all the way up to like 200 the
Italian wants to crazy one with this,
the straightaway where they actually
get up over 200 miles an hour.
I mean I just,
and their ability to fall,
how they fall,
even fall off the bikes gracefully
unless the high side him and then the
technology of the soup with is like
an airbag in the suit that immediately
detects that you fallen off your bike
and inflates it, protects you vitals.
And then the leather is just such
high quality or whatever they got.
They just slide down the
track and they get up.
Yeah.
Do they stay fucking wipe out at 200
miles an hour and they get up like they
fell off a tire swing at a cookout.
That's fucking unreal.
So congratulations to Mark Marquez.
Um,
I'm a big Ducati fan, so I like,
uh, I root for the fucking, uh,
I wrote for the Italians,
you know, I liked that guy.
A what's in it, you know, it was
great. Is that guy from Britain though?
Who is actually going to Honda?
That cal crutch low.
He fucking rides like a maniac.
I also like Johan Zarko.
He's from France. He
rides a Yamaha, but uh,
divisio so I like, I just love Ducati's.
I think they're a fucking work of art.
But if you ever wondered
how much those bikes,
because I think they were like the
worth like two, $2 million, those bikes,
I'm like that million,
2 million bucks. Um,
I love when they're going
down the straightaway and
they fucking given so much
throttle that the front
tire comes up a little bit.
You gotta understand at that point you're
going 200 miles an hour and you don't
have the urban that split second.
You don't have the ability to steer when
your tire was off to be on the fucking
balls that those guys have. I stopped
riding a bike because I couldn't ride,
you know, but actually know something.
Probably riding the streets of La
in your fucking dad jeans with
your leather jacket on. That's way.
And that is way more dangerous.
I don't have a fucking airbag
Fiverr get a motorcycle again.
I want to buy one of those
moto GP fucking suits.
But the thing about it is,
is even if you fall off,
even if the fucking thing like
inflates and all that shit,
the differences is that the track,
you don't have to worry about somebody
coming in from the left or the right
driving a bus or an SUV and running
you over and crushing you. Um,
that's basically it because I have to say,
I would love in a perfect world,
in a perfect world, I would love,
I would love to have a Ducati.
I've never written one, but everybody
I know that ever rode, wants to do.
You never ride anything else. I need
saline. Like, um, uh, like I said,
I'm a big fan of fucking machines and uh,
there's this one on,
there's a out here in la on last Sienna
got this one and write that right up the
street from this vegetarian place when
I'm not being a fucking Moron and eating
shitty pizza and drinking booze and
smoking cigars like an asshole from eating
right when every time I go there,
I always got a pop in there
and then the guys away. Can I help
you? I just want to be like, Nah,
I'm just as scared married guy with too
much to lose. Just drew. I'm, you know,
I'm going to say that
next time I come in there,
gone in this so many times. The guy
probably knows me. Um, all right,
let me read some of these.
Uh,
let me read some of these
advertising advertisements here. Oh,
gimme the loot crate everybody be the
envy of your friends and get a 100%
exclusive
crates@lootcrate.com slash burr and
enter my code burb Gurr to save $3 off on
any new subscription.
July's loot crate theme is
animation likeF is for family.
Um, on a quest for epic gear, housewares
and collectives. Loot crate has it.
Lou Crate offers an epic range of pop
culture items for less than $20 a month.
If you're more of a fanatical fashionista
than try out Lou where I have no idea
what any of this shit is.
Luke to me is money in a,
Craig is a giant fucking box that
is like lifted up with machinery.
Okay.
I don't know. Offer expires July 19th
at 9:00 PM Pacific in July's loot crate.
You'll find items from teenage
mutant Ninja Turtles. Bob's burgers.
Love that show. Futurama loved
that show. And Rick and Morty,
which I heard is great. I haven't seen
it. One lucky subscriber will also,
when a mega crate of
serious epic proportions,
uh, do you have until the 19th at 9:00
PM Pacific to subscribe and receive that
month's crate. And when the cutoff
happens, that's it. It's over. Uh,
go to Luke craig.com/burr and enter
my code birdie say $3 off, um,
on any new subscription today.
And lastly,
but not leastly movement watches.
Talk about your personal experience
with your watch. Um, I liked it.
My Watch listens to me. I feel like
for me when I put on a movement,
watch people respect me more.
The company started by the company,
started by two broke college kids
I always loved that were broke.
Let's start a company. How does that
work? Uh, they wanted to wear stylists,
watches, but couldn't afford them. So
they started their own watch company.
Cause God knows starting your own company
is cheaper than buying a fucking watch.
How is it this like your, how is this
like how you started build a following,
launched into a podcast,
youtube, radio, etc.
I'd say exact same way except I didn't
eat anything other than gas money.
I commend these two broke college kids
that were able to start their own fucking
company. I don't know
how you did that. Um,
how I've started everything in my
business is I always worked for free for a
long fucking time and then
eventually made some money. Um,
and I had some shit thrown
at me on the way up.
A movement watches start at just start
at just $95 at a department store.
You're looking at four to 500 bucks.
You know why?
Cause they got paid for
the overhead of the store.
Mood figured out that by selling online
they were able to cut out the middleman
and retail markup providing the
best possible price. Classic design,
Quality Construction and style.
The minimalism.
Get 15% off today with free shipping
with free returns by going to
movement.com/burr. This watch has
a really clean design. Seriously,
I've been getting compliments ever
since I put it on. Why do they do that?
I guess I'm supposed to read it
beforehand. I don't even know I am.
I don't have a movement. Watch on
me right now. I gave it to Andrew.
He fucking loves it on a bed. He's getting
complex, right? Compliments right now.
I have a watch. I don't
know where it is. All right?
So I'm not getting any compliments
on my fucking freckled wrists.
Now it's time to step up your watch game.
Go to movement.com and v
empty.com join the movement. Oh slash
birth joined the movement. All right.
Okay. Uh, all things comedy. Oh, here we
go. All things comedy. My comedy network,
which is producing its
first standup special,
starring a Trenton New Jersey Zone,
Paul Versey.
It's going to be taping August 13th.
All right,
tickets are going fast.
You're going to want to be there,
me and Pete Davidson and going to come
out and do a little smothers brothers
shit up front.
I think we're just going to go up with
a notebook and try out new material and
just shit on each other as new jokes where
everybody's going to have a good time
and then Paul's going to come
out and absolutely crush it.
And I have to tell you,
he killed so fucking hard
this weekend up at um,
uh, what the fuck is it called? A
port Chester the Capitol Theater.
I told them on the first night,
I said,
you're officially not a
fucking opener anymore.
The level of laughs that you're getting
and the quality of material that you're
doing, it sets it, you know, I'd sit,
he's going to be a fucking nationally
fucking selling out headliners soon and
I'm going to miss them.
Ooh.
Um,
all things comedy has launched its own
Patrion page to give you exclusive access
to podcast videos and a behind the scenes.
Look at our latest projects.
Go to patrion.com that's p a t r e o
n.com/all things comedy for access to
exclusive content there you'll find,
uh,
my new Sunday vlog before
Monday video podcast. Yeah,
I did a video podcast paint.
You got a c p a t r e o n
patrion.com/all things comedy.
I did a Sunday vlog before Monday video.
I actually had a great time doing it. Uh,
Al Madrigals, new podcasts, secret
of my success and the first episode,
a features Philippe as Rza. Um, all right,
so I talk about everything I
wanted to talk about. Okay.
Talk helicopters for a second.
So I got back into flying those fuckers.
I fly once a week. I have a great time.
And, uh, last week I flew great. You know,
I just, you know, I didn't really
have to look down at my altitude.
I was just able to maintain it,
pull in 19 inches on the
fucking a fucking inches gauge.
They would have the fuck you call it.
Um,
so I'm getting ready to solo again and um,
you know, it's, it's the fucking
hobby costs the God damn fortune.
So I was sitting there thinking like, you
know, buy a helicopter with a fucking,
I could just, you know, it can get really
good at this because I love it. So um,
oh my daughter's crying.
She wants to just woke up.
Anyways. Um, so the one,
I'm not going to say the name
of the one that I've flown,
even though I've said
it before, okay. This,
this certain things with
the design of that thing,
it's a two bladed main rotor system.
It's over slung and semi articulate it
all this fucking ground school shit.
But basically because of that, if you
were for whatever stupid fucking reason,
if you slam the stick forward and
got yourself into a low g situation,
which is basically you'd feel
like you are light in the seat,
like there's a chance that you risk mass
bumping, you risk sharing off the tail.
You risk fucking with the mass bumping
the main rotor, literally spinning off.
You watch it a, there's that thing
that's producing lift. Right?
And then you just crash to the ground.
Or if you get into a low g situation,
literally the fucking thing could just
start rolling to the right because the
rear tail rotor is now compensating
for the fucking main rotor that,
that the helicopter is not loaded
underneath anymore. So when,
when you go to the right,
rather than think all my God
go to the left with the stick,
you're actually supposed to go gentle,
gentle as you fucking rolling over. Like,
Holy Shit,
am I going to be upside down in a second?
You rather than go back to the left,
you're supposed to fucking override that
intuitive move and you're supposed to
go gentle aft cyclic so you don't
share your fucking Goddamn tail off.
And, uh, you know,
people with very little hours all the
way up to people with a ton of fucking
hours have died in those fucking things.
And the company that makes them rather
than fixing that fucking problem has just
basically told people what to
do when that problem arises.
And if you don't do it correctly
and you fucking die, they blame you.
You know? So it's a lot like being
in a relationship with a woman
in that it's always going to be
your fault. It's not what they did,
it's how you reacted to it.
So you know,
in order to get the a fully articulated,
uh,
main rotor system where you can fucking
basically is my instructor said fly like
an Asshole, which is stabbed
the thing forward. You know,
I don't think on any of them you really
should be doing any sort of quick
fucking movements.
I don't think quick movements in any
aviation has never fucking good unless
you're getting shot at and
you're in a fucking [inaudible].
But any sort of mass bumping,
low g, none of that bolt,
like that's all taken off the table.
But the problem is is to buy one of those.
They're like, well over a million
dollars. So that kind of bugged me.
So I just kept doing my research
and I found this French helicopter,
I'm going to say it wrong.
It's G U I M B A l gamble Cabri g two
and it's a little more expensive than the
one that I fly. It has a fully
articulated main rotor system.
And then all these other
features, I forget what you
call it, when, when the, uh,
the tail rotor is completely enclosed.
You don't,
one of the major causes of deaths is
like people walking into the fucking rear
tail rotor. You, they just, I don't
know. They just don't see it. So this,
see why you have a passenger,
you have to tell them to stay in the
fucking thing until they shut it off.
Because I still don't know how you
walk into a fan that's making that much
noise, but they do it.
Um, they solve that.
They got like these,
I don't have these rubber fucking
bushings and all this shit that, you know,
like if you land, you're not
going to turn your fucking spine.
If you have a hard landing, you're not
gonna turn your spine in the Goddamn, uh,
you know, gunpowder. Um,
I really just wish I had the article here.
All of this shit that they had.
It's basically they looked at what I
flew in, they addressed everything.
And then for an extra, you
know, half a bag of cash,
you can fly this thing
and not have to deal with,
with any of these fucking safety issues.
And um,
I looked it up and basically the only
problem with it is because it's so safe
now. People are flying like assholes
and they've had three of them crash.
And one of this,
one of the guys that crashed,
and I don't want to laugh cause
I don't know if they died or not,
but what they did still a carborated
engine, right? So you can deal,
you know, you always have to
pull your carburetor. He had,
cause you don't want the fucking, if it
freezes up on you, the engine shuts off.
And you know,
you don't have to know a lot about
aviation that that's not a good thing.
So with this fucking guy did,
was to show somebody that this,
you can fucking stab the stick forward.
He stabbed it forward and
started like nose dive and down.
And because of the way the fuel line was,
it caused not enough fuel to be going
through the carburetor and he fucking
stole.
But why do people do that?
If I ever got one of those things,
I would still fly it the way I fly,
the fucking thing that I fly now.
And I would just feel lucky that,
you know,
God forbid if I was ever flying and
I hit some turbulence that caused,
you know, the helicopter to fucking
nose over or something like that,
I don't have to worry about me rolling
to the right and having to remember to
slowly go aft cyclic to
fucking reload the thing. Um,
I mean that actually affects like
where I fly out here the time of year.
Like I won't go out until like the fucking
desert or something like that during
the summer because I don't need all
that fucking turbulent air throwing me
around knowing at any second I
could start rolling to the right.
I just don't want to deal with that
shit. So I find this fucking thing. Now,
the only downside that I've found,
there's always a downside, right? Um,
is that this thing,
because it's European,
the main rotor actually
spins the other way,
which I didn't think would be that big
a deal. But what it actually does is,
is all my muscle memory is
for a main rotor that goes
counterclockwise, suspense,
clockwise. All of times when I think
left pedal, it's now right pedal.
But I talked to my instructor,
he said it's about three hours and you
start getting it down and then you find,
but then, you know, three hours, I mean,
three hours. I get to fly in a helicopter,
I have a great fucking time.
And then I just keep flying
the same one every time.
Then I get it down and then I have
this really safe thing that I could fly
around.
It's got a little compartment you can put
stuff in and it's a little fucking two
seater. Check it out. G u.
I. M. B. A. L. Cabrice, g. A.
B. R. I. G. Two. I mean, I
think they're the shit. Um,
there's always concerns with any
fucking new helicopter, whatever.
But I just feel like it addressed
all the safety issues that fucking,
you know, anytime I solo,
I'm just thinking about that,
which is good because I had, you know,
the guys that trained me were great.
So I'm always thinking
about that shit and um,
but you know,
you read up on it a lot and yet it
becomes like this fucking terrifying thing
that I really don't feel like, uh,
I don't feel like dealing with. So,
um, I dunno. I just want, you know,
you don't want to really wish,
I just wish fucking school's around here,
start buying those things so I can
rent those instead. Because I mean,
okay,
it's still too much money. There's so much
fucking money, but I'm just saying it,
you know,
in a fantasy world,
I would have one of those and I'd ride a
Ducati to it with an airbag suit on and
they'd be no bus to run me over a five.
A fucking laid it down.
But we all know that that's
not the case. So, you know,
maybe I'll just get a poster and
put it on the wall and my girls,
Roger,
that's what
it's a been a married guy.
Is he in your garage?
You have a poster of all this shit
you'd buy if you didn't have the
responsibilities? Um, Oh God, that's that.
That actually made me a little sad.
All right.
F I know this is some people up in Oregon
that sell them. I believe they finally,
uh, they got, I guess rated over here,
whatever the terminology is, but, um,
I fucking love him and it's a great look
and helicopter too. I fucking love him,
man. I'm hoping more so. I'm just
giving them free advertising open.
More people start to use them. All
right. F one eight s Billy boy,
uh, Mercedes has 1500 people
working on two cars simultaneously.
1,498 of which probably
went to prestigious colleges
and graduate schools of
none of which get to race these cars.
The two employees that raced
these inverted rocket ship cars,
hated school. His kids, at least Lewis
Hamilton admitted to it. Your thoughts.
Um, oh, what did the Tom Brady gets
all the fucking credit. Well, yeah,
okay.
Absolutely. This is, this is
like white hidden figures.
The end of the day, the person
that gets in the fucking rocket,
you know,
be it the monkey,
the dog or a fucking human being who
gets in the thing and actually fucking
rides it.
You know,
what do you want to those 1,498 people
of Lewis Hamilton had a fatal fucking
accident.
They have the luxury of walking around
away from it feeling bad that had
happened. Where is
Louis would be dead. So,
okay.
That's why he gets to Bang Rihanna. I
mean, I don't know what to tell you. Um,
I thought you were going to explain why.
Uh,
yeah,
the Mercedes team and the
Ferrari team are so much,
you know, better than everybody else.
But in the more I read about f one,
it seems like people go through phases.
Like I said,
red bull won three years in a row.
Mclaren used to be the shit.
A Martini. Williams had
their run. So I don't know,
maybe this is just the era of,
of the Mercedes and funny all Ferrari's,
but doing shit for a long time obviously
got us the biggest understatement ever.
I'll never forget the look on that guy's
face when I said when I said good race
after Montreal when uh, they came in like
eighth or no, he came in like fourth.
Just the guy go from a vet will go from
the back all the way up to almost a
podium is what I was trying to say.
And this guy fucking looked at me.
MMM [inaudible]
I thought it was a dead man. Anyways, he
goes, lots of luck at count Basie theater.
Hope you kill it will not be in attendance
to do you guessed it. School. Ciao.
All right. Father and son circumnavigate
navigating globe in a helicopter.
Well,
how the fuck do you do that?
You'd have to go up to
Alaska crossover to Russia.
Oh,
I got to see this.
Hey Bill
thought you might find this interesting.
Canadian father and son
are circumnavigating the
globe in a helicopter.
Here's a link to the article. Oh,
that's nothing about that helicopters.
It can fly up to like five
hours where the one I fly,
I mean two and a half hours and then
you put it on the ground. So, um,
I dunno. It's fucking amazing.
Oh No, I would look at this.
I got to copy and paste this.
Let's stay patient. Let's just,
just note this thought here. You're
sitting on the bus watching the trend,
not on the bus.
I'm sitting on a bench waiting for a bus,
watching the traffic going.
Bye. Oh, come on. You fucking cut.
So that difficult.
All right. Take off a
helicopter. Father and son,
team begin global odyssey to look at
their fucking helicopter. Holy Shit.
Wow.
Yeah. These guys are the real
deal though. Do they get sponsors?
They have fucking flight suits.
Bob and Steve Dangler embark on a 39,000
kilometer trip around the world to
celebrate Canadian history
and support charities.
That's kind of annoying. Flying through
your country and the celebrating Canada.
Go Fuck Yourself. Celebrate the world of
fly around us. Um, for a year and a half,
my father,
Bob and I have been planning
and organizing a journey
we call c one 50 global
odyssey.
It was,
it's the first Canadian circumnavigation
of the globe by helicopter and the
world's first ever father,
son aerial circumnavigation.
I don't give a shit about all of this
other than you and your plan. Oh,
here we go.
Okay,
here we go. Oh, you know what? I
guess they're cool with Russia.
They're cool with Russia. So there, I
don't know where they're going. Okay.
They start the start.
Finish.
Okay.
Uh, but looks to be somewhere
in the Toronto area. All right,
so they're going to zigzag across.
Oh, they're going the other way.
They're going to zig over to the fucking
maritimes up to fucking Greenland.
Jesus.
That's fucking scary right there.
Over that fucking ice cold water.
Then Greenland of fucking Iceland.
How long is that flight?
Iceland over the fucking Ireland down into
Perry Cross Europe. Uh, Christ fucking,
oh, I'm sorry. England. That's
England there. Okay. Yeah.
And they go across to Eastern Europe,
then right through Moscow to Russia.
Right back over to fucking,
anybody can crossover to Alaska.
And then they come back down to Vancouver,
up to fucking yellow knife
for whatever fucking reason,
I guess to celebrating Canada.
You have to go with those fucking
rocky mountains too. That's scary. Uh,
we start in Vaughan and our first stop
is the Canadian aviation and Space Museum
in Ottawa where a grand send
off his planned from there.
We fly east along St Lords
to Newfoundland. I guess
I could have read this.
Instead of trying to guess with their map
north along the coast of Labrador tea
equals
equality,
eat east and through Greenland and Iceland
and the Faroe Islands to the UK.
Then through Europe and into Russia,
a full third of our trip is
through Russia. Exclamation point.
They're excited because they're Canadian.
They get along people.
We returned to northern North America
via Alaska and then Zig Zag and Canada to
visit as many places as possible.
We finish up back in Vaughan
taking 35 to 40 days in total.
We'll be flying some of the far most
far flung and beautiful places in Canada
and drinking deeply from
its diverse beauty. Oh,
I thought it'd be booze and I was like,
these guys are nuts. Urban skylines,
Arctic seas. When sa you
modify it. God bless these two.
What a great fucking thing to do.
More importantly,
what kind of helicopters at that's
a fully articulated rotor system.
No, fucking rolling over the
writers. Your Dad's slide in India.
Um,
Holy Shit.
That's fucking amazing.
I want to keep up on them.
When did they say they're doing it?
Starting July 1st.
They're already off on their way going.
Can I follow it?
Do like a dad and son
Amelia Earhart,
except they're gonna make it right.
All right, well good for them.
What a helicopter talk this
week. All right, here we go.
Weird new new coworker. Uh,
hey Billy, hold your nuts.
I might've gone over the line at work
and want to know your or Nias input,
uh, would be, uh, would be on
this. Okay. Long Story Short,
I essentially quit my job today because
a coworker was taking pictures of me
before you jump to any conclusions here.
Me Out,
and you might agree with me in the end.
I already,
I don't like that somebody's taken,
it sounds like you didn't
want your picture taken. Uh,
this Monday we got a new employee that
basically acts like she's in a reality
show.
The first day I thought she might be
joking around by doing the classic go from
one person to the next and
whisper turning around,
talk about the other
employees in the room.
Okay. Go from one person to the
next and whisper turnaround.
Talk about the other employees in the
room because she's already talking shit
about everybody.
But then I realized she's just crazy.
She's taking pictures and videos of
all the men at work and share them with
their snapchat or Instagram or whatever
crap it is she's uses to communicate
with other people that are on her level.
It sounds like she's trying to get a
reality show herself and become famous or
something.
The first time she did this,
she was standing a few feet away from
me and did a one 80 jump spin that
would've made Dennis Rodman
proud and with a phone,
took a picture and said
that one was for Instagram.
It startled the hell out of me and I
plainly said, don't take pictures of me.
Over the day.
She continued to take pictures of the rest
of the guy without consent, of course.
And I got to see a couple of them.
One was of my bosses asked
with the texts over it.
That's said debt booty
though. Oh God, this is,
yeah, this is, somebody just spends
too much time on the Internet.
I don't know why you quit your job.
You should just go into,
don't you guys just go to HR?
Um,
so the only thing that got finally got
me was when I was restocking the shelves
and realized after walking across the
store that I felt I was being watched.
I looked up and saw her grinning while
holding her phone and I asked her if she
had taken a video of me.
She said she was taking a video of the
rain outside and I happened to walk
across the path,
obviously bullshit.
I called their bluff and asked her to
show me the video from the beginning,
and it's clear that it
starts and ends with me.
20 seconds of me wheeling
merchandise around.
You can barely see a window on the back
where you can't even tell it's raining.
Uh, she's standing 60 feet away
from the fucking window. All right.
Now before you say, Oh,
maybe she likes you to do it,
I'm on your side and wants to
see you. Uh, let me be clear.
No one is touching themselves to a
video of a guy with the dad bod wheeling
around merchandise.
It's not that,
and she knows I'm happy in my
relationship with my longtime girlfriend.
Regardless. I complained to
my boss who have to two days,
finally talked to her about it
and then she told me, she said,
I walked in front of a rain
video she was making. I said,
if it was the other way around and
it was a guy taking videos of women,
I'm sure that would've been
grounds for dismissal. Absolutely.
I also forgot to mention that she went
through my boss texts when he wasn't
looking to see which
women were talking to him.
It pissed me off that he was more than
willing to believe that she was suddenly
a parttime media allow meteorologists
than just believing me that it was the
40th video of that kind
she was taking of us.
So I kind of snapped and told them not
to bother insulting our intelligence by
trying to believe his excuse.
And he said,
if she tells him the picture of his ass,
wait.
And I said,
if she tells him the picture of his ass
she took was intended to be a picture of
morning fog until he got in the way to
just keep it to himself. And I quit.
A dude just snapped. You
snapped. You know why?
Sorry Dude, I got the volume up
too high. You know why you snapped?
Because like me,
you had expectations and you lost your
patients and that caused you to lose your
fucking mind. And you know what?
You're 100% in the right. At least I'm,
I'm hearing your side of the story
here. Um, so what do you think?
Did I go too far?
Should I have given her time to adjust?
I'm sure you deal with unwanted
pictures of you every day,
but I'm not famous and I haven't done
anything to deserve this. Uh, yeah,
I mean, exactly. That's it. I mean,
you're not jumping around
like a monkey on stage. Um,
I feel like I'm being followed by
the worst Pi and I can't help it.
It gives me anxiety.
As far as I know,
she's already has pictures of me
with the eyes cut out at home. Uh,
the way I see it,
I'm not wasting time waiting until a
coworker grows up to learn the difference
between right and wrong.
She happens to be 19,
but I'm talking about mental maturity,
uh,
because I've worked alongside as teenagers
before who know perfectly well what
the appropriate way to
believe to behave at work is.
And this shop pays lousy enough that
it's no big loss as far as I'm concerned.
Thanks and help you and Nia have a little
and the little one have a good 4th of
July. You guys are a plus families as far
as I'm concerned. Thank you very much.
Um, I agree with you want to
present. The only thing is she's 19,
so I think they just need to talk to her.
I wish you didn't quit your job,
but it sounds like you're
not really worried.
So I don't think it was your dream job.
I mean,
maybe her behavior opened
the door to for something.
You got to turn it into a positive.
Um, and you also have to learn,
like I'm trying to learn
with my behavior in Verizon,
in the fucking bank this week.
Uh,
you know, I, you know what it
was, was you asked her nicely,
she ignored what you, what you,
you, you asked her not to do,
you went to the person of authority and
he swept it under the rug and then that
was enough to make you fucking snap.
I completely understand that. Um,
I think your behavior
is completely normal.
I'm surprised you didn't tell your
boss to go fuck himself. And, um,
but at the end of the day, you
know, you don't have a job now, so,
and you're actually a
good guy. I mean, I want,
what are the guys say when you quit?
He was all right with that.
MMM.
I think kids grow up today and they,
because they so overshare
on all of these things,
their boundaries with privacy
is pretty much nonexistent.
I mean,
there was like a famous woman took video
of an older woman naked in the locker
room going, oh my God, look at her
old ass. And she got him to like,
and like she had no idea though.
Like that's why would you do that to
somebody and somebody's mom or their
grandmother, but I dunno, people are uh,
yeah,
spat and I,
I gotta be honest,
it gets bad enough when someone comes
up to you and just takes a picture you
don't want, but people walk
up with the video already on.
Um, yeah, I I, yeah, I don't like that.
And even with what I do,
cause you know,
they usually are extremely selfish person
and the whole moment is about them and
you know, that whole whoa man,
Yolo, look at my life right now.
Have shaken my head. Whatever the
fuck dumb shit that they're doing.
It really is funny though,
when you watch these fucking kids
on like Instagram and everything,
everybody's acting like they have like
a hit show and that they're like these
celebrities themselves, like
always taking like, you know,
snapchat is fucking pictures of
like the food they're eating,
the car that they're in,
the fucking view that they have.
Everybody's like acting like a,
I dunno if that they're flying every
trying to act like that flying around in a
fucking private jet. I don't
understand it, but I'm also,
I'm realizing that I'm fucking old
so, uh, I dunno. I Dunno. I think,
I think you reacted in
a normal fucking way.
I wish you didn't quit your job though
because I think you're 100% right. Um,
in the future I would just go to HR
and when your will go to your boss,
when he does it, I would make a formal
complaint and that would stop it.
And um,
but I know,
I would know at that point that I
would hate that 19 year olds so much.
That would be hard to even be
around her. Like, I have a big,
I have a big issue with forgiving people.
Like once you're in,
in the con column, it's, you know,
it's kind of a life sentence.
Um, so there you go. Yeah.
Move on with your life and just
kind of learn from the ship.
But a good for you for speaking up.
But I don't do anything else.
Don't go back to the fucking business
like a lunatic and fucking keys,
somebody's car or anything that just
fucking walk away from it. All right.
Girlfriends, Opportunity.
Um, hey Billy Redwings. Uh,
so my girlfriend is
really doing well at work.
She's been offered a job in Switzerland.
She would rather move in with me
and stay in the United States.
I feel that she's missing out on a
great career opportunity in Chicago.
I love her,
but I'm not in love with her yet.
She's also considering leaving your
job too. I like our relationship,
but I'm more practical.
You should take advantage of things
that's come across your life.
What are your thoughts?
My thoughts are you don't have the
balls to break up with her and she's
committing to you in a way that you're
not prepared for and you need to break up
with her and tell her to go to
Switzerland and not quit your fucking job.
That was an easy one. I love her,
but I'm not in love with her yet.
And you're going to fund,
she's going to quit a job and move in
with you because she's head over fucking
heels. Yeah, boy do. Yeah.
Tell him to go to Switzerland and
fuck some blue eyed fucking specimen.
A blue eyed blonde in specimen
and forget about you. All right.
Girlfriend wants me to change
my name. Dear Bill, I'm to,
I'm a huge long time fan of yours
from the younger generation.
Um,
F one
F ones for family is o.F is for family.
God, I can't read my name on my own.
Fucking that's an eyeF is for
family is fucking awesome.
Can't wait for season three to come out
to see what happens next. Well thank you.
I was hoping you could give me
your 2 cents in this situation.
I've been in a relationship
with a wonderful young lady
for over two years now.
We met at a community college in my
state and hit it off really quickly.
She's smart, outgoing, beautiful
community, college, easy. Hey,
I don't know what the smart thing
there. All right. No, I'm kidding.
A lot of smart people go to
community college. They do.
They just fucking scatter brained. A
lot of dopes go there too. She's smart,
outgoing, beautiful, has and has a
great sense of humor. She's tall,
slim black girl.
While I am a greasy hair to Italian,
white guy and we get along great.
The problem first started with my dad.
He's a total racist and since we can't,
you can't, we can't afford to
put me in a real university.
I have to live with them.
I've tried to get him to change his ways,
but it's like you said in your act, old
men like him come from a different era,
so there's probably zero
chance I'll ever change as my,
you can't change somebody's mind.
They got, they have to want to,
I told my girlfriend how frustrating is
with them and she understands that even
though my dad hates her and
doesn't want us to be together,
then I'm nothing like him,
at least where it counts.
Even though I can't
stand my dad's attitude,
I know that he only wants to
only wants the best for me.
So I try to be a good boyfriend and a
good son while keeping my father and
girlfriends separate from each other.
We also spend time out at her po or out
at her place and Shelly comes over to my
place and my father is on a business
retreat. Jesus crisis is complex.
It's really inconvenient,
but we've been making it work for over
two years in spite of the tribulation and
we're still going strong. Uh, it seems
like I got everything figured out.
All right. Jesus, this is
a fucking long one. Um,
it seems like I got
everything figured out, Bill.
But here's where things get tricky.
Since I'm his first born son,
my dad named him after
himself since same first name,
middle name,
and last name.
My girlfriend hates that the guy she's
been in a serious relationship with for a
long time has the same name as it can
tanker old races. Daigo I like it.
You being racist about about yourself.
Greasy Italian Daigo anyways,
who hates her sexy black ass
for no justifiable reason.
Jesus Christ. It sounds like
bad fucking dialogue in a porno.
She wants me to legally change
my name completely first,
middle and last so that there is no
connection to my father whatsoever.
When I asked her what name she
thinks I should have through this,
like I don't believe this,
you gotta be shitting me.
She said I could change my last name
to the same as heard her own name.
Last name.
Uh,
Prince sees what the fuck I told
her that if it would make her happy,
I would be willing to change my name.
But if I did that,
my dad would feel betrayed. He would
hate her even more for stealing away,
stealing only son away from him and the
rest of the family think I'm a total
trying to disassociate myself from them,
which is totally not the case.
She got upset with me and has given me
regular reminders since then that she's
serious about wanting me
to go through with this.
This isn't the first time I've
considered changing my name.
Even before I started dating this woman.
It's a very Italian sounding name.
So what?
You're very Italian that people always
made fun of me for throughout schools.
So I've come to dislike
it myself. Yeah, dude,
you got a lot of self loathing
going on here. Tines of the shit.
Who makes better food than
you? AH, Japanese. Uh,
no. There's you guys make like the
best food in the fucking planet.
The Ferrari did du Cati
yeah,
you fucking women to Mediterranean
lifestyle. Dot. What do you,
what are you walking away from here? So
bill, what the fuck should I do here?
How can I make things right with my
girlfriend as well as my dad without
accepting one party or the other?
She stopped introducing me to people
using my name and show your first to me is
my boyfriend.
I've been able to and circumvent
hostility between my dad and my girlfriend
before. But I've totally, I'm
totally lost with this one.
Any advice would be very much appreciated.
Thanks.
And Go fuck yourself sincerely. That's
funny. Any fucking leaves his name.
Um, is it deal to eat? First of all, um,
this isn't about your dad and
this isn't about your girlfriend.
This is about you. Okay? You date.
Who the fuck you want to date?
And your name is your fucking name and
your heritage is your fucking heritage.
All right? Like what?
What of her fucking her,
her parents didn't like you because
you were white and you said, okay,
you're named after your mom.
I can't stand your mom.
Change Your fucking name and I'm going
to pick the name and it's not going to
sound like,
you know,
I guess black people don't have their
fucking ethnic names anymore. Do they?
Thank you white people. But you know
what I mean? Yeah. Fuck that dude.
You can't do that shit. You
can't do that shit. Fuck that.
Your name is your name and your Italian
and you should be fucking proud of it.
Okay.
And you're not your dad and she needs to
fucking accept that you're not changing
your fucking name and she has a problem.
She can fucking walk away.
She can fucking walk. All right?
You know what you really need to do?
You need to get out of your fucking house
and you need to fucking build your own
life. Okay? Anything you need to be
with somebody like this is fucking nuts.
Like I got to tell you,
dude like that.
If you thought about shifts that
came from you, that's one thing.
But the fact that she fucking wants
you to do that, that's fucking insane.
Don't do it.
You know your,
you're given into everybody
else and you're not,
you're not staying true to yourself.
You've got to figure out what the fuck
you want. And you have to be yourself.
Jesus fucking Christ, man.
Your Dad is who the fuck he is.
Your girlfriend is who she is
and you are who you are. Okay?
And you should be proud
of who the fuck you are.
Work on the stuff you need to work
on and be proud of your heritage.
And I don't, I don't, I don't fucking
get that at all. You know? I know.
I know number of people like Italians,
they always asked us to,
to Italian sounding name.
Who fucking gives a shit?
Well, I don't understand. Like I don't,
I don't know. I wouldn't do that.
I miss all the fucking ethnic names.
Everybody's like homogenize
their fucking names. Um,
I think it's interesting when you
meet somebody that's like that. So I,
I think you need to pump the
brakes here, sir. All right.
Is now was getting fucking crazy and um,
yeah,
don't do that to your dad. Don't change
your fucking name. Who gives a shit?
He's an old crabby fucking racist. This is
a deal, dude. He's going to die someday.
All right? And you're going
to continue on. So what you,
what you haven't done yet is you
haven't created your own life.
You still living at home with this guy,
so you have to fucking move out.
All right? The name he gave you is
the name that he fucking gave you.
Don't change it because of his
stupid fucking thoughts. Okay.
Embracing the fuck you are. And if this
woman, you can't fucking deal with it,
tell it a walk.
Tell her to fucking walk you young.
There's plenty of fish in the fucking
seat. You know, you get Jesus Christ,
you're gonna fucking bend over that far.
You're bending over backwards.
Flip you like you're fucking Jim is, you
know when they do those things to hands,
foot, hand, foot, hand, foot,
all the way across the fucking
diagonally across the Goddamn Mat.
Fuck that. Fuck all of that. You know
I liked your girlfriend at first.
By the end of this fucking thing,
I didn't like her.
Okay.
Cause she's waging war with your
dad threw you and you're innocent.
All right? You're the guy taking
her out for fucking ice cream.
Why do you gotta do all this shit?
Yeah.
With no,
I mean Jesus Christ that without her
telling you to change your fucking name
would be you to tell her to go get a
go. Can you get like a week, a week,
like a blonde weave or some
shit like that? I mean,
what the fuck you gotta be able
to fuck you are. God bless you.
You tell [inaudible] son of a bitch,
stay Trudy average.
Stay true to your fucking name.
Continued not to be racist
and fucking just be yourself.
Change your fucking name. Ah,
Jesus Christ. Anyway. All right.
That's the podcast for this week.
Um,
I'll check in on you on
Thursday. Ever happy, safe, uh,
4th of July. And if you're not in this
country, a, enjoy your fucking Tuesday.