Hey, what's going on?
It's Bill Burr and It's time for the
Monday morning podcast for Monday,
May 15th, 2017 halfway
through the month of May.
Oh Jesus Christ.
Do you know Bobby or scored that fucking
overtime goal on mother's Day to win
the Stanley Cup back then? You know,
I think you only had to win eight.
It was like fucking 12 teams. He had
the original six and the expansion six,
the original six really
weren't the original six.
They would just to six leftover after
fuck in the stock market crash or some
shit. They were the only guys
left or after World War One.
I can't remember. Didn't
like the Lusitania sink.
And then that like half the players on
them fucking Montreal maroons were on it.
I don't know. What does his stump
the fucking shwarmy over here.
You don't? He has been been,
uh, she's been recording um,
the sports jeopardy, Aka
Buffalo wild wings. Jeopardy.
I would tell you, even as a sports
fan, it's not easy, but, oh,
do I seem like a smarty when I'm watching
that show to the point, Nia goes,
if they ever do any sort of
fucking, you know, comedian,
uh, sports jeopardy thing where you
can give the money to a charity.
I love that shit.
It's like I'm going to go
on TV onto a game show,
one of the hardest game
shows out there. Jeopardy.
Granted it's all going to be about
sports, but they do a lot of shit of like,
you know, you know,
who was the first free agent to
fucking get new a fight with Al Davis,
Amsterdam. I don't fucking know. Right.
I'm named the last three
owners of the Seattle Seahawks.
Like they take it to that
level, you know what I mean? Um,
but I love how you know, you, me, he was
like, oh, you should go on then just,
you know, give the money to
a charity. Fuck the charity.
I do enough benefits as a comedian.
I can't go on TV and try
to win some money from me.
Okay.
You know, hit a couple of categories,
sitting there going, well, you know,
I'm going to go on TV and expose
how limited my fucking,
I don't know my world is,
I don't know.
I'm going to go on TV and make an ass
of myself and then give it to some dirty
face kid afterwards. I'm gonna lose.
And then what some kid who grew up in
a fucking chimney is going to sit there
crying cause I went there and basically
did the babe Ruth thing, a kid.
I'll go out there and hit
a home run for you today,
except I'll do it with my mind man.
And I'm going to go out there and I'm
going to fucking lose cause they're gonna
be like, ah. Yeah.
What brand of baseball glove did goose
Gossett's use when he was still on the
fucking Oakland ace? A
Rawlings? Oh no, sorry.
The correct answer was a Wilson
douchebag family with the chance
to steal. Um, I actually did, uh,
you know, if I can remember the category,
my problem with those
shows is sometimes like,
I don't understand the, uh, you know,
they'll say like get Carter and it takes
like me for like fucking three in a row
to understand like, oh, these are,
everybody's got the last thing. Carter,
I got the hardest one too.
Or maybe I'm just the oldest.
They brought up the fucking,
the dude on Michigan who then I
think went to the fucking USFL.
I'm like this fucking
Anthony Carter number one
first started watching college football.
He was demand out there with
the wolverines. All right.
Popped bar, Bar bar,
Bar, Bar, Bar, Bar bar.
That doesn't look great. Fucking fight
songs of all time to Michigan world.
Lorene's yeah.
That uh, that uh, that uh,
that uh, that Duh, I'm fine.
Go with you. I know why.
What goes hail to factors value and
I was singing the Notre Dame song.
Oh, Jesus is tank Milo Jay.
Sheesh. They go on foot.
Two point conversion there. Jesus,
what do you got to say? Well, you know,
I mean, if they make it, they make
it. I mean, I love everything buddy.
Get out of this fucking locker room. You
Baird it hippie. That's what happened.
If Jesus came back,
Jesus ever went to the locker room
and Newt Rockne was in there, right?
Oh, five foot, nothing of them
considered fucking average height.
Way Back in the day before they put the
horse tranquilizers in the fucking horse
meat that they fed to the horses that
they then fed to the cows. Right.
That then in my burger.
Okay,
maybe that's why I have
such a fucking disposition.
I eat a lot of red meat.
Okay.
This is how much red meat I eat. I don't
consider hamburger red meat. To me,
red meat is, I had a steak.
I have a burger man. It's,
it's a, it's not, it's not red.
After I'm done cooking it, you know?
Actually it's not even true.
I like, I like all of it.
Medium rare and what I've been told by
a life freaks where they're like, look,
you can have a steak medium rare.
That's a lot less of a risk because
that's just one cap. You know,
you rolling the dice, it's like your
bang one hooker without wearing a glove,
a Chase's bill. Right.
And then hamburger though,
it's like you bank
Vietnam. I don't know. Oh,
I picked Vietnam some reason I went to
fucking full metal jacket. Hey Baby,
you got go from Vietnam.
It's like you banged a
fucking country or that,
that's what hamburger is.
Cause it's just a bunch of cows
all fucking mulch together. Right.
You have a stake. It's like you just
fucked one cow. That's what I'm trying to,
or steer I should say. What's the stair?
Well that's a bow without
his balls buddy. All right.
And take off it's fucking horns.
Um, I don't know what it is anyways.
And if you have hamburger
that's like, you know, you know,
you're just Freddie mercury running
around fucking the whole free world.
Isn't that basically it? I mean,
I'm not, you know, I'm not,
I don't know my way around the kitchen
enough to s to know if that analogy
worked or not. But, uh, I will say that I,
let's just get back to the original
point. Okay. What was the original point?
Yeah.
I don't consider hamburger red meat or
was it that I'm not giving some fucking
kid who lives in a chimney. I don't
know why. A chimney, you know,
you know what, seeing broke children
is always sad unless they're white.
This just something fucking
funny. But yet, you know,
I think it's just a relief as a white
person that the guilt goes away.
You don't know. You know, anytime you
see somebody from another race broke,
you know, white people fucking pushed
him out. They put a Walmart down, right?
They put one of those, Derek's in there.
They started sucking all the
fucking shit out of it. You know,
I wonder if people around the world
when they watched the beginning of the
Beverly hillbillies start crying. You
know, when they just see the white man,
even though the first they laugh
like, oh my God, it's toothless,
broke white people hilarious. And even
they discover oil and they get to keep it
solely loaded up. The drunk
animal, the Beverly Hills. That is
um, I wonder if they cry
when the children cry.
You know, nobody gets to movie. I
was talking about, I kept references.
We had problems with
defeat and we baggy shit.
Yeah.
Um, anyway, so let's apply. Speaking of
that, children cry. That's white line.
Everybody when the children
cry was actually a hit.
That's how fucking off the
rails music went at one point.
Okay.
Little Chat
[inaudible] I was like on the
top 10. I remember watching it.
I didn't give a fuck about that song,
but I was like that lead guitar instead
of all these fucking guys trying to be
Eddie van Halen.
Am I saying this guy was there
trying to do the shit that Eddie did?
That fucking guy in white line.
He came the closest, you know,
out of all the white bands, you
know the white lions, the fucking,
who else was it? A, it was
white Lion Jews. Great White.
It was white snake. It was eight Aye.
It was a little known all white funk band.
Cause then what people used
to yell when they want to say,
I can't remember how it goes. I Dunno.
Um, anyways, speaking of children crying,
my condolences to, uh,
all the fans of the Washington capitals.
And you know what happens when you hit
the fucking wall for the third time when
you win the president's trophy, you
know, under two different presidents.
Okay. When Obama brings you to,
and Donald Trump comes in with
his tie hanging all the way down,
his tie would still touch the ground.
Even if he was wearing skates.
He comes walking in the locker room
and he gives you that fucking trophy.
You're right, you're on
your second damn president.
You've left the ugliest uniforms in the
history of the fucking game of hockey,
possibly. Definitely up there.
Those blue ones with that
gold fucking eagle, you know,
it just looks like they
put a stamp, like the,
like the post office had a
limited stamp thing, you know?
Then all those weird fucking smelly
people, you know, people who don't bathe,
collect stamps, you know, and
I'm not saying that, you know,
with all this stuff, like what do you
identify with a man or a woman, you know,
being a man, I don't, I, I'm a
man, but I don't identify as,
don't identify where he imagined the
fucking emptiness of that every day.
Waking Up, shave and going,
what the fuck is this?
I can't relate to this
fucking beard on my face, man.
You know, when am I, Ted's going to
come in. I just, I can't imagine that.
But whenever there's other
people that can't, you know,
they don't identify with other
human beings, forget about,
they don't identify with their own gender.
There's another group of people that
we all need to care about and wear a
certain color on a certain
day or maybe a ribbon for,
and these are people that can
identify with other people.
They just can't identify
with human beings in general.
And these people collect stamps, you
know, they just sit in their room.
They're not bothering anybody.
Taking that big giant fucking
book off that shelf, you know,
blowing the dust off it.
Cause they finally got the Washington
Capitols fucking horrific Jersey from the
mid to early two thousands whenever
they had that. It was that awful period.
That's why in the NHL,
the added too many fucking teams and
everybody changed their uniforms.
I should put it all on the capitalist,
Washington DC. Fucking horrific.
Thank God they went back to the red,
white and blue. You know, I mean,
you are there in DC for
fuck sakes. You know,
if anybody shoved the color of
the flag, you should be you guys.
You know the Buffalo Sabers,
that fucking IHL horseshit
they had, you know,
where they put a sheep on the front
of even was like a bull anymore.
It was terrible. Fucking terrible. Um,
props to them. By the way, when they,
they finally admitted that
they made a fucking mess.
That was such a horrible period.
They had that strike that.
They lost a whole season
of the NHL. All right.
They added a bunch of fucking
teams. Too many goddamn teams.
They had the Atlanta thrashers, they
had the fucking Florida Marlins, right?
That's right. They played hockey first
before. They suck so bad. They were like,
you know what? Let's just fucking play
baseball now. If the Florida panthers,
the lightning, the coyotes,
and I think the north stars
moved down to become the stars,
at least they kept the kind
of the there are right,
cause they kept the same fucking uniforms.
Then of course they knocked down that
stadium in Minnesota and they put up the
mall of America there.
But it's so sad that you know the place
would dino Sorelli smashed a stick over
that fucking guy's head.
You can now sit there standing there
eating frozen yogurt without a care in the
world, you know? Or did what?
Was that a road game anyways? Um,
fuck am I talking about
here? That's right.
So then you had all these new teams
in the NHL and then on top of that,
all these teams that had been established
all changed their fucking uniforms.
So you, you, you come back after the
strike and you just watching like, dude,
is this the fucking Olympics? Well
actually that's not true cause that,
or they started doing that in
the 90s because when the Sabres,
the Sabres got fun in 1999,
you know, back when you could
even have a fucking shoelace.
Tough like fucking shoe leather. That
mood Sarell Huh? Who knows that one?
There's another obscure tough
like fucking shoe leather,
that Mozzarella, Mozzarella, whatever
the fuck you said Mozzarella. Huh?
Who knows that one? If you're religious,
you might know that. That's a hint.
The title has something religious.
Every religious figure in it and
it's not Jesus Christ superstar.
That's the last hint I'm
going to give you. Um, yeah,
the savers got fucking 1999. Was
it Brett Hall? Was it fucking,
uh, uh, Danny Mashburn? I
don't know who the fuck was.
Joe B Joe Barry Carroll who had
that foot in the fucking crease.
I can't remember.
But the whole year they're calling it
until the biggest goal of the year.
The one that decides to Stanley Cup
Classic NHL. Yeah, that new rule.
That's been fucking everybody
all year round. Yeah, forget it.
We've decided to change the rule and
over time in the clinching game of the
Stanley Cup playoffs, that's
how we do it. That's right.
That's how we do it. We take
breaks every 20 minutes and a,
we have rules that all of a sudden
the rules go away. So anyways,
my condolences to the city,
to the district of Columbia capital
fans, man, they fucking did it.
T again. You know, when you keep
showing up cause you real fans,
you know what's going to suck.
Now they're going to dismantle
the entire fucking team.
Hopefully they keep a veggie skin. You
guys are out of your fucking minds.
If you get rid of him, are they
going to blame it all on him?
Did you see that picture of his
leg? I'll fucking bruised up.
He looked like somebody
tried to get information out
of him and he wouldn't give
it up, you know, fucking
vein sticking out.
Um, uh, my daughter's crying
in there. Oh Jesus Christ.
And I feel like a bad dad, but he is
in there. Okay. He is handling it.
Don't worry. Can you hear that? Yeah.
This is the time of night.
Like she's so like wants to know
everything that's going on that she does.
She won't nap enough during the, and
by the way, fuck all your suggestions.
I don't want to hear
a million suggestions.
Put one of her shirts in in the bath
than that. We've tried everything. Okay.
It's just, you know,
it's a phase she's going through and I
am done listening to fucking people who
are not wearing lab coats and if you don't
have a lab coat on and you don't have
a fucking little degree
hanging on a wall behind you,
just keep your fucking
ideas to yourself. Okay.
The level of shit that parents talk every
fucking one of them as a Goddamn cure
for every fucking thing that happens.
Every one of them just glided through
fucking being a parent or four figured it
all out and for some stupid reason they
didn't cash in on it and write a book.
Why would you do that when you can just
show up to somebody's house and vomit
all your fucking ideas on a,
if any of your people's
fucking ideas work,
you should put it in a book and go on
the Oprah channel and you guys can sit
there holding each other's fucking hands
and she tells you how amazing you are.
Instead of coming over here, boring
me with it and then I go and try it.
You know? Actually, you know what the
shirt one worked, the shirt one did work.
I will say that. I should,
I shouldn't have fucking said that because
a relative suggested to me and it was
fucking great. That's just the
first thing that popped in my head.
I was actually thinking about somebody
else that annoyed the shit out of me with
something else.
I'm trying to feed my kids solid food
three months into her life. Oh no,
it's fine. It's fine.
Oh God. This is, this is
the danger of riffing.
Cause you ended up shitting on the person
you're not upset with. Um, anyways,
plumbing ahead. Uh, where am I? Oh yeah,
the condolences. You know, so I would,
I would definitely keep Ovechkin
you got to build around the guy,
build around the guy again in a, you
know, get a coach with a neck and,
you know, you know, maybe he can see
if something was off sides and not,
and he could,
he could throw the flag or whatever you
do to challenge it instead of sitting
there with his, his, his spine fused. Um,
somebody made the joke said that every
coach in the NFL in the NHL looks like a
bond villain. And uh, it is true.
I, I gotta go with that.
You know what I mean? Um,
although I would say that closed
Julian closed. Julian looks like that,
that dude in the swamp thing that when
he got turned into a monster became that
little guy running around.
That was such a weird fucking movie where,
I don't even remember
the name of the movie.
The whole thing about the movie
was it was this chicken shed,
these giant fucking tits and you're just
waiting for her to go into the lake.
So they'd show a little side boob.
Now, this is the early eighties.
That was a big fucking thing when you
were like 12 years old. All right,
so the deal with the swamp thing,
which is where I got that thing I had
broken with the, and we Becky's, that's,
that's where it's from. It's from the
swamping. I'm obviously fucking with you.
Um, what am I talking about? Yeah, the
swamp thing. Right. So how that worked.
He was, he was, I forget what headed
the guy was walking near a swamp,
you know the usual thing.
And then a telephone pole
falls into the fucking swamp.
He gets electrocuted and then he becomes
the swamp thing and he's as strong as
shit and there's some fucking bad guy.
So they figure out how he became the
swamp thing. So then the bad guy wants,
he wants a swamp thing, have
him send army a swamp thing.
So whatever you can take over all the
swamps. I don't, I don't remember. Right.
So this fucking little weasel,
he dude, he does the same thing.
And when he turns into a monster, he
says, little as fucking weasely monster.
So then the bad guy goes, well, how
come he didn't turn into what you are?
And it says, well, you know,
when you get electrocuted in the
swamp and you turn into a swamp thing,
it just enhances your
personality. All right?
So if you're a fucking stud like me who
even know I look like a swamp thing,
I could still bang that big tinted
hor over there and the lake. Uh,
if you're a little weaselly con you just
become an ugly weasley con with like
mud and leaves for skin. They
go people and I, you know,
I can't think of a bet. Sorry,
just blew out years there.
I can't think of a better time to
read a little bit of advertising.
What do you say? What do you say
that, what do we got here? Oh wait,
I've got to finish. So you know. Okay,
well I think I can say to DC fans is a,
when you finally fucking went
it, it makes it all the sweeter.
Just going through all
of this shit. All right.
I watched the Bruins from about 79 80
and I had to wait til like 2011 so what's
that?
A a nine 99 2009 I watched
him for about 33 years.
All right. Um, and I know you guys.
Woo Woo Woo. Oh, shut up. Shut up.
All right. You got all those monuments.
She could fucking walk around Ya.
Cheer up. Did look at the window.
The wizits forced the game. Seven.
I'll talk about that a little later
after I'd read a couple of fucking
advertisements here. Hell, x
everybody. Helix. You're unique.
Oh, you're a special
little fucking content yet.
You don't walk like everyone else.
Talk like everyone else. Sleep shoot,
chariot like anyone else.
So let me ask you this,
why is your mattress one size fits all?
I hate this question. It's just
because there's a general height that
okay, from a little baby all the way up
to like if you make a mattress that fits
somebody about six foot four,
you're covering like babies all
the way to like 90% of adults.
It has to be right. I don't know.
What do I know about mattresses?
About as much as I know
about reading out loud,
but I'm going to continue because a truly
customized mattress will cost you five
to 10,000 bucks until now.
Go to helix,
sleep.com answer a few simple questions
and they'll run a 3d biomechanical model
of your body through the proprietary
algorithms they've developed with the help
of the world's leading
Ergonomic biomechanic experts.
The results of fucking robot
shows up to your front door,
who looks exactly like you with
the mattress strapped to his back,
it gives you their old forearm fucking
shiver and next thing you know he's
banging your wife from the
bed that you paid for. Sorry.
No,
what really happens is the
most comfortable mattress
you've ever slept on shows
up, right? You lady lays in it.
She's like, oh my God, this is great,
right?
She reaches over for your fucking Meat
Hammer and next thing you know you need
to buy a new mattress.
He likes customers report a
30% improvement in overall
sleep quality and for
couples. They customize
each side of the mattress.
The beginning of the end
of your marriage, um,
is when you have the custom telling
you that's the beginning end of it.
That starts with that. And
then he goes, you know,
it'd be great if your tits were
a little bit bigger, right?
And then she starts redoing herself
like Matt Damon in the Liberace movie.
And then one day just gets rid of her.
And maybe nowadays with millennials,
it probably goes the opposite way.
The way these broads a slap and
the guys around in the shows now,
it's unbelievable hanging them off
of fucking balconies and stuff.
Your mattress arrives at your door in
about a week and shipping is 100% free.
That's why everyone from GQ magazine
to Forbes are all talking about helic
sleep. That's what they're doing.
They're not talking about ties.
They're not talking about the
next hostile takeover, right?
They're talking about mattresses. Do
you have a hundred nights to try it out?
And if you don't love it,
they'll pick it up for free,
gross and give you 100%
refund. No questions asked.
Go to helix, sleep.com/burn
get $50 off your order.
That's Helen's sleep.com/bar
hey, he likes sleep.com/pur
ah, here we go. Me On ds. But Oh,
here we go. Goto boat boat me on.
Ds me On d please look at
that fucking robot dude.
[inaudible] me on deeds. His
balls a metal. Don't say that.
Not he walks up the doors,
slammed you in the face.
Fucks your wife. Doesn't
can. No race cars is metal.
Nuts and nice and soft.
And then he lays down on a helix
mattress and banked you sister.
Alright. Elevate your underwear game
to the next level with me on this.
You've perfected your wardrobe.
But what about the stuff?
Not everybody gets to see. We're
talking about your junk. Everybody.
It's time you braided. You pubes oh
wait, this is the wrong copy. Um,
if you've been settling for
store underwear, five packs,
I have something that will change your
life for the better. It's me undies.
What's the first thing you put on
and the last thing you take off? Oh,
it's not your socks. Oh, it's not your
contacts that you fucking drawers.
It's your underwear.
Make your most important piece of clothing
the best it can be with me. Undies.
Follow up colon. What is me
undies? Ah, just seriously soft.
Feel good undies delivered right to
your fucking door. Read Colon by why?
I'm going to read all of this
shit. Mandy's are designed in La.
That's either Los Angeles, a Louisiana,
and made from sustainably
sourced micro modal, modal,
a fabric three times softer than
cotton. And then you know what?
I believe it now because I haven't, cotton
hasn't said a fucking word about it.
And I've been saying this fee
is Mandy's softer than soft.
Luxury undies come in and ever
changing selection of classic colors,
bold shapes and adventurous patterns,
venturous patterns. What are the,
outline your Dick on it.
So you can tailor your undies to your
own personal style. And guess what?
You can save time and money each
month with a monthly subscription.
And if you're not ready for a
subscription, that's okay man.
You can still save. There's
no pressure here, man.
That's because me undies is offering
you 20% off your first pair.
Just use our special URL me
undies.com/bar and get
20% off your first pair.
So go ahead revamp your underwear
drawer. You deserve it yet. Coke.
Once again, that's me.
undies.com/burr Mandy's dot com slash.
Bar How many more are these fucking
things out there? All right.
Dollar Shave Club do.
Mm.
Dollar Shave Club is this smarter choice.
You'll get a great shave at a great price.
Conveniently delivered right to your door.
You no longer have to Schlep to the store
to buy a cheap disposable razor that
gave you a cheap shave or spent a fortune
on razors with gimmicky shave tech
technology you don't need.
And when you use dollar Shave Club's
executive razor with their doctor Kawis
shave
the blade
just gently glides, giving you a
smooth shave. Dr Carver's shave butter.
Um, talk to cavies. Easy shave butter.
His I call it is transparent
for a more precise shave.
It's transparent and visible like the
flames that burned Ricky Bobby helps
prevent ingrown hairs and fights.
Razor bumps. Look at that.
Make the smarter choice by joining
Dollar Shave Club for a limited time.
New members can get their first month
of the executive razor with a tube of
their doctor. Cute, but
only $5 with free shipping.
After that razor is just
a few bucks a month.
That's a $15 value for only five
bucks. There are no hidden fees.
No commitments cancel anytime
you like. It's a one night stand,
but with the razor,
you can only get this offer
exclusively@dollarshaveclub.com
slash Berg that's
dollar shave club.com/bar I don't
know if you guys have noticed,
but I've gotten much better
at reading out loud. You know,
watch this. I'm going to say it right now.
I Bet I only make three mistakes in the
next two fucking reads. You want to bet?
What do you want to bet? Huh? You want
to bet a little cavities? Shea butter.
I bet she a fucking handful
of that shit. All right,
policy genius. All right, and I
never said how fast or slow I'd go.
Life Insurance. Do you have it?
See that nailed that first
sentence. If not, why
too expensive or a hassle? Man,
if you don't have life insurance,
what would happen financially if
something happened to the primary earner?
What are you talking to the wife
here? God knows the primary earners.
That is the man. And that's not a
sexist statement. I'm just saying I'm,
I'm just,
I'm just a progressive male and I've
listened to all these women bitch moaning
and complaining that we all make
more money to do the exact same job.
But wait a minute, how many women are
plumbers and then marry a plumber?
Okay,
well that'd be the worst of
your own fucking competitive.
Um, both going to bed,
smelling like fucking shit and wrenches.
Alright, let's keep going here.
Life insurance is a good idea
to protect the ones around you,
but where do you go to get the
best prices or the best policy?
But the best service policy genius
policy genius has a very simple use of
friendly website to shop and compare all
the top rated life insurance companies
and give you the best
options while you're there.
Check out their other insurance
offerings like pet insurance,
pet insurance for what?
[inaudible]
case you fucking fish reverse drowns
when it flops out of the fucking tank.
Okay.
I don't know. I guess for dogs
getting their fucking teeth clean.
Go to policy genius.com today and save
over 40% off prices for life insurance.
When Life Insurance sellers compete
for your business, you save money.
Is that a job? Love life insurers. Ah,
that's the first mistake that is going
to get an eagle on this fucking hole. Ah,
that's policy genius.
P. O. L. I. C. Y. G. E. N. I. U. S.
That's a second mistake I fucked
up on the.com. Please spell it out.
I just did zero jargon,
zero sales pressure.
Fuck amount of mistakes. I
still got one more to go.
Zero hassle life insurance made easy.
Free quotes. I got the Yips. Zero Hassle.
Peace of mind. Don't wait. Go to
policy. genius.com today. All right. Oh,
believe me, any bit of it. Oh,
believe me, I've got one more here.
Air. Oh no I don't. That
was the last one. Oh,
this is this guy giving me
shit about airline bumping. Oh,
he fucking went off on me.
He fucking put me in his place when
he sat down in his goddamn keyboard.
I'll get to this in a minute.
I will get to this in a minute.
I like this guy who gives me shit about
the airline bumping. You know why?
Because it's very few people out
there that defend the man. All right?
Anybody can attack the
man every once in a while.
It takes a fucking a fucking, I
dunno, the Internet version of that.
Clint Eastwood Spaghetti Western guy
coming into town with his little fucking
Mike Tyson's colorful Mike Tyson
towel over his fucking head. Bye.
That's how broke Mike Tyson was when
he was a pony. First started out,
he was like, I want to dress like Clint
Eastwood. And they said, all right,
we'll get you his underwear, his boots,
and we'll get that little fucking,
that little Sharley
puts over. But you know,
we can't afford to put
any color on it, you know?
And that's the kind of thing that
leads you to bite somebody's ear off.
I'm just saying, I'm not trying
to say that what he did was right,
but I'm just saying I understand. Um, hey,
how you doing up there in Montreal?
Everybody Moray all Canada.
How's things going up there?
Enjoying the fucking off season.
God knows you're gonna have enough
time to come and see me in June.
This is what I'm loving about
the predators. All right.
Although they seem like they're
losing right now, I'm taping the game,
but I'll fuck, I'll fuck myself over
here and I'll just look it up right now.
Oh, look at that.
The little time trial thing and
you're going to fucking load for me.
I think the ducks were up
five to two or five to three.
How fucking weird are these playoffs
this year? You know? Anyways,
now you know, I always give you guys
shit about pet, the curse of Patrick Wa.
You humiliated that guy. I mean, what
you guys did to him when you watch like,
like horror movies, you know what I
mean? When somebody like, you know,
thinks their prom queen and then you'd
dump a bunch of blood on them or they
think that they're going to go make a
wish in a well and then their mother
pushes them to the bottom of it. You
know what I mean? They think they get,
you know that, that all of
that shit, all of that Shit,
right? Somebody drowns in a fucking lake.
You guys did the hockey version
of that to Patrick Wa, you know,
he thought you guys loved them.
They see why there was like Kerry,
he came out there, you know, has one
fucking bad game. You won't pull him.
You leave him in there, you
fucking do a mock cheer.
When this guy who redefined the position,
first ballot hall of Famer,
continuing the tradition of winning
fucking Stanley Cups, you know,
and he wanted to earn the real era
when there was like 30 fucking teams,
28 teams,
not all those cups that Canadians and
maple leafs one back in the day when it
wasn't even the state, it was
like a fucking shot glass.
It seemed skating around with the
thing. Let's say a fucking baton,
you know, before it became
that giant Goddamn thing. Um,
anyways, they booted him out of town.
So ever since then there's been the
curse of Patrick Wa and I think the next
fucking part in the next
chapter of the curse, okay,
is PK sue. But you know, you know what?
They ran him out of fucking
tee ran that guy at attempt.
Now this wasn't your fans. I
think it was the organization.
I also think it's because I'm a Bruins.
I just love giving you guys shit
cause what am I going to do?
Talk about championships. You
guys are going to destroy me.
So this is this little fucking little
thorn I can put in the underneath your
fucking elephant foot
here. All right. What?
PK was a fucking great dude
and he gave too much money.
That children's hospital,
he started becoming bigger than the
Canadians and the Canadians could fucking
handle it. Like when Colby couldn't
handle shack and he said, look,
either he goes awry, go
and they said, okay Colby.
And they sent shack to Miami and then
he went to fucking title there, right.
Then they had to bring Phil Jackson back
and another 50,000 fucking free agents
as they always fucking
do. You know, I, you know,
I just give Koby Shit for the
first, the first three rings,
get the Fuck Outta here. The last
two. I'll give you those, you know,
even with the officiating in that
second time you played the Celtics, hey,
let's call fucking 38 files on one
team and 17 on the other. That's,
that makes for a good game. Seven doesn't
it? Not Saying that we would've won,
but it would have been nice to see
the Lakers beat the Celtics that year.
Just saying, um, anyways, plowing ahead.
So now the predators are up one to nothing
against the fucking Emilio s Istem as
is the Shane's. Whenever the fuck
you call them down there, the mighty,
the mighty Shane's. Okay.
The Anaheim s Devis is the mighty
ducks. I don't like the ducks.
I don't like ducks. Don't give a
fuck. I just don't like them. Okay.
I don't like the Honda
Center. Okay. I you go there,
there's no fucking vibe. There's no
vibe in Anaheim. It's just a fucking,
it's just, I don't know what it is.
It's just a strange God damn place.
Anaheim is fucking weird.
It's whole fucking La Aries weird. Like
people weren't supposed to live here.
You know what I mean? They weren't
supposed to fucking live here.
It's a fucking desert. We still water
the whole, the whole thing's weird,
but at least you know this, this
cool shit to look at. You know?
Except when you go to Anaheim, I don't
know what you look at. All right,
and you go down there, there's no
fucking vibe. Maybe it's better.
I went to a ducks game in the late
nineties they were still early, right?
There was still the mighty ducks.
They still had Donald duck with
the broken bill in the front.
Isn't that what they had for their
logo? I don't know. So anyways, what if,
what if,
what if p k leads the Nashville predators
to a Stanley Cup championship this year?
I'm just throwing that out there for
everybody up there on St Catherine Street.
You know with the acute little pocket
squares that matches the color of your
socks. You know,
what the fuck are you
going to do then Nashville,
that Banjo play in fucking
washboard down by the fucking river.
You haven't been to Nashville.
I mean half the structures
there still have dirt floors.
It's unfuckable. It's ridiculous.
You know like when they went this day,
when they went to Nashville
this year and they were like,
you know who you voting
for for for president,
they allowed like I'll tell you one
thing, I ain't bought Bill Lincoln.
Are you all just afraid slaves?
That's how backward Nashville is.
You know? I know there's all this shit
out there saying it's this growing city,
you know, and they're trying
to get people to move there.
The reason why they're trying to do that
is because so many of the structures
still have dirt floors. Okay.
Now if he can go down there,
all right. And, and, and fucking
lead them to the Stanley Cup,
the big boys Stanley Cup,
not that little shot glass that you and
Martin the you and fucking Toronto one
like fucking 15 times each. You know,
I'll give the Canadian say last 10 cups,
but I, I look at him like, Dang,
I can't even say they're equal Detroit
because Detroit was back then when it was
a shock list, you know, sort
of a fancy shot glass. Um,
anyways, um, I'm just fucking with you. I,
I've no idea how the fucking
predators are in the finals,
the western conference finals with the
ducks and then the Ottawa senators.
What the fuck is going on with
when, when is, when is the,
the glass slip are going to
turn back into a fucking Punkin.
I'm telling you, if Ottawa goes
any deeper into the playoffs,
they're actually going to sell
out a home game. Ms Unbelievable.
Did you see the first game of the
Rangers Beer? 2000 of the Rangers series.
They had 2000 empty seats. That's
because they stopped playing the Bruins.
You know what I mean?
And the Bruins were just close enough to
Ottawa that that shuttle flight wasn't,
it wasn't too expensive, you know,
then they played the rangers
and God knows Rangers, fans,
all those fucking Manhattan cops. They
got the money to fly up to Ottawa.
But then New Yorkers don't. What,
why would I? They got boy's head.
They got a slice of
cheese. Why would I travel?
Look over there and see
empire state building.
Ooh,
that's what New Yorkers are.
They, they're, they're fucking,
they're like country people.
You don't have to be low Lee fucking
Skaggs in the fucking five boroughs.
Um,
I am in an extra country mood and I am
just trashing people that I have no right
to trash. Okay? My team is
not in the playoffs. Okay?
My team has not won as many
championships as the fucking Canadians.
My city doesn't have as many
skyscrapers as New York City.
A don't fuck with my shitty. You
just fucked with the wrong Shetty.
I have problem with Bailey
baggies. If you touch my family,
oh fucking kill you. Those lines
will never get old in Hollywood.
You don't get another fucking hacky thing.
I'm so sick of every other fucking show
doing the speed dating fucking scene.
How many times can you do that and one
fucking lunatic after and maybe it's not
that bad.
Jesus fucking Christ people showing up
with like half an ax and that side of
their head. People live with their mother.
The person who's actually gay pretending
to be straight the fucking side.
I mean,
Eddie Murphy did this shit fucking
and then coming to America in 1989
Jesus Christ.
Why don't you just have somebody come in
and slip on a banana peel and then get
a pie in their face and then do the dating
thing. Hey Bill, you're so talented.
Why don't you come up with
something new? Because I'm limited
[inaudible]
all right. I never said I fucking,
I would reinvent something. Um,
all right.
Unfortunately I have to take a little
bit of break and I'm going on a nice
little roll here. I'm on a nice
little roll here, but I have a, yeah,
I got something I've got to take
care of, which is why I'm doing this.
At nine o'clock on a Sunday, you know,
but why do I need to tell you guys?
Cause this is only gonna be a fucking
second of your life. Um, alright, hang on.
Hang on a moment. Okay, I'm back.
I'm back and I am is
illiterate as ever. Right?
You want to listen to somebody just
fucking tearing me a new one here.
So I was talking about a fucking United
Airlines and Delta and them just yanking
people off of flights and
like what happened to customer
service and all of this
types. You know,
I felt guilty flying United the way they
just dragged that Chinese dude off the
plane though. The two going to
China, just assuming he was Chinese,
Asian. You can give me that right?
Who knows, who knows? They wait,
I'm so fucking hard. I don't
know. You know, fucking
fucking. Anyways, airline
bumping, he said, he says, Hey,
you uninformed cunt and I'll tell you
and nothing makes the reader want to read
more when you just start
off with the insults.
He said Congress and the passenger's bill
of rights have led to more passengers
getting bumped due to more cancellations.
And do you think he gives any examples?
No, he just moves on to his next point.
Also, if people showed up
for the flights, they booked,
the airlines wouldn't be overbooked.
Many passengers book multiple flights.
How about if you buy,
so you're just assuming that the guys
that they're yanking off the flights,
that those people, I don't do that.
I buy one fucking ticket and
I show up. That's how I do it.
So you're telling me that that Chinese
do to that other fucking person on Delta.
You're telling me that, that, that those
are those people. So they said, Hey,
you book like 20 flights. You only showed
up for one, Eh, get out of that. Fuck.
I said, yeah,
you're telling me that's what happened
or are you telling me that because other
people do that because the guilty people
did it that United and Delta's now just
going to grab some random innocent person
and throw them off the fucking flight.
I heard the reason why they did it was
because they had another plane that they
had to get a flight crew to and they
just fucking yanked the guy off.
That has nothing to do with that
other shit as far as I know.
But I hate what am I am just uninformed.
Cont evidently you who just like me
just make statements with no fucking
evidence behind it. Alright,
plowing ahead. He goes,
how about if I buy a ticket for a
flight and miss it for whatever reason,
you lose it. Question Mark.
Is that how you run your
shows? Was that a point?
How about if I buy a ticket for a flight
and miss it for whatever reason, comma,
you lose it. Oh, how about if I
don't have a problem with that?
I don't have a fucking problem with
that at all. I'm on the same page.
I hate when I show up on time for the
security line and somebody else shows up
super late and then they get rewarded
and get breezed through the fucking line.
Like they're in that t like
they're part of the TSA party.
They're the precheck people.
Yeah,
dude, you bringing up all this other shit
that has nothing to do with a fucking,
just somebody who bought a ticket
and sits on the plane. I drive a car.
Other people steal cars.
Should I be yanked out of my fucking car
cause other people are stealing cars.
This makes no sense. I
might be an uninformed cunt,
but you are a pompous,
arrogant, uninformed continent.
I could say that cause I'm in show
business and you know we're all down to
earth. All right, let me read some more
of your air quote points. All right?
Is that how you, is that
how you run your shows? No,
I don't run my shows like that.
You know, this is my fucking,
this is how I've run my fucking show.
I don't have anybody kicked out ever.
He can be the biggest cunt ever.
I kicked the first fucking
person out in 10 years
because he was so fucking drunk. I'm
a hell of a guy. I don't give a fuck.
I'm a great guy when
it comes to that shit.
How dare you lump me in with United
Airlines and Delta, you, you,
you, you hateful so and
so. All right, let me,
let me at least finish this point here.
Is that how you run your shows or if
someone buys a ticket to your show and
misses it due to traffic leaving
the house late, et Cetera,
do you honor their ticket to the
next show? I will tell you this.
I've had plenty of people fucking reach
out to me and I have hooked plenty of
people up with tickets.
Okay, how about that?
Has everyone reached out to me? Has
AV, I've seen every fucking email.
No, but I hook people up. I've run into
fucking people walking down the street,
driving by in a Kygo and I'll fuck,
I didn't know. You're like, Duh, hey,
can I go to the show? And I'm
like, it's all soda. I go, fuck it.
What's your name? I've done that
countless times today. He goes, sir,
I don't know what you're talking about.
So the equivalent to that is I fucking
pull up and stand outside the gates of
the airport. Go, hey, you guys fly
to Minneapolis? Uh, yes sir. We are.
Could I, can I buy a chicken?
Sorry, though. It's all sold out.
Oh, bombing. I don't worry
about it. Don't worry.
We'll get you on the plane and
then they fucking Yank someone.
They yanked somebody off.
I don't know
why they pick the Asian guy. Huh?
Why couldn't they pick some fucking
white dude in a suit? You know why?
You know why? All right. Uh, leaving
the house late, do they? Okay.
Well that is what the airlines
do. If you miss a flight,
they put you on another one. So fuck off
you nonreading pigment and paired con.
That's not what they do.
That's what they do sometimes.
Other Times they yank you off the plane.
Other Times they tell you to go fuck
yourself. Other times they say, hey,
you have 200,000 miles.
You can't use them when you want to use
them and if you don't use them by next
Wednesday, we're taking them all
back. Other times they say, hey,
which is charging extra because it's
post nine 11 we lost all this money,
which is charging for food,
but eventually we'll fucking
stop overcharge and we'll
stop charging for this
shit for all the money that we
lost in nine 11 which you know,
we're now going to pass
onto our fucking customers.
So they take the hit when was fucking
nine 11 I know I'm an unknown or
uninformed con as far as my calculation.
We're coming up on the 16th
anniversary this September.
You still paying for
Pringles, aren't Ya sir?
I'm all for defending the fucking
man when it's, when it's for,
I mean I don't know what you just
fucking, you just brought up a bunch of,
but I guess behavior by for
the frequent flyer people.
So then evidently I should get yanked
off the plane at some point because other
people overbook and shit.
You know what you're,
you're the kind of person that probably
likes that dead where they call it the
trap ride or the trick car,
whatever that fucking show is.
You probably like that show. You probably
think that that's a good fucking show,
right? That shit,
I can't even believe that fucking
show was on television for the,
it's on true TV. We
should change the name,
the fucking horrific TV they fucking take.
They drive down to like the
fucking projects and they take,
I believe a car with the door open keys
in it running and then they wait for
someone to fucking steal it and then
they act like they got a bad guy off the
fucking street and I was reading
comments underneath the, you know,
I love that they're going to go out of
their fucking way to go down there and
try to get someone to go to jail.
Why don't you go down there and try
to help somebody out? I saw one guy,
he actually stole the fucking car. He
knew it was the trap car or whatever.
He's driving with the door open
because he knows that they just locked,
they fucking hit the
locks. He can't get out.
And he's saying he knows it's the trap
car he's waving to the camera and all
that. They asked him if he knows a
trap car, why did you do it? He said,
I don't know, maybe I
just want to get on TV.
And then he left and everybody's
like, tech guy's crazy.
I want to party with that guy. That
guy's a dope or anything. It was, it was,
to me it was fucking depressing like that.
That's the level of options this guy
has in his fucking life that he would do
something like that and somebody
else brought up a great point. Okay.
Like why don't they take that car around
the fucking suburbs to the whites,
the sax. Why don't they
do that? And he was
still cut the fuck they don't. They
absolutely do. And I'll tell you,
there's a point in my fucking
life I would've done that.
I absolutely would've done that
just for this stupid fucking,
just to have the story so I could talk
about it loudly around chicks that I
liked because I didn't know
any other way to approach them.
Okay.
If they ever did that in a fucking
suburb, in a bunch of white kids,
started going to jail over
that shit. That shit would not,
there'll be entrapment.
It wouldn't be held up in court and
the fucking show would be shut down.
All I'm saying. Okay. You, sorry.
You probably liked that type of shit.
You probably liked that show. Do you
think that's a good show and hey, let's,
let's, uh, you know, rather than giving
this guy an opportunity, you know,
they could just as
easily couldn't true TV,
have a fucking show where they go down
there and they try to give somebody a
fucking job, you know?
Okay.
I Dunno. Anyways, plowing ahead,
making your own baby
food a Billy burp. Um,
had my first kid a couple of
years ago, congratulations.
A friend suggested we make our own baby
food because it's easier to get them to
transition to real and healthy
foods. We tried it and it was fun.
Okay.
For instance,
that we make our own baby food because
it's easier to get them to transition.
Okay. All right. We could, hi, there's
another fucking guy. No lab coat.
No degree. We couldn't do it 100% of
the time, but it was totally worth it.
My kid isn't that picky of an
eater and I liked that. Thank,
I think that days of pulverizing fruits,
vegetables and oats into tasting
meals. Oh, it's because of that.
I'm sure you can afford that.
Good stuff for the little lady,
but just thought I'd throw it out
there. Thanks. And Go fuck yourself yet.
I don't know too. I don't
know what to tell you.
I'll cross that fucking road running.
Everybody's always like, you know,
you've got all these goddamn
suggestions. There was somebody fucking,
you know everybody talking about like
private schools versus public schools.
It's like these fucking kids, they
don't even get to be kids anymore.
They should be out fucking, you know,
this whole fucking thing that you know
from day one, like he gets gotta be like,
you've seen what it does.
Look in these countries that
fucking push their kids too hard.
They, they have like
ulcerated fucking bottles.
Like they've been working on fucking
Wall Street for 60 goddamn years and then
like seven. The level of stress
that they put on them. Fuck that.
My Kid's going to be a
God damn kid. All right.
I flunked everything fucking in in
high school. I fucked up everything.
I got arrested for drinking and
driving. I was unloading trucks.
I did all of this shit. And then one day
I just figured out what the fuck do I,
what do I want to do? You
know, found a passion.
And I followed it and I was fine.
And I remember back in the day,
they used to fuck, oh, you
need two years of a language.
If you don't have two years of a fucking
language, you can't love all that.
It's all fucking bull. You know,
I used to say that the fucking
language teacher, fuck everybody.
Fuck everybody.
Let your kid be a Goddamn kid and fuck
all these fucking private schools within
nine zillion dollar fucking, you know. Oh,
you better get in when the kids
are just playing with blocks.
The early you you get in,
the better chance you have for your
kid to continue on. In other words,
start fucking line in our pockets now.
You know, why don't you
just have you, I don't know,
want to be cheaper to just
have your kid homeschooled.
You're going to drop
all that fucking cash,
like he's already going to Yale and
fucking going to school and they go on the
wheels on the bus go round and
round. Round air. That'll be enough.
Yeah. The credit card didn't work. Yeah.
I can't teach you the rest of the song.
All right. Birthday Boat Party. A bill,
a bald headed eagle. Jesus.
Go and fucking old school on that one. Um,
hey, a Chesler. Hey, a sidewinder.
Recently my girlfriend dumped
me over a text message.
I swear to God if that, if that
existed back in the day, I would,
I would fucking be lightened phones
up if that wasn't bad enough.
I got the texts just as I was
walking into a movie with a buddy.
She told me straight that she didn't
love me anymore. I took a like a man,
watch the movie, went home
and cried like a bitch.
I honest guy.
Two days later I went to a party
on a boat. I spotted my now ex.
We made eye contact and she looked away.
So now I'm trapped on
a boat for four hours.
You didn't know that she was going to
be there with a bunch of drunk cons.
I don't want to be
around. And of course her,
I made an attempt to ask her why the
fuck she didn't have the balls to dump me
face to face, but she ignored me
totally. As she's young and immature,
I then saw her walk over to a guy
and start kissing him. Jesus Christ.
I commend you, sir,
for not throwing yourself in them also
overboard and fucking double murder.
Slash suicide bill. I have no fucking
idea. I didn't punch this con,
but I decided not to. I now wish I
had punched his stupid fucking face.
And my question is, what should I,
should I have done something? Fuck now,
why are you punching him? He's doing
what he's supposed to be doing.
He supposed to be out there trying to
fucking hook up with women. All right?
Any bad feelings you have should be
towards her. But here's the thing, dude.
You know, in the long run she did your
favor because she didn't love you. Okay.
And eventually she could've done that
while you had two kids with her and you
actually had to pay her fucking
money. She did you a favor. All right?
Yeah. Don't ever do that.
That's the dumbest shit ever.
When people fucking date somebody and
then they get dumped and then they're
fucking dating somebody else. I mean,
and then you go over and you confront
the other fucking birthday that they're
outside the circle, you know? So, um,
what should he have done? You should
just been a fucking gentleman.
That's what you should have done. You
just be a fucking gentleman. Just be like,
hey, you know, evidently, you know,
she doesn't want to be with me anymore.
I mean, dude, I know. Listen, I got
dumped. I know fucking hard. This is,
I'm on time.
I actually fucking was talking
to somebody's heart on the table.
This woman dumped me out of fucking
nowhere. And I'm in a bar, of course,
and I'm talking to a buddy of mine. And,
and the problem was he got dumped like
four years earlier and he still wasn't
over it and he fucking hated women. So
this is why I'm pouring my heart out to,
and I was like, you know, I mean I
thought everything was going fine.
What the fuck? And I did all that shit
and he just goes, hey, you know, I dunno.
Maybe she wanted to fuck
somebody else. And I just said,
you know what to I said, you know
what? Fuck you. I actually flipped out.
I was like, fuck you. You fuck. That
has nothing to fucking do with this.
That has to do with that
fucking shit. That fucking cunt.
You dated four fucking years ago.
You still not over and I've been having
a fucking carry you off the field like
Kellen Winslow after that fucking overtime
game for laugh on every fucking bar
for the last four years. You can't
sit there. He's like, dude, I'm sorry.
Tag Off. Fuck off. Not
just part of a bad memory.
I'm actually, did I say that?
That's probably what I
said on the way home.
I think I said that on the way
home. I think I just said, fuck you.
And I walked out of the bar.
That's right. That's what happened.
That's how old I am. I'm so
old. My memory is the fantasy.
Okay.
My memory is what I should've said.
I did say fuck you. And I walked down
Zocalo you know, just fucking walked up.
Uh, one of the few times I didn't pay
for my round of beers, I was just like,
fuck you walked out. Um, anyways,
he said, hope you're well,
thanks and go fuck yourself
dude. You took it like a man.
What are you going to
do? And um, you know,
keep taking it like a man and keep going
home and private and cry it out here.
That's what women do. Fucking they cried
out of them and then they can move on.
Uh,
the fact that she dumped you and then of
course it does immediately make an hour
with this guy is really suspect.
But you never know with them.
You never know. That could have just,
she could've just picked that guy.
Yeah,
because you were there. You have no
fucking idea. And here's the thing, dude,
even if she was already banging that
fucking Douche, wow, I'll make an hour.
That douche when she was with
you, then that's the time.
That's who you are with. So
good fucking riddance. Alright.
That's what you had you,
you thought you drafted somebody in the
first round that didn't fucking work
out. And you know what? That guy just
picked up her contract for you. You know,
so now you got all this
cap space. All right,
go cry or out of your fucking heart. You
know, but don't go around hating women.
That's what I did. Big fucking mistake.
All that does is it stop you from meeting
a fucking sweetheart because you know
who loves an angry woman hater. A
fucking psycho chick. All right,
there you go. All right.
Russian girlfriend,
a Billy blue balls. Hey
Man, I was well, hey man,
I was wondering if you
could give me some advice.
I'm a 27 year old from New Zealand
and current resident and current.
Oh Jesus.
And current currently residing is what
you should have said instead of current
residing here. Current resident
here. Currently designing here. Okay.
I've met and recently started
dating a girl from Russia.
We've been officially dating
for about five months now.
Everything is going
great. Never been happier.
If she ever asked you to take a boat
ride, don't get on the fucking boat.
All right. And I'm not talking about
because of the last thing. All right,
this one, you show up as a couple
other shifty guys there and then, uh,
your identity gets stolen and we never
see you again. All right. She's hot.
Best in bed I've ever
had and I've had a lot.
Ha Ha got a great personality and someone
I could see going further into the
future with. Okay,
well you're writing me so I know
the other shoe's going to drop.
The only issue is that our visa is
about to run out in a few months. Oh,
before she moves back. Unless we can,
she can find a decent job here.
The only issue with that is the job market
over here for the type of work she is
after is very small, a translator.
We've been checking the job sites and
whatnot over the past month with not much
luck.
So I've put up the idea of maybe heading
over to Russia and try to start a life
over there. Oh No, fuck no,
but that's a great way to see if she's
with you because she wants to be with you
though. A,
my qualification could take
me anywhere in the world,
but I'm still skeptical on, well,
should I just uplift my whole life and
move to a country that doesn't really
speak much English?
Apparently with my girlfriend that
I've only known for a few months,
plus not knowing much Russian. Yeah.
Plus you don't know how
that country fucking works.
All right.
You have no idea how that
fucking country works, dude.
Okay.
You're talking like you're
dealing with the fucking mob.
Wow.
Hang on one second. All right. Sorry.
I just realized I double book myself.
I had to fucking figure something
out. Yeah, dude, you have no idea.
Like what's going on over there?
Like if that's a whole different
fucking animal over there,
that's a whole different government.
The level of influence that the mob has.
I mean that shit is fucking hardcore
over there. Russia is no joke.
What the fuck did you
say you account from?
You've gone from New Zealand or Russia.
You gave him the gardening. Fucked up,
dude. Fuck that. Fuck debt
fucked up.
Get her a job interview. They'll see
how beautiful she is in, you know,
you know, do what you can fucking do,
dude. Fuck that. Fuck that
repeat. Fuck that. I mean, I remember
when I had been reading the rest of this.
Fuck that. Do not move from
fucking New Zealand to Russia.
Jesus fucking Christ.
Do not do that. Please don't do that.
Okay? I never beg in the podcast,
but I'm begging you right
now. Do not fucking do that.
Jesus can go from the fucking garden of
Eden to then. Now you're the immigrant.
Now she's trying to get you a fucking job.
You know what kind of money
you're gonna make over there.
Okay?
I got no fucking, I def.
Fuck that. All right.
Soccer coach rips off shirt after
rejection. Hey Billy. Dad. Sec.
Okay.
Oh,
that was as original as Billy
Bald Eagle was a not all right.
Saw this video and thought it might
interest you during a recent soccer game.
And Argentinian player accidentally knocks
a player out from the other team and
ends up getting a [inaudible] from the
game. As a result, after he gets ejected,
the coach freaks out. Yeah, watch
the clip, starts yelling at the refs,
then he gets ejected. So when he
realizes that he's also objected,
he rips his shirt off only to reveal,
and he's an older guy too, you know?
I don't know. I can't tell all the guys.
Somewhere between 40 and 50 rips his
shirt off only to reveal that not only is
this dude fucking shredded,
but also his whole back
is covered in tattoos,
making him look like he spends his free
time going to bare knuckle brawling down
by the shipyard. Thanks for all the
laughs and go fuck yourself. Yeah,
I watched the clip of this.
This guy looks like a,
this guy looks like he's
done some time in prison.
What's amazing is the rest of his body
that you can see, he has no tattoos.
And then on the back it's just like,
I don't know what the fuck he's got
going on, but his entire back is covered.
And it's all of those,
you know, uh, you know,
if you touch my family, I will fucking
kill you. It's those kinds of tattoos.
It's not the A, I was in a frat and I
got drunk one night and uh, all right,
this is my old girlfriend's name and we
fucking turned into a swan or whatever
the fuck they do. This is
like hardcore, you know,
this guy's going to
punch you in the throat.
Okay.
It's a great clip. I really
appreciate it. All right,
let me make sure I did everything here.
A Russian girlfriend do not stay in
New Zealand birthday boat party. Yep.
A, you got a lot of cap space. Good
for you making your own baby food. Yes.
You know, I'll, I'll see about that
airline bumping a agree to disagree,
but I like the fact that you went out
there and stuck up for the airlines.
[inaudible] I think that's it. He's
right. All the things, right. Oh,
I didn't talk about the f one race
motherfucker. Did you guys watch it?
They have. I got, I know, I know.
After Nias just absolutely
eviscerated watching racing.
I hope if you were going to watch a race,
the Spanish Grand Prix was a great
one. Lewis Hamilton had the pole.
Sebastian Vettel uh, I think was, yeah,
it was in the second
position. And then, uh,
Boris Karloff Leboeuf I can't
keep forgetting his name.
Fucking Lewis Hamilton's
um, uh, driving mate there.
His fucking car caught on
fire. But the first guy,
the other guy who drives for
Ferrari, whatever, fucking his,
whatever his name is, Ricky
Ricardo. I can't remember. Um, no.
Daniel Ricardo drives for force India.
No, he doesn't. He drives for red bull.
Why don't I just fucking go on
and look up the Goddamn names?
Cause most of you guys don't
watch this shit seat on it.
You don't know what you guys
know as much as I fucking know.
So here's what happened. All right.
The race starts and uh,
what's his face?
Lewis Hamilton has always
gets a bad fucking start.
Sebastian Vettel goes around them.
That'll drives the Ferrari's.
Lewis Hamilton's with Mercedes. Uh,
Vettel is out in front on how
many fucking points he was ahead.
He was like 15 points
ahead of some shit. And uh,
in the old days last year when I wive
on watching for a year, the old days,
which is Monaco of last year,
when I started watching, if you,
if you went to the turn
first, whoever won got,
got through the first turn first in
first place, drove in the clean air.
That was it. You won the fucking race
unless you messed up a pit stop or you,
your car shit the bed. So
he gets out in front. Um,
and then his is his buddy there.
The other Ferrari guy gets
knocked out of the race. Okay.
And they fucking, they cut to a,
this kid in the stands were in this
Ferrari thing. Where are the drivers?
Why is it so difficult?
Drivers, here we go. Here we go.
I should add this all
ready to go. I'm sorry.
I'm like slowing this the fuck down.
The Reagan in guy gets
knocked right out of the race.
And this little fucking
kid, they cut to him,
he's wearing all Ferrari gear and he's
just crying his eyes out and in they're
sitting there going, well,
like federal still in first place
while he must've been a big uh,
Reagan and fan over the fuck he say his
name and they showed him twice bawling
his eyes out. I couldn't believe a
kid this little was that into racing.
I thought it was really
cool. And uh, later on, um,
the driver got knocked out of
the race Ferrari. They actually,
they brought the kid in and he took
a picture with them and everything.
So I ended up being a good deal,
although he probably cried again when
Lewis Hamilton went around and, but um,
anyways, it was a great race from
front to back. These new fucking tires,
I guess. I have no idea why they
got more grip that's more passing.
Um, Lewis Hamilton past, um,
Sebastian Vettel I think on like
lap light. It's like 20 laps to go,
which never happened last year.
The second place guy just could never get
around the first place guy once he was
out there. Um, I dunno,
it was a great race.
And then Lewis Hamilton for some reason
was like fucking out of breath when he
was talking cause he was saying because
they got the fatter tires they could
pull more gs in like just the physically
what the fuck they were going through.
And Lewis Hamilton didn't
have any drinks on board.
I didn't know they had drinks on
board. I then never even dawned on me,
but he didn't want to add
any more weight to his car,
so he lost like four and a half pounds.
So they go, you know that actually,
you know this people out here in Hollywood
that have enough money now that the
day before they have to go to like a
red carpet event. They're gonna fucking,
you know,
drive around in a fucking race car for
three hours so they can drop that final
fucking four and a half pounds. I'm
telling you, it's going to happen.
So I believe the next,
next race is in Monaco. Um,
I don't know.
I'm enjoying watching it and he has
got me all self conscious about talking
about it. Now I'm going to blame her
then I wasn't prepared to talk about it.
Um, was there anything else
on my, my little list here.
So as you nerds always wanted to rift the
whole thing? Pretty much. Pretty much.
But I make like a setlist a
shit. Didn't want to talk to,
if I can fucking find
it. Where the hell is it?
I give up. I fucking give up with
this shit. What did I have on here?
I don't know what that is.
We'll close this window.
This is the most anticlimactic
ending to a podcast ever. All right.
I said predators. Louis Han Hamilton,
Sebastian Vale, Daniel Ricardo,
first time he was on a
a podium this year. Oh,
he had to give a shout out to a force.
India still rocking the Fuchsia,
whatever color that is. Um,
I think that was it. Oh,
happy mother's Day.
Belated Mother's Day to all the
mothers out there at a great time.
We went to brunch. Yep. That's where
I am right now. I went to brunch.
My parents came out, met
their granddaughter there
over the, over the moon,
loving her. She was so cute and was
just, didn't cry at all the whole meal.
And then she got in the
car and then that was it.
She had friggin had it and was
just crying up a storm. And uh,
but it was, we ended up having a great
day and I came home and I was like,
it was crazy. You know, I've just
finally entered this part of my life,
you know, my parents are
older. I got a little one,
I'm at Brunch and I have
no say in the matter.
And you know what? It feels good.
I had a great time, you know,
we had all kinds of
family, had a big crew,
seven or eight people and we went to
this fucking insane brunch and everybody
threw down and uh,
had like 3000 calories each. Great
conversation, great people. It's just,
it was awesome. All kinds of pictures
and that type of shit. And, uh,
other than the fact I forgot my fucking
wallet because I decided to wear a suit
and I was going to be the big shot picking
up the fucking check and I had to go
to my parents. So now, now, you know,
when a few days when I'd
take him to the airport,
I've got to give him the fucking money
back. But Oh god, it was embarrassing.
Really embarrassing. Um, so anyways,
that was my mother's Day. Uh,
go fuck yourselves.
I will check in on you on
Thursday and let's go predators.
And um, I don't know. I mean, I got
a bunch of friends. I, you know,
in Pittsburgh. I'm just rooting
for extra hockey at this point.
I hope both series go seven games.
I don't want to be this little fucking
Cunty Gargoyle shitting on the ducks.
I don't want to fucking
do that. You know, why?
Why do I gotta bring it to predators?
Success and then shit on Canadians fans,
you know,
all their pocket squares are all soaking
wet from them blowing the noses and
crying about losing to the
ranges. I don't need to do that.
Not to mention I have no bragging
rights. My team that fucking bounced out,
you know, I'm going to try to be a,
I'm gonna try to go cutlass for the
rest of the Stanley Cup playoffs.
How about that? Uh, Celtics
first, the Wiz, ease on down.
Ease on down the road tomorrow. Um,
my brain says it could go either way,
but my heart says this no fucking way.
There's no way they come in to the
garden even though it's not the garden.
It's the fleets at the garden.
Fucking slash whatever fucking Gossett
jr whatever other fucking tags they have
for that thing. And uh, I just
don't see them doing, I feel like,
you know what it is to Celtics.
They got that sound in their crowd the
same way the Yank old Yankee stadium had
it, you know,
knowledgeable fans put a
history of success and they
that can push your team to
fucking win. And I think they're going
to do it. Oh, by the way, Derek Jeter.
Huh? I missed it. I was at Brunch.
I missed it. But that's a what?
A fucking class act, man.
He's such a class act.
He can go into New York and wing
his speech and still kill it.
Um,
that statement, they're artists,
single numbers. See if I can do it.
Billy Martin, number one. Number
two, Derek Jeter, number three,
Babe Ruth. Number four.
I was fucked this up.
That scared five is Dimaggio and six.
I looked up today cause that's
the one I always forgot,
but they said it was Joe Tory, but
I thought somebody else had six.
Uh,
sevens. Mickey Mantle. Number
eight is fucking Yogi Baron.
Somebody else. Nine is Roger
Maris. 10 is Chris Chambliss.
11 is Gary Sheffield. I
don't know the rest of them.
Thurman Munson's 15, a little
store. I remember Reggie Jackson,
they added retires. That was 44.
A Bode Diaz with somebody.
What do you were 30?
I don't fucking know. All right, that's
it. That's the podcast. I will, uh,
I will check in on your Thursday. And
uh, God bless all the mothers out there.
Okay.
Work with the family. Becky's
all alright, I'm done.