Hey, what's going on?
It's Bill Burr and It's time for the
Monday morning podcast for Monday,
July 4th, 2016 how's it going?
Happy Birthday to the
United States of America.
Happy Birthday.
United States of America and
the North American continent.
Yeah.
Happy Birthday to you. What's going on?
And I thank you for the well wishes
of happy birthday from all the other
countries around the world that
realized we are the best. Huh?
You think you've got fat people?
Huh? Take a look at that.
Beat that mother fuckers.
What else you think he can
Peterson? Huh? What do you want?
What do you want to have it? What do you,
what kind of fucking battle you want?
Oh, you can see around the
world you stole our jeans,
all those cool American chains.
You guys would defect from your country
just to get over here to get a pair of
button. Fly fucking five oh
one blues. Remember that Shit.
All of a sudden, you know,
couple of fucking wars and everybody
forgets how much you loved your jeans.
That's, you know, that's just
typical. That is just fucking typical,
you know, fucking England
coming over here, stealing it.
Re fucking cycling our fucking music,
walking around like
they're doing something,
redoing the fucking music from the
people that we didn't accept. Fuck.
Are you guys doing? Um, anyways,
um, I'm having a great three day
fucking weekend. I'm not doing shit.
I am, uh,
I'm back in the workout mode so the
needle is pointed in the right direction.
Oh, freckles is going, Dad, Dad,
dad fucking looked in
the mirror last night.
I could tell I was starting to
lose weight. Made me feel good.
You know what I mean? That's a fucking
tough thing. Being a red head, you know,
use a really small window that you
have to exist in or else the beating.
Start again. And it's really
something you can understand. Um,
all right, I'm all over the fucking
place. I got a bunch of Shit I have to do.
I'm having some family over
today for a fucking cookout.
I'm going easy this year, rather than
trying to smoke something and blah, blah,
Blah and do all that shit. I'm
fucking go on Burgers and dogs.
Perkinson talks the way it used to be
before the fucking food network showed up
and everybody's gotta be
like a top chef. You know?
Remember when you were growing
up? That's what it was.
It was burgers and dogs and everybody
was fucking happy right till the boost
started coming around then yeah, then
I got a little sideways, but hey man,
it happens. So, uh, yesterday, um,
had some friends over and we
had some cigars, right? And uh,
you know the deal, it's like,
all right, your buddies are over.
Your wife's going to be like,
how are they going to bear? Um,
even if they're cool, like my wife's cool,
but there's always going to be an
element of how are you going to bed?
They're going to be loud. They're
going to be upstairs and as, hey,
it's like, yeah, I'm having
people over. Do I do that?
When you have a little twice, do I?
You have them over for the fucking wines
and you're all sitting there laughing
with your high pitch fucking voices.
You don't think that that's putting
cracks in the walls? I don't,
I don't fucking bitch about it. I go
down to the old fucking hardware store.
I get out to spackle right
then with every little cackle. Right.
Another fucking line in the wall.
You don't hear me complaining
and got my putty knife out. Oh,
you have a good time, ladies. Right. Um,
anyways, uh, so we have,
we were a hanging out with
actually fucking hilarious
because I'd gone out and I
bought, you know, got some
Cuban cigars. I want to fuck it.
I cleaned everything up. Right. The
thing that, what you want to do,
this is what I've realized when
you're living with a woman,
which you want to do, is you
just go all out. Right? You fuck,
I cleaned the fucking place
up. Okay. I even like,
like the deck on the back,
like I fucking host it off so they
wouldn't be traipse and dirt in and out of
the house or whatever. Right. And
she's sitting there going like, wow,
you're really going all out. Yeah.
There's a reason Sam Kittleson.
There's a fucking reason.
There's a fucking reason why.
Because what you want to do is what you're
doing is you just put yourself into a
position where you did
absolutely nothing wrong.
So when they complain, cause
they're still gonna complain,
you got all of this fucking Ammo, right?
I cleaned this whole fucking place up,
right? Cleaned out the back porch down
the backyard, the whole fucking thing,
cleaned it up. And we're
having family over here today,
which was another great one to be like,
well I'm also doing it for your family,
right? So, um,
I'm doing all of this shit. I got,
I got the booze, I got
the fucking thought,
the outdoor patio furniture,
get everything all cleaned up.
I got an ashtray upstairs.
I got one downstairs,
I got the backyard lights on, I got the
whole fucking thing, I got the music,
I got the whole thing.
And then at like six o'clock at
night I realized I didn't get cigars.
I bought cigars, but I
don't have a humidor.
And I said I was going to pick them up.
And I had this fucking panic
attack because it was Sunday
before the fourth that
they were going to close.
And it was six excruciating
rings before they picked up.
And I was able to run down there
and get them right. And um,
they showed up, I ordered some
pizzas and all that fucking shit.
And here's the best part,
right here is the best part.
I, my wife went to sleep, right?
We smoking with tell him
fucking stories. You know,
I got all these orange
sodas for myself, right?
And I turns out everybody there wanted
one because it had the real sugar and it
went great with the
cigar. I'm telling you,
Cuban Cigar and the Phanta
orange soda is the Shit, right?
They drank all my orange soda.
So I had to drink grape soda like a
fucking six fucking year old, right? So,
um, anyways, the end
of the night, it only,
I fucking cleaned up everything. You
wouldn't, you wouldn't even fucking know.
You wouldn't know a god
thing. You wouldn't know
that a fucking soul was here.
And that's what you do. All these fucking
married guys who sit there, you know,
is that back and worth it. It
is fucking worth it. You just,
you just have to do it
perfectly, right? You go all out,
you clean up the fucking
place, they come over,
you have a great fucking
time. When you leave,
you fucking cleaned the whole
place up again. What can she say?
What is she going to say to you?
You're not allowed to have friends.
Um, little things like that,
cause I've had buddies in my coming
over here like on dude, you fucking,
what are you doing? You did all that
and you fucking wash the dishes. It's,
there's a, there's a genius behind
what I do. I'm talking shit here.
I'm drinking throat coat
tea and I'm talking shit.
What can they fucking say then go to
this is if you do everything perfectly,
then they're leaving
themselves totally exposed.
If they start complaining
that they're all there,
basically can complain about at that
point is that you have friends and you
invited them over to the house. All right?
And they know they don't have
a fucking leg to stand on.
So the bitch and goes
down by like 90%. Now,
if you have your fucking friends over and
you leave the fucking ash tray out and
there's footprints all
over the fucking place,
they can make it about that
when the real thing is,
is they don't want you
to have fronts, right?
But they can hide behind the other shit.
But then the real thing is they don't
want you to have friends and they want to
slowly kill you so that they can, you
know, have the house to themselves.
And if you, you know,
go to the obituaries,
there's a bunch of guys dropping
around 58, 59 60. And that,
that's what happened.
What really happened was they had
friends over and they didn't clean up,
you know, which gave their wives the
window to bitch them into an early grave.
And now they're sitting there in the
fucking house having a hell of a time,
right? Getting to play the victim,
getting all the sympathy cards
and eating all the poundcake.
And that's a fact, you know, come in with
the truth here in 4th of July. Hannah,
if the fuck I'm talking about,
um, anyways, so afterwards, right?
So we're drinking sodas.
I'm stone sober, right. And,
uh, everybody leaves except for
one of my other buddies. And, um,
he wasn't an AA. Right? The older you
get, the more your friends just fucking,
they quit. You know what I
mean? They just fucking quit.
It's like being a lifer in the military.
Everybody doesn't sign back up.
All of a sudden you're
the old guy, you know,
fucking walking around. Where'd I
fucked all my friends go. Right.
Walking around, all sad
with the fucking smoking
bear hat. I didn't hear you. Uh,
so he still drinks so they leave. So
I get out the giant fucking ice cubes,
a poor couple of Johnny blue.
I would fuck it. Boom. Right.
And uh, you know, he has to drive. So
He's, he's doing a little sippy cup shit.
And I live here, so I'm doing the
home port, right. Thousand 1000,
2000, three, six, right.
One of those pores.
So I have a couple, two or three of
those. I'm feeling good and uh, you know,
but I'm not, I cleaned the whole fuck
up too. When I say I cleaned the whole,
the all the leftover pizza, I wrapped
each slice individually in foil.
And then I put a letter
on it, p for Pepperoni,
s facade passage m for fucking
Margaret took the pizza boxes out,
put them in the recycle Bin,
took out the fucking chemicals,
fucking spray down the counters.
You wouldn't fucking do that.
God Damn forensic team of forensic cops
with their fucking dusters would come in
, would have no fucking idea
anything happened. Right?
So now I'm feeling all proud of myself.
I've got my little fucking sippy drink
there and I put it on the TV cause I'm
not ready to go to bed yet. And what
do I see? Time, life books or whatever.
Time life records presents. Easy
listening. Love songs. Right?
And I'm sitting there watching
it, right? I'm not in love.
Don't fuck it as big a pitch.
Put Your picture on the wall cause
it's the stay there. Right. I'm like,
I remember that fucking song and okay,
forget this one angle bird hopper dig
please big go
GTA. But listen to the lyrics of
that song. It's like for Fuck Sake,
just break up with her. He literally
says something like, I've talking about,
I found a new love. Her lips
are warm and yours is so cold.
It's like angle park. Just
enough with the fucking details.
Just break up what you're just say,
look, I'm not in love with you anymore.
You know, going to bring up the
other fucking broad down the street.
Just got your heart racing. You
fucking cunt. It's such a country song.
But you know, I heard
it when I was younger,
so I'm listening to all
of these fucking songs.
God doesn't make little green apples
and fucking something something bad.
And next thing you know,
I'm on the phone calling one
800 gimme those fucking cds.
So the guy picks up the phone, he goes,
Hey, this is rob from time live records.
Who Am I speaking to? The cds? I'm
like, you're speaking of Bell, rob.
Are you doing buddy up? Do
a great, uh, walk. What? Uh,
what can I do? You've four.
I'm like, well, you know,
I'm watching ankle per cup predict
given this broad too much information.
But uh, you know, I like the sound
of it. I want to order the CDS.
And he goes, great. Yeah, great. Can
I get a phone number? I'm like, no,
you can't not giving you
my phone number. He goes,
well then I can't complete
this order. Just like that.
Like I was the 90th
person in a row that said,
I'm not giving you my phone number. Right.
And he was tired of hearing it just when
he gave me the old right there for it.
Well though I can't do the order. Is
there anything else I can help you with?
And I'm like, Whoa, wait
rob. Well let's go on.
And we just went from zero to 200 here.
Why do I have to give you my phone
number? And he's like, oh, um,
you have to get phone numbers so we
can complete the order. It's like,
I understand you're saying that, but
I'm asking you why. And he goes, oh,
it's just cause it's company policy.
And I'm like, why is it company policy?
If he goes, because I need the phone
number in order to complete the order,
I go, okay, see what we just did
there? We just drove in a circle. Okay,
I'm trying to get out of this centrifical
fucking force here and get over to the
reason the fucking racing. Right.
Okay.
And he finally just goes, well, you know,
the reason is that if there's a problem
with your order, we need to call you.
And it's just like, well, if
there's a problem with the order,
meaning you're charging my card in the
cds, don't ever come. You don't think,
I'm not going to call you. You get
literally had, when I called up,
if there's a problem with
your order, press two.
So I just, we just keep
going round around. I go,
you just want the phone number
and I go, not you personally,
but time-life does so they can sell it
to other people. Next thing you know,
I'm walking my dog at some Qantas
calling me up going, congratulations,
you're the lucky business
winner of whatever, right?
So it fucking escalates to a really
hostile, you have a good night, sir.
I'm like, you, I have a good
night to rob. Right. Hang Up.
And I'm sitting there for a second. Right?
During the whisper yelling
fucking cocksuckers they
can fucking stupid enough to
give you my phone number. Right. All by
myself. Like, like a complete lunatic,
you know?
Okay.
And then the background, the fucking
commercial still on Muskrat. The,
that fucking cock sucking
motherfuckers. Right.
Just fucking send me the fucking
shit. I bought this before.
I never had to give you my phone.
Number three is he played with
the 29 a lot of five. Right?
You're getting my fucking money.
Okay.
You gonna call me up pages.
This is rob from time life.
Just call them the check to
see if he got those cds. Right.
So anyways, um, I really
want these fucking cds.
So I called back again and for some reason
I decided to just go into a southern
accent and I was like, when they
asked me for their phone number,
I'm just for my phone number, I'm just
going to give them their phone number,
see if they, they notice like, can
I get your phone numbers? Sure.
What 800. Right. And I was
going to do that shit. But uh,
what happened was by the time
the lady picked up there,
it was the end of the infomercial, it
went on to something else. You know,
something that me,
them makes you skinny or fucking
helps clean up FDA goddamn kids.
I forget what it was. Right? So she,
she answers the phone. She's like, Hey,
this is sound, blah blah blah blah
blah from fucking time. And I'm like,
I ain't doing, I like to
order them a hazy listening,
a Sadie's five easy payments,
29, 905. She's like, okay,
can I get a name? Who Am I speaking
to? Unlock bill, Bill [inaudible],
right. Just totally does not sound
like a southern name. Whatever.
Southern Billy Joe, Bill
Burr. Um, and uh, she goes,
can I get a phone number?
I just decided I was just going to
give her area coats. I was like,
my phone number is eight one eight
three two three two, one, two,
five. And she goes, okay,
that number is eight one eight three
two, three, two, one, two, five.
I'm like, yes it is. Yes ma'am.
Just like I got my tapes,
they're going to fucking show up,
right. My cds, no fucking problem.
I gave him a fake email, like I said,
too damn tall@aol.com and
you know what that means?
Can I get an email arts? It's a two.
The number two number
two and d a m n tall.
Like I didn't say damn like
I was trying to be polite.
So then she had to read it back.
So that email is number two d a m
n tall@aol.com like that's right.
Yes it is.
And I got him calming five fucking CDs,
five CDs for 30 bucks. Three payments.
I Dunno what the fuck it was.
That's gonna be a lot of
cds. You know what's funny?
My Prius still has a CD holder.
When my new car gets here, it won't.
And then what the fuck do I
do? Well, I know when I do,
I sell them for one easy payment
of nine 95 on Ebay, you know,
and no phone numbers required.
Just give me a fucking address
and I'll send it to you.
What do you think about that?
Um, all right, come on up.
He'll type in your fucking
password out. Jesus Christ.
So rumor has it that Kevin Durant is
going to go to the fucking Golden State
Warriors.
Yeah.
And as a sports fan, I cannot think
of a more boring fucking move,
you know what I mean?
And I fucking hate how ESPN
and all these sports places,
they just don't call them out on it.
Like how bad that is for sports fans.
I wanted to see if Oklahoma City, now,
he hasn't done it yet, but you know,
sources say rumors and all that shit. I
wanted to see if you know, what the fuck
can Oklahoma City get by
golden state next year?
Could golden state redeem themselves and
win a fucking championship? You know,
it was such a great
series, exciting series.
Oklahoma had them beat,
they had their foot on their neck and
then the fucking golden state comes
roaring back. This is like, this is
great. I want to see this again next year.
Like when the 76 is tried
to get past the Celtics.
Dr J didn't just sign with the Celtics.
Okay.
Granted they got Moses Malone. I
guess it's been going on for awhile.
I just don't fucking get it. Still fucking
get it. It's like, all right, these,
this is a great rivalry.
They're evenly matched.
It went seven games. Hey,
let's take the best player or one of the
best players depending on if you like
Westbrook prayer and we'll just stick
them on the other fucking team and now
that rivalry is null and void.
Now it goes from wow seven game,
great series to fucking, you know,
four or five game
series. Who gives a shit?
I don't fucking get it. It's fucking
Jerry West going, you know, if he,
if you sign here, you're, you're
rebounding is going to be modus more.
Your blurb of bloods can be a
charity. You don't give a fuck.
You don't give a fucking for if all the
best players in the league or all on one
fucking team. And it's the worst
fucking thing ever. You know,
this is coming from a Celtic fan and
I watched us do that with that. Kevin,
Kevin de renting, Kevin Durant, Kevin
Garnett team. You know, like they,
we just bought that.
We went from literally last place to
winning the championship in one fucking
year. And I realized that
there's a skill to it,
but as a crabby old
fucking curmudgeon, um,
I just don't, I just, what is
exciting about that if he goes,
if he signs with the Golden State
Warriors, well that's great.
Why don't you have Lebron jump on that
one to remember those great Miami Heat
teams. Remember how exciting
that was? If you lived in Miami,
everybody else, it was
a fucking snooze fest.
They'll sit on a fucking yacht. Hey,
y'all want to be on the same team?
We'll win three in a row and we'll,
we'll be like, we'll be a dynasty.
Like the fucking, the bulls will be like
them. Yeah. Except they didn't pile on.
Oh, I'm in a mode. I hope that
moves doesn't happen. You know,
it's going to happen. I just, Ah, you
know, whatever, it's his fucking career.
But just saying as a sports fan,
as a guy who fucking watch his sports but
doesn't really pick up on anything and
then runs his fucking mouth on a podcast,
I am not in favor of that
fucking move. That would suck.
You know? Yeah. I just wonder,
well, what are you gonna do?
Well, that's what they, that's what
these kids do nowadays. Oh Man.
Actually it's been going on for
30 fucking years. Biggest, um,
I guess free agent signing or trade or
whatever of my life of my life was a
Wayne Gretzky. Go into the kinks.
If ever there wasn't an unmovable guy,
like there's no fucking way this franchise
is ever getting rid of this player
unless we just completely, I don't know,
went out of business folded
and had to move or if our, uh,
I don't know.
Our owners son fucking financed
the Michael Jackson victory tour,
you know, so now daddy has to sign,
sell the fucking team because
Michael Jackson stage was so big at,
ate up all these fucking seats that they
were losing money every night and then
racist Massachusetts said that they
couldn't do the show out in Foxborough,
you know,
cause they didn't want a bunch of black
people coming out to Foxborough Masco
and for fucking three hours, evidently
that was going to be a problem.
I could see them making
the fucking move. Right.
Do you know that that
promoted told me that.
That's how I always used to
think that when Billy Sullivan,
the original owner of the
Patriots, his son Patrick,
somehow was the promoter for the Michael
Jackson victory tour. And I remember,
um, at the last second, you know, it
was supposed to be at Sullivan Stadium,
which is what's a Patriot's
old stadium. And um,
at the last second FoxPro
was just like, yeah, no,
you're not having that concert out here.
And it was just because it was going to
be a bunch of black people out there.
Right. And, uh, but Michael Jackson
had in his contract that, you know,
once you sign it, whether the show
happens or not, you gotta pay me.
And I used to think that that
one show fucked him over.
But this promoter in Boston told me, no,
he had this giant ass fucking stage and
the Sullivan's didn't take into account.
This is all alleged legend here of the
amount of seats that that was gonna take
up in the arena, you know? And uh,
and they didn't realize that
when they were making the deal,
they were calculating a certain number
of seats versus what they would play in
the Jacksons and it all worked out.
And then when they saw the behemoth
of a fucking stage, they will let go,
my God. So they go to Michael, they're
like, Michael, he was like, yes.
They were like, can you make
your stage a little smaller?
We're going to lose our shirts here.
And Michael Jackson was like, no, I,
if I have it, smaller prints is going to
outdo me. Like he had, like, you know,
that rivalry with him going on. I
don't know if that's fucking true.
Somebody told me this story and then I
just repeated it as fact. I mean this,
this is what I do on the podcast. Um,
I'm just running my yap
here. Uh, did anybody watch,
did you watch the Austrian Grand Prix?
If that didn't make you a
fucking formula one racing fan?
Holy Shit. That was like
fucking days of fun.
I actually tweeted that
yesterday, dude. It's like, okay,
this is the deal. The German
team, the Mercedes Benz, right?
They got Nico Rosberg and
Louis Hamilton. All right.
Nico Rosberg is a German, right?
Lewis Hamilton is a, he's
from England, right. And uh,
evidently from the isle of Man,
from what people were texting
tweeting me the other day. So
Nico is ahead. He's, he's beaten
everybody in the points in the standings.
And Louis is like the fucking upstart
guy, I guess. I don't know. Right.
He wears the big fucking diamond chain,
you know what I mean? He's from east,
from England. I don't know what his is,
his racist. I don't know if he's mixed.
I don't know what his deal is.
And he's got the bling
going on and all this shit.
So all the old fucking um,
traditional fans of the
sport, traditional wink, wink.
I like the Old School Formula
One, wink, wink. Right. You know,
at that fucking means they don't like
this guy ever tell me they don't like his
bling. They don't like his,
uh, you know, his whole basic,
I dunno, I don't want to fucking
throw the ugliness in there,
but it seems like there's a little
issue there, right? So anyways,
earlier this year, I guess in the Spanish
Grand Prix, I didn't see that one.
They both fucking, they banged into each
other and was coming around the corner.
He's pushing buttons on that
playstation steering wheel,
whatever the fuck that thing is. You
just, you just have a fucking stairwell.
Then it was a steering
wheel with the paddles.
Now it looks like a little game boy,
and they're pushing shit
to fucking conserve energy.
And I don't know what the fuck it is,
but they some out do this going like 180
miles an hour, which is amazing to me.
120 miles an hour and a fucking turn,
as if did dealing with the g forces
of slowing down and taking a turn.
Well over a hundred miles an hour,
they're sitting there on fucking
pushing buttons, you know,
like texting while driving
fucking doing this shit.
So earlier in the year
they had one, uh, you know,
Hamilton tried to pass him on the
inside and then Nico was defending his
position or whatever the
fuck he said. He came over,
he put Lewis on the fucking,
uh, grass. He spun out,
he clipped it back in Nico's car,
they slammed into each other and uh,
they both got the old deal right
there for at the DNC, right.
Did not complete the race, which caused
Mercedes a bunch of fucking points.
So evidently they probably sat him
down and was like, Hey, fuck heads,
you're on the same team here. What?
Say you don't knock each other
out of the race. So whatever.
They got this whole rivalry going and it
seems like Nico thinks he's the fucking
guy and Louis is just like,
well I don't, I, you know,
I respect that you're the guy,
but I'm trying to be the
guy to so go fuck yourself.
So yesterday they're
fucking racing and uh,
I, you know, I don't know
much about this sport,
but evidently there's soft tires and
if the soft tires aren't soft enough,
they got super soft tires.
And I guess the softer your tires are
depending on the weather condition,
the faster your car goes.
So whatever fucking reason they give
Nico the super soft ones and they give
Lewis just to soft once, so
they're fucking them over
with each lap. All right.
So Nico's obviously the golden child that
the corporate guys like and Louis just
the fucking upstart, right?
He's the Tom Cruise. Okay.
The other guys to fucking
establish con who's winning. Right.
I'm just guessing all of
this shit. So, um, I dunno,
there's something about the pitstop
Louis' was slower than Nico's.
They gave all the fucking advantage to
Nico Cause Nikos went in in the points.
I think that they want him to win the
fucking race cause they want to win the
championship and Louis
wasn't fucking having it.
So he's driving like a fucking maniac
on soft tires when Nico's got the super
soft and next thing you know
he's right on his fucking ass.
It's the last lap of the fucking race
and Louis goes to pass him on the
outside of the turn taking the long way
around. He's on his fucking
ties around the white line.
He can't get over any farther
if he's going to pass.
If you see he's going to
overtake them on the final lap,
the fucking announces are going nuts and
fucking Nico just drove right into him.
You said he had a breaking
problem. It's like, Oh yeah,
did you have a stair in problem two?
You fucking drove right into
him and it's like, oh my God,
they're going to knock each other out of
the race again. And they get out of it.
And then they came back
together in the end. Fucking,
I think the back of Hamilton's car clipped
the front of a Rosberg's and took his
little finfin things off the
front. So now we can't drive fast.
And when your car's damaged like that and
you blow in debris all over the track,
I didn't realize this. Evidently
you're supposed to pull over,
supposed to hit the old rest
area. Just be like, well,
I guess we're going to call it a day
because all that shit that you're putting
in the track and blow out somebody's
tire caused them to crash.
They could get injured and they're
not going to fucking finish.
And it's not their fault that you
fucking drove into your teammate.
But this car keeps driving his car,
shrapnel all over the
track. And he finished,
he got panelized long story short was
Lewis Hamilton and end up winning the
fucking race. And uh, they
were cutting to the, uh,
whatever the owners of the Mercedes
team and they're all fucking pissed.
And, uh, one of the guys on the Mercedes
teams is the guy that, you know,
went for that movie rush. I should
really have the guy's name here.
I'm new to this sport, so forgive
me for not knowing his name.
The Guy who had that horrific crash on
the Ferrari team in 1976 and he had the
fire, they showed it in a, that movie.
Russia was absolutely terrifying. I mean,
what's more terrifying? They'd
being alive on fire, you know
me. See,
what would you rather be alive on fire
or in the ocean watching a great white
shark approaching, you know,
no one is gonna fucking
take your leg off. I mean,
I actually think you got
to go with the shark.
Just fucking bite my leg off.
There's a major artery right there.
I'm going to fucking be like, ha.
And then the dopamine is going to come
out and I'm gonna have that goofy smile
on my face is the hammer head
comes in to finish me off. Right.
Okay.
So anyways, they would to him afterwards,
Nico said that he had a and problem.
I don't know. I don't fucking know.
So now there's all these conspiracy
theorists out there going like, well,
you know, it's the German team.
Nico's a German. All right,
fucking Hamilton's a,
you know,
from England and he doesn't look like
your fucking English guy being made and
he's not a white dude. Maybe there's
some racism going on there. I don't know.
But I just became a Ha Lewis Hamilton
fan. I still like Rosberg, you know,
he's racing, he's out there, you
know, can't fucking handle it.
He's one of those,
he seems like one of those guys you
have to go out and you play like pickup
hooper, pickup hockey,
and it's just some fucking nice guy and
all of a sudden the game starts and they
get that fucking look in their face.
Like they'll blow out a
knee just to score a goal.
You know those loaded lunatics.
Yeah.
You just sit in there
going like, all right,
I'm going to fucking steer clear slash
try to annoy the shit out of this person.
Okay.
I'm gonna try and make sure this guy
doesn't fall on my fucking leg. You know,
I had a buddy of mine, right fucking
nicest guy ever. He's a psychiatrist.
He works with troubled inner city youth
who just gone through all kinds of
fucking horrific shit. He has the
patience to sit there, you know,
and work with these kids that are acting
out because of all this horrible stuff
that that's,
that's happened to them in their home
life and he sits there and he handles it
and he loves it. You fucking
get that guy out on the ice.
He's a fucking lunatic.
One time I took the,
we mean the other guy,
we fucking taking the puck away from him
and I heard his breathing change and he
just fucking brought his
stick up and I'm telling you,
this is why I the full
birdcage, right dude,
45 degree angle across my
whole face. It just Bam.
It hit my fucking cage and I looked at
it, I was just like, dude, what the fuck?
For whatever dumb reason,
I was one of those people,
you know that comes out plays
pickup hockey only wearing a visor.
Those guys are lunatics,
especially when they,
because there's always the person
out there that can't skate,
which is usually me. And you
start doing that run in place.
I'm going to fall forward, I'm going to
fall back, I'm going to fall forward.
And you got like this stick in your hand
that's coming up and taking somebody
teeth out. So I'm, oh my God, what a Luna.
I literally would have needed like
fucking plastic surgery. I was kidding.
Who the fucking face like
mine. You just ride it out. Oh,
there's this name right there. I got
it right here. I'm sorry. Ah, Nikki.
I'm going to say it wrong. Lau,
D A, I don't want to say Lotta,
I swear to God. So he was,
they talked to him and I'm looking at
this guy looking like the old racing guy,
like one of his ears. It's like, you
know, mostly burned off and shit.
He's got the scars on the side of
his face. I gotta be honest with you.
He looked pretty fucking
Badass. You know what I mean?
And another guy named, I swear to God,
Toto Wolf Todo like the band
I want up that's on the cds.
A level I want to do, man awake
at be in the morning is the,
um, all right, let's do a
couple of reads here. Oh Jesus.
I was 32 fucking minutes of just
running my Yap or simple faith.
We have somebody new here.
Everybody's simple faith.
Thousands of people seeking home security
get ripped off every day at the home
security industry. And,
and the home security industry wants
you to believe it's your only option.
They got hoards of salesmen out there
trying to scare you into signing one of
their longterm contracts.
You get stuck writing huge checks
month after month with capital letters.
No way out,
okay?
It's robbery by contract and
it can cost you thousands,
but there's a better way to
protect your home. Simple faith,
home security. Wait, what the
fuck are they talking about?
These contracts at home security is you
didn't want you to believe it's your
only option. What are they?
Do they sign you a contract to do
what? Simple. Safe has no contracts.
None. You'll get award winning 24, seven
protection named best in the industry.
Oh, I see.
Security professionals watching ready
to instantly send the police and it's
just,
they're not going to
go in and do something.
Jesus fucking Christ. I could do that.
There's gotta be another way. Oh,
and I know they sit in the van. All
right. My fault. Sorry. Simple faith. Um,
I just simple, safe. I thought they
were to tell you to have a home safe.
It's just 1499 per month.
That's less than half of what most
companies charge. Protect your home.
The smart way. Visit simple, safe. Uh,
just a simple slave. Safe birth.
I'm assuming that slash Burr,
I don't know. It says simple
safe. Burb B U R r.com.
Today for an exclusive 10% offer,
it's gotta be slash bar has to be and get
a free key chain remote worth 25 bucks
only when you go to simple safe
bird.com. That simple. Safe bird.com.
I hope that's right. I don't know.
That might be one and done. All right.
Blue Apron, everybody. Oh, blue apron.
Blue Apron. Knows that when you
cook with incredible ingredients,
you make incredible meals.
So they set the highest quality
standards for their community of artists.
[inaudible] supplies, uh,
suppliers, family run farms,
fisheries and ranches, whether
it's Japanese ramen noodles,
wild caught Alaskan salmon
or heirloom tomatoes.
Blue Apron is bringing you the best. None
of that shit existed when I was a kid.
It's all because of the food network.
Like the level of options you now have
as a person to eat. You know what I mean?
It was fucking chipped beef on toast,
chicken noodle soup, tuna casserole.
Alright, cube steaks, these fucking
kids today, this is what they can eat.
These are kids in their struggling. They
can actually have so great blue aprons.
You go from that horse shit
to Japanese ramen noodles.
Wild caught Alaskan
Salmon, heirloom tomatoes.
There was one fucking tomato when I was
a kid for less than 10 bucks per meal.
Blue Apron delivers seasonal recipes along
with pre-portioned agreements to make
delicious home cooked meals. Um,
variety new recipes are created
each week by blue aprons,
culinary team and are not
repeated within a year.
Customize your recipes each
week based on your preferences.
Choose delivery options to fit your
needs. There's no weekly commitment,
so you only get deliveries
when you want them.
So if you gotta lay in your life,
you can cook her some meals.
If she fucking leaves you, you can
go right back to fucking Eaton.
What the fuck did we use to have
steak ups? Oh, I'd love to stay calm.
I swear to God the last nine
periods of my school day,
I would be sitting there thinking about
the steak and I was going to make when I
got home, right? Fry it up in the Pan,
like one of those whores with the
high heels and the lipstick, right?
And then you'd put it on the white
bread and watch the grease turning gray,
little bit of ketchup and some cheese.
Fucking phenomenal. But anyways,
back to blue apron. Each
meal comes with step by step,
easy to follow recipe cards
and pre-portioned ingredients
and can be prepared in
40 minutes or less.
Check out this week's menu and get your
two meals for free with free shipping by
blue apron.com by going
to blue apron.com/bar you
will love how good it feels
and tastes to create incredible
home cooked meals with blue apron.
So don't wait. That's blue
apron.com/burger blue apron.
A better way to cook.
What do we got left here?
We got two more left. Let's
break it up. Okay, let's,
let's give you a break from my reading
out loud or my attempt at reading.
Uh, we'll go back to the fucking
podcast here. Uh, where did I go?
Where did I go? Where the
fuck is the other shit up?
Did dddd um, all right. So should we
get into the reeds here for this week?
Why don't we, all right.
Governor Gary Jackson.
Gary Johnson, sorry. Governor
Gary Johnson. Hey Billy Shatner.
Billy fucking shit. I'm not a libertarian.
I never said you were, I'd never
been affiliated with any party.
I voted both parties in
four elections. I voted in.
I've been eligible for six.
You sound like a blogger when you're
going to criticize a comedian going like,
I have a great sense of humor.
You know I find this funny, I've,
I love this and Blah Blah Blah. But
what I saw last night in a comedy club,
all right, so this guy has established
himself that he's open minded. All right,
because he says,
so I'm not into the fringe candidates
and I don't buy into conspiracies.
I guess what I'm saying is I'm
not the typical Gary Johnson Fan.
Now what? Because you say so. I
guess what I'm saying is, well,
why don't you figure out what the fuck
you say and so you don't have to write
extra words in a sentence. Giving me more
opportunity to trip myself up please.
All right. However,
I am a fan of his and I think he
could actually win if he got on the,
on the debates. He's basically Bernie
who I supported for the most part.
They just don't, I'm not a libertarian.
Well he was a Democrat, right, man.
Well he was and then he became a
libertarian, then became a democrat.
Does that not work? I don't
know. I love Bernie Sanders.
Whoa. Oh No.
Loved them. They align on 80%
of the issues. His running mate,
his former Massachusetts
Governor, Bill Weld,
Bill weld still in the game like
fucking Gordie Howe rested piece.
A wondering what your thoughts on Gary
Johnson and also bill weld having lived
in the state, uh,
when he was in office below was a short
campaign video of the two of them.
Well, I, well, what the
fuck? I don't, I don't know.
I thought you were going
to tell me about him.
I guess I was supposed
to watch this before.
Okay.
You Dude, you just gave
me homework. All right,
let's put this fucking thing in here
and we're going to try and watch it.
No Shit. I'm running for Paris in it.
I'm [inaudible] running for
president. I'm running wisdom.
Jazzy music. As the
governor of New Mexico,
I vetoed wasteful spending 750 times,
cut taxes 14 times and left the states.
Why is he so breathy? Richard's schools,
hospitals and $1 billion
surplus without raising taxes.
I panic as governor of Massachusetts.
How would I know that you just
said that you did it. Now how do I,
I can't fact check all of that.
I Dunno. I mean, it's exciting.
We're going to move the country
forward. Music. [inaudible] hi.
Hi. I'm Jerry Johnson. Um,
I'm sure he's a great guy.
I'll look into it. I mean,
I like that you're giving me other options
because there's no fucking way I can
vote for Trump or for
Hillary, you know? Uh,
we all know the old bag's going to win it.
She's going to show up with lipstick
on her teeth and that fucking maniacal.
Why'd I fucking smile? She does.
Okay.
Oh, she's going to carve this country
up even more. They are fucking evil.
I swear to God.
Okay.
If Trump wasn't such a fucking dope,
if he wasn't such a dope, I actually
think he would be the lesser of two evils.
But I, I have to be honest with you.
There's no way to listen to Donald Trump
and not think about Martin Sheen in the
dead zone.
Okay? Can
Somebody please Photoshop Trump holding
up the baby? You know, when fucking,
what's his face? Um,
oh Jesus Christ one Watkins up in the
balcony there or the dead fucking the
parades are away, gentlemen.
Um, I have no idea, sir. I,
I commend you for, uh,
being smart enough to not vote for
Trump or for Hillary. It's a a,
it's a really low point and
I wasn't a big Obama Fan,
but at least Obama, at least, you know,
the guy could speak intelligently,
you know,
after fucking eight years of George
Bush or Shasha when that guy was,
that guy was like the presidential
version of me reading out loud.
All right. I just, Oh God.
There has to be so many other fucking
women out there that would meet,
make such great, honest
precedents. We really have.
Why does it have to be the one
with 52 pending felony counts?
All those Clintons are
filthy. Oh, Hillary Clinton.
She's dirtier than her husband's
Dick. Ah, right. Here we go.
Facial hair and low lady.
Hi, what's going on? I
forgot to do two weeks.
I'm actually in my garage right
now. Echo. All right. Score
score. Mickey. I know Dan. Really
amazing in here. Right score bit.
You're paying too much for tickets
between all the mockups and last minute
convenience charges, even print at home
seats. What are you fucking kidding me?
Do you end up paying courtside
prices for nosebleeds?
Seats score big is here to change that.
Did you know that 40% of all live event
tickets go unsold and did you know that
there's a place to get
these seats at huge savings?
It's called score big scored big works
directly with your favorite teams and add
it to get their unsold
seats at unpublished prices
only with score big can you
name a ticket price and be guaranteed
to pay below? Box Up is up to 60% off.
Here's what you do. One,
go to score big.com and download the new
score big app on your iPhone and find
the event in seats.
You want to make an offer which score a
big name a ticket price feature. Three,
you get an instant answer and save up
to 60% on your tickets, never any fees,
and shipping is always free.
You can count on unbeatable prices and
great seats when you're in and when
you're in. Great seats. You actually
enjoy the game or the show. All the more.
Next time you see any game or show,
go to score big first and see how much
you could save for the easiest way to
save on tickets. Download the
school. Big app on your iPhone.
You already told us this shit and a Promo
Code Burger at the checkout and you'll
save an extra 20 bucks off your
first ticket purchase. No, no iPhone,
no problem.
Get $20 off online@scorebig.com that's
[inaudible] dot com promo code burst.
scorebig.com Promo Code. Okay.
Okay. All looks the way it is,
but up do beyond the meander [inaudible]
where I'm in a fucking garage.
[inaudible] get a small Maddow
[inaudible] tight up on your ball.
[inaudible] oh, they coming? Cool
colors. Your lady, he'll like them.
Maybe she'll swap your day. Oh yeah.
And do what on the 4th of July. Oh,
[inaudible] whether you're
wearing a suit or sweats,
you spend almost 24 hours a day in
your underwear unless you're a fucking
animal.
But instead of making a statement like
Superman's tight under his everyday
clothes, your underwear
is probably boring.
The under youth is here to change that.
Please include all the phone, mobile,
motel.
Every pair of neon is made
from a sustainable source
of modal of fabric that's
twice as soft as taught. Nothing can
describe the fit and feel of me on these,
but once you try them on,
you understand why they are called the
world's most comfortable underwear.
I go where and if you don't
love the first pair of youngies,
they're free. No questions. Ask me. I,
he says dozens of styles and
limited edition prints to
help you make a statement
with your underwear. What did anyone
can see them or not? Remember Superman.
All right.
Shipping is free in the U S and Canada
and you can save up to $8 a pair with the
Mandy's subscription plan. Get
the subscription or a single pair.
Get 20% off your first order.
When you go to [inaudible] dot com slash
bar that's [inaudible] these.com/burger
for 20% off [inaudible]
dot com slash [inaudible]
a deer, big belly fat belly. Um,
I'm a 17 year old guy who will be
starting college in the fall in the great
state of Massachusetts. Um,
Jesus starting at seven,
you must be turning 18 later on in the
year. Um, I'm always jealous of that.
I started, I started
college when I was 19.
I was already 19 then I fucked up my
first four years and I was like a 23 year
old sophomore. Um,
my high school's a dress code allows
guys to grow facial hair in the last
semester of senior year. What, what,
what fucking school are you going
to? So a few months ago I said,
what the hell? I'll give it
a try. But you're only 17.
The last semester of your senior year,
you're giving yourself a hell of a
lot of time to grow. This shit said,
I ended up growing up growing a nice dark
full beard that seems to suit me well.
I got a lot of compliments for
it. Mostly from other guys,
but some from the ladies.
I remain single as I have
always been during this time.
I still have the beard now,
but I don't know whether I should keep
the beard or ditch it and arrive at
college. Clean Shaven.
Do you think it's a good or bad idea to
make my first impression while sporting
a beer? In terms of the ladies,
is the beard a sign of manliness
and strength or more of a turnoff?
I don't fucking, I got to ask Nia.
Hang on a second. Jesus Christ.
How the one out of fuck
would I know? Well, you know,
I always thought Dan
Fouts with sexy. Hang on.
Okay.
All right. You happy she
was sleeping? I just,
I didn't know if she was sleeping. I
was fucking nightmare you have there.
All right, well there you go. So
you fucked the whole thing up.
The cleaned up and then I woke her up.
Um, anyway, dude, I don't fucking know.
But you're saying that you're not,
you're not allowed to have facial
hairs at this fucking school.
You go was elegant type
Typo or something. My,
Oh my high school's not college.
My high school's dress code allows guys
to grow facial hair in the last semester
of senior year. Ah, okay. I thought
it was like saying that college. Um,
well look to when I was a kid.
The only reason to grow a beard was so
you could buy booze or get served when
you were still under age. You know,
whether women liked it or not.
I have no fucking idea. Um,
yeah,
I don't, I don't know. Go there
fucking clean shaven and then, uh,
you know, get a little scruff going
or some shit. I don't know this,
this is like a cosmo question.
I have no fucking, do they,
is it a sign of manliness?
I have no idea. I mean,
if you grow too quickly,
it might be a sign of a hairy back and
that might take you out of the game.
Some women might be like, Oh,
my dad had a beard in the subconsciously
that gets into them, you know? Oh yeah,
that reminds me of feeling safe with
my dad. And next thing you know,
they're blowing you. Then they're like,
what the fuck did you, what happened?
Right. I Dunno.
Let's move onto the next question. That
was a hard one. I had no fucking idea.
All right. Cheating Bitch,
girlfriend out. Geez there.
Hey you red face. Fuck.
Okay.
I don't know why I find that
shit so endearing. Um, so do you,
what the Fuck's wrong with me?
Already about a month ago
I started dating this lady.
She seemed really quiet and pretty
innocent. After about a week, I realized,
I just pictured that woman in that Vince
Vaughn movie, the wedding crashes. Um,
whoever that actress was was fucking
hilarious in that movie. Anyways,
after about a week, I realized that
her last boyfriend was a total freak,
like jeans, shorts and shit. Fuck,
what do you mean freak like a
Weirdo or was fucking, you know,
having threesomes with this chick anyways,
like jeans, shorts and shit. Fuck.
So I did my best to just ignore
that and have fun together. I was,
in my opinion, a great boyfriend to her.
I took her on a lot of dates and it
seemed like everything was perfect.
And this was my first girlfriend.
I'm only 16 and pretty introverted.
So having a girlfriend was a big
step for me. Yeah, that's huge.
Good for you man. Anyways, after a
few weeks, she started acting weird.
One day at lunch she told me that our old
weird boyfriend and her had sex before
school that day and they also had sex
a couple of other times while we were
going out. I didn't know what to
say and it really fucked me up.
She even said it wasn't her fault and
I shouldn't be mad. Oh, you know what?
I was actually going to give this girl
props for being mature enough to own up
to what the fuck she did.
And then she said that
don't be mad at me. Um,
after a fight I told her to fuck.
I told her to fuck and left. I
think fuck off is what you meant.
Cause she's already fucking
dude. You don't need to tell her.
You should have told him to less
fuck two x nay on the fuck a.
Um, she then started saying that it was
my fault. I don't know what I did wrong.
Oh, you poor Bastien you're only
16 years old. Right? So you didn't,
you didn't have your deflector
shields up. Is that what it is?
Did you say you was 16 right?
Fuck was that, I'm only 16. Okay.
So now everyone knows that school
because high school is bullshit.
Um, I know I, I'm now known by everyone,
including my family as the guy
who got cheated on this bitch.
Not only made me feel like shit,
but also kind of ruined the whole
aspect of finding a nice girl.
I don't trust them and feel as
if I will never move on. Yeah.
These are the catastrophic thoughts
you have when you're 16. Uh,
because your world is small. You still
live in an home with your parents.
You go to school, you see the
same fucking cuts every day,
and you feel like the
walls are closing in.
All of these feelings are
100% normal. Um, how do you,
how do you move on after
being fucked over like that?
The only things I've done is got
a job and started lifting weights.
Maybe then when school starts again,
I can show up shredded and do better
next year. There you go. I like it.
Turn a negative into a positive. Um,
here's the thing. You're a nice guy,
right? You're a nice
guy. Uh, well, you know,
so that means there's the Nice woman
out there that balances you out,
right? If you're a dick, there's
plenty of cops out there,
but you're a nice guy. So
what I would do is, uh,
I would thank my lucky stars that that
fucking woman is out of your life.
You know, she's totally fucked up, right?
She's going to go back to the gene short
guy and they're going to fuck before
school and they're going to do
all of this other shit. And, um,
who gives a fuck? I don't
understand how, like,
I don't know how, how there's no reason
for you just me listening to this,
why you should feel bad about yourself.
I, you know, I got cheated on,
you know, it's happened
to everybody and uh,
it makes you just more feel stupid
is what it is. You know what I mean?
So I'm trying to count the amount
of times that's happening to me.
First girl I was with was like
fucking way older than me.
I went from like zero to 90
miles an hour in fucking,
Yup.
She ended up cheating on me and breaking
up a fucking marriage and a [inaudible]
.
Okay.
How did I, oh, I remember
how I, I didn't even know.
I ended up running into the wife of the
guy that she cheated with and then they
will broken up and she told me, and
I just, my, just my, my thought,
which I just went like, Huh.
You know?
And there was a lot in that
because it just let me know that,
uh, you know, I just thought guys
did shit like that, you know,
I thought we would just the fucking
animals. And it was just like, wow.
So she was doing that and they'd
come home and smile. Yeah.
And that fucked me up for a long
fucking time. Yeah. You know what?
And I didn't trust women, you know?
And I started lifting weights.
Did I write this thing 20 years ago?
What the fuck now? Um, yeah dude,
this is the deal. You know, it's gonna
take time to get over it, but you know,
you're gonna meet somebody
nice. And I think, yeah,
you're the prime of your life. You
throw the weights around a little bit,
you show up fucking shredded. Right.
Okay.
And then you show,
you show up in September and
just start chatting up the women.
And this is a thing too. Women love
a fucking, they love a project,
you know, so you can use the fact that
this woman cheated on you, that, oh,
you know, I have problems, trust in
fucking women and now they'll just help.
They'll be coming at you. You beat them
off with a fucking stick. All right?
Yeah Dude. Fuck that. This is the thing.
You don't have a letter anytime anything
bad happens in life, you don't have it.
You don't let it. You don't,
there's two things you can do.
You can either just fucking,
yeah,
yeah, I dunno. I, I view liked those
types of thoughts. Like, you know,
when you watch like bugs bunny,
they would have like that, wait,
that just said one ton
on it. I view like that.
That's what that thought is all right.
And you're standing next to
a fucking pool. All right?
And the thing's got a chain around it
and you either just fucking let it go to
the bottom of the pool itself or you
stick your head in the chain and wrap it
around your neck and you let it take it
down and then you just down there in the
bottom of the pool. You know,
why would you do that? Fuck it.
Fuck fucker. Just let that whole thing,
I'm not saying don't deal with it,
but you got to turn it into a positive,
which is what you seem to be doing.
Fucking work out and chat up a bunch of
women. This is thing maybe a, you know,
start your list of fucking
requirements. You test,
you lock the door test and maybe to
try to get a good one. Uh, you know,
women always say, find a good
finding a, a good man's hard to find.
So's a good woman.
So what this woman did is a help
you start early on a checklist,
because I didn't start a checklist
for a long fucking time, you know,
I was well into my thirties and I was
still just like, hey, you want wanna fuck
every, all everything you do, everything
on my list is checked off. You know,
all, here we go. All time underrated
quarterbacks, you'll be fine.
You'll be fine. Shake it
off. It's fucking your fault.
That's hilarious that that poor woman,
she's got a lot of issues and I bet
she's has a terrible father, you know?
So in a way you can look at it like
that because you know she is young and
immature, but if she continues to
live her life that way, that is,
that is a bad fucking
road to go on. You know,
that's fucking White Symphony
Dale's or the red wine,
gray teeth with the fucking tramp
stamp. She's going to go down that one
girl and the piece of shit guys,
she's going to meet Jean shorts
will be the least of her problems.
I hope that doesn't happen to her either.
But anyways, here we go. All time,
underrated. Qbs dear Billy White
shoes, Mary, nice reference.
Billy White shoes, Johns of the
Houston Oilers and the a [inaudible].
Alright by friends tear me apart for
being a huge Vinnie Testa Verde fan.
I truly loved the man and feel he
flies under the radar as an all time
quarterback. Maybe not
hall of fame caliber,
but someone who could have won a super
bowl if he didn't have to face Elway.
Tarell Davis in the 1998
Denver Bronco Machine.
Well, you realize what you're saying.
He could have been a championship if he
didn't have to play the best team in the
league. Well, I mean, yeah, well shit.
San Diego Padres could be a fucking
dynasty if it wasn't for all the other of
the fucking 1998 Yankees, you know,
or the late nineties Yankees, right?
I don't know. Anyways,
he played 22 seasons and in his final
season with seasoned with the Carolina
Panthers,
he won his first game after only being
on the team for three fucking days at the
age of 43 a he was definitely a bad ass.
Nobody could be in that backyard playing
horseshoes with their son and then out
of football in two days
later be under arrest,
under center and fucking winning the game.
Like he did that like I think three
times in his career. He was sort of like,
maybe it just happened once, I don't know.
But I just feel like he was officially
retired at least once, if not twice.
And he was in the backyard
eating a fucking Burger,
having a chorus light and
all of a sudden, Hey Bernie,
this is the fucking whatever
Seattle Seahawks calling or Tampa.
But where did he play?
Tampa. The jets. Carolina.
That's a great one. Cleveland.
And he played with Cleveland or was
that Bernie Coza I get, I get confused.
My older age. Let's look up
off any tests of verde vet a.
Then he had the fucking veal. All right,
you guys want to hear a great, uh,
you guys want to hear a
great fucking La Story.
I went out to an Italian
restaurant the other day, right?
And was sitting up front near
the bar and it was too loud.
And one of the guys I was eating with,
he goes, this is too fucking loud.
Let's try to get a table in the back.
So they end up hooking us up with a table
in the back and as I'm going to walk,
you know, to the back, one of the
guys there up to bar, he goes, yeah,
go in the back. You know,
you can barely hear yourself
thinking just the way he said it.
I can't remember what he said, but
he said something along those lines.
Super Italian guy. And the way he said it,
and the fact that I was
moving as I went past him,
I felt like I was in that tracking scene
in Goodfellas when they was showing all
those characters, you know, get
the papers, get the papers, a guy,
it guy took care of that thing, right?
Literally it gave me like
a shock the way he said it.
So I said to one of the guys that we
have, I was having dinner with. I said,
Hey Mike, go Jesus Christ. Go.
That guy just made me feel like I
was in Goodfellas. Classic La Story.
And why it's so amazing to live out
here. He goes, do you know who that is?
And I said, no. He goes, that's the
guy who played Johnny roast beef,
and then I fucking looked at him
again. I was like, oh my God,
this Johnny Roast beef,
one of the greatest pieces fucking acting
I've ever seen is when he's trying to
explain away that pink Cadillac,
and he starts to stop and then then he
starts to talk and then he stops and
actually had, I talked to him about
it for a second and he just laughed.
He said, one basically said,
when a man is scary as Jimmy, the
gent is yelling at you. He goes,
you don't say a fucking word.
Remember that? No, it's,
it's in my grandmother's name. What's
the matter with me? It's a matter of me.
You're going to get us all fucking
pinch. That's why some matter with you,
it's a matter with you. Take it back,
take it back at it. The fuck that.
Look on his fucking face. And he goes,
he just keeps going. I'm sorry. I
okay.
I'm sorry. What did I tell you?
What did the fuck, what did I tell?
I fucking love that seat. So anyways,
I'm Vinny Testaverde.
Here we go. Benny fork.
Intense diversity over
Ovi. Um, here we go.
Vinny Testaverde. Let's see.
It was him with the panthers.
He's 52 years old. I swear to
God. I bet he's still in shape.
And if you fucking, if you, you
know, if you call them up right now,
if you call him up right now, he give
you a decent outage. What the fuck?
87 to 92 we played for
the Tampa Bay Buccaneers.
93 to 95 he played for
the Cleveland browns.
96 97, the Baltimore Ravens 98 to 2003,
the New York jets, which is
how I remember him as a jet.
2004th, The Dallas Cowboys,
2005, he goes back to the jets.
2006, he played for my patriots.
I don't even remember that.
2007 he played for the panthers.
20 year fucking career. 21
seasons. Wow. Two time pro bowler.
96 98 Heisman trophy 86,
uh, David O'Brian, but blah, blah.
Sammy bar trophy sportsman
of the year 86 let's see,
tds verse interceptions. This
is what fucked them over though.
275 touchdowns,
267 interceptions.
Wasn't somebody rap like that in
incomplete like Testa Verde. Uh,
but he didn't say intercepted but he
threw for 46,233 yards back in the day,
you know,
for the most part when you actually
they could cover receivers before Jim or
changed all the fucking rules cause
he couldn't beat the Patriots.
But that's okay. I know the
ball was under inflated.
Let's kick them out of football.
Passing rating pass passer rating
75.0 all right. Well yeah. Okay.
Those are great. Fuck. You
know, you play 20 seasons,
but he did throw a lot
of pics. So anyways, um,
where he's the oldest quarterback to
ever start and when a pro football game,
yeah,
older than George Blanda.
Okay.
What? I thought George Blank, maybe
he was just kicking at that point.
Everybody always reverts back to the
days, his days in Tampa and Cleveland.
But I'd argue that those Tampa years
where some of the worst pro squads ever to
trot on a football onto a
football field. Yeah, absolutely.
You can't blame somebody for that.
You know, it's like Joey Harrington,
he goes and he fucking plays
for, uh, the lions, you know,
art right out of the gate. There is no
way as bad. He was as bad as he looked.
Those lion teams were fucking horrible.
I'm not saying that the guy would
have played in the league or whatever,
but you know,
for the longest time if you got
drafted by the lions or the browns as,
as a quarterback, that was
a fucking death sentence,
which is another brilliant
move that John Elway made.
Cause when he got drafted by
the Baltimore Colts, he's like,
I'm not fucking going there and getting
the shit kicked out of me and I'll be
out of football. I mean that
almost happened to Troy Aikman,
Troy Aikman when he got
drafted by the fucking cowboys.
So got the living shit kicked out of him
his first few years. If that continued,
I mean that guy, he would
have been out of football.
But fortunately the Herschel Walker trade
went down with Jimmy Johnson at deck
cowboys. Right. They got that fucking, uh,
all those 300 pounders in front
of them. I Dunno. Anyways,
let's plow ahead here. Uh,
he said as a patriots fan,
I'd like your thoughts on
him. Are My friends right?
Saying he was just an average
quarterback at best? No fucking way.
No Way. No Way. He was, he was w a well,
you don't play for 20
fucking years. Okay. He was,
he was above way above average,
I think. I think he was a, a,
he's not a, I wouldn't say he's one of
the greats, but he was definitely a, uh,
he was a really good quarterback,
you know, he wasn't like, um,
what does he, if he was, if
he was an average QB at best,
you don't play for 20 years,
be an average unless you're
Steve to Berg and just some out.
You just look so great with
a headset and a clipboard.
People just wanted you around. He was
like the David Hasselhoff, you know,
a fucking quarterbacks. It just,
I think just sold more tickets
because he never had his helmet on.
The ladies could come down and look
at him. Look up Steve to Berg here.
Steve the Berg. All right.
Oh yeah, the David Hasselhoff.
He looks like Eve's look like,
you know, whenever they had those coming
of age movies and you got the Nerd,
who wants to date the fucking cheerleader,
but she's dating the guy who's
just a complete fucking Dick. Uh,
he had those, those
level good looks, dude.
I'm telling you right now. Look this
guy up. That's fucking hilarious.
He looks like he on Baywatch
played number 17 on.
Now we got it out. This,
this, you know what?
This is actually morphed into the
greatest NFLs greatest journeymen.
I'm going to look this up. Great is,
Oh God, I love the Internet. I love that
somebody made a page about this shit.
Best NFL journeymen,
the seven most unkillable
journeyman quarterbacks.
I love the Internet because of shit
like this and all the fucking free porn.
All right, here we go. Um,
there's a good chance that
at one time or another,
your team's hopes were riding on
Ryan Fitzpatrick, Brian Hoyer,
or one of the NFLs other
well-traveled signal callers. Oh,
don't be all just new guys. Come
on. All right. Ryan Fitzpatrick,
Brian Fitzpatrick, a played for the
Texans, the titans, the rams, the Bengals,
the jets, and the bills.
All right. Josh mccown.
Uh, Brian Hoyer. Uh, Know
Matt Castle. Matt Castle,
Matt Flynn, the perennial
backups. I'll come on, man.
Tim Tebow. Now this, this
was done by some youngster.
You've got to have Steve to Bergen there.
You've got to have any tests of Verde
journeyman, NFL players
who just won't go away.
Do I have to type in all time?
Is that what I have to do?
Okay.
I think I got to type in all time.
Come on, man. You've got to, if, if,
if Steve burst not on your fucking list.
B's not on your fucking list.
Journeyman quarterback. All right,
we'll just go Wikipedia.
Oh, this is depressing.
I thought it was going to be great.
Okay.
J T O'Sullivan played for 12
professional teams during his career.
You know what? I bet in his
man cave, he should, they,
the NFL should give him
all 12 of those helmets.
All 12 of those fucking helmets. Am
I all wrapped up in the fucking here?
What's going on?
Okay.
All right. Here we go.
This is what happens when you fucking
lay down on a couch and there's why is,
um, JT O'Sullivan,
he played on no less than 11 to NFL
teams. Oh, professionals. Okay. So,
and then he also played for the
Saskatchewan rough riders in the Frankfurt
Galaxy.
Chris Chandler holds the record for
starting a game for the highest number of
different NFL teams with
eight. Also, he started okay.
There's no accepted definition
or threshold at which a
person is regarded as a
journeyman quarterback. Um, the term
is descriptive rather than definitive.
David Craig enjoyed 11 stable careers
with the Seahawks before leaving.
Let's see, mark rip, Ian Notable
examples. Here we go. Here we go.
Trent Dilfer, Brad Johnson, rich Gannon.
What the fuck is Steve to Berg?
Notable journeyman quarterbacks.
Tough. Come on, come on.
Yeah.
All right. You know, I'm just gonna
look up Steve Debark. I'm sorry guys.
This whole podcast just you just listened
to me surf the fucking Internet now
too.
People still say surf the internet or is
that from the nineties I'm old already.
He's 62 years old.
He played for the San Francisco 40 niners
from 1977 to 1980 the Broncos from 81
to 83 the Buccaneers from 84 to 87
the chiefs from 88 to 91 back to the
Buccaneers. 92 93 the Miami Dolphins,
1993 he was out of fucking football in
94 he was out of football in 95 out of
football, 96 out of football,
97 and then what the fuck?
1998 he's back with the dirty birds.
The Atlanta Falcons who upset
the 15 and one Minnesota Vikings.
Right. And then went to
the fucking super bowl,
one of the most forgettable
Superbowls of all fucking time.
Okay.
When the Denver Broncos repeated who I
was the last fucking game of John Elway's
career, all right. TDS to interceptions,
he had 196 touchdowns
versus 204 interceptions.
He threw for 34,000,
241 yards and as a higher QB rating
than Vinny Testaverde it's 74.2.
Right? Or was he 75? I
don't fucking remember.
Steven Lee. Roy [inaudible].
There you, that's, that's my, um,
that's my vote. You know,
it's funny like I bet he doesn't have a
lot of problems walking or anything like
that cause he just got so he has a low
miles on that odometer as far as like
actually playing in the fall. I'm
not trying to insult the guy here.
I'm just saying like if he was
a car, you know, it'd be like a,
those are all original
miles. It'd be a, yeah. Yeah.
He sat in a garage with a fucking
clipboard for all those years. All right.
That's the podcast for
this, uh, this 4th of July.
I hope you guys all have a
happy and a safe one. All right.
You fucking drunks.
I know it's a fireworks and
it's supposed to be fun,
but you know they are
explosives. Don't be that person
in one of those youtube fucking videos
of like top 10 stupidest fucking moves
done with fireworks. Did
you see that fucking guy?
He actually took like a mortar
or some shit, put it on his head.
I don't know if he thought
it was going to take off.
He literally blew himself up. His
friends go. You don't understand.
There was nothing left of him.
There was nothing left to help.
You know? They just showed
up and there was Jay.
There was like a belt buckle and
like a shoelace. He was gone.
So please don't do that to yourselves.
All right? All right, cleo.
Um, all right, that's the podcast.
You guys have a great week.
I will check in with you.
Go fuck yourselves. I'll
check in on you on Thursday.
All right.