Okay.
Hey, what's going on? It's bill burn.
It's time for the Monday
morning podcast for my day.
April 22nd, 2019 what's going on? How, ah,
yeah, right now you're probably
wondering what is with his tone.
He sounds happy and I, and
you know what you're like, oh,
what did the Bruins when yesterday,
what happened? I don't know.
Yeah.
All right.
Cause right now I'm watching live,
I'm watching the Bruins Toronto with
1445 to go in the second period.
Hey, come to pro and straighten up
the right style. Sorry. Can't y'all?
My daughter's taking a nap.
MMM.
I don't know what happened with this game.
It was just like Toronto came out like
fucking gang busters and I was like, Whoa,
this is finally there year. You know,
they just a better God damn team.
But you know what?
The Bruins came back with a goal by Brad,
my Shan.
Oh No. Who's got the first one?
Tory crew got the first one,
then Marshawn got the one right off the
face off after Burgee one version where
I'm one one yet another face off.
So right now it's two to one. Um,
obviously the next goal is huge.
MMM.
I feel like whoever scores next
is going to win this fucking game.
That's what I think.
That's my big bold prediction.
So I got the game on in the background.
MMM.
This is like a fucking NBA game
where it's like, it's a game of runs.
Cause like all of a sudden now,
now fucking Toronto can get the puck.
I'll tell you know, I'll never understand
this game of hockey, you know. Um,
anyways, I want to thank everybody that
came out to the F is for family, a um,
panel that we did on a Saturday.
Uh,
it was really cool, man. I
felt like the crowd was really,
I had something happen after season
three where I think we finally pushed
through to not being underground as much,
where people are finally actually
watching the show. And uh, yeah,
it felt really proud.
It's sitting up there with Mike Price,
Vince Vaughn and Peter Billingsley.
Ah,
the fucking Mount Rushmore of the
show. Not Kidding. It said it takes a,
it takes this city. But, uh, we had a
bunch of voiceover actors showed up. Uh,
Trevor Deval was there, Phil Henry,
Debbie dairy. Barry was there.
Imagine there was a couple of others
that of course I'm going to forget. Um,
I think mo Collins was there and
maybe Kevin, Michael Richardson.
Um, any Ho um, it was a,
it was a great time and people set a
bunch of Nice things and what I was loving
as much as it was saying, oh my God,
the third season is your best season.
I actually think season four
is going to be even better.
And I'm thinking sometime
around season 11 or 12,
I think we might, I think we
might get nominated for something.
What are you going to do?
So anyway,
I am sitting here on pins and needles
hoping my Boston Bruins are going to push
a, a force a game seven.
And if they don't,
I'm rooting for the leafs
and I've come to this new,
this new,
a place as a sports fan.
Okay.
Where I just realized all those years
I spent hating teams and Hayden,
great players and then they go
when they retire. And I'm like,
wait a minute and I'm going to miss
this guy. This guy was great. Um,
I know your root against them because
they were on the other team. But, uh,
I dunno, it feels a lot better if you
lose to a team to be, hey, you know what?
Good. Good for you. Good
luck to Ya. You know,
what the Fuck is Boston supposed to
win? Everything every year. I mean,
how long can this run last? Um, no,
I'm just, I'm gonna, I'm
gonna go into that mode.
This is all me getting read of
my ridiculous fucking anger.
I'll still have it.
I'll still have it for my comedy act.
God knows I went up
last night and oh Jesus.
I went up down the Improv here on Melrose
and I went up at the laugh factory
down in Long Beach and
woo. Oh, stinker roof.
The new jokes,
just not just not working.
I'm kind of coming out with this really
fucking stupid one that I just ran by a
bunch of jaded guys and they all told me
it was funny. And then like, you know,
women in like anybody who's
like remotely happy as a man,
they just all staring at me like,
come on bill,
don't you think you're a little bit
better than that? Um, all right, well, um,
you know,
you saw that documentary free Solo.
That's what this podcast
is like right now.
Cause I don't have any advertising or
any fucking emails because my stupid
emails aren't loading.
And then I went on the Internet and God
bless this guy in a second language he
was trying to tell me how to do is
I go to guard your part of Jerky,
bar their board and I couldn't
understand what the fuck he was saying.
And then he was on his phone and I slowed
it down and in large the thing so I
could see what the hell that guy
was talking about. And uh, I dunno,
every fucking 10,
I Google shit every time I Google stuff,
like whatever they're saying, it's
like, okay, click on the apple,
go to system preferences and then
click on a fucking, uh, I don't know,
software update or whatever they say
and their shit. It's just Bam, Bam, Bam.
And mine is always like, Bam,
Bam, go fuck yourself. It's like,
I don't have that. I mean,
I don't know what I need.
I got to have like automatic
updates because I feel like
everybody's always like
two v two episodes ahead of me. Whatever
the hell it is you're supposed to say.
Um, so I don't have any fucking
emails. I asked Andrew to,
to send them via text. He
responded with sure. You know?
Sure. It's a very funny word. You know,
it's one of those words that's like
positive and it's also very passive
aggressive. Would you
mind doing that? Sure.
Or sheriff a lot of ways.
A lot of ways to read that.
Um, lovely knee is in the background.
Haven't been on the podcast in a while.
I know you're going to come
on. Yeah, I want a little
bit. Oh yeah. You get over it.
You graceless get it out of there.
Yeah.
Yeah. Come the Bruins down the ice. A
possible two, one, one and we fuck it up,
Scott.
Yeah.
How the fuck did he score on that?
Sorry.
All of a sudden we slow down all my God.
Can I just turn on the TV and
listen to the fucking silence?
What happened? I don't know, but
he was anymore. I've got a kid.
The whole thing fell apart.
He just stopped. I think
he just flat out beat him.
Did he tip that in?
They made,
oh my God.
Krag softest hands in the
NHL over at the brassy. Tip
three to one absolute deafening silence
up in Toronto.
We win this game.
It doesn't mean shit because you have
to understand is a leaf fan okay?
Provided you didn't win today.
All right.
You know dead.
Even if you guys beat us,
your team is going to torture you.
It's not gonna be easy.
It was like the other day when you had
his fucking beat and then you let up that
late goal. So you still
had to be like, fuck,
I'm all the Games are running
together for me. I don't know.
I just know you totally dominated us
in our own building and game five.
And I was just like, well, maybe
this is finally the year. And, uh,
the first 10 minutes of this game, I was
just like, they just the better team.
I feel like we're going six a, you
know, five against six out there
fucking Bruins. I love
this team. I swear to God,
I know the Celtics won four games
in a row, which is fucking awesome.
I got to get on that bandwagon.
I just haven't, I just
don't have the time. But um,
I really, uh, I really am a
hockey fan over basketball.
Um, I just am Oh, Jesus. And
I stick to the fucking taint.
That'll be a penalty.
Right? It'll be a pet. Oh,
Jesus. That's dangerous. Oh
yeah. Hate to see that. Good.
He got his knees out
of the way. Um, anyway,
plowing ahead here.
Uh,
so I'm getting ready to leave to go over
to Iceland middle part of this week and
uh, Amy, I want to talk to
you about my packing. Huh?
She's already given me shit.
Yeah,
she doesn't get it, man. She's
going to Iceland, but I'm,
I'm starting an Iceland did,
she's going to leave after that
and then I'm going on this.
I don't even know where this
fucking toilet takes me.
I know I ended up in Israel, you know. Oh,
do I get some open and jokes over
there for them? Um, all right,
a second. Let's see. Bill,
burger.com fucking funny is that,
I don't even know where I'm going.
Shows I'm going to
Copenhagen. Oh, I always had,
I always tell me to take a Copenhagen.
I think of that Conti fucking
taxi driver I had. All right,
this is what I got. I'm in, uh, Reykjavik
Iceland on the 29th.
I'm in Copen Copenhagen on the 30th.
Both of those shows are sold out.
The second show in Copenhagen is
sold out denim in Stockholm, Sweden.
Fuck.
I've been there in forever
triumphant return May 1st and uh,
that's sold out. Then I have two
shows in Helsinki on May 2nd, the, uh,
first show sold out.
The second one is not Oslow Norway.
This spectrum tickets still available.
Then I'm in Amsterdam, Netherlands.
Um,
that's sold out and then I have a day
off and I'm so fucking tented to go to
Spain and go to that moto GP race. I
just, I just not going to have that.
That's the old me would have done that.
And then I'll go here for five minutes
and then I'll go there for five minutes.
Or I could spend two days in Israel,
you know.
Oh my God.
Do you know what the name of the place
I'm playing in fucking Israel is Nia?
You know what? The name of the place I'm
playing in Israel is how great is this?
I'm playing this Shlomo Group arena,
uh, to be confused with
the [inaudible] funny bone.
What's the matter is they're
not like someone's name.
Shlomo yeah, yeah. That's what I mean.
Yeah, that's what I'm saying. Okay.
Why did you get all like that was like
some antisemitic shit cause I, you know,
I thought you were making fun of the name.
I'm like, isn't it a Hebrew name? Yeah.
So that's great. Oh, okay.
We don't want to play a cousin
Vinnys fucking arena in Israel.
Shlomo Jesus were to take a fun traveling
moment and turn it into a Hashtag on
Twitter.
He sounded excited,
but was he really
antisemitic when we return,
another white person in their 20s
tries to destroy somebody else.
Odd fucking social media.
I've been having so much fun
fucking trash and all those cons.
Fucking young people out there just
trying to ruin people's lives for their
goddamned cause.
They fucking lunatics fucking lunatics.
And like as I've sent somebody
takes a dick out at work.
Obviously you got to say something,
but this fucking ticky tack Shit and
you're going to sit there and try to twist
it around like shit around.
Like you fucking Fox News and CNN.
It makes somebody look like an asshole.
Just cause you don't like that political
opinion is it's fucking beyond me.
Um, anyways, I'll be at the Shlomo
group arena. That is fucking awesome.
MMM.
I should double up and
go do one in Palestine.
You know,
little surf and turf over there. Get
both sides of the story, if you will.
MMM.
Oh fuck.
He's walking in Ed [inaudible].
Yeah,
Clara in the zone. Will this be
icing? Don't ask Douggie Hamilton.
You don't know. Poor bastard. I
liked Douggie Hamilton, by the way.
I don't know why I said that, but he
fucking, I don't know what happened here.
It was the other night I
was watching the caps game.
It didn't matter cause they got the shit
kicked out of him but he like pointed
like he called icing and the ref didn't
know bench can came in and took the Puck,
pass it to his buddy. They're
right there. Fred Bing Bang, boom.
MMM.
By the way, I didn't know Calgary
are the best record in the east.
I mean the West I would have devil
would have been exciting but then they
fucking shit the bed just like Tampa.
Pittsburgh is out.
I'm going to show you that man.
That shit is fucking wide open here.
I got to tell you right now,
if these Washington capitols could
get by the hurricanes. Carolina.
Okay.
They got a really good shot.
They got as good as shot as anybody to
go out there and when the cup and that
would be a repeat for the first time
since the fucker Detroit Redwings is that
right? First Time since 97 98 I
think that be the four already.
The penguins doing.
Maybe the penguins didn't,
I think they did it a few years ago.
Um,
this will be the all Ho to guy
just did it out of the fucking air.
Um, yeah. Come on on the podcast and talk
about your packing versus my packing.
Yeah.
Yeah. At what point did you stop
giving a fuck about the podcast?
Or is it me? You used to always be
like, I love going on the podcast.
Then all of a sudden we have a kid and
you get other priorities since when does
our kid come before the podcast?
Nia,
I'm asking you,
I love this commercial with
this guys in like a racing suit,
like a fire retardant suit and he's
sitting there going, I love my job.
And he's all excited because he's
driving a fucking Honda civic.
Rarely does that get your fucking balls
in an uproar there guys dressed like a
race car driver and he's excited to drive
a fucking sophomore in college chick
car if you've got money.
Right. Okay. Then after,
after Israel, the next show I have is, uh,
the Wilbur Theater in Boston,
Massachusetts for the, uh,
Travis. Roy Foundation.
And then after that I'm doing September
6th, the Cosmopolitan Hotel in Las Vegas.
And I have to tell you people, uh,
over the summer, I will be, uh,
putting my act together in local comedy
clubs and I'll try to be giving you the
heads up as I do that,
uh,
over the summer here
in loss on golf a visa.
Um, all right. Hey, let's read,
let's read something that I actually
just found it an email that I could
actually read.
Um, oh, that ain't it.
That's notes for season five. If we
get it, that's how far ahead I am.
Notes on season five for F is for family.
This guy from Australia sent me an email
and, um, let's see what we got here. Oh,
and I somehow fucking deleted.
So fucking annoying, man.
There it is.
This fucking guy sent me something.
He said, good day, Billy. Red Nuts.
Love your podcast mate.
Uh, you crack me up.
I'm also an older gentleman who has a
small child close to your daughter's age,
so I love to hear how she's developing
as my lad is doing the same things.
It's great. I hope this is where
you get your emails for the podcast.
Any who probably hasn't
made news over your way.
But here in Australia there's been
considerable problems with militant vegans
invading private farms.
They're really pissing people off.
What has happened to the left? Maddie's
fit going fucking crazy. I kinda like it,
you know? Um, yeah,
so they got militant vegans,
Jesus Christ.
How much is Australia changed?
You know,
they used to have a crazy guy wrassling
alligators down there and now all of a
sudden they got people fucking
going nuts about kumquats. Um,
anyways, it really pissing people off. A
friend came to me the other day and said,
how do you know if someone's a Vegan? I
said, I don't know. He said, don't worry.
They'll fucking tell you. Ha it
cracked me up. Keep it up, mate.
You should head down to Adelaide,
South Australia sometime.
Get stuffed your mug.
The fuck does get stuffed.
Me can only imagine that some sort
of fucking take a dick in your ass.
MMM.
I've got to tell you right now,
I'm watching this fucking game and what
the fucking Bruins are doing right now.
If these maple leafs of Toronto don't
wake up this fucking game, it's,
it's over with six minutes
left in the second period.
I said it before, the next goal is going
to win. Although the way hockey is,
I'll say the next goal, we go up four
to one. I will be feeling good, but if
Austin Matthews gets another one,
he had caught fucking great is that guy,
they already showed them
the beginning of the game.
They showed them skating slow motion.
Like when they had the maple leafs in uh,
emblem on the ice and he that,
that 34 Jersey is already
Iraq. Uh, ironic, iconic.
I'm looking at that thing like this guy
is, he's going to be a hall of Famer.
I mean, that's not too
hard to guess. You know,
considering we scored four
goals in his first fucking game.
MMM.
Bruins. Just down the maple leafs
and the entire second period,
at least the point that I've been looking
at. All right? So militant vegans, Nia,
militant vegans are going fucking
nuts over there in Australia.
I guess they're marching onto farms.
Here's the thing about militant vegans.
All right? You might think
they're assholes, but I gotta
be honest with you there,
right? The way we treat animals, a,
I'm all for killing them and eating them,
but this shit,
like you ever see what they
do to chickens and stuff?
They shoot steroids into their fucking
chicken breasts and they can't even walk.
They're tipping over.
They clip off the front of their beaks.
The shit that we do to animals,
um, is fucking horrible.
And I gotta be honest with you, this
whole fucking thing is we do it, you know,
so human beings don't suffer. Uh,
you know, I, I don't know about that.
I think at this point they're
just doing it for money.
I think enough animals have suffered.
So I actually agree with these militant
vegans as far as like how they,
they view what we do to animals,
but I stopped short of just marching on
to somebody's property and scaring the
shit out of families
and stuff. I about, um,
the problem though is when you do shit
like that is everybody just says you're
an asshole.
But no one was listening to them before.
So what are they supposed to do?
I'm calling this right now.
Militant vegans are going to invade
mmm
oh farm and their love of animals will
make them approach an animal they should
not approach. And somebody's gonna
get hurt on the beacon side. That's,
that's my prediction. Nia. What
do you say about that? Yeah,
that's it. Can you Cheney just come,
I don't have any fucking emails.
I don't have any advertising.
Can you fucking pick up a microphone and
helped me out for a couple of minutes?
Jesus quite,
you know what's funny about you?
The level that you stress
when we go to the airport,
I'm just packing. I'm getting myself
together. Okay. Let's try to be prepared.
Okay.
Is this going to be the energy?
Are you going to come in and have a
little fun in the middle of my thing?
So I was kind of focused
on that, but uh, unpack,
I'm bringing a backpack and
a in a little carry on. Okay.
For this trip and I'm
just letting you know,
I'm packing one shirt and one pair of
pants from my entire tour and then I'll
have a,
I'll have a fucking,
is this guy a bookie track suit and for
my flights and then I'll just have some
walking around town close and then
a bunch of underwear and socks.
That's how I'm doing. That's
not doing it. Okay for you.
Where are your comedy instincts?
Just what you're supposed to go against
it like you did last night. We were like,
we're going to be going out to
dinner. I was, I was getting there,
but you just jumped in. I had a
chance to, I was going to say, okay,
well what about, and then I was going
to get into it. All right, Andrew,
edit all of this out.
All right, well, Gee, I don't
know. Don't edit this shit.
I don't give a fuck what no is,
it really isn't really gonna bother you
if I went to same shirt every night.
Yeah. Like you know, I think we're going
to be going out to dinner, this and that.
You're not gonna switch it up at all.
You know what it is,
and yet when you're going
country to country, country,
which I will be doing after we have
a little few days there in Iceland.
[inaudible]
it's like your stuff just becomes
a burden. Yeah, no, I got it.
So you just want to like,
you know Jim Morrison where
the same fucking brown
leather pants his entire tour.
Look at that guy.
Everybody still loves him.
He's not dead because of his pants. Are
you comparing yourself to Jim Morrison?
My traveling? Yes. Jesus.
The way I travel. Wow.
If it was good enough for Jim Morrison is
good enough for me. Right, right. Well,
I talked to Steven Adler and I said,
dude, you going on a one world tour?
What are you doing? He goes, easy. He
goes, one pair of pants, two shirts. Yeah,
sounds disgusting.
Well,
you're going to hit somebody who's going
to give you a shirt while you're out
there if you're a rock star,
right? So you're just trusting.
So that's what you're going for us.
And I'll look if you're a regular guy like
me, when you audience list Copenhagen.
Oh, this is how, that's
what you're waiting for. No,
this is how it works is pretty stylish.
So maybe they can help you out.
I don't know.
First of all,
any European gives me a shirt is not
going to fit because they were like child
sizes over there. Yeah. Um, there,
there's this slim Whitman over there. Now
here's the deal. As far as a rock star,
you're going to bang a chicken.
Then they're going to give you stuff.
That's how it works. When you're a rock
star, if you just a regular guy like me,
if you bag somebody,
you lose a shirt.
That's how it worked when I was a
single man. Okay. I'm not saying now,
I'm not saying I'm going to go
this Shlomo arena they and try to,
I wish I was going to Tel Aviv. I bet
you do. Well, I'm going to go there.
I'll get the lay of the land.
I'll go to the weep and wall.
Was that what they call it? I don't
know. The crying, weeping Lawson's right.
Is that right?
[inaudible]
I dunno. I don't, I don't, I,
I'm not into any of that stuff so I'm
going to like respectfully stay away from
those things. I'm going to go over
there and see if they go to Mcdonald's.
I'm perfect.
Get myself a quarter pounder with cheese.
No, I'm actually really looking good
forward to it because uh, you know,
historically speaking Jewish people as
some of the funniest people on the planet.
You know,
if you go through showbusiness,
you remember that Adam Sandler Song
there, Huh? Yeah. All three stooges.
[inaudible] the Hanukkah Song.
I know that song. Yeah. What do,
what do you mean? I'm just saying he
named all these fuckers funny people.
He was naming all these people who
are Jewish. Yeah. Yeah. That was fun.
I don't know why this is so hard.
Nia.
What happened to our chemistry and I know.
All right. At the height of you loving
me, scale of one to 10 was it at,
what do you mean? At the height of me?
Lemme Yeah. What is that supposed to mean?
Why? I know you never got
to 10 dip down. Yeah, no.
Where are you at currently? Okay. I know
you still love me, but as far where's the,
like the, the like is what
shifts in a marriage. Oh,
that's true. Yeah. On one to 10.
It's like a pretty solid like seven. No,
that's good. I'll take a seven and a half.
Good. I've been pretty good about
not a yelling right. I'm a good boy.
Can you pat me on the head? Oh, thank you.
You on the other hand,
leaving the damn door open while
we get the fucking heat on near.
You got the door open. You're like,
I'm going back out. And it was like,
and also she was walking in and out of it,
so it was kind of like letting her do
that before I got all our stuff together
to go out there. If once again I express
something and there's just, Oh my God,
can you imagine taking that hit from
shower? Jesus, he went up high there.
That guy just fucking helmet almost
came off. Yeah, that's a good deal.
From the uh, he scored
the goal for the uh, oh,
he didn't score the wrong guy. There
was a guy from the king's though Muslim.
Um, all right Nia, this has
been a incredible, you know,
I know you're distracted.
I'm sorry I've distracted cause I am
trying to like get my stuff together here.
Is that a green bag now? It's a little
green. Yeah. Green like this microphone.
What does it go to call it a
window and say that's lime green.
You're bringing neon green. You're
bringing the eighties back. Yeah,
it's neon green.
It's my carry on.
So I'm trying to get it together
and see what's happening.
I downloaded that album,
I downloaded that album where
they took that sample from.
It's such a killer album.
Uh,
the only reason why I know about
us because I'm reading the uh,
the Beastie boys book and
who got you that book?
You did.
And you know what's really cool in the
middle out of nowhere, not in the middle.
Towards the end is Cha chef Roy Choi.
Ah Yeah. He's in there.
Cause he's a Beastie boy fan.
He got to know them and he actually
gives you some recipes. Really? Yeah.
In the middle of their
frigging autobiography.
How great is that book really has
everything. All right, so here's an album.
You got to download a, you gotta
download. Uh, the fuck is this guy's name,
Eugene McDaniels, headless
heroes of the apocalypse. Uh,
you got you gotta check that out.
The supermarket blues might be my
favorite fucking song on there.
The drums are awesome. I don't even know
what that's about. Just sounds funny. Oh,
well he's not kidding around.
Now this is a very, uh,
I believe why people would say
militant rather than he's a,
a African American man expressing
his displeasure with white people.
We say he's militant,
which sounds borderline military,
which white people do support unless
it's a black only sort of movement
as far as I could tell.
Minute 22 to go in the second period.
And yet you're Boston Bruins are
up three games to one. Oh my God.
He missed Jesus Christ. Nice thing. Maple
leaves. That is the Toronto may police.
This is an original six playoff
series is what you're looking at here.
That was awesome. Well, this
has been great. Uh, I'll
catch you guys on the flip.
On the flip refilling.
Okay. Enjoy your packing.
Yeah.
You know what sucks about traveling with
your wife is no matter how light you
pack, you still got to go downstairs
to that fucking baggage claim.
It's the purple one.
Yeah,
the purple one with the Hanky on it.
It's always like piled on top
of three others. You fuck up?
You Alumba now the maple leaf,
so race and down the ice.
Look at this shit they
use in the maple leaf.
She saw in the first 12 minutes
of the game, but he had come yet.
Boston Bruins dumping. Oh, tell a little
dump and chase here the other way.
We just contend to go in up three to one.
I hope butch Cassidy,
he gets on the rest. Why not? Fuck, we're
job that tried to get called up before.
Okay.
You're trying to make me have
to put my house on the market.
That's what I would say as
a head coach in any sport.
I would always bring up
the fact that if they lose,
I'm going to have to sell my house and
go home and tell my children that we're
moving away from their friends.
All right.
Or You fucking assholes could go out
here and score some goddamn goals for me.
Neo, do you think about
militant vegans in Australia?
Sounds pretty scary. Yeah. That down
there shaking her head of fucking lettuce.
People
yelling about how much protein's in
iceberg lettuce versus a chicken or
something.
Yeah.
I have to be honest,
anytime I have eaten just vegetarian,
you feel great,
you feel light and all of that shit.
But there's definitely man, you eat a
fucking steak and cheese, you need a nap.
Speaking of which,
Nia.
Oh,
I said stay.
Speaking of which they can chase.
Oh,
favorite sandwich I know has been fucking
killing it at the gym and on a diet.
Yeah,
it's amazing. And you know what? She told
me really warm my heart. She told me,
you know why I'm losing this
weight? I said, why? She said,
I'm doing it for you because what you
think about me is my entire self esteem.
And I was just like,
that is the most beautiful femme
trying to get it back on the pockets.
That's the most beautiful thing
anybody has ever said to me.
Okay.
And then she told me,
you know what,
I really think these
feminists are out of line.
One of the worst things that ever
happened to women was we left the kitchen.
It's just unbelievable.
Okay,
listen,
you already threw me under the and did
you already threw me under the bus at
Conan. All right, so I'm not gonna take
anymore fucking slander out of you. Thank
you very much. Time out. Time
out word slander is abusing.
Slandered my name.
How?
Because you went on Conan and
threw me under the bus hop. No.
Slander is if I go and I say
something that isn't true.
Acting like you know things you don't
know anything. I know it's swearing.
You guessing everything and you throw me
under the bus and I'm sick of it. Well,
wait a minute. Wait a minute. What?
Did I throw you under the bus?
Or was it slander is both.
This was not bus throwing.
It was not. You said white people
in the Middle Ages. I'm not.
I'm not into it. First of all,
it was made in jest. Okay.
Kind of all you know. Yeah. I don't know.
It wasn't meant for the public to hear
act that Nia, can I tell you something?
And most people thought it was
funny. Well, I got dragged.
Which gay?
You got 18 fucking Instagram messages.
You got people you know,
making up fake burner accounts,
trying to troll me and
all that kind of stuff.
Do you realize how stupid Asshole, I'm
still not going to watch game of Thrones.
I don't give a fuck.
I don't care about white people in the
middle ages or white people with fake
accounts.
You and your incest dragons and
all that shit that you like.
Y'All can keep that and listen,
there's plenty of black people
who like game of Thrones,
so why don't you go hang out with them?
But this black person will be over here
and you're working with different work.
Okay,
what can we do with game of Thrones?
You can send that shit straight
into blockbuster because
yeah.
Oh, have we brought that to
the podcast yet? That's our
new, that's our new saying.
Bill came up with it. Oh yeah, of
course. Oh, you're watching some trailer.
There's something, some movie and
I didn't like it. Oh, funny. Yeah.
Like you can take that shit straight to
blockbuster cause I ain't watching and
then now die.
Now what that's become is if some is just
suggested, hey, we should go to brunch.
There's a new place down the street.
What do you think about that?
You can take that shit straight to logic
and watching it. I ain't doing that.
That's it. All right. Let me get back
to what I'm doing here. Okay. Ania,
just for the record,
you know,
just so I can throw myself onto
the bus and be there to, um,
I don't care about black people in
Superhero movies as in you don't want to
watch them. I gotta be more honest
or white people in Superhero movies.
I don't like superhero movies.
Superhero movies. I get it.
Okay, you're a nerd, but you're really
a superhero. And for some reason,
some people don't realize how fucking
shredded you are underneath he is dumb
sweater and your glasses.
All right.
It's so fucking stupid and all
that other kind of stuff. No,
I don't mind the comic books when I was
a kid. But this whole fucking thing,
like I don't like how nerds go there
and they look at these people in
just peak human slash uh,
whatever, whatever else.
They are fucking alien a condition and
they actually have the balls to sit there
and say that they can relate.
You clearly haven't watched any
because you don't understand the whole,
like how the story goes for those putting
me, I haven't watched any, that's like,
they're all like allegories for stuff
going on and like actual life and like,
you know, human condition and
that type of thing. It's not just,
it's not that deep. It's not that deep.
I see it when I watch, when I watch it,
I'm saying I didn't need
you to explain that to me.
Well I know when I go see a Pixar movie,
I know I say Jews about global warming.
Okay, but you're, I mean,
I'm just saying though,
you're acting like you don't know cause
you're, you're very, uh, your leg.
Very dismissive of the people who
like, uh, the, the superhero stuff.
Don't you want to stand? My business
formula is attacking popular shit.
Oh, right. Uh Huh. Yeah. Oh,
you don't think it's working?
All right. I, I've Shit on
star wars since day one,
which they keep taking new ones and
they're doing better and better.
Not since day one.
I liked it when I was a kid.
MMM.
All right. Well, I guess she's
gone again. See that look,
see how that just worked there. All right,
let's get back to slandering my wife.
What are your hobbies? Flying helicopters.
Playing drums, slandering. My wife
is something else in the said and she
said it's specifically about white people
in North Carolina.
She was like,
I'd have all that dumb
southerners that are out there.
White people in North Carolina.
She never said that.
MMM.
Sorry, I'm typing in my password
here. All right. It's three to one in.
There's one period left.
Okay.
And I don't think there's anybody
relaxed right now on either side of this
fucking red line. All right. I'll tell
you when you got someone of that caliber,
Austin Matthews and whatever Tavares
his first name is, and I'll tell you,
Addison is no slouch doe at this
score a take away from all these kids,
but playing for these first five games
to this series, I'll tell you right now,
the Bruins, I mean I know they're
happy to be up to two goals here,
but they still got their work cut out
for him. By the way. I didn't see it.
Did anybody see the fucking
rough and rowdy in West Virginia?
How bought a fucking round of
applause for West Virginia?
Everybody's always shitting on them.
Okay.
But no one ever talks about how
fucking entertaining they are.
You never going to see
a group of people jet,
I mean the level that they threw them.
So just the highlights from those fights.
You see that fucking guy,
he was getting fucking
lit up by the other duty,
just ducked down like Marshawn back in
the day when he would tip somebody over,
he fucking went down, pick this guy up
and just body slammed. It became like an
MMA event. Um, and I have a, uh,
I actually, I retweeted the, the, uh,
the clip from a Dan Katz centered over a,
or tweeted it out. How the fuck you
supposed to say? Rough and rowdy.
I'll tell you right now
that rough and rowdy,
the more rough and rowdy
the city they go to,
the more rough and rowdy it becomes.
Um,
okay.
I miss going to those fucking events.
I want to fucking the next one
that comes out. If I'm not fucking,
I'm always working.
I've got to stay home one night.
Yeah.
With a bunch of other comics that were
just off that night and I want to watch
that fight. Well, maybe I'll just tape
it. Why don't I do that? I Dunno, Bill,
there's a lot of technology out there.
Jesus Christ.
Do I need some fucking reads at
this point? All right. Here we go.
Oh my God.
I thought I had a new advertiser.
I thought there was a new
website called my for skin.
Okay.
It's actually an email says my
wife is disgusted by my, for skin.
That is the dumbest shit ever.
It's like she'll get fucking had
it when you met her. You grew one.
Yeah.
Jesus Christ. Will you coming down
the aisle and she's just like,
why am I marrying this
guy with an ugly Dick?
Isn't that ridiculous?
How they fucking,
they just mutilate you the second you
come out and women find a mutilated man.
Disgusting. Can you imagine
that? Aimia you know what?
I find your clip disgusting.
Sorry, I'm just trying to get
her back in here. Um, all right,
let's do some reads here. Oh, look
who's here. Everybody. Old Zip
hiring used to be had multiple job sites,
stacks of resumes,
a confusing review process. Why do
I have to take off my shirt? But,
but today hiring can be easy
and you only have to get,
you only have to go to one
place to get it done. Zip
recruiter.com/burb
ZipRecruiter's sends your job,
sends your job to over 100 of
the web's leading job boards,
but they don't stop there with them.
Powerful matching technologies,
zip recruiter's scans, thousands of
[inaudible] emails, thousand sorry.
Sizes of resumes to find people with
the right experience and invites them to
apply for your job to your job
as applications come in. Zip.
Okay?
Yeah.
Analyzes each one and spotlights the
top candidates so you can see you never
match.
So you never miss a great match.
Help me out here now and right
now my listeners can get old zip
for free at this exclusive website,
ziprecruiter.com/ [inaudible] that's
ziprecruiter.com/bar spell it out,
Z I pee.
Bye.
R E C R U I t r.
Dot com slash burr.
Ziprecruiter is the smartest
way to hire simply safe.
10 years ago, getting home
securities stunk. It was silly.
It was a soliloquy.
Uh,
it felt like companies went out of their
way to make your life miserable with
long contracts.
She never knew what you'd get.
You'd pay and they made you
rewire your whole, whole home.
This was normal.
Then simply safe comes along and
totally transforms home security.
They did everything right. They built a
better system and they treat you right.
Simply safe stands up to the
unexpected from burglars to blizzards,
to blackouts,
blizzards.
What is it safe to when there's a
blizzard out? So keep your jewelry warmer.
Let's have an internal heater,
blackouts, Nia, um, anyways,
all those little swim goggles for,
you know who that I mentioned? What a
good swimmer. My daughter is already.
She doesn't even use floaties anymore.
She's just on that little let long
little worm float tube thing, whatever.
They got the noodle crushing it.
A simply safe as 24,
seven professional monitoring and police
dispatch everything to keep your home
safe. It's a PC mag readers
choice and a wire cutter top pick.
And it one's seanet editor's
choice twice and simply safe.
Makes your life easy.
There's no contract,
no hidden fees and no rewiring your home.
You already said that 3 million people
are protected by simply safe already and
not one of them is locked into a contract.
Checkout. Simply save for yourself.
Visit simply safe bird.com.
That's s I, m P, l, I,
safe Burr,
um,
dot com and you'll get free shipping and
free returns plus a 60 day money back
trial. Uh, what else do we got is the
last one for the love of fucking Christ.
stamps.com. Always the headliner
first. They are last to leave.
Here we go. stamps.com no one really
has time to go to the post office.
You're busy. Who's got time
for all that traffic, parking,
lugging all your mail and
packages. It's a real hassle, man.
That's why you need stamps.com one of
the most popular time saving tool tools
for small businesses.
stamps.com eliminates trips to the
post office and saves you money with
discounts that you can't
even get at the post office.
Simply safe uses your computer
to print official US postage.
24 seven for any letter, any
package, any class of mail,
anywhere you send your mail,
uh,
once your mail is ready you
just handed to your male Carrie,
Carrie or drop it in a mailbox. It's
that simple. stamps.com is a no brainer.
Saves you money, time and
money. So sorry is a no brainer,
saving you time and money.
It's no wonder 700,000
small businesses already
used stamps.com right now.
My listeners get a special offer that
includes a four week trial plus postage
and a digital scale without any longterm
contracts. Just go to stamps.com.
Click on the microphone at the top
of the homepage and type in bird.
That's stamps.com enter bar. All
right. How much should we up to?
We're up to 42 minutes here near,
we're in the break between
the second and third period.
The Bruins are up three games to one
and I think I owe it to my listeners to
podcasts right through the end of
this game. If they give a fuck right.
By the way,
congratulations to the second batch
of stand up comics that went up on our
premium blend style show
for comedy central. Uh,
my good buddy Josh Adam Meyers closed
out the second one and absolutely
murdered.
Um,
so many people had fucking
monster is sets during this, uh,
during the taping and they made all things
comedy look really good and a comedy
central was psyched and uh,
hopefully we'll get to do it some more.
And I loved the whole process,
getting to meet all these young comics
up and come and getting to know who's the
funny people and whatnot.
And uh,
I dunno. Uh, it was, it was, I
think they, we got a home run there.
So anyways,
let's get to some of the emails here
for the week and then we'll watch the
Bruins game together.
We,
although I imagine a bunch of people in
Toronto will be fucking turning this off
if it stays the same or if they
have a miraculous comeback.
Here's the deal. Uh, I'm going to do
it until fucking the end of regulation.
I'm not gonna fucking,
I'm not going to keep going and you know,
one of these fucking triple
overtime games. Um, all right. Okay.
Emails, Kate Smith,
dear Billy booboo bird,
check out this video about the
God bless America controversy.
Classic case of generations
not understanding each other.
Love you and love the podcasts.
All right, let's check this out.
God bless America. Hey,
why is it when you know,
every time?
Um,
all right,
morning yesterday that the game he's
quit claims Ms Rendition of God bless
America during the seventh inning
stretch after the club was made aware of
Smith's potential racism this morning,
newspapers in Philadelphia report it
fliers or cutting ties with Smith to know
when a statue honoring her with a
blanket. Smith, a popular singer,
the 1940s.
Do you know what's hilarious? I got to tie
them out. That thing that they covered,
the thing that they just covered Kate
Smith statue up with made her look like
she was the next level. She looks, it
looks like she's wearing a Klan Hood,
except it's all black like this,
you know,
the grand wizard clan guys,
I think he has a couple extra patches.
It's Kinda like this cub scouts
except with a lot more hatred. Um,
are you kidding me?
Ties with Smith to covering a statue.
Honoring her with a blanket.
What is the evidence opera singer in the
1940s has been dead since 1986 she rose
to fame in 1938 when Jewish composer,
composer,
urban Berlin Railroad,
God bless America,
specifically for Smith and as a peace
time protest of Adolf Hitler because of
Smith's rendition.
God bless America became this
country's second national anthem.
Wait a fucking minute. What is
this shit? This new evidence.
Katie Smith racist evidence.
I mean, what did she send a text
message? Somebody just bomb.
Okay. Wait a second. Wasn't
everybody racist back then?
Cause even if you are liberal,
what you thought was nowhere near where
the fuck we are now. This is so dumb.
This is really bad,
man.
You can't fucking go back when somebody's
not alive to defend themselves.
All right. How come nobody
back then said she was racist?
Is that because everyone was
racist back then? And if they were,
wasn't she just evict them of her time
with the information that was available?
I mean there was time people walked
around, they thought slavery you. Yet.
It makes sense to me cause that's
what people did it. That's you know,
there's a lot of shit
we're doing right now.
Do you think you're going to fucking get
to 80 and look back on shit you didn't
your 20s, you're like, oh my God,
I can't believe we used to do shit or
said that are eight data thought this all
right.
Who says one fan can't make a difference?
It was one fan who contacted the Yankees
about cage Smith's racist singing
background that caused them to remove
the God bless America from the seventh
inning stretch which cause Stefan Bondy
of the New York Daily News to write
about it,
which also caused the Philadelphia flyers
to not only remove her song but cover
up the statue outside the extent,
uh, expanded he live as well.
I spoke with Bondi before his insight
edition experience it appearance.
He said, I obviously didn't
expect the reaction that it got.
Well what did you think was gonna Happen?
Says Bondi,
but I think it's a sign of the times in
a good sign that the flyers also reacted
the way they did.
Meanwhile,
the Redskins are still called the
Redskins. None of this shit makes sense.
So as Katie Smith really a racist or
struggling artists trying to get work,
nobody knows, and I think that's still
part of the investigation. Bondi said,
well then what the fuck?
How are you going to investigate that
after she's dead and everybody else who
was part of the class was dead.
How are you going to investigate this?
You just slandered somebody fucking name.
Speaking of slander,
there's not been much as to
who Kate Smith is as a person.
There hasn't been any stories to
suggest that she did anything racially
insensitive in her private life.
But there are these songs.
Bonnie said she was born in the south,
raised during the time of Jim Crow laws,
yet this isn't her fault. It
was a racist time. They were.
These were different times and
some of the things she said
would have been racist back then.
You still get to pick
what,
wait a second,
and some of the things she said
would have been racist back then.
You still get to pick some of the songs
you sing. This is these fucking people.
Who is this Brody person and let me,
can we investigate your life through
this level? You never said anything.
You didn't do anything.
You didn't laugh at somebody.
Can We destroy your fucking life now,
but a fucking sack over your head?
What about the fact that these songs
were recorded so long ago when the times
were so different? Obviously says, I
look at it talking to his Bondi person,
like this person,
some sort of expert.
I'm sure it was interpreted differently
in 1939 but it's not 1939 yeah,
but it was when she did it
this shit back then. Dude.
That's like when they
come up with a new law.
You can't prosecute somebody for doing
something yesterday that today is now
illegal,
but it's not 1939 and that song is being
played to all sorts of people of race
and color and creed at
Yankee Stadium in 2019 yet,
God bless American at the racist song.
I don't get this.
I don't get this at all.
I don't get, I don't get this. Then
they try to get the flyers in trouble.
You can also add the flyers to that
list is people not playing the song,
but one has to wonder what
would they have done if it,
if it were game seven of the Stanley Cup
finals and they played this song before
the last three wins.
This is all this is.
This whole fucking error is just
trying to get people in trouble.
I think when you do something like that
to somebody, they should immediately,
they should immediately
investigate your life.
If you're going to take somebody down,
we're not gonna investigate your life
to see if we need to take you down too.
And you know what?
Watch everybody shut the fuck up
because we're all guilty of something
myself included. Give me a fucking break.
We've all done shit. We've all said Shit.
We, I mean part of life
is growing as a person.
I bet if you asked her
at the end of her life,
what do you think about those songs?
I bet she did have a different
opinion than when the fuck she sung.
It didn't even say how old she
was when she sang the song.
It's so fucking stupid. I think that's
ridiculous. I think it's ridiculous.
And it's this fucking thing that
white people who live now do,
and they try to act like they're trying
to be brave and sensitive and what
they're really doing is they're using
somebody else to fucking show how awesome
they are as something it's I big.
It's all self serving.
I don't know. And I'm also assuming this
person's white check probably shouldn't,
but I dunno. I just know all of my black
friends, when I brought that country,
it's about John, John Wayne.
They all just laughed. Like,
who gives a fuck about a dead white guy?
We're dealing with the white people
that are still alive. All right.
Ukraine president. Uh, dear bill,
President Day Oh oh oh
to virus point blank.
58 58. So up by two Corollas. Dear Bill,
President Date A, theirs is hope
for the world. Oh, thank God.
Hey guys, how about some more positive
shit too? By the way, a company,
a comedic personality from the Ukraine,
just beat the incumbent in a
landslide to become president. What
is that a good thing?
Yeah.
I don't think I want a fucking
clown run in my country. Uh,
when are you running and
what's your slogan going to be?
A what will you do about the Middle East?
Who will be your vice?
All right, I'll answer these questions.
Uh, is what I do about the Middle East.
Toronto just scored.
Oh,
and now ladies and gentlemen,
we have a fucking game here.
Was that Austin Matthews again?
He's fucking awesome.
Oh my God.
They keep getting us with that fucking,
let me watch this replay.
Oh my God. He came eat. Oh.
Tuco went from right to left and then
he shot it over his right shoulder like
the fucking sniper that he is top shelf.
And look at the look on his face.
Look at him. Jesus Christ. All right bro.
Oh fuck me.
Fuck me.
I was relaxed and now I am not.
Toronto wins the face
off in the Bruin zone.
All right. Just relax. Don't be a bunch
of punk. Jason. Jackasses and just fuck,
fuck. Oh boy. Oh boy. Oh
they got the puck. Oh Jesus.
They go day to day.
Okay.
All right. I can't watch this shit. Here
you go. Take the fucking body something.
Anyways,
um,
hey man, what the fuck was talking about?
Oh, how I would solve the Middle East.
All right. First of all, I would
convert this country to solar power.
I would enact that guy from Tesla's
plans for that solar shit on the roads.
And then is is,
is I would just convert all
of this to solar. All right?
And uh, I would give, you know, all of the
money to the oil companies and just say,
listen,
you're going to be out of this fucking
business and we're going to help you go
over to this other business.
All right?
So you're still getting all the
money from the energy you cons.
And then what's going to happen is there's
going to be no fucking money in the
Middle East and then they won't have
any money to finance the terrorism.
And then we're going to get the fuck
out of there and leave them alone.
Okay.
That's what we're going to do.
And then they can fucking live their
lives and we're going to live our lives.
And then,
uh, I dunno if I would
have the power to do this,
but I would go and I would evict all
the Jews out of Israel and all the
Palestinians out of Palestine.
Fuck. Where would I put them?
I gotta Give Him Beach Front property
cause it seems to be really important to
those people.
Cool.
I give them all timeshares in Florida,
Boca Raton,
we get Ahca poco going again,
you know?
No, there's no, there's no
self in the Middle East.
But I would get us the fuck out of
that Hornets nest is what I would do.
And I would leave those people alone
because it's their countries and they
should be able to figure out what
the fuck goes on in their countries.
And I'd converted to solar power.
That's what I was doing.
My vice president would be
somebody way smarter than me
and I would have them sound out all the
big words in my speeches before I went
on TV. So you guys all thought I
was smart and you kept the faith.
All right. Then I would go to
blackwater and I would, uh,
I would carve out a deal with them,
um,
where we would take the
banking system back. All right.
And, uh, we just whack
a couple of top bankers.
I didn't think we'd have to do that.
We would just walk in and take them over.
Take over. The banks are too big to fail.
Is that what you think daisy? All right.
Their friend and they would
all go to fucking jail. Okay.
And then the next one I would go to,
let's just like in a perfect world,
like every,
like all the politicians who get paid
by all these fucking crooked cops would
somehow come along with me.
Then I would go to the food fucking
industry and I would get al of those cons
the fuck out of there.
I'd find I'd go through their files
and find out what's really in our food.
And simultaneously you'd go
to the pharmaceutical, uh,
fucking industry and find
out why the fuck what,
what they knew about
fentanyl and all of this.
Because I've had a bunch of
people that I know affected by it.
I've had friends die, I've had,
uh, friends have children die.
It's just been fucking awful. That's
what I would do. And then, um,
I would,
uh,
and then the last thing I would do
was I would try to have some sort of a
recycling program that works. And, um,
I dunno if that's what the fuck
I would do and my vice president,
who would it be?
Who would it be?
Um, oh, I, I get al Franken.
I'd have him as a vice president.
Goats, all comedians in office.
MMM.
I Dunno.
I try to just get people that actually
give a shit about people rather than
power and money. Like all of these
other fucking assholes, like the bushes,
the Obama's, the trumps, the
Clintons, they just all bad people.
Like, I feel like the last human being
that was an office was Jimmy Carter
and
you know,
let me look at the guy.
What has he done since he's retired
other than build 4,000 houses for the
fucking homeless, all these other
fucking assholes. What do they do?
They go in though the,
the speech tour and they go out and they
give speeches to the biggest fucking
anti American goddamn corporate crooks.
Don't even get me started on this shit.
I want to give me fucking started.
Yeah.
Where everybody loves fucking Obama in
his first two speeches and with two of
the biggest fucking predatory
banks from fucking 2008. I mean,
it's like they don't even try to hide,
but he's got a blue tie. So I like them.
It's like these fucking morons.
It's that can't even admit that
Trump is a fucking dope. I get it.
You're Republican. I get it. You're
conservative. I get it. You want a wall?
I get all of that. If that's what the
fuck you want. And I respected it.
Fucking take it to the point where you
can't say that this guy's a bit of a
fucking, you know, I understand
wind. Uh, I know all about the wind.
I mean the fact that you're comfortable
with that being your leader. I mean,
I don't know what the fucking say to you.
Yeah.
That is as annoying as people who prop up.
Okay.
You know,
the Obama's like,
these were these great fucking people
rather than they were your typical
politicians that had their
faces in the fucking pig trough.
Just like all of them.
MMM.
No, he wears a different
color tie. He wears the color
tie that I like. All right,
let's get on.
Let's not talk politics here.
It just makes me annoyed and then I
start acting like I can solve all the
problems and that I know things that I
really don't. So why don't we avoid that?
Although that could be
part of the entertainment
though, right? Um, all right.
What's the next thing here? Jesus
Christ. This is a long email.
Why the fuck is this here?
Wife's a douchebag. Jesus Christ.
Noisy sex. Ukraine president. Okay.
MMM.
Noisy neighbors having sex.
Dear Bill,
you are one of my favorite
car of a thank you. Bye.
Problem is I can hear my
neighbor's having loud, obnoxious.
Well, it's the only way it's obnoxious
is if they're doing it to annoy you,
they might be lost in
the throes of passion.
When was the last time we want to
fucking face off in this fucking game?
MMM.
Anyways,
uh,
loud,
obnoxious sex at various times of the day,
I left a note to them
addressing the problem.
They left a condescending response
back with their phone number in it.
Why on earth would I want to
discuss their sex life with them?
Oh, I would've called them back
in a second. As you can see,
I'm in quite the pickle here.
That is my next move.
Uh,
and what should I do? Sinceriously
your biggest fan from New Paltz,
New York. Oh two this is easy.
Go get yourself a sound system.
All right? You got to do
a little research. Get us,
get a sound system point of speakers
at the walls of your neighbor's house.
All right? And then what should do, I
don't know if you can do a Google search.
Find the most obnoxious sex
sounds from a porno you watch.
You ever watch a porno and somebody is
like fucking over the top going like,
oh wow. Like, you know, and it
literally takes you out of it.
I would record that on a loop
and every time they have sex,
you know,
I would play that.
Or you just make a tape of
saying your mom's vagina,
your mom's vagina,
your mom's vagina is wet right now.
Just anything that will make that
guy lose his fucking hard on,
have fun with it.
And then just say that you're listening
to a new song by Yoko Ono and the
plastic ono band and you know,
I think you'll get away with it.
You gotta have fun with it, uh, recorded,
you know, have somebody animate it and
all of that shit with you and your fucking
yeah, send us, send us audio of it.
We, I have animators. I'll pay for it.
We'll fucking,
we'll fucking make a little cartoon
it and then do that other shit.
Just fucking annoying
back. Fuck them. Um,
and you also have their, uh, oh. And you
could like put their phone up now. Don't,
don't put their phone number out there
that there'll be a mean thing. Uh,
that'd be to meet taking it too far.
Ah. Alright. Wife's Douchebag boss.
Oh God.
Your wife has a douchebag boss.
So guess what you have to hear about
every night at dinner. What's up bill?
Billy Ball sniffer. Hoping forwards. Vice.
Why is Scott at douchebag?
Boss? Just a little background.
Oh, this is gonna be one of
these. No punctuations no
capital letters. No nothing.
Just a little background.
My wife is 45.
I'm 38 wife's Douchebag
boss 28 this jackass.
Thanks
this Jack has thinks it's
okay knowing she married.
Oh Jesus Christ. Dude. What the f this is
even a fucking, this isn't going centers.
This jackass thinks it's
okay knowing she's married.
Juju hit on her on a regular basis.
Little more backstory.
Last year at our Christmas party,
we were all drinking and he decided
there was okay to start hitting on her in
front of me. She has a great
job for a retail company in a,
in a, in a mall, make 70 k a year.
So I didn't want to screw it up, but
beating the ever living crap out of him
by, by beating the ever
living crap out of him.
I decided to let it slide the next day
he apologized and let it and I let it go.
Figuring he was just drunk,
whoever since he likes to throw
little comments about how she smells.
Nice is dress great.
The little prick even likes to walk up
behind her and brush up against her act.
Well, what the fuck? She can't just
go to human resources at this point.
You don't even need evidence to get where
you got like fucking evidence of this
shit.
Just do that.
He says,
cool.
I know my wife is not the cheating type
or she wouldn't be telling me all this.
Yesterday she came home,
send me upset and told me while she
was in the food court eating lunch,
he came up behind her and told her,
you think she would be great in bed.
So here's my question,
before I drag this little shit stain
down to the food court and po and pull a
good fellows and stick his fucking head
in the pizza oven, what should I do?
So I don't end up going to jail.
This advice would be great.
Maybe something from near, it's
near with an n, not meal with an m.
Um, now you can't do that because then
you're going to go to jail and he won't,
I don't understand why she
doesn't complain to somebody.
I mean,
at this point,
all she would have to do is go on
Twitter saying who the fuck he was in his
career would be over.
I think she can just threaten to do that.
But if you fucking say one more goddamn
thing to me, sexually or otherwise,
I will go online and I will end you
fucking career faster than you can say
Harvey Weinstein. Alright. Um,
I actually think she should
just go to human resources.
I don't know why she doesn't.
Uh,
but you should not go and beat the shit
out of this guy because you're going to
get caught and you're going to go to jail.
Um,
and then that guy is going to continue
PR and then you think he's brushing up
against your wife as then. Forget about
when. What about when you're locked up?
Don't do that. I think you should. You
should go to the proper channels here.
All right, advice. My wife
is disgusted by my, for skin,
a brother.
10 minutes to go 10 minutes ago.
Please tell me we're not playing.
Not to lose. I mean not to uh, yeah,
to not lose.
However the expression goes.
Oh boy. Oh boy. You know
they're going to tie it up.
You know they're going to tie it up.
Jay says Christ,
get it out of there.
Yeah.
Oh my God. What are we doing? What
are we doing? All right. Hey, billing,
Billingham, fire crutch. Love the
podcast and the advice you give.
First off,
I'm personally fine with my old twigs
and berries and haven't thought before
skin going to be an issue.
But recently my wife of two years
has confessed that it makes her gag.
I noticed her reluctance to the one
eyed snake from the first time we were
together.
My first thought was she didn't like them
face to face or maybe she was the size
was the size of my staff
that she didn't like.
It's not live very long,
but I am girthy and that's fine with me.
I like to make the joke. I may not be
able to touch the bottom of the tuna can,
but I can touch all the sides.
MMM.
Long story short.
Yeah.
She's asked slash demanded that I
get surgery to remove the excess.
I don't know how to take that.
Isn't love beyond the physical.
Thank you very much built. Um,
I'll tell you this right now.
There is no fucking way you could ever
tell your wife to do something like that.
Um, I don't know what to tell you, dude.
You need to talk to a professional
about this one. I can tell you this.
If someone was going to make me
remove something from my Dick, uh,
they would have to be in writing a
guaranteed number of blow jobs per month.
Here's the thing, dude, what do you,
if you do that and then she
still doesn't like your Dick,
you know there's been women that married
guys and then they get divorced and
then all of a sudden they have a
girlfriend. You find out they're gay.
Anything can fucking happen before
you start cutting shit off your Dick.
Fuck that. That Shit
Dick. I wouldn't do it.
I wouldn't do it.
I wouldn't do it. And I think it's
really fucked up that you know
that she married you.
If she was looking,
if she fucking went on a date with you
and the first time you took out your
little fucking a stumpy fifth thing there.
Aye
Is.
She should have been honest with the,
instead of fucking gross me out and
you guys could have left it at that.
Now she's two years into this shit.
This is,
this is all her fault for not fucking
communicating to you that she thinks
should dick is gross. And I'm
to tell you right now, dude,
do not fucking do that on any
level. Fuck you. This is my Dick.
This is the deck I showed up with and
this is the deck I'm leaving with.
Okay.
And if she walks, she fucking walks, dude.
Fuck that. I'm telling you right now.
Don't do it. I got a bag.
I remember platoon. I got a
bad feeling about this one,
man.
I got a bad feeling this
could you say to her, you
know, uh, you know, you're
fucking, I don't view your tits.
Gross me out.
I Dunno.
I Dunno man. I wouldn't do it.
Don't fucking do it. That's,
that's my advice. Do not do it. Keep
your dick all original matching numbers,
barn fine. Uh, Bruins. Almost
scored in that fucking breakaway.
God dammit. Then almost go had
a breakaway but did not score.
All right. Advice friend is,
isn't prison. Hey Billy boullion.
I have a huge problem that
needs some need. Your advice?
A friend of mine whom I've known since
the late nineties recently went to
prison. He was a great guy, funny guy.
And we have the same sense of humor.
We've stayed in touch for almost two
decades, sharing life's adventures,
family stories,
joys and sorrows.
So it was met with sadness when he emailed
me a few months ago to explain that
he was experiencing serious legal trouble.
They had a potential decade in prison.
Well, what did he do? Tax
evasion. Embezzlement.
He said he wasn't able to explain the
details of the case. Uh, touch somebody.
I emailed him back a week later to hope
things worked out, whatever it was.
I said I didn't need to know the
details because I believed he was a good
character.
Eventually his wife responded and said,
he's in prison. She offered to put
me in contact with them. All right,
well then he didn't touch somebody
if she's still fucking there.
And that's my guess,
eight 36 to go.
Um, all right, so until, uh,
today I kept in contact through the prison
email service and he's been friendly
and upbeat.
I didn't ask about his situation because
I thought that whatever he did can't be
that bad and he won't want to talk
about you is going to jail for 10 years.
He did fucking did something. Guys don't
talk about emotional stuff. After all,
I told him to stay positive and
just get through it the best he can.
I wanted to show him
pictures of my new car,
but the prison email can't do attachment,
so I asked my partner about
posting some photos. She go,
this president site, it's a federal
prison. She asked me what he's in for.
I honestly said, I don't know,
and she started snooping.
Oh boy.
Then we found a new story from town.
He pled guilty to having
thousands of Kiddie porn pictures.
There it is on his computer.
It's 100% him, no doubt.
Not a case of mistaken identity.
I feel so dumb for not googling
his name months ago. So bill,
my question is what do I do?
The easy answer is to ignore
him and cut him out of my life.
That was my first thought,
but I'm also human and he's alone.
Sitting in a prison cell,
realizing his mistake is possible to
someone still be a friend to this guy.
Can pedophiles change as far as
I've seen? No, not even remotely.
Could you somehow change
what you're attracted to?
You're attracted to what
you're attracted to.
I don't want to lose my friend
because I don't have many,
but he did unforgivable things.
I feel let down.
But he supported me as a friend
for 20 years. What do I do? Well,
I think you just answered it.
You,
you're a good friend
and he's a good friend.
But, uh, you just said what he did was
unforgivable. So if it's unforgivable,
you can't forgive him.
MMM.
I Dunno dude. I'm sorry. Go through. It's
pretty heavy fucking email. As a father,
it's easy to just cut them out of
your life too. You're a father,
you have kids yet you got
to get rid of this guy.
You gotta get rid of them anyways.
But imagine if you can,
if one of your good friends did this,
I can't forgive him.
But this moral ethical
decision is killing me.
Thank you very much for your
time and go fuck yourself.
The last email was long and takes a turn.
Wasn't sure if you want to read it or not,
but I threw it in there.
That's hilarious. He sent that
after he's after the email text.
Um, yeah. Uh,
if you think you owe it to him
as a friend to explain why.
MMM,
I would do that. But yeah, it's,
it's a rap and then I would just,
if you feel bad about it,
I would just talk to my wife about her
or if you feel you need to go talk to
somebody about it, I would do that.
Um, but dude, you got kids. You May,
you know those people that are sick,
there's something wrong with them when
they haven't been able to figure out how
to fix them. And you got to
protect yourself and your family.
So sometimes you know,
you got to choose yourself.
And I think this is an easy one.
You said it yourself.
What he did was unforgivable. All
right. That is the podcast. All right.
You guys have a great couple of days here
and I'll check in on you on Thursday.
Um, those of you who want to listen to
the final five minutes and nine, eight,
seven seconds of this fucking game,
uh,
you can listen to the rest
of this fucking podcast.
Yeah.
All right. Now we're in, now
we're in overtime for the podcast.
Get fucking so Dadi sleeping.
Just screamed and I yelled the f word.
Oh, Toronto is on the edge
of their fucking seats here.
I love going.
They keep fucking Shannon Tucows name
like Keith that's going to rattle him.
He's been playing great.
They scored on a deflection.
Do you know,
can't blame a goalie for
a deflection. Um, men,
the second one was a nice goal.
I could live with both of those,
especially if they don't score another
one bro and spring in the pocket to the
Czar God,
down half wall
retina by some con from Toronto.
Why didn't you fucking
Ah,
Jesus? Now they've got to
clear the zone. Oh my God,
it was right there. You know what
happens when you miss one of those?
The other team fucking scores.
Jesus Christ
to viruses. Matthews out there too.
They're on a different line. Thank Christ.
You know at the end of the game,
that bolt's going to be out there.
The fucking goalie pulled. Why
do I do this? Why don't, why?
Why do I give a shit? You know?
Look at his asshole standing up.
Get the fuck out of the way.
Oh, look at that sweet rebound. Just
sitting there waiting to be picked up.
Let me turn this up so
you can at least hear it.
Okay.
Three Oh nine ago,
three Oh eight to go.
Yeah. You know you want to game seven
right? Tell me you want to game seven.
That's right.
Two one one
oh,
action.
Dapa down the ice.
Okay.
Yeah. Calm the Bruins. Here come the
Bruins. There comes one borough in any way
for a stoppage of play to 38 to go.
He just goes, it's wonderful, isn't it?
Now if your heart's in a fucking game,
it's wonderful.
If you don't give a shit about,
I'm a Calgary flames fan
and I'm watching this.
I'm fucking probably having a good
time cause my team's already out of it.
Ah, boy. You know what I didn't take
into consideration here is commercials.
You guys watching the Lexus
going around the race track?
Lexis is a great car for the
money. Huh? I'd like to think so.
Was that shot in areas?
Um,
in Australia they give me some militant
vegans running out in front of them
because the fucking,
I'm so glad they moved onto this guy.
This progressive commercials
is progressive. What is this?
The guy with the parrot, I couldn't stand
that one with that Asian chick going,
Woo. How? Like what the fuck was that for?
White person did that,
that you'd be in trouble.
Okay.
Ooh, child. All right.
No, I hit pause. Then they got
a black guy dancing with food at
Tgi Fridays. We what?
What is, what is going on?
It's like progressive
and then it goes back.
All right.
Okay.
Real estate.
Everybody's doing commercial stuff.
There's more celebrities and commercials
in there are super hero movies,
you know. All right. Back to the game.
Challis McAvoy getting a skate on that.
Okay.
How the fuck did Matthew's miss that?
Because probably in the year,
I know it wasn't his fault
and Nakira fucking gold score.
He's fucking imitating crazy there.
Okay.
Innocent big time saves.
You know what else he has?
He has big time rebounds and I got it.
Thank y'all bro.
Ones are going to be there to pick one up.
Come on.
Come on Bruins till 36 to 35
there you go. Keep it near
end. Cycle it around dog.
Half Wall.
Come on. Come on. You fuckers.
Yeah.
Oh Jesus.
Get it out of there.
The fuck are we doing two minutes to go
through the fucking Toronto
scores and found two minutes.
I'm shutting this fucking thing off.
Ah, game seven everybody. Oh my God.
Listen to how fucking quiet is in there.
Why the fuck did they pull the goalie?
You're only down by one goal. I don't,
I don't fucking get debt,
but the minutes ago maybe.
Yes.
Fucking Marshawn man.
He's the best.
Okay.
He's the best deck. He's just
fucking money. He's just money.
Yeah.
Oh, all the Bruins to score for
Toronto fans to get pissed off at
all. Right. Not a respect for the Toronto
Maple leafs. I watched the rest of this
may believe. Fan staying there.
Look at this. Very impressive.
What a fan base like those
Montreal Canadien fans.
They would all fucking take it off.
Oh,
is that a tripping call?
What?
Just white?
Yeah.
Minute 22 to go.
The always dangerous Austin
Matthews. All right. Out of the zone.
I can never skate like then. These
fucking guys, defense men are amazing.
That fucking asshole sat down. Didn't
he? Down by two goals? Probably left.
Yeah.
Get it out of there.
Get it out of there, please. Ah,
fuck. Not this guy. Not this guy.
Yeah.
You know somebody who's
got this fucking game,
that gambling and they gonna
fucking pull the goalie like this.
Don't they care about gamblers? Aw, look
at that. Just swallowed it up. No rebound.
Unlike Anderson.
Yeah.
Oh, we got a game. Seven.
We got a game. Seven.
Yeah.
Look at that fucking pass.
Unbelievable.
Tuukka Rask is always there. Yeah.
Chan his name now. Toronto fans.
Jan His fucking name now,
not by any means saying we're going
to win this series. I'm just saying,
I'm just glad it's going to go seven here.
Okay.
Huge. Like a Babcock.
What a great coach. Callow
yeah,
what exactly is saying there's 31
fucking seconds left, you know.
Alright.
If he could score on a face off in the
zone and then somehow after the face off,
yeah, you can score at the
red line. Can we do that then?
Maybe score again and we can get
out of here. Not going to overtime.
Yeah.
Uh,
[inaudible] Boston Bruins
back out to center ice.
Yeah.
Hi. How many times can they be Toronto
in a fucking playoff series when we'll
Toronto get the fucking first
round monkey off their back.
I'm not going to lie to you. I thought
they had us. I thought they had us,
especially the first 10
minutes of this game.
And that's why I'm not a professional
athlete because I am a quitter.
And you'll Boston Bruins do not quit.
Fuck.
Why is Austin Matthews always on the side
of the side of the fucking net within
the two cars?
On the other side,
just just sitting there
with his stick on the ice.
16.7 seconds to go near.
There's gotta be a game. Seven.
Perfect.
All right. You don't have to listen
to the final 16.7 seconds. All right,
everybody, thank you for listening to
the bonus time here on the podcast.
Congratulations to the Bruins.
Animate believes great playoff series.
Who knows who's going to win,
but a game seven is on Tuesday,
14 seconds.
(312) 111-0987 fucking icing again.
Jesus fucking Christ.
5.4 now I've got to stick it out,
right? Said I was going to stick it out.
Okay.
You don't. Yeah, you know me, right
when I say I'm going to stick it out,
I stick it out,
right?
Didn't that used to be my bathrobe?
It used to be.
It used to be my bathrobe
and then she took it.
Look at this guy
fucking referee.
Bet the over as far as time goes.
How long this game would take
kicking people out of a face,
off fucking 5.4 seconds left. 42
game. There you go. That's the
ballgame. Fucking huge, huge victory.
Congratulations to your Boston Bruins.
All right.
I'll check in on you on Thursday.