Yeah.
Hey, what's going on? It's Bill Burr.
It's time for the Thursday afternoon.
Just before Friday.
Monday morning podcast and
[inaudible].
I'm just checking in on you.
You're not going to believe what the,
what I just did a,
you probably will have in you listened
to this thing enough to know that I'm a
fucking moron. You're not going
to believe what I just did.
Why don't you do bill? Well, I just
recorded the Thursday afternoon podcast.
Right. And I forgot my cord that I
usually end up, I have a routine.
The second I do it, I upload it and
I'm done, but I forgot the cord,
the UCB Chord, whatever the fuck it is.
USBC fucking public bank cord. Yeah.
So it took me out of my routine and I
just wanted to like robot mode and I
fucking erase the podcast.
I just did.
Why would I do that? I was
so psyched. I was done.
I just came back from Boston, dude.
I came, you know, I woke up early,
I'm still on east coast time. My
beautiful daughter, lovely wife.
I was sleeping, I paid all the fucking
bills. I got everything ready to go.
All the way to do is knock out my podcast.
It's a quarter, eight in the morning.
I'm done. My kids just getting up,
I'm ready to make everybody breakfast.
I'm crushing it.
And what do I do?
I just had a race and I hit a race
and you know, once she had her race,
she can't stop it from a racing.
And I was like going, oh my God,
what did I just do? And it's just, it gone
over.
So now the big thing is,
is I can't compete with myself
from a half an hour ago.
All right?
I can't be looking into the past and
thinking about what I talked about.
I need to go into the fucking,
yeah.
All right.
I hope you guys all have
a merry Christmas. Okay.
Have you noticed Mary
only goes with Christmas?
Do you notice that it's happy Hanukkah.
It's happy Kwanzaa.
It's go fuck yourself and it's
merry Christmas. Isn't that weird?
Mary Hanukkah.
Merry Kwanzaa.
Okay.
Marry Muhammad.
What is their Christmas?
MMM.
Have a merry, merry Mohamed Edge.
The best time of the year.
Buddha do to do.
I know there won't be snow
cause we're in the Middle East.
They have any moms out there.
Do people go skate and I rack?
Have I ever sewed a dumber
in my life? Well, you know,
considering I just recorded a podcast
and then promptly fucking erased it
promptly.
Like within fucking two minutes. That's
all I'm gonna do. I'm gonna Bitch,
Moan and complain and whine about what
I just did rather than move on with my
life. All right, setting the
tone for 2018 once again,
we're going to look back rather
than being in the moment.
That's one of my goals for 2018
is to tell somebody who tells me to
be in the moment to shut the fuck up.
And when they say, well, I
like, Hey, I'm in the moment.
You're annoying me in this moment.
Now that moment's gone.
I'm still talking about it. Did I
not take your advice? You can't.
Can you stop acting?
Is there anything,
you know some of the most spiritual
people have the most fucked up lives?
Are you enjoying it? Did you take it in?
Did you take a moment to fucking chill
the fuck out of my face?
MMM.
Anyway, sorry. Sorry. Whatever.
Whatever. Well, this four minutes.
All right. Four minutes. I just, I
just got it back. Oh, guess what?
I got some big news for you.
Um,
after a 131 days of being sober,
oh, GH. Oh,
Billy red face fell off the fucking wagon.
Um,
I put up a good fight right through
the holidays. I made it to December 26.
What kind of a fucking
asshole falls off on the 26?
I can see New Year's Eve. I could, I mean,
Christmas Eve I could see Christmas Day.
I can see New Year Z,
but the 26th and the history of
people falling up the fucking wagon,
who falls off on the 26? What do
you, what are you crying about?
The fact he didn't get a fire
engine the day before for Christmas?
Um, yeah, fell off.
I'm going 131 days and very
proud of myself. I, yeah,
I can definitely, I was definitely in
the moment. Uh, this is what happened.
Um, first of all, I had,
I had the best Christmas I've had since
I was a little kid and I still believed
that some fat stranger came
down the chimney. All right.
Uh, it was awesome. And
I was actually like,
I had a lot of stress about it because
I was flying back with my lady and my
lovely daughter and I was thinking like,
oh my,
all I've ever heard is people talking
about flying back with an infant.
It's a nightmare. Everyone,
you know? Yeah. You know,
by the end you're ready to get a
divorce and all this type of shit.
I gotta tell you something.
It was the fucking best Christmas I've
had since I was like eight years old.
When did I find out there was
Jake and the fat man was bullshit.
When did they find that
out? Uh, first grade
I found out in first grade because my
older brother found out in third grade and
he quickly told me,
and I remember I wasn't mad either. I
actually felt like an adult, like, oh wow,
man, I'm in a, I'm in on the
secret. Right. So anyways,
uh, coming back with a kid ended
up being the greatest thing ever.
It just, it takes all the pressure
off of you in your relationship.
You just come back like
we got married,
we reproduced no more questions of when,
when,
when that's over.
And then the best thing too is you come
on with the toddler and all everybody
wants to do is interact with the kids.
So nobody's asking you about your life,
nobody's giving you the third, what do
you got going on? What are you doing next?
What do you think about this?
Are you sure you're going to do
that or is that the right move?
And next thing you know,
you're fucking boozing it up and
you're all fucking depressed. Um,
or getting into arguments or talking
politics of or guy, I dunno what,
um,
all of that was gone and I,
yeah,
it was just great.
Yeah.
I came in and he was like, how are you
doing? Oh my God, look at your daughter.
And then that was it. There was no, you
know, I got a lot of social anxiety.
Like when I go to like
parties and that type of shit,
I was always the guy up on the wall,
you know?
Yeah.
It's a bunch of guys sitting around
watching a game. Then I'm in my element.
But when once it becomes like this
social thing, there's no game on.
And uh,
I,
I don't know know there's all
this fucking weirdness going on.
You've got adults are so fucking
weird. You know, there's all this like,
it's just like the playground
when you were a kid,
but it becomes like an adult
shit, like a, you know,
I don't know.
Competing.
Yeah.
You know,
I don't know how much you make in dreams.
She getting married, whatever the fuck
you going through just becomes this,
all this, there's all these
storylines that are going on.
Okay.
Maybe that's why my wife
has always watching those,
those reality shows I guess.
Cause all of that shit that's just
going on. You know what I mean?
Of just watching people so caught
up in bullshit that, you know,
your neighbor gets a better spatular
than you and it like affects your fucking
mood.
MMM.
So anyways, so we went back
there and just watching people,
meeting my daughter and her like,
you know, her big thing now,
she knows she just waves
at everybody and uh,
she could say hi now, although
she, she's yet to say it,
she looks in the mirror and says me.
And then she also says hi,
and I've yet to see her
do either either or.
Although there's video of her saying hi.
Um,
anyways, everybody was,
you know, flip his, she,
she, she killed it. She killed
it. She was a little starlet.
Everybody absolutely loved her and
her personality is really coming out.
And, uh, I got to tell you what's
really fucking crazy is like,
the more her personality develops,
like the more I love her.
It's crazy. Like every time
you think he hit the ceiling,
like I could not love this kid anymore.
There's like another level.
And um,
I always hated when I didn't have a
kid and people will go in like it,
you don't get it. You don't get it. It's
like, dude, I hit the kid, you know,
hate to say this, but, uh,
they were right. They were.
Right. But I haven't said that.
I will never tell somebody they
don't get it. Who doesn't have a kid?
That's a douchey thing to see. Now.
You don't get it. You don't care. Yeah,
neither did Jill. All right.
Stop acting like you're smart.
All right. There's 10
minutes. 21 minutes to go. Um,
so, uh, I don't know. It's
just so many great things.
Uh, I got together and jammed
with a couple of my brothers.
We used to play used to butcher hair
metal tunes back in the 80s into the early
nineties.
We had not gotten together
and try attempted to play
music in almost 24 years.
And one of my brothers, uh, rented this
place. Uh, I got to give him a shout out.
It's in Somerville,
Somerville,
which was known as
Slummerville when I was a kid.
Now it's all hipstery with like cupcakes
and fucking burger joints and shit.
Um, it's like a upscale
thing, right? And uh,
this place is called the jam spot
out in Somerville, Somerville Lumber,
that's all I remember from out
there. It was, uh, uh, the jams.
Paul was just a beautiful clean place.
Rooms were awesome.
All the equipment was the shit.
And the guy who worked there was just a,
just a great guy. Family man actually
got a kick out of the fact that a,
we were all brothers going to go down
there and play and we hadn't been playing
together.
Then that fucking long.
We went in there and we
butchered some songs.
Sounded all right though.
And then at the end a couple more of
my relatives came down and like doing
karaoke at the end and they sang and we
actually had the place from 12 to four
in the afternoon.
I remember thinking like two,
two hours is going to be more than enough.
We know like six songs from almost,
you know,
a decade and a half ago.
We're going to play for about 20 minutes,
then we're just going to be
staring at each other. And um,
that's actually not what happened.
It flew by and uh,
what we were trying to work
on a couple of songs, uh,
ACDC walk all over.
You touched too much highway to hell.
We always had that one down.
And uh,
then one of my brothers always
played Stevie ray Vaughan,
so we played a bunch
of that stuff. And, uh,
then a few more relative
showed up. Maxine, you know,
we played Zeplin the ocean
and uh, it was, it was just,
it was fucking awesome.
And then after that,
that's when we went out
and got a steak and a,
one of my other relatives
hadn't been drinking since June.
I had been drinking since August, so like,
we're going to do this. He's like, yeah,
let's do it. Fuck it. So
he orders a Johnnie Walker
black. I'm like, come on man,
we're going off the wagon after
six and four months. Say we got it,
let's get the blue. So we ordered
the blue, but it was a steak house,
so it was around the holidays
and they were out of it.
So I forget if we've got the gold or
the platinum, but it was really good.
And my buddy stopped at one,
I had one more and uh,
and then that was it.
We called it a night and then like two
hours later I was back in the hotel room.
I gotta be honest with you, I felt
like shit. And I was just like, wow,
I do not miss feeling like this. Um,
I don't think I like drinking anymore.
And then yesterday I went to the airport
and of course they are the American
Airlines terminal at Logan.
They have to Cisco Brewery and I love
Nantucket and I love Cisco Brewery.
So I'm like, well, I gotta go in there
and get a fucking beer. So I had the,
a whale's tail Pale Ale had that nurse,
that thing that was delicious. And
then I get on the plane, I'm like, Eh,
we don't have a fucking drink.
I know. Nah, don't do it.
Don't do it. Don't do it.
Right. Fortunately, uh,
I avoided that a, and um,
I think what I'm going to do is basically,
um,
I think,
yeah,
I'm just going to take a few days off
as far as not drinking and then just go
back on the wagon on January 2nd
I'm going to the road school.
I've got to have a couple
of cocktails when I'm there,
but I don't have to drink today. I don't
have to drink up until the rose bowl.
And I think that's just how I'm going
to boost rather than trying to go like a
whole fucking year and you know,
so many days or whatever.
I just think I'm just going to pick
my spots. So being at the Rose Bowl,
it's a playoff game. That's a good
time to have a couple of drinks.
And then I really don't see excuse to
have one for the rest of January. So
February or March, I don't really
don't see any event coming up.
Maybe a super bowl party,
I don't know.
But I think that's the way I'm going to
booze and I'll keep the weight off. Um,
I won't be a drunk dad or whatever.
And uh,
I think that's basically the
way I'm going to do it. But, uh,
my daughter actually caught a cold,
you know,
so many people picking up holding or,
you know, just that time of year was it?
I guess it was inevitable. So we were
flying back and I was like, Oh God,
six hours on the plane
with an infant with a call,
this is going to be a nightmare.
And actually, uh, she was a trooper.
She fell asleep for like the first,
like 40 minutes and then was just up
for the rest of the flight. And, uh,
she was a little bit whiny or whatever,
but anytime she would whine,
I just take it for a walk up
and down the aisle, you know,
cause I don't want to bug other people
in the plane with my crying kid. And, uh,
I never resented people
if their baby was crying.
The only time it bugged me is if they
just weren't making any sort of effort to
try to entertain the kid. So, uh,
I was just walking up and
down the aisle and, uh,
of course she went over the stewardesses
and then they will hold in her for a
minute. So it all worked
out. And I'm funny,
fucking dad moment changing a,
uh,
a diaper,
you know,
on the plane, you know, in the bathroom
there. I never even noticed it.
Got a little thing that
fucking comes down.
I sterilize the whole thing with one
of the wipes the best I could. And uh,
that's a big thing.
Making sure your kid doesn't
touch anything and then
you got a wipe down their
hands and their feet and
everything when they come back out.
But a change in a fucking shit
diaper during turbulence on a plane.
I was like, all right, this is it.
I'm officially a dad. I knocked
it out, I knocked it out.
And um, yeah, I got to
tell you something too,
like all the things that I loved about
my lovely wife, you know, seen one of,
see what an incredible
mother she is is uh, I dunno,
that's a whole other level too.
So whole other level.
So I don't know what to tell you. This
is weird. I'm actually really happy. So,
I don't know how know how funny
this fucking podcast is going to be,
but I had an awesome Christmas and,
um,
I was really at all this stress
thinking like, oh, I'm like,
all I've ever heard is, oh my
God, going back to holidays,
bringing your kids and everything.
It's like as a parent you don't get
to rest and blah, blah, blah, blah,
Blah and all that. Uh, I had
a great fucking time and um,
I was thinking that we were just gonna
fly back this time and then start
establishing Christmases out here by at
such a good time with like two days left.
I even sent an d, I was like, if you want
to do this again next year, I'll do it.
Cause you know, it snowed, it was
out. It was just, it was the shit.
And um,
yeah,
yeah. And my kid is awesome.
Even though she wears me out,
she'll literally wear me out and then
she'll finally go to sleep and then I
closed the door and I get this to,
you know, to lay down for a second,
like [inaudible] and like five minutes.
I'll just sit there and laugh and five
minutes later I just start thinking like
I miss her.
I was at possible,
how was that possible? But I
dunno. That's, that's how it works.
So I'm not complaining. Um, so anyways,
uh, oh, you know, when I could drink
again after the new year's, maybe, uh,
the night of the Patrice o Neal benefit
to get that plug in there. There you go.
The Patrice O'Neal comedy benefit,
uh, entering, it's, let's see,
is this the sixth or the seventh one?
I think the seventh,
right. Let's see here. 13, 14, 15, 16, 17.
18 is 61. And I want to thank
everybody that's been buying tickets.
We're almost sold out again
this year, which is really, uh,
it's truly amazing.
And um,
I have to thank Maureen Taren
and everybody else who, uh,
gives their time every year.
Jim Norton Calling Quinn, uh,
David Tell Bobby Kelly Dane Cook all of
his friends that have taken time out of
their lives and uh, it's just fun. You
know, it's like a high school reunion.
And then also to see like a,
you know,
we always have a couple of the
young, you know, I call them kids.
I went old fucked out, but, uh, and just
see, you know, they were teenagers when,
when Patrice is stuff staying up,
first started coming on TV and he
actually influenced them to be comedians.
So getting to hear those stories and
getting to see the young, the young guys,
the uh,
Michael Che's,
the Hannibal Burress is and see them
coming out and how funny they are and all
that. It's just, it's just
a great thing. So, uh,
I will once again tweak the link.
I'll keep tweaking it until we, uh,
sell the whole thing out.
But once again,
thank you to everybody who's been over
the years been a helping to support that,
a wonderful cause. And as always,
after we pay for the, uh, theater,
all the money goes to Patrice has loved
ones that he was supporting while he was
still alive, taking care of them. So, um,
with that,
what are we going to do now?
How are we going to talk a little sports
here? A little fucking sport. Oh Shit.
Do you know what I watched
what documentary I watched
that was only like an hour
and 20 minutes long, but it took
me six hours to watch because, uh,
my lovely daughter would not go to sleep.
I watched
this documentary called, uh, Newman.
Right.
So I was initially attracted to the
title cause I thought it was going to be
about Paul Newman, who's like one of
the coolest guys ever saw. I'm like,
I gotta watch this. See what
they're talking about. Right.
And uh, you know, what's
it going to be about?
It's going to be about racing
career is acting career or his,
uh, his charity. I always wondered
how involved he was with that.
I just can't see the great Paul Newman's
sitting there listening to people
talking about their balsamic vinegarette
or spaghetti sauce. Yeah, I bet.
I bet. At the beginning he just wanted
to have a business. He's just like,
I don't want to deal with this shit.
Just that, just fucking running,
give them money. The poor, um, by the way,
did you see some fucking jerk off?
Bought his watch,
his actual watch for 17 point $8 million.
What, what kind of a fucking
asshole then what do you do with it?
And you put it on like, oh, like I feel
as life force, maybe I can act now.
Maybe I'm cool.
Um,
I just don't,
I don't understand that type of shit.
I Dunno. I guess I do a little bit
maybe with like musical instruments.
I think it'd be cool to see a
couple of really famous instruments,
but I wouldn't want to own them.
Yeah.
You know, like if you had somebody
like some famous person's guitar,
they pass away and you have that guitar
and then you're playing their music on
that with your skill level. You
know, I know the guitar is an alive,
but if it was when it started crying,
um, anyways, uh, so I,
I rented this documentary called Newman
and it was about this guy who came up
with a electromagnetic
device that produced energy.
And the big thing about it was not
only was it clean energy was the device
itself,
somehow it created more energy
than it was using to run.
And I didn't know that that was a
problem because I have a horrible science
background. So, uh, just, just watch
it to see what you think. All right.
Basically I wasn't aware of any engine
and he sought of turbine anything,
whatever. I guess what, even
if it's used to create energy,
maybe they all are, I guess, you
know, some sort of turning force.
I don't know what I'm in.
I'm in way over my head.
They had always day, always like you're
always in a deficit because it, it,
I guess it uses more energy than it
actually fucking produce as well.
This thing that this
guy created allegedly,
like it used 10% of the energy
that it actually created,
which was fucking unheard of.
So when he went down to get a patent,
they will like, what you're
doing is impossible, sir.
That sounds like witchcraft.
This,
it basically defied the laws of
physics as we know them right now.
So they were all saying what,
you've probably got some transforming
hidden somewhere on your property.
They tried to find it.
They couldn't find it.
They just refuse to believe that this guy,
what he was doing was true,
which then goes, you know, they
wouldn't give him a patent.
And then it goes into all this
conspiracy theory. You know,
that a big oil company,
politics and all of this shit,
we're standing in the way of this guy
because he was basically going to put them
out of business. And, um,
I gotta be honest with you.
I believed everything that I saw in it.
Uh,
and spoiler alert, cause I'm going
to continue talking about this.
You should definitely watch it.
I believe that his device worked.
I believe that the patent company probably
with pressure from the oil companies,
um, wouldn't give him a patent.
I believe he got death threats.
And then I also believed that
he was out of his fucking mind.
I believe that he had
a god complex and um,
they certainly had a temper.
Just check this.
This guy's one of the most
fascinating people ever.
And there's no way to
watch this for me anyways,
for me to watch this.
And I'm not talking about
the genius side of this guy.
I'm talking about his flaws.
The Newman dude,
his,
the is flawed personality.
I couldn't help but watch that guy.
You know,
when investors would come around and
he'd be like, I know what you want to do.
You want to steal from me, I'll put
you right in your fucking face. Right.
I couldn't,
and I'm not even exaggerate.
I couldn't help.
Yeah.
When I was watching that
to not see myself going,
that looks like me when I try
and rent a car or when I try to,
yeah.
Good customer service. That's what I
ended up doing. And even though I'm right,
I become wrong because
of the way I behave.
And um,
it's really fascinating and it's
one of those things where you just,
you just want it to be true and it'll
be so great if it was just a way to
seamlessly have that thing developed.
Give the Guy Newman is credit.
Yeah.
He makes a ton of fucking money.
You let the fucking oil companies run
the goddamn thing and they keep making,
I don't give a fuck.
I'll keep paying what I pay for oil.
All right,
let's quit.
If we can pollute less and
have to liberate less people
around the world because
of our fucking dependency on this shit.
You know,
I really believe, you know, I, I
actually, I know you guys. Yeah.
They always say you get
your tin foil hat on.
I don't even know where
that reference comes from.
But yeah,
does seem to be this
incredible progression
as far is like,
uh,
in energy and in curing diseases and
then all of a sudden it just came to a
screeching fucking halt.
And it's my belief that it's because the
amount of money that is being made and
how entrenched those entities are and
how many's people's livelihoods are
attached to them that
they don't want that it's
okay.
There's just too much conflict
of interest to have it progress.
Like, uh, I dunno,
I'm one of those people that believes
that they can cure way more diseases than
they let on. And eye doctor told me one
time a long time ago, he said, look,
there's no money in the cure.
The money is in the treatment.
And I know that's thought that human
beings would actually fucking do that.
But the way a corporation works is
kind of like the way back in the day,
the war games,
the way they would shoot off the warheads
where it's like it took two people.
Everybody's fucking got to
turn a key and every, oh,
and they would gas somebody
or shoot somebody, you know,
and the firing squad,
somebody had like a fucking rubber bullet
or in an empty gun so everybody would
fucking do it. Uh, I
dunno, I didn't, you know,
something half by the end of that, that
didn't even make sense to me. But I just,
I don't,
I don't believe in people when it comes
to that doing the right fucking thing.
Well,
that's to probably whatever.
I watched the fucking thing
and decide for yourself.
I explained it so much better.
Oh,
now living in the past and
the podcast I already did. Um,
anyways, being back in Boston, you know,
something I really fucking missed was uh,
the Herald sports page and the globe
sports page. I was in fucking heaven
reading that sports page.
One day I sat down and they had all
the Bruins stats for this season.
All the Celtic stats,
all the patriots stats,
and then they had these giant
articles about all three teams.
There was still breaking
down the Patriots.
Buffalo bills game and rating the
quarterback, the running back,
the receivers, the offensive
line to defensive line, the
linebackers to secondary,
the special teams, the
coaching, grading them.
It's fucking phenomenal.
I'll tell you what wasn't phenomenal was
watching those fucking assholes trying
to stir up some bullshit right into,
we're going into the playoffs about Tom
Brady and his fucking personal trainer
who gives a fuck whatever his personal
trainers doing, it's obviously working.
The guys ran out of digits on
one hand was Superbowl rings.
Now he's moved onto the other one.
I swear to got the local media.
What would they be?
I tweeted that.
What the fuck would they be doing if
they weren't trying to sabotage the local
team and all you fucking cops out there
who then pile on and start commenting
and calling into these sports shows.
Anytime there's shitting on the
fucking home team like that, like look,
if it's deserved, it's deserved, but
if they're just trying to stir up shit.
Okay.
Just stopped. I wouldn't
just stop listening. Turn
the channel. That's, I mean,
that's what I do.
MMM.
By the way, you know what was funny
is, uh, I saw yet another, uh,
eat guy in ESPN talking
about bill Belichick's press
conferences going to like
God, there's there so intimidating.
It's like what is intimidating by it?
Stop acting like you don't know
exactly what the fuck the guys doing.
He knows what you're doing.
You're trying to get him to give you a
quote so you can build your story around
that and then you can exaggerate and
take all his shit out of context and give
the other team bulletin board material.
That's why he doesn't talk to you guys.
Jesus fucking Christ.
Did you see that coach Auburn after
they beat Georgia at the first time they
play, we beat the dog shit out of
them. Whatever the fuck he said.
I bet that was all over their locker room.
Fuck it on the ceilings above their
bed until they played them again.
And what happened? The
Georgia bulldogs. Hey,
they came back and paid them
right in the fucking ass man.
They came back and beat him. That's why
bill Belicheck doesn't do that shit.
All right. That was another thing I
liked about Newman was that this guy was,
this was a good old boy
from fucking Mississippi.
And just being out here in La and
watching all these fucking actors and
actresses just openly shitting on anybody
lives in the middle of this country
because they have the audacity to vote
for somebody different than they do,
you know,
independently.
Evidently because they don't live next
to an ocean that makes them a fucking
moron. Just watching what this
guy did, allegedly, you know,
Johnny Carson was from like Nebraska.
I just don't understand. I just,
I don't get people out here and I'm
not saying I shouldn't act like it's
everybody, but it's just really
fucking ignorant. Anyways,
that is the podcast. All right, and
that is the last podcast for this year.
2017 was the greatest year of
my life becoming a dad. And,
um, I know just so many
great things, you know,
happened to me this year.
So I'm going to thank all you guys.
Everybody came out to shows
and all that type of stuff.
I really want to take the time. I never
do this. I always call you guys cons.
I like to think it's a daring, but thank
you guys for the best year of my life.
And um, I hope 2018 I don't even
think it needs to be better.
Just match this one. Just be
in the cruising altitude. Joe,
live the path. You have to be
the presage shut up. You can't.
Um, but anyways, uh, that's
it. I'm not doing shit.
I have basically all the
fucking January off and uh,
I'm going to put together another 20
minutes to add to all the bullshit that I
have.
That's sort of my goal and
I'm going to court.
I went to a lot this year to put it
that way and I'm looking forward to an
amazing year. Alright. Enjoy this music.
And then a throwback episode
at Thursday afternoon,
just before Friday. Monday morning
podcast. Have a great weekend.
[inaudible] happy new year
and I'll talk to you in 2018.
[inaudible]
Hey,
what's going on?
It's built bar and it is the Monday
morning podcasts from Monday,
uh,
December 28,
the final Monday morning podcast for 2009.
Can you believe it?
Another decade has flown by.
Dude, this was like the most,
um, stealth decade of all time.
And I'm going to tell you why,
just in case you were worried,
I would make such a bold fucking statement
about the Goddamn calendar and then
never give you an explanation.
I'm going to tell you why.
Because every decade that I've lived in,
at least that I can remember that I lived
in the 70s everybody would discuss the
70s what are the 70 [inaudible] like? And
then the 80s, the big eighties, right?
And then, you know, people
talking about the, you know,
the 90s people would make
references on sitcoms, you know,
about the coming nineties,
right? It had a fucking name.
Every decade that I've been
in has had a name, seventies,
the 60s, the eighties and the nineties
but this decade had no fucking name.
Oh, the arts, the two thousands we,
we never decided on a fucking
name. Therefore, you know,
I wasn't really paying attention.
I wasn't really paying attention as this
decade whipped by because it's kind of
like the odometer went back to zero.
Right.
Uh,
this is this getting shaky here.
I just realized I'm really
getting into some shaky territory.
It's kind of like it went back to to
the two zero. Right? Except it didn't,
it was,
it was at 2000,
which actually comes back after 1999.
I'm just saying. You know what I mean?
It's like, what the fuck? What happened
to this decade? You know? I don't know.
That was pathetic. I really sounded
like I had something to say there.
And it went absolutely fucking nowhere.
Um,
which is the theme of this podcast
every damn week. Every fucking week,
you know, for the last few weeks
ago with a gratuitous fucks.
Why am I saying fuck so
much this fucking week?
You know why I have not been on
stage since I take my latest special.
I have been on
vacation and uh,
I haven't been doing shit.
I've been stuffing my fat
face with holiday cheer and a,
I don't know what, you guys have a good
Christmas. Did you have a merry Christmas?
Isn't that just put a song in your
heart and say that to somebody?
Merry Christmas. Uh, what the
fuck? Who's calling me now?
Ah, Shit. Hey, I'm doing my podcast.
Let me call you back in about 40 minutes.
Okay.
There we go.
Anyways,
merry Christmas to one and all. Um,
yeah, I gotta get on stage here because,
uh, now that I've basked
in the glory of, uh,
not fucking up my special, everything
went great. Now I can take a vacation.
Now, you know, there's this little voice
in the back of my head going, dude,
you know, um, you don't
have an act right now.
Technically you really don't. So,
uh, why don't you go do some shit?
It hopefully some funny
shit will happen. Um, um,
speaking of which,
um,
some of my girlfriend's family came out
and we took them out to Venice beach out
here in California and a, if you
never been out there, you know,
there's a bunch of freaks out there,
but there's enough regular people sort
of tourists that it waters it down.
But a big to being the fact
that it was the Christmas week,
there wasn't a lot of tourists out there,
there wasn't even a lot
of regulars out there.
So when we showed up it was pretty
much wall to wall freaks and uh,
just had a fucking great time out there.
This guy was standing in front of some
sort of fun house shit that I'd never
seen before and he was that
classic, you know, you know,
step Brad half step right up and
he's going to see the rubber man,
see the electric boy.
And then he goes and look,
look what just came in from the space
station and he reached into a bucket of
water and he pulled out
a two headed turtle.
It was one of the greatest fucking
intros to something. He Yell,
look what they just look what just
came in from the space station. Right.
First of all,
I like the fact that this fucking shitty
on Venice beach standing next to a
crack head has some sort of direct
link to the space station. All right.
I also liked the term the space station.
Is there a space station?
I haven't seen a report on space for a
long fucking time considering NASA really
fell off. They really fucking
fell off of, you know,
when I was a kid,
you know they were going to the Goddamn,
they'd been to the moon. All right.
That was like the godfather moment,
or at least they pretended to go to
the moon. I don't know what they did,
but I bought it and they would literally
feeding us Tang at school and for all
you youngsters out there,
this was, it was this,
this powdered orange drink that they,
that's what the astronauts drink.
You know when they're up there and I, you
know, outer space and they don't have a,
they don't have the, I don't know
what I'm trying to say. They, they,
they can't get into any decent
fucking food or liquids.
Would you like to see what it's like to
drink a poor excuse for a orange juice
and be like an astronaut? And of
course you did. Of course she did.
There was actually a dream of many kids
growing up. What would you like to be?
I'd like to be a hockey player.
What would you like to be?
I think it'd be a heel keeper.
I'd like to be a fucking
astronaut. Well, that's nice, Tim.
He could you say it again without
the curse words? You little cunt.
Why do you have a fucking bowl cut?
Because it's the 70 sweetheart and my
dad grow up with malaria and curly.
Um, remember that? Remember the seventies,
remember that shit when it was still okay.
It was still acceptable for your
parents to cut your fucking hair,
even though they had no
beautician skills whatsoever.
My Dad cut my fucking hair
right up until a sixth grade,
sixth grade,
just laying a template for no pussy,
right through fucking a
right through high school.
What am I trying to say? So
there was, this guy goes,
look what just came in
from the space station.
Now obviously there's no rubber man.
There's no electric boy.
I know it's all bullshit. But you figure
if you're going to make, uh, a, uh, uh,
a reference to space,
you're gonna pull out something that
looks like it came for fucking space,
some sort of rock that you found on the
beach claim. It's part of an asteroid,
maybe part of a bigger asteroid
that's headed right towards us.
Whatever you got to do. This fucking
guy pulled out a two headed turtle.
Look what just came in
from the space station.
They were up in the fucking space
station and look what came floating by
a deformed,
uh,
fuck an amphibian that needs to be
within this atmosphere and a fucking know
what I'm trying to say here. I just
thought it was fucking hilarious. And me,
my girlfriend and her family
laughed for like fucking 10 minutes.
You know that when someone just does
something stupid out in public and then
that just becomes like the catch phrase,
you know what I mean?
The coupon truck and moment of your
afternoon, anytime the, you know,
the conversation would die down.
Someone would just say, hey,
look what just came in from the space
station. Oh, and we would laugh.
We had a great fucking time,
bunch of freaks out there.
I saw a black guy in the yellow
phone walking on broken glass. No,
we didn't have a thong.
The other guy,
it was an American flag Thong and the
other guy was dressed as skin tight,
fucking yellow. I don't
know what it was. Um,
he was basically walking barefoot on
trash, but I got admit he pulled a crowd.
I was impressed, very impressed. Uh,
the best one I saw was I saw this
dude who was wearing a derby,
which is a type of hat. I don't if
it's a bowler hat or a derby. I don't,
one of those, one of those, uh,
let Charlie Chaplin hats and his big
Shtick to get money was he would walk
backwards in front of tourist with
his hat on and he had an empty, uh,
like Paper Cup that you'd have cocaine.
And he was just sort of hitting it up
in the air and before it would land,
he'd hit it up with the
other hand and it would,
would go no higher than
just the top of his hat.
And he had this look on his face
like, Eh, am I doing something?
And then there was another dude out there,
this drug addict who had his side
kick me in the ass for a buck and a,
he started yelling at me to do it.
And I just was laughing cause I'm sorry I
can't, I can't do that. I'm not, I don't,
first of all, I'm not going to kick in the
ass for a buck. I don't want, you know,
it's humiliating.
I don't want to do that to you.
And then not to mention the second you
bend over, I'm going to fucking do that.
You know, you know you have a kick your
friend in the ass and you kick him.
So you want to kick him so hard that
you misjudge it and you actually hit his
ball bag from the, from the
other side. That's what I,
I envisioned myself doing it at that
point. I, I would think that, you know,
then I've got to fight a fucking drug
addict and I get hit hepatitis, whatever.
Look at me acting like a, you know,
that's what I was going to do now.
You weren't bill, you weren't going to
do that. That's what you wanted to do,
but you didn't have
the balls to do what's,
he laughed like a little girl and
he continued on down the boardwalk.
That's what the fuck you
did. You know? You know?
Speaking of a new era of comedy,
that's something I always wanted to talk
about on stage and I always thought it
would be funny,
but I never really kind of was able to
make it funny was those fucking people
always you tell, tell him something
that happened, something bad to you,
and then the second had done
listening to it. They always go, dude,
you know what I would've done? You know
what I would've done? Let me guess.
You would've done something that worked.
Now that you're basically in the
future and saw what the fuck happened,
asshole and I believe I parked
my car and I go to get out of it.
All of a sudden it started
rolling down the fucking street.
I don't know what happened. I
had the thing in gear, dude.
You know what I would've done?
I would've had it an emergency.
I would have put the emergency brake
on and I were to turn the fucking tires
towards the curb.
That's what I would've done
in anticipation that the
one fucking time he didn't
put the emergency brake on,
that your car that never slipped out of
gear before was then going to slip out
of fucking gear. Shut up,
you asshole. You know,
if you had that sort of intelligence,
he wouldn't be friends with me hanging
out in this shit hole. Fucking bar. Right.
All right then. All right. Now that
I got myself worked up into a lather,
look at me wearing my Christmas
patriots. Jersey. What a fucking nerd.
How old are you look like
if she's standing with a
book bag waiting for a bus,
you know, it's just not
cute anymore. Um, all right,
let's get on with the podcast. If you're
new to the podcast, welcome, welcome.
Um, I got some news this
week. Everybody. Uh,
I know I keep threatening to join
Facebook and I'm going to have to do it.
I'm going to have to do it because there's
just nobody left Tehran my space. Uh,
I'm a, I'm given up. Um, I'm pulling the
flag down and putting up the white flag.
I surrender you when Facebook,
you when God dammit,
if it wasn't for those
meddling kids. Um, all right,
so let's get on with the podcast.
If you knew the podcast,
I try to hype my shit and this is
what I got going on. I'm on vacation.
Okay.
I just taped a new special called let
it go and it'll be out in 2010 at some
point.
If you can't wait that long,
why don't you go on iTunes
or going to my website,
[inaudible] dot com and go buy my
fucking DVD. Why do I do this? All right.
So I can get a little check and get my
little fucking $3 or whatever the fuck I
make on those things. Um, anyways,
my next Gig is an, uh,
Seattle January 15th,
and I'm doing the Marty reamer. Funny
Fest. Marty Room was a great guy,
great radio guy up there in
Seattle and he's got this, uh,
this big comedy show that I have
been trying to do for years.
And I'm going to be up there with a bunch
of other big shots like a Jeff garland
and a,
and a bunch of other people.
I can't even fucking remember who else
may up there with Christian Finnegan.
Remember,
I hate that the other white dude on the
Chappelle show who had some people you
want to Chappelle show. Will you on the,
uh, the mad real world? No, I wasn't.
That was the other guy. And then people
try to argue with me. Not that was you,
that was you.
Why would I lie? Why would I, why would I,
why would I try to knock down my
pathetic entertainment resume?
I'm all about patting it. All right,
let's get on with the podcast here. Um,
what do we got here? Let's start off with
Douche bag of the week. All right. And,
um,
my nominee for Douche bag of the week
is the NFL network for showing a fucking
game on Christmas. That was only on their
goddamn network. You know what dude?
Fuck the fucking NFL network.
All right.
Have any of you guys out there actually
looked into what it takes to get a
Goddamn dish? First of all, if
you're renting somewhere, right?
You landlord's going to be a cunt.
If you start drilling into the side
of the building, right? You know,
a repair that's probably going to cost
him $80 but somehow we'll take the entire
12 to $1,500 a year fucking
deposit, you know? And then also,
you know, I don't know about you guys,
but when I actually first moved out here,
I was getting a flat screen. I was like,
fuck it. She's going to light up the card.
And they're like, would you
like to get direct TV? And
I'm thinking, yeah, fuck it.
I'll get the NFL network. I can
watch the pats games. Why not?
And they wanted me to sign up
for like two or three years.
Like it say ya like a cell phone company.
I don't have to do that with cable
cable right now. I could call them and
say, you know what? I'm sick of your shit.
Go Fuck Yourself. And they make ramps.
I'm tearing. And Carol Amery Karen,
appreciate it. You didn't
use that language. Fuck you.
You fucking Sunday
working cable cont right.
And they would just shut it
off and then that would be it.
And then I could back on Monday and
be like, yeah, listen. You know,
I don't know. I was, I was drinking,
I was lost some money on the
games and I took it out on,
I believe her name was Samantha.
I don't know where she was
stationed in your states, but uh,
is there any way you can turn it
back on? Absolutely. Absolutely.
There'll be a Yay.
$80 a raw go fuck yourself.
We start up fee to match
the $90 cancellation fee.
You know, that's the way they
get ya. Okay. But I got mobility.
I got freedom.
Mean I have a feeling of control going
to sign a fucking three year contract.
You know,
the level of,
of of Douche baggery by the NFL network
to show a game on Jesus's birthday
guide's son. He sitting there trying
to think, Jesus has fucking direct TV.
I don't think he does,
you know, fucking hippie.
You think he's going to be involved in
some sort of corporate contract? Man,
I dunno. You know what I mean? Look,
I don't mind if you're gonna show
the random Thursday game. I get it.
You're trying to get me,
you know,
you're trying to get me all right and
you have your best matchups. Okay.
And you got to ll cool j on the
fucking TV licking his lips,
telling me about all the
fucking games that I'm missing.
A how many fucking tubes of chapstick
does that guy go through a year?
Does that make your lips chapped?
If you're on saliva,
if you keep them glistening with
your own saliva, that's one of those,
uh, those evidently urban sexy
moves that makes, I don't know,
white people in the suburbs just cringe.
Like really they do that.
They lick their lips and that's
like a good thing. Um, anyways,
I like how I just meet all white people
in the suburbs feel the way I feel about
ll cool j licking his lips anyways, Douche
bag of the week. NFL network. All right.
You fucking assholes.
If you want to show a random Thursday game
and you know into to try to get me to,
to, to buy it. I get it. You're a
business but don't do it on Christmas.
You asshole. You know what you did. You
just made me more of an NBA fan. Okay.
Cause they had the Celtics magic and
they, their, their best guys out there.
They had Lebron, Kobe, Shaq. All right.
The big three up in
Boston and Dwight Howard,
who's got a bicep the size of my entire
body and has absolutely zero fucking
baseline moves. Jesus,
what's his one movie? Dunks.
You know,
if that guy would just steal one move
from a fucking Kevin Mchale via a chemo
Olijahwaun he would be unstoppable.
But he doesn't, he's got nothing.
He's got no turn around jumper.
He's got nothing.
He's just got a bicep the size of a
fucking credenza. He's got two of them.
Um, anyways, seriously do.
That's like the biggest fucking
human being I've ever seen.
So douche bag of the week is
the fucking NFL network and I'm
fucking cough. Um, I dunno, I
really want to write them a letter.
I just have to take all the
fucks and cuts out of it.
And I don't think that they're
really gonna give a shit,
but I'm going to go biblical on him.
You know what I mean?
Because everybody pays attention with
some stuff saying that you offended me
religiously.
And speaking of which,
I am introducing a new
segment here on the podcast,
and this is the,
uh,
the religious segment where you can
ask questions about other religions.
You can bitch about your own religion or
you can say why it's great and why you
like it. All right? Uh, the name
of this segment is, oh Geez,
because you know, last week,
I don't even know what
the fuck I said about, oh,
I remember that guy was saying how you
were, um, how he thinks you're a, you,
you make a choice to be gay.
And then he starts, you know,
making some quotes with the
Bible. And I was just like, ah,
you fucking people you
know with the Bible, right?
So this guy writes in and he goes,
trash in the Bible at Christmas.
What have you gone?
Stark raving mad or something.
This guy sounds like a a
born again Christian cause
he's obviously not going to
curse here.
Have you gone stark raving mad?
I mean Jimminy cricket spell. Anyways.
Did you hit your head or something lately?
Okay. Let's see. You do
believe in God, right?
But you went to a Catholic church where
they filled your skull with guilt,
horror and hypocrisy. Then he puts in
parentheses the little boy thing. Oh,
is that what you call children?
Getting molested
grown men fucking children. You call
that the little boy thing. All right. Uh,
or whatever they did to turn you off.
Okay. Understandable. Understandable.
But for crying out loud,
this, this right here,
this email is why I don't work clean
as a comedian because you have to use
expressions like for crying out loud.
Have you gone stark raving mad?
Um,
many ways for crying out loud.
What makes you think God is like that?
He's not exclamation point. I
never said he was, he's fucking,
people don't even listen to me. I'm
saying the Bible was written by people.
That's what I feel. Okay. He was with
my people a long fucking time ago.
They thought the earth was flat. Okay. A
lot of its metaphors, a lot of the shit.
I know a lot of stuff, you
know, makes sense or whatever,
but it's written by people.
All right?
And I don't believe that Jesus
was the son of God, okay?
I don't believe you rub Buddhist stomach
and don't believe any of that stuff.
Okay?
All those stories are the bridge between
right now and back when we used to draw
a deer on the inside of caves,
all right?
I'm not saying there's not
a fucking higher power.
I'm not saying I don't
believe in an afterlife.
All I know is that you don't know what
the fuck is going on until you die,
all right?
So you can make your guesses.
Your guesses are, are, are, are,
you know, qualified. You know,
I'm not saying you can't make your guests
if that's what the fuck you want to go
for,
but you know,
I'm not saying you can't believe
what you want to believe.
I just don't believe in that stuff. I
just don't. Do you really believe that?
Do you really believe Jesus was
the son of God and he, and he just,
he had a wicker basket and he just
was pulling fish out of it and fed 800
fucking people out of this little basket
that you usually throw a fucking hot
steam and washcloth into,
you know,
and he walked on water and
then he rose from the dead.
You really believe all of that. I don't
know. Why is my voice going up so high?
You really
believe in Jesus Christ.
Um, I, I'm envious of that.
I'm envious of that. I, um,
I dunno. I just, I don't, I don't believe
that, uh, you know, I don't believe Noah,
I don't believe any of those stories.
None of those stories are believable
than me. They're just not.
I can see the earth flooding
and everybody drowning.
I can see that.
I can see,
I can even see a guy making a fucking
boat or maybe people who are already on a
boat. You know? Why didn't
those people survive with Noah?
See, I can't even fucking
answer. I don't know why.
Then you're going to fill it up with
all those animals shitting all over the
place. You've got to capture all
the animals. It's just, it's not,
it's not fucking believable on any level,
on any level. It lacks credibility.
I liked the Ted Commandments. I
love the seven deadly sins. Uh,
I like the end of the world shit,
but I don't take it that seriously.
And this is not me slapping anybody
in the face. I just, you know,
and I would take going to say,
just because you have an open yourself
up to Jay's is when you open your shelf
full up the new ship, him as
your one and only savior. Yeah.
Why can't I do that?
Why can I just do that?
Why do I then have to go to church and
fucking pay for somebody else's lifestyle?
Who wants to dress like James Brown's
in the fucking blues brothers? Huh?
And you guys out there
going a mega church,
you guys seen those things down the
south, south down the south, down south.
You've, you seen those? I don't know
what the fuck I'm talking about. Look
the same way, that guy standing
out there going, you know,
look what they just brought
in from the space station.
That's what preachers are doing.
And let's say they took,
they're giving you like life advice, but
when they just start talking about that,
uh, you know, and then on the third day,
God created the shrinks yet add GI
or where's written dead children need
something to play on. That word swung
them back and forth. [inaudible]
brutal.
Fucking brutal.
This is really just going to cause a
shit storm and I hope it does. All right.
And, and all of this, I'm
not disrespecting your
religion or what you believe.
I just don't fucking believe it.
And I don't believe that you believe it.
That's how unbelievable it is to me.
All right. But I believe in a, in,
in something, you know, you know
that shit where you like, yeah,
you'll walk to the phone
and before you say, you just
know who it is. That kind of
weird shit or a Deja Vu that's,
there's a lot of weird shit
out there. You know, uh,
you forget to look and you change
seven lanes and you don't die.
And then you think, wait a minute,
that I, that I just look back there.
I can't really remember. You were
in this fucking zone. I don't know.
I don't believe in ghosts.
You know,
I don't get what can it
go studio other than,
than wake you up in the middle of the
night. I guess I can do that. Going on
beyond that, what can they do? You know,
that's how I got over my fear
of the dark when I was a kid.
When I would imagine that
there was a monster in there.
I got so mad at the fear.
One night I started giving the monster
the finger and it didn't kill me.
And I was like,
all right,
any respectable monster's not
gonna put up with that shit.
And it would come over here and fucking,
there's no monster. There's no monster.
The stupid,
this is actually just nature's way of
telling me it's time to go to sleep.
And they're making it easy by not having
the sun there that I ever tell you that
time. Uh, one of my
friends was, was on this,
I can't say it was on a date. You know
that shit when you were like high school,
when you're basically drinking outside
and you just start talking to some bra
and you try to hook up with her.
All right, so let's get into dusk.
And there was this moment,
okay, right around dusk
where the sun's going down and the
moon was a, sounds like a fucking song,
doesn't it? Um, the sun
was going down in the moon,
like I going down in the west of
the moon was kind of like, I dunno,
I guess at like two o'clock or whatever.
And this girl was go and someone's like,
Oh wow, the sun and the moon were
out at the same time. Wow. You know?
And this girl was like,
wait a day.
How can the faculty sat in the movie?
Yeah,
let's say fag attack it.
And at first they thought that she didn't
believe that you could see the moon
until the sun completely went down,
which I guess would be understandable.
But they quickly realized that
she thought that the sun and
the moon where the same thing
and that evidently at night,
I guess God or Jesus or Buddha would,
I don't know,
not necessarily blow this,
I guess she thought the sun was on
a dimmer and they would just sort of
gradually bring it down and uh, I
don't know. I don't fucking know.
And that's just one of those
moments where they always a kid,
you just have that first moment of,
is this thing too dumb to try and fuck.
You know,
I always had that I could
never fuck somebody. Whoa.
I really thought was stupid.
It just, it just felt like,
uh, it was a form of rape,
you know what I mean? If you
just sold like, I don't even
say it, I'm a smart guy,
but you know, when someone's
just like borderline, like wow,
high school really? And
College. College. Wow. Okay.
All right. Anyways, let me read the
rest of this though. Jesus here. Um, um,
above blah, blah, blah, blah. So the kid
thing, um, he's not a, he, he doesn't, oh,
this is a great line too. He's
saying that God is not mad. I,
this is one of my favorite sentences
of all time. He's addressing, um,
the view of homosexuality.
He says,
God doesn't hate fags either.
Oh, that's good. It's good. He doesn't
hate the, he doesn't hate cock suckers.
God loves the faggots.
Um,
he loves everybody and that
is written in big letters. Um,
even people that hold up traffic,
a gay guy or not,
he died for everyone.
Everybody's sins so they can accept
that free gift at the, see that's,
that's right there.
That's what I find annoying
about Jesus is the whole guilt.
He died for you. Dude, I
didn't ask you to do that.
Idiot. Can fucking walk on water,
you know, float off the cross.
Wow. I'm really, yeah, this is really
getting bad. But I'm just saying,
isn't that common fucking sense?
Like when you watch your karate movie
and Bruce Lee's doing all this shit and
you're like, just get a
gun. Why did you shoot him?
All I know is if I was the son of God,
I would not sit there getting crucified,
or at least I cheated a little bit.
You know,
I'd sort of semi levitate so it looks
like the nails are really fucking ripping
at me and they have for you,
wouldn't you?
Wouldn't everybody caves
under, under, under torture?
They all do. I don't, I don't
buy any of this shit. You know,
it'd be funny is if all of this stuff
that I'm saying isn't true is true.
And then like I die and then they play.
Mike.
My damnation is this podcast and you know,
they just playing this podcast and God
is just sitting across from me, you know,
with his hands up. Uh, you know
that shit where you, uh, okay. You,
you don't have your hands together.
You just have the tips of your fingers
together and they're kind of spread apart
and you just sort of bouncing
them, you know, the classic, um,
what am I going to do with you?
I am in a position of authority over you.
What is your sentence going to be?
Um, anyway, so fuck it. Let's see how,
how far into hell I can dig myself?
Um,
what else does this guy say
that I don't agree with? Uh, no.
We know Jesus didn't sit
down with stationary and
write the Bible at some desk,
but it is his words. You know
why? I would love to know why.
I would love to know your proof.
Okay. I'll tell you why Jesus.
He anticipated my answer
because on the fuck is it?
Because I know you don't know.
It was inspired by God.
Jesus through the certain chosen
people that physically wrote it.
Yeah,
I hear you saying bullcrap.
Why can't you curse if you
believe in Jesus? I don't
understand that.
You know,
you don't think when they were nailing
his fucking limbs to that piece of wood,
he wasn't going, fuck yeah, Mama.
Fuck Dude, I am. Do you
know my dad is your mother
fuckers? Come on. All right. All right.
Jesus Christ. I'm really fucking,
you know, this is stupid to do this,
but here we go. Let's keep going. Um,
you know something,
they never really fucked with his balls.
I always thought that was amazing.
You know,
the smashing like a reads over his back,
you know, and putting thorns into his
head when just kick him in the nuts,
his holier than now nuts his ball bag.
That fucking died.
I did it for you. Oh God. Is that
annoying? It's really annoying.
I swear to God, if Jesus at the mall
signing autographs, I walk right by it.
I'd rather meet Charles Bronson.
He was still alive, you know,
talk to them about being in
Poland in that mine. Um, anyways,
I hear you saying bullcrap,
but you are wrong.
If you're saying that I didn't say
bull crap. I said Bull Shit. Uh,
that just means you don't understand
spiritual and supernatural things.
T that's another thing about these really
religious people is if you don't agree
with them and they can't be like, oh, you
know, this is what the fuck you think.
You know, I'm not saying what
this guy is saying is wrong.
I hope it's not coming off like that.
I'm just asking questions. You know,
how come they never
kicked him in the balls?
You think he didn't curse when
they were fucking with him?
They were playing the upright bass with
his juggler or whatever fucking horrific
thing they did to him.
Um,
I actually understand spiritual things.
I don't understand supernatural things.
No, I don't. I don't believe in
ghosts and neither do you. Okay.
And just because you read a fucking book
doesn't mean you understand it, right?
You don't. All right. Uh, so
like so many other people,
you feel the need to stop on something
just because you don't understand it
fully, and that makes you mad. Okay. Well,
how about instead of getting mad you,
you asked Jesus himself to explain it
to you. Okay. I will hang on a second.
[inaudible]
Jesus,
could you explain the Bible
to me cause I don't get it.
Okay. All right. So now what do I
do? This is really getting creepy.
This is, I feel like I'm at the
fucking weegee board right now. Um,
I can't even read the rest of this. All
right. That's probably a fucking stew.
I really should not do this podcast.
I should just fucking hit a race,
you know? All right. Let's talk about
movies. Shall We? Let's get out of this.
I saw the movie Sherlock Holmes,
uh, this week, me and half of,
uh, the, the, the American
population all went out.
That's Jesus get me back. Um, yeah,
I saw Sherlock Holmes and uh,
this is my movie review.
This is the best way that I can put it.
It was watching Sherlock Holmes.
It was like a,
this is how he said it to my friend or
friend of mine who actually have, who, uh,
also does not believe in Jesus. I said
it was like Sherlock Holmes was like,
it was like the first time
you ate a fat free cookie.
Do you remember that confusion? You're
just looking at the cookie being like,
you know, how can this not be good?
It's, it's a fucking cookie. You know,
how can a cookie be bad?
And that's literally what I
felt like when I was watching,
when I was watching Sherlock
Holmes. You know, I'm like,
how is it Robert Downey Jr
has given a great performance?
Fucking what's his face? Jude
Law was great. Nick Guy Ritchie.
I've loved all his movies.
How is this not fucking good?
And I don't even know. I can't explain
it. I don't know why it wasn't good.
It just wasn't bad. It
just, it was it, I dunno,
it just, it wasn't good. Um,
I like how they dumbed down Sherlock
Holmes though rather than having them be
just an egg head. They,
they made him like this guy,
like they turned it into like fight club.
First of all was great about the movie
was that they had elements of Jujitsu in
England in the 18 hundreds,
which I thought was hilarious cause as
far as I knew it came from the fucking
Gracie family. Right.
Then they get credit,
a very least Brazilian Jujitsu and he
came up with it and like the twenties or
east right. Isn't that what happened?
I don't know if they did that.
They had a little bit of Zeitgeisty in
there, a little bit of fight club and uh,
and then after he beat
the shit out of people,
then he would do all that
Sherlock Holmes Shit.
And he would say all the Sherlock
Holmes is fast as like an auctioneer.
You're probably wondering how I knew that
because that thread indicates that you
are in the Middle East
and blah, blah, blah,
name would fucking fly through the
whole thing. And uh, I don't know.
It wasn't good. I'm thinking about
seeing Avatar though, you know,
but that even that movie annoys me. I
don't like that the whole, you know,
I wrote this and I had to wait till
technology caught up with it. Oh my God,
you're such a fucking
visionary. Jesus Christ. Heaven.
You want enough wards? You don't have to
fucking rub your own balls and public.
I don't think I'm ever going to book a
movie again if anybody ever listens to
this fucking podcast. All right, let's
plow ahead. Speaking of which date night,
I actually saw a preview
for it and I was like,
I'm in this mother fucker and I was so
afraid I was gonna see my big fucking
head that I actually stared down at my,
uh,
the fuck was eight and junior mints,
Junior Mints,
the Classic Candy that you would never
buy if you actually had a choice,
but you just do at the movie theater.
They're awful in this.
So much peppermint or whatever
[inaudible] or whatever, the mint,
I'm a fucking idiot.
It actually had the answer in the name.
There's so much mint in it
that after like three of them,
your fucking throat starts to hurt.
It's like you're eating Vick's vapor rub
covered in chocolate. Um,
anyways. All right. Uh,
I'm probably going to pay for
that. Oh, is fucking segment.
But maybe that'll just be a onetime
only and I hope the fucking people that
wrote that shit and don't be a
cunt about it. What would Jesus do?
He just looked down, shake his
Gregg Allman hair and be like, ohh,
golly, Gee, what are we going to
deal with this guy? Um, all right,
last week I talked about men who
abandoned their families and,
um, I, I mentioned obviously that I,
I don't agree with that and I'm sure
Jesus doesn't either forget about Buddha,
although Buddha was too fat to leave his
family. What's he gonna do? You know,
he'd have to hit the lottery.
When you get that fat as a man,
you need some sort of, uh, it
needs some power, you know,
to pull the hot broads, you
know, little bit of vague,
you know,
they are liquid Viagara they,
you guys see that commercial
yet is fucking unreal.
His show with late at night liquid
Viagara you pour it in your hand and you
literally start rubbing one
out and your dick comes up.
I was watching it and it was a
fucking unbelievable commercial.
And if you believe that you
believe in Jesus, I'm all right.
I'm really being an asshole right now.
And I don't mean to be all right.
I respect all religions and I'm actually
jealous that you go to bed every night
thinking that there's a real life Santa
Claus waiting to Koresh you and rub your
forehead and your brow.
Um, all right. So anyways,
I talked about guys who were abandoned
their families and I was saying how, uh,
obviously I don't condone it,
but I am jealous of,
I want to feel that level of euphoria
because in order for you as a man to do
something like that,
to leave somebody who you actually agreed
legally to dedicate your life to and
then you then had children with.
Right now I don't have any kids,
but I see the look on people's faces when
they talk about their kids. You know,
even if it's a pain in the ass and
that they really could go back,
they wouldn't have kids.
There's a look they have on their face
to that unconditional love to fucking
walk away from that.
All right.
Like the level of misery that you
have to be in. I just, you know,
and it must've been like,
like how men della felt when he
finally got out of fucking all right.
It was a little big,
but you know what I mean?
So I was talking about it and I was
thinking like, you know, last week,
like what music would you listen to?
What is the soundtrack to fucking
leave in that? And you guys all like,
wait in, somebody said highway
to hell and another person said,
you listened to wish you were here.
I don't know what I
would listen to. Um, I,
I would just, it would be
just, I would just some,
any song that just made go, yeah, I
would just, I don't know. It's unreal.
But anyways, beyond
these fucking songs, uh,
Saudi actually had a story about it and
this isn't great contribution by the way,
to the podcast,
as was this stuff about religion,
even though I was a jerk about it.
But you gotta understand,
I've got to keep this shit funny.
That's my out. Um, anyways, uh,
built during your last podcast,
you mentioned about fathers decided to
suddenly abandoned their family. Well,
about 11 years ago when I was
stationed in South Dakota,
the guy that I work with did exactly
that. He left his wife, he left his kids,
uh, in hopes to start a new life. All
right. The story goes something like this,
settle in everybody. You're still wearing
your course, your Christmas sweaters.
All right. It was back in
1997 a what a great year, Huh?
Clinton was getting blown. Nobody knew
about it. Boy Bands were popular. Right.
How innocent. What a great fucking
time before it all got ugly, you know,
and people started lighting then nuts
on fire trying to fucking take a plane
down. Um, anyways, uh, Mike, uh,
this Guy Mike was assigned remote duty
for six months in Panama at this point in
Mike's life. He had about 14
years in the air force, um,
that is being tasked with re remote
duty playing bullshit war exercises and
being restricted to a military lifestyle.
So one day when I showed up to
work my squadron's first shirt,
I don't know what that means,
I guess the guy in charge. Um,
and a few officers had had
maps laid out on the table.
I asked what was going on and
one of the sergeants replied,
we have a briefing and
15 minutes in formation.
During that briefing,
I believe it was the base officer who
mentioned that Mike has been missing since
the day before the FBI had
some other military branch, uh,
and some other military branch was
involved to find Mike by Searching South
Dakota by feet,
automobile and air with helicopters.
So my coworkers and I,
uh,
were tasked to drive about 50 miles to
some remote location in South Dakota to
post missing posters
of Mike See Attachment.
And he actually has the attachment
here. So anyways, he says, uh,
we thought he was in danger.
Uh, we were concerned for him.
He was a good guy helping people
out, um, when p when help is needed.
So I'll be totally, there was no sign
that this guy was going to do this shit.
He said he plays bones, which
I guess is dominoes during, uh,
during lunch with us while
listening to classic rock,
he never came across as being disturbed.
But then again,
I was much younger so I might have, um, I
might've missed some science. All right.
Back to the story of searching for him.
A few days after the search,
someone reported they found supposedly
his lunchbox with his military id in it.
It was several miles north of where we
were stationed close to North Dakota,
South Dakota border.
Um,
then they found his car in a
parking lot of a Canadian airport.
Shortly after finding his car,
they detained him in
Panama where he was found.
Mike left his family in exchange with
some Panamanian woman he met during his
duty there. Uh, we always wondered what
the hell he was thinking when he did this.
Supposedly he left his lunchbox
near a road with his ID,
this id in it as a decoy.
And when we drove to the car,
when he drove to the Canadian airport
to flight, he then flew to Panama.
And a,
the big joke was that he was listening
to the song by Van Halen called Panama
when he left.
So they arrested him and discharged him.
Uh,
his wife forgave him,
so evidently I guess he went back.
Dude, you know what I love about that
story? That is the perfect fucking song.
Oh my God. Just driving away
from your family, his dad.
It would it would it reach down?
He's the seed pack.
Ah, fuck. You know what? I think you
know what? I think the, the, the,
the feeling of euphoria as you guys ever
watched Ferris Bueller's day off. Sure.
We all have. Do you know when those two
guys, the parking attendants, you know,
take the car out for the day and they
show that slow motion thing of when they
go up and over the hill and they get
that look of absolute joy with the wind
blowing through their hair.
I think that's what it feels like to
abandon a family if you're that fucking
miserable. So, uh, God bless
that woman for taking them back.
That's either a deep kind of love
or just no options whatsoever.
Um, so there you go. And I think that's
going to be the podcast for this week.
Let's do some classic stuff here. Some
overrated, underrated, real quick. Bill.
Overrated skinny girls.
I've never understood the
appeal of super skinny girls.
They look more like little boys
than women. Plus they're a,
they usually snobby and expect
you to do all the work in bed.
They like Kobe Bryant. They are jaded and
sex is more like a job for them. Dude.
What you hook up with coke?
Uh,
they don't understand the magic
of the game anymore. Okay,
I see what you're saying.
Do we talk about Colby?
Did you see Colby a yes on Christmas it
down by like 20 points and he's still
draws an offensive foul.
That guy,
I'm a Celtics fan and I admit that's
a fucking best player in the league.
All right. But my big complaint
about Colby Bryan is um, AH,
Jesus Christ my fucking
alarm. Um, anyways, my uh,
my big complaint about Kobe Bryant,
I just want Laker fans cause
you guys watch them every night.
I'm not being a jerk, but when was
the last time you saw him take a shot?
Missed the shot and not look
over at the ref for a foul?
It's almost like he's saying ref. It
didn't go in. They must have found me.
That's how fucking good I am. It's
annoying. But I totally respect that guy.
I love his game. He needs Nisa that whole
teams riding on his fucking coattails.
Um, alright. Underrated fat chicks.
Fat Chicks are the real deal.
They do everything they
can to please you in bed.
They're the only ones who
can give you a decent hump.
They are like the guy t uh,
taking the half court shot for 10
grand no matter what the outcome.
They still have a smile on the face and
they're just happy to be there. Do that.
I'm telling you, some of you fucking
listeners really ought to do stand up.
Let's just, you know, do you want me,
comedians could write something that good.
All right. Probably a few of them,
but that's really impressive.
I forgot to do the life advice.
Doctor Bill.
I get a blow through this and speaking,
speaking of, uh, becoming a comedian,
somebody who wants some life advice
and this is a rough one. He says,
I got some shit going on in my life and
it's really starting to make me reflect
on where I'm going and, uh, what I want to
be. Okay. So I need some answers. First,
my grandfather raised
me from the age of two,
almost died and recently had a
quadruple bypass on his heart.
No idea how long he's
going to make it, but, uh,
it's definitely given me a new perspective
on life. All I think about now is, um,
what were the things that he
didn't do and always wanted to, uh,
fuck regretting things you did. I wonder
about the things he regrets not doing.
Um,
I'm 29 years old.
I work as a senior manager for a
major company that builds airplanes.
I make over a hundred grand a year
and I fucking hate it. I mean, uh,
this part of the world and
I'm not going to mention, uh,
I do stand up comedy almost
every other weekend, eh,
at one of the comedy clubs there.
My question is this,
can I ever make a trans transition from
work to stand up performing outside of
La or New York or do you think I will
have to quit everything and move to one of
those locations also? Do you think
it's worth it? I know I'm funny.
I know I'm a good comedian.
I feel I make like, uh, uh,
I feel like making a living as a comic
would be similar to winning the lottery.
Even though I'm funny.
It's still one in a million shot that I
would ever be able to make it a career.
Thank you. Uh, thanks for any
advice you have. Alright. Do that.
Those are tough questions because I've
never seen your act and those are really
questions that only you can answer.
I'm not trying to cop out here.
All right? But, uh, I do know this.
If you do a job and you're miserable,
you know, I mean, we want to, if
you're making $1 million a year,
I mean a hundred grads fucking sneezer.
Uh,
I dunno dude. Um, all I can do
is tell you how I looked at it.
And when I went into being a comedian,
I was not making a hundred grand a year.
So it was very simple for me to
make that choice to go there.
And I never really thought about not
making it other than a couple of times,
if I was doing a college gig in the middle
of fucking nowhere and I was sitting
in a super eight and I bombed that night,
then I'd be going like,
what the fuck am I doing?
This is crazy, you know? Um,
but being able to make a living as a
comedian is not a one in a million chance.
And, uh, believe it or not,
making it as a comedian is not a
one in a million chance because a,
I'm going to go out on a limb and say,
there's not a million
standup comedians out there.
Your rods are better than that.
It might be 750,000.
No, dude, you gotta, you gotta
look, do you go out of the
club and in like, you just,
you go in there and you just feel
like this is home. You know, like,
this is where I'm supposed to be. If
that's what you feel, then I would do it.
And you don't have to live
in New York or La to, uh,
to get a career going.
Um,
oh Jesus. I'm trying to give you an
example. I mean there's, there's every,
every stand up town has the,
the local guys who never left, who
make a living at it, you know, um,
it's just one of those things where
you want to expand your horizons after
awhile where, uh, you know,
you want to start making better money
or whatever, but, um, I dunno dude,
like if it's your dream in life,
that's what you want to do,
then I would definitely do it.
Especially cause if you're at work and
you're fucking miserable than I would do
it. And making a living at it is not
as difficult as it seems. You know,
you get a college age and you
stopped booking college gigs.
Granted you've got to fly all
over the fucking country. Um,
but you know,
if you want to go fucking see Sherlock
Holmes in the middle of a Tuesday,
you know,
dress like a shithead and not take a
shower till seven o'clock at night,
that's one of the great things
about being a comedian. But do,
that's a huge decision. You gotta
make that on your own. But a,
I would make the happy choice.
Don't choose money because you're going
to end up like one of those Stepford
wives. You know what I mean? We got
all this shit. Any of your fucking,
you've got all this stuff,
but you're miserable. So, um,
I don't know man. That's, that's too big.
That's too big a question for me to ask
you to answer for you a without knowing
you. So I hope I helped you
out. Uh, I probably didn't
help you out at all, but uh,
it believe me do it. It's not as
hard as you think it is. All right.
It's not fucking easy,
but it's really not as hard as you think
it is a to make a living as a comedian.
All right, let's get
to a question bill. Hi.
My question is when you are a cup
in a couple situation, situation,
spelt with a c,
what is the protocol for who or how
you decorate your Christmas tree?
Do you do it together or
separately or in stages? You know,
one puts it in the stand when
puts the lights, et Cetera,
or do you put a not put one up or not?
Um,
all right. Uh, Christmas tree question
questions are real late this week.
Um, now my thing is if I buy it, you
decorated and if you decorate it, no,
if you buy it, you better decorate it
because I'm not doing it. In other words,
I, I don't, I don't decorate Christmas
trees. That's how I do it around here.
I go out and I buy it. I stick it
in the stand. And uh, then my girl,
she goes nuts. She decorates it
and she goes, does not look nice.
What do you think about, you didn't
say anything. No, I think it's nice.
I know that I thought, I thought you were
just going to come in and be like, wow,
look at it.
It looks beautiful.
Christmas tree fell Christmas. See, I buy
that. You're going to do that. Really?
What would you do if I did that?
Speak of the devil.
Mino
Hey, I'm doing my podcast.
I'm doing it right now.
You're on it,
everybody.
All right. All right. All right. Okay.
Okay. Let me call you back in two minutes.
I'm almost done. Hi. Bye. He's Christ.
I'm such a space shot. I like half.
Forgot that I was doing a podcast is, hey,
just calling to let you know then I'm
not home yet and I'm gonna be home soon
and I just wanted to start talking
to you are ready. Um, you know,
a lot of people, a couple of people
have been emailing me saying,
I'm mean to my girlfriend. I'm not, I'm
not meeting my girlfriend. I give a shit.
It's my way of, um, protecting
what I have in this relationship.
All right? I keep it light. I
fucking break balls. Oh, by the way,
I'm doing this on a Sunday because I'm
going to the Celtics fucking clippers
tonight.
And uh,
I'm actually walked away from
the TV last I saw was like 15,
14 cults over the jets.
Um,
I dunno if I should say,
I'm not going to say this.
You know what you guys remind me next
week to tell you my prediction of rex.
I actually,
my prediction earlier this year of Rex
Ryan was that he was gonna break his
tailbone in a failed attempt
to hang himself at some point.
I've never seen, I have not seen
such a desperate need to be liked.
I'm telling you,
that guy is emotionally on the edge.
All right? That fucking bizarre
Christmas wishlist thing that he did.
Like, uh, you know, I'm hosting SNL,
but I'm actually fucking a coach.
And he said to that guy is
out of his fucking mind,
and he's broken down crying
a couple times, and I've
made predictions this year,
Dad, I'm telling you, I can't tell
you who's gonna win a fucking game,
but shit like that. I'm telling you, I
watch that Pacquiao fight and I fucking.