Hey, what's going on it's Bill Burr.
It's time for the Thursday afternoon,
just before Friday,
Monday morning podcast.
And I am just checking in on you.
Who's that checking in on you? You
can't, sorry. I'm in New York, you know,
all of a sudden you just got to start
doing your little sin, natural vibe. Um,
Joe and I'm going out and I'm buying
a new pair of fucking sneakers today.
Go Away. Are you going to get you? Do
you gotta get the Jordan Five's? Dude,
I know what I'm going to get.
You know I'm going to, I,
I'm getting some old man running sneakers.
I need some workout sneakers.
You know about the ones that were on
better call Saul for the old ladies.
Did you guys watch the rest of
that a series? Did you see it yet?
Can I ruin it for you?
I've got to tell you in the last episode,
in the last scene when the guy says,
just trying to get all you guys to scamper
for your fucking pause buttons. No, no,
no.
I didn't watch it yet.
People literally run out of the room.
People run out of the fucking room.
When you'd start talking about a show,
they haven't seen the last episode yet.
Have they do that?
You know what I mean?
But if you just sit there and you're
fucking, somebody rips a fight,
people just put a fucking shirt
over their nose. Oh, who did that?
You're literally inhaling air
from this guy's ass. You know?
And that doesn't make you leave
the room. But if, God forbid,
somebody brings up the last
episode of a fucking show,
you haven't seen everybody runs
out like the building's on fire.
Um, it is a perfect, perfect
day in New York City.
The breeze don't this breeze
top five breezes ever.
This breeze,
my top five ever.
That's a verse you think for as you
would actually rank his breezes top five
reasons ever. Dude, I was sitting there,
I had on a pair of Jordan's sexes with
the Fucking v Neck with the chain on the
outside over, over. Waitress came up
to me. She could barely take my order.
She couldn't,
she couldn't even like she was taking in.
The whole thing was ridiculous.
New pair of guests, jeans over.
Oh fuck. Anyways, um, yeah, so
I'm up in fucking port Chester.
I didn't know what port Chester is by no.
Westchester,
there's east Chester and Alva daily.
Those port Chester,
which I believe is just Connecticut.
Um,
there tonight I'm there Tamara and then
I'm there on Saturday and then I'm done
and then I'm back. And uh,
I'll tell you right now,
you have not experienced loneliness
till you have a fucking kid.
It meant and then you leave my favorite
part of the fucking days when my kid
wakes up.
You know what I mean?
Cause like they're super fucking
rested and they just, you know,
life hasn't beaten down yet.
They don't have any credit card debt then
know got some psycho blowing up their
phone. They don't have this shit.
They got to do some fucking receipt.
They have to find, they got, they got,
they the look of contentment on her face.
You know when you go down,
when you go to give her a kiss,
like she lifts all of her limbs come up
like a baby's ability to do leg lifts.
I don't know how the fuck if I tried
to do what she did, just straight up,
just lift some write up.
I don't get it.
Sit there and suck in their toes.
Evidently hours that flexible at one
point tell you that a couple million miles
in the back of the fucking plane,
that'll,
that'll take the infant right out of you.
That'll take this Flaco
right out of your eye. Um,
that's what I missed the most,
so that I won't always face time
with my lovely lady. And um,
as the best. It's the best, but
it sucks and I'm on the road,
but I just out here being like, you
know what? I'm earning money someday.
So when she has to go to private fucking,
uh,
kindergarten for 90 grand a year
or whatever the hell it costs,
because evidently if she goes to a public
school, she's going to get stabbed.
You know what happened?
What happened to the public schools?
Was that the computers? Is that what
it was? Everybody had to have a tablet,
a laptop, some sort of
interface. Is that what happened?
And went right through the fun and all
of a sudden we couldn't keep up with
China.
How to fuck is China beaten
us the overhead of a fucking
billion people alone?
I mean,
we should be like,
we should get everything at a 60% discount
over here as far as educating our own
people.
Does it make any sense?
Does any of it make any fucking sense?
Does it make any sense how so many people
are fucking struggling out there and
they just keep building these luxury
apartments and he's fucking giant goddamn
houses who, oh, right. And they, oh yeah,
it's money from Russia.
It's Ronnie from China.
It's oil money from the Middle East.
Now listen,
I don't know what to do about China.
I don't know what to do about Russia
and I don't know what to do about the
Middle East,
but that's not gonna stop me from telling
you what to do about all these things
I just ate. Why is my
stomach grumbling? Um,
this is all you've got to do for the
Middle East. Okay. All we do is we just,
you fucking, you embrace
solar power. That's it.
How do we do that? How do we do that with
the oil companies? If somebody fucking,
and we'll be,
if we actually went to solar direction
when a bunch of planes start crashing
that had the leaders of the
solar movement on them. Yes,
that would definitely happen.
They would definitely take them out.
So what do you do?
This is what you do.
You give the son to the oil people.
Okay.
You draw up a contract and you
say the sun is yours. All right.
Now what are they going to do with
the site? They can't put it out.
They can't touch it.
It'll burn their fucking hands,
but they just make the money off
the book and uh, the solar power.
Okay. And if they could
just somehow handle that,
those people in the Middle East is sitting
on a bunch of goop that they can make
money off of. They could just seamlessly
fucking walk away from that Shit.
If I was president,
I would literally give oil companies
federal fucking grants to fucking get the
solar thing going.
You guys own the sun.
I would just keep walk. But you own
the sun and they'd be sitting, well,
both on your book. There's stuff in this
stuff. When the mill waste over, dude,
fuck that stuff.
All right?
You want that stuff? Is that, that
stuff's like God took an Atari.
It's like the Reebok pump.
Nobody gives a shit. Okay,
this is the new shit.
This is the new shit we're
giving you the fucking son,
son.
You understand that you own
the center of the solar system.
All right?
In every fucking little bit of heat that
comes off that thing that trickles down
on a Mike freckled bald goddamn head.
You own.
Yeah,
you put a fucking meat or red on
my back. I don't give a shit. Okay?
And I want you guys to
thinking, Eh, built. This
doesn't make any fucking sense.
I don't give a shit. Let's
listen to me. Hear me up.
You give these people the sun,
you give them the God son.
All right? And then what? What
happens over in the Middle East,
they sit in on all of this fucking Goop,
all right?
And all of a sudden it's not worth,
it's not worth diddly squat.
Okay. And all of a sudden the
fucking, the bills started piling up.
They don't know what to do. They start
selling their properties over here.
They want to give money
to the terrorist groups.
Then I'll get the money to do it.
You have fucking bleed them dry.
Then that's it.
And then they go back to doing whatever
the fuck they want to do over there.
God forbid they live their lives they
way they want to live it over there.
God forbid they're not into Jesus
and Starbucks, God for fucking bid.
They want to walk around and some clothes
that are actually functional for the
part of the world they live in.
You just leave them the fuck alone.
And then all they gotta do is just keep
driving around in cars and all of that
shit. So they, you know,
they'll make a lot less money,
but they won't have us over there going,
hey,
you should do this and you should do that.
We just get the fuck out of there.
Then we're over here,
solar powered everything
right?
Just think about everything
and think about your shirt.
Solar powered everything.
Everything fucking solar power. I
know what you're thinking. Well, Bill,
what happens at night?
You go to bed.
Okay,
what do people do in Alaska
during the winter? Fuck them.
We got to get out. We
got again, that place.
If it's the last thing we ever do,
it's bankrupting us.
It's making it very few people,
a ton of fucking body is bankrupting us.
We're not going to seek,
cannot solve that shit.
Okay,
so now that we know you can't solve it,
because I said you can't solve
it without doing any research.
Now that now that I've established
that as a fact on my own podcast,
the only thing, other reason to be over
there is it sitting on all that goop,
but now we don't need the group. The
group, the group, the group is on fire.
We don't give a fuck.
Keep it
right.
You give the son to the oil companies,
that's it. Just go total
solar power. You know Jimmy,
that Georgia peanut farmer, he
said it 40 years ago. He said,
we are addicted to oil. We've had. We
just kept going and going and going,
and now look at us now.
Look at us now.
Look at US spending all this
fucking money over there.
They're giving it to the constant
of shooting shit at us, right?
And then when shooting back at them,
they're making all this money and then
they'd come over and they buy a 50
fucking thousand square foot
house overlooking our shit.
Oh look in RJ. Hey, we overlook you.
We're up on the hill.
Not the other way around.
Huh?
You give them the sun. Oh God,
you guys, I'm telling you,
I would have to,
I would fucking sell those oil guys.
I would have a meeting under a mountain
or wherever the fuck do you meet with
these fucking people that really run shit.
You know,
you're underneath the mountain.
You got this fucking underwater
waterfalls and shit. Right?
There's like these planet of the apes
plucking things walking or whenever the
fuck goes on underneath that thing.
Right. And you just tell them,
is that shit flow?
And I can't,
I can't do a waterfall on my fucking
the dude from police academy.
I can't do that. Sound effects?
Yeah. Gentlemen. I came here.
I came underneath this mountain tonight
to keep me as a son. I'm sorry. I don't
have my proper recording equipment here.
I can't. I can't do my illuminati
media. You give him the fuck him.
The fucking Sun.
Yeah,
give on the fucking Sun.
[inaudible] that's what I would do.
Instead of going over there and
talking about evil doors and doors,
the evil and fucking this,
that and the other.
You pack the whole fucking Shit Up.
That's it. You pack it all up.
You sent over 10 cargo planes.
You bring the men and women of the
Arab forces. You bring them home.
All right.
You say you can keep your Google,
you can keep you safe,
but I want some of those cool clothes.
I like the clothes they wear over there.
The Jane Open ended one, Z,
whatever the fuck you call it.
I think those things are cool. Matt.
I wish I want, I want one of those.
Can I buy one of those
without offending Muslims?
Could I talk my way out of a beheading?
If I put one of those on, just went,
look man, I'm a, I'm a red head. It
was hot out. I look on page. Am I,
what am I supposed to do?
Yeah.
Then they get my face.
You'll blow away. Um,
that's it. That's all I wanted to say
today. Give the oil companies, this son,
he gave it to them and then the
whole fucking thing is over.
Whatever.
I believe I can fly.
Um,
so I got to get here tonight
and I'm going to go, well,
I'm going to go play some drums, is a
little rehearsal studio down the street.
I'm going to go play my fucking
drums for a couple hours.
I was going to go right around and one
of those fucking Citibank fucking banker
cut bicycles, but there's never any,
they got like 14 for the whole city.
And then also what kind of an
asshole rides a bicycle in a city.
You know what I mean? What am I in Europe?
How many people die a year in Europe?
Just riding around on
bicycles in a fucking city.
So is fucking cars go by walk.
We bought, we bought, we bought,
we fucking yet another ambulance going
over to pick up some fucking, yeah.
Six foot,
three inch fucking 110 pound European
that taken out on his bicycle that has a
basket on the front.
MMM.
I like riding bicycles. Oh, you know what?
I watched this documentary
called ovarian psychosis.
Right.
How do you not click on that?
I first clicked on this action movie
and it was just the same fucking shit.
The one guy who beats the
fuck out of everybody. Nobody
ever, they all have guns,
but they never think to use it.
And I was just like,
I've seen this a million times.
It's really loud.
And look at that nice classic car.
They're wrecking the fucking thing. I,
I can't watch this shit.
So I shut it off and I saw this thing
called Ovarian psychos and I was like,
I want, I want, I got it. I to see what
this is about. It was about some, uh,
some women in east La,
mainly Mexican who are sick of fucking
being scared women and they started their
own group when they ride around
these women's only, um, you know,
riding bicycles when there's like
a full moon or some shit. I Dunno.
I Dunno. So I was watching this stuff
and of course typical guys look, Whoa,
women's all we go slow
or the fire guys only bug,
right.
I hate when people act like
it's a level playing field,
you know what I mean?
It's like they're having this thing
because it's not a level playing field.
One of the women,
and there was this like everything's kind
of full fucking men only. What's your,
it really is when you really look at it.
Okay.
I don't want him to fucking come off as
like a, a complete God damn liberal here.
All right. But you know, it
really is, it's, it's just,
it's there for the taking for
you. When you're a guy, you know,
not saying you're going to get it.
Nine out of 10 people still fail.
That's one thing that feminists
don't realize. You know,
when you listen to them talking about
what it's like to be a guy that had this
cartoonish idea of what it's like
to be a guy, you just show up. Oh.
And the classic one, the more you act
like a Dick, the more people respect you.
I love that one. If a women of a woman
does it, she's considered a bitch.
If a guy does it,
it's like,
have they ever done a survey?
Just ask the general public, Hey,
if you had your choice between working
for somebody nice or working for a
complete fucking asshole who treats
you like shit, which would you pick?
Yeah.
Yeah. Nobody does. I think the,
when I meet successful people,
truly successful people that get it.
Yeah.
Successful in there, personal life
and in their professional life,
those people I always meet, their
always humble. They're self deprecating.
They walk into a room, you want
to be around him and they, they,
they're good at talking to people.
They don't come in like fucking
Alec Baldwin in Glengarry Glen Ross.
Um, that bullshit that men respect a guy
like that fucking record of fucking with
him. No, I don't,
I don't respect anybody like what I see
as an insecure asshole who's afraid it's
all gonna go away by the
afternoon. Um, anyway,
so I'm watching this documentary,
check it out. It's actually really a,
you only get bothered me
about the documentary is the
way they spelled psychos,
ovarian psychos. It's
like, but you're on cycles.
So why didn't you spell the first half?
Like cycle and the rest like psycho,
you know, a little word play
there. Nothing. All right. Anyways,
so I watched it and it was interesting
and actually it's this one woman said in
it, you know, cause she'd been through
all this shit when she was, uh,
a little girl with their mother and
then she had a daughter, I believe she,
and at least she had a kid, she became
a mom. And then her mother said, well,
now do you at least understand me?
I bet you understand me a lot more.
And she said to her mother,
no,
actually I've never understood you less.
And actually cringed when I, when I
saw that and I was just like, you know,
that's something if you feel it,
you don't say to your mom
like, what do you get out of
saying that's your mother?
All you're gonna do is devastated her
and make her feel like she completely
failed as a mom and it doesn't
get you any real estate.
That's something you say to your
friend and now that I have a kid,
it's just like,
I don't even understand what the fuck my
mother did to me even more and have it
in your fucking clink your wine
coolers and then that's it.
You don't say it to your mom
or checking callers.
Um,
I just watched the Schick
hydro transformer ad that
made those dollar shave club
ads make even more fucking sense.
The blade literally turned into
one of those fucking robots.
Okay.
Why is my tumble wagging his finger at me?
Like he just blocked a shot in a mobile
one commercials. Is he out of NBA Money?
Where the fuck did he
come from out of nowhere?
Did he buy one too many fucking gold
chains is some shit and then easily called
up as agent or I need to work again.
Is that Schwartzenegger? I don't know.
Okay.
I don't have no idea.
Um, I don't have my ads.
I'll have to read the ad at the end
of this fucking thing. Whenever that,
whenever the fuck that thing comes
in, I have no idea. Oh, by the way,
I forgot to bring this up. Season three
of f is for family is going to happen.
Thank you so much to everybody
who watched, we are now, um,
breaking stories for season three.
It's animation.
So season three ought to come
out somewhere in late 2019.
Now we're hoping that we can
have a come out. You know,
we came out May 30th
of this year, so we're,
that's what I'm personally,
that's what I'm shooting for it now.
I haven't communicated that to
anybody I've worked, I'm working with.
I'm just assuming that they already know
that. And then if it doesn't happen,
I will just get quiet for
no reason around them.
That's the way I was taught to
communicate with others. While growing up,
do all the math in your head,
do not communicate it to anybody.
And when they don't see it,
the way you see it,
you just stopped talking to people.
That was the way it was done.
And then you just don't talk to
him for like three days. And then,
then when they finally like,
well,
I guess I'm not gonna fucking talk to
you again. You then out of nowhere,
it bring up whatever game happened last
night and you start talking about it
like the last three days.
Never fucking happened.
That's the way it was done
when I was growing up. Um,
they, one of these days,
I'm actually going to fly up
to port Chester and helicopter.
I'm trying to convince this guy
to put dual controls. I mean,
it's the whole fucking
purpose of me going right.
Fly over the George Washington bridge.
I just want to see how you, uh,
transition through all this
fucking commercial airspace
where you have j f k you
have LaGuardia and you have new work.
But I see helicopters all the time
going up and down the Hudson Bay.
So there's gotta be some corridor
that they're allowed to fly,
like probably I would
guess no higher than like,
I dunno the flight really fucking low,
but I never know if it's like sightseeing,
but I wouldn't think you'd be any higher
than a thousand feet and you just Kinda,
you know, and then just look out
for sully when he comes to landed
in the Hudson Bay. Um, I do know with lax,
you either transition along the beach
at a below one 50 or you go along
supported a boulevard,
which I never do that one.
That one always scares the shit out of
me because you look down and there's a
jumbo jet underneath you.
And I always think like,
what if she aborts is landing and
just fucking yanks back on the stick.
Then I got this fucking 300 person missile
coming right at me and my little art,
22,
you know,
you ever see a cheetah
running down a baby, whatever.
That's what it would be like accepted.
See Aviation version of that.
And I would be the baby gazelle,
not even out a baby turtle.
How slow is a baby? Turtle.
Is there anything sadder than
watching that documentary?
When those baby turtles try to make
it to the ocean and all those fucking
seagulls come down and pick
off nine out of 10 of them.
I fucking love turtles.
I had a pet turtle when I was a kid
and um,
used to feed it like dead grass offers
and shit. I love this fucking thing.
I love cleaning the tank,
making sure it's shell stayed fucking
wet and all that so it wouldn't crack.
And uh, had my little tank set
it up. I fucking love this thing.
I love watching it coming up
for air and all that shit.
So one time I went to church because
that's what I used to do every Sunday.
Right. So I went to church
with my family baggy shirt.
So we go to church and uh,
I came home.
Yeah.
And the turtle was the way I'd
position the rock. The turtle
had gone head first into the water and
it's turtle ass was out of the water.
Yeah.
And I mean we went over and I picked
it up and its head was sunk all the way
back.
Yeah.
It's like Shell and its
eyes would close in.
His mouth was open and it wasn't moving.
Yeah.
And I was like, Oh fuck, is
it dead? Did it drown? And I
went downstairs and I said,
dad, it's my turtle dead.
And he goes, yeah, he's gone.
And I was fucking devastated.
So I took a red and take a brown,
you know,
you put your lunch in the Brown, like
lunch bags, put the turtle in there.
And then I went out in the woods and
dug a little grave and put the marker up
and then that was it. And then my dad
was like, we'll get you another one,
we'll get you another one. I was like, no,
I don't deserve it. I blame turtles. I,
it was my fault. I set up
the fucking, the rocks wrong.
And that was just said San Jose.
That's it. That's it. I'm done.
You know,
I've done,
I'm not going to kill another fucking
turtle. And it was so weird, like,
like four days later we were driving
down the street and it was a turtle
crossing the street. This is when
there was actually animals, you know,
before we fucking killed and
ate all of them. You know,
I blamed the food network for that.
You know,
when all these fucking assholes
going around eating bizarre foods,
I'm in Timbuktu,
Wheaton magnets right now all of a
sudden everybody's gotta Eat Maggots to
servant grasshoppers at fucking Mariner
Games or whatever the hell they doing
out there, um, was America.
We don't eat grasshoppers.
We Doritos,
Taco Bell.
Yeah.
You give them the sun.
Everybody I'm telling you that
would turn this country around.
Turn this country route.
Just give him a son.
That's it. So anyways, I
flew the other day on a,
on Tuesday.
I hadn't flown in like a month and I
flew like a fucking champ to the point.
I actually got a God damn compliment
from my instructor with unsolicited said,
you're flying great today.
Made me feel really good. Okay.
I've done my auto rotations.
I'm ready to get back out there and solo.
So there's a flight I want to do.
I want to fly up to San
a fucking Barbara solar.
So that's what I'm working towards. And,
um, I'm really looking forward to it,
but flying a lot in the
valley and everything, getting
to know all of that stuff.
Um, it's so fucking cool. Yesterday we
will actually going to two days ago,
we're going to try to fly over to Santa
Monica airport cause I know that they're
gonna they're allegedly
closing it in five years.
We'll see what the fuck happens. So I
was like, well, I never landed there.
I might as well go over there and check
that place out. But what we wanted to do,
like pad work,
they don't let you do that over there.
Noise abatement's and all that.
They don't want some helicopter
flying around and all that shit.
So we just said fuck it.
We flew up along the coast and went
by the Pacific Palisades and you just
sitting there, look in this. What this the
whole give them the son Shit came from,
I looked, I said, look at that
fucking house they are building.
This house was the size of this house.
I looked at it and I said
to the instructor, I go,
that looks like if the building of fucking
mall that I would never go into going
like that's going to be too crowded.
And it was somebody's house.
It was going to cost half
a fucking billion dollars
and there was some prints of
some fucking country in the Middle East,
you know,
was going to move. That's like his fucking
house on the other side of the world.
That's his cottage. And that
right there, I was just like,
how much fucking money we
give it to these people.
Yeah.
It's time to give the oil companies
to son. That's, that's all you do.
So they're still in control of everything.
You know,
they could give us empty threats, well
shot at, you know, like they could do it.
Um,
so anyways,
you were flying over there and I'm just
looking at all these fucking houses and
I look down, I see this one,
it was fucking beautiful
house. I got Jesus Christ.
Look at that one.
I'd have this glass where you
couldn't see in at all like ceiling.
The floors is fucking look like a yet.
But it was a house and uh,
and those guys,
they was give tours so they know
all the celebrities like, oh,
that's so and so's fucking
house. And I was like, wow,
that's what 20 million a movie gives you.
And I'm not going to say the guy's name
because he probably has enough fucking
people looking at his house. Although
recently they said that he sold it.
So I have no fucking idea.
But anyways.
MMM.
I had a great time.
I did have a great time.
The only thing is whenever
I land off airport, I all,
all the fucking shit that I
know to do the downwind checks,
you know, all of that. I forget to do all
of it. That's the only part I fucked up.
So we're doing like this
pinnacle landing and I, you know,
you set up downwind base and
then go final and I fucking,
you know, always coming in for a
landing. I was still doing like 65 knots.
Like I'm supposed to be down to like 30
you know, slowing down and shit. Guys go,
no,
you go on a little fast.
They want to do some s turns
here. But anyways, Amr, yeah,
very excited to do that type of shit.
And a,
this is the time when I would
usually read some advertising there,
but I don't have any, what else can I
talk about here? Let's look it up, man.
I have to have my
password. I'll say, can't,
you know I got in here late and they
watched the little at the end of the
fucking Yankee scheme,
the BB bombers over there fucking
kicking the shit out of everybody. Um,
Oh,
you know I love about my building here
in New York is we have rooftop access and
Tim,
I feel like that's part of,
uh, the New York spirits.
She gotta be up on a fucking roof.
The only thing that sucks is you
can't smoke up there. You know,
they just have like chairs. I don't even
think he can smoke. I just said smoke.
I don't think you can eat.
You know what I mean?
I think you just can go up there and like
read books. It's like, what the fuck?
You know what I mean?
It's probably camera's up there.
Can and go up there and bang your bride.
Huh? You like this going like, Huh,
look [inaudible] and he can't do
that anymore. Back in the day,
back in the 90s when I was there,
I got pine sharp on in the background.
Somebody is trying to
sell a Murray eliminator.
Yeah, it looks like that looks
like an Apollo three speed. If he,
I don't know if you guys noticed,
but bill on f is for family has a bike
like that and there was a bike I always
wanted and my parents were like,
no,
we're going to get you
the nerdy more fucking,
we're not going to get you one of
those cool chopper looking bikes.
We're going to get you one of the fucking
nerdy once you know beach rambler.
Let's see what the fuck this guy's
asking for this the f three eliminator.
I mean
eliminate or mark to or
what are you going to do?
How much you're going to get through this?
Okay.
I'll check them out
and is where they always fuck
them over. Actually the seat. Uh,
some of metal fleck, as you can
see, has a little scratch on it.
So I'm going to give you one 90th
of what your asking price was.
MMM.
You don't kills me. Those fucking bikes
were like, I don't know what to do.
They were probably 60,
70 bucks,
which is a lot of money back in the day
and now they're worth like hundreds and
hundreds of dot. Yeah. Dot.
It's called inflation. It's
called the Federal Reserve.
Um, all right. I just went down the
rabbit hole. All right. Um, that is,
I was just checking in and you guys,
I've just given you a couple of laps on
your ride home or whatever the fuck it
is that you're doing.
Um,
I guess I'll do the advertising read
whenever the fuck I get that and I'll just
splice it on the end of this,
which is what you're gonna
listen to in two seconds.
So I don't know why I just explained
it. All right. By the way, um,
balcony seats for Paul Versey standup
special on August 13th at the Tarrytown
Music Hall have now gone on sale.
Uh,
tickets are going fast for the two shows.
I'm very excited about me and, uh,
Pete Davidson are going to go out,
go out before Paul's show to a
warm up the crowd that night.
Do a little fucking
smothers brothers thing.
I think we're just going to try out new
material. I'm going to run that by him.
We just, you know, he'll try a new
joke. Then I'll try a new joke.
And then you guys get the judge
who's you like better. All right.
And then who ever fucking wins gets
a Goddamn Pie? I don't know what.
We'll figure something out.
It's going to be a great night.
So thank you everybody for watching.
F is for family and thank you for
helping out the all things comedy network
reproducing our first stand up special
with the Great Paul [inaudible] who sued
to become a household name.
She'll just start selling out nationwide,
developing a drug habit, leaving his
family, taking his family. Becky says,
did taking the fucking Hollywood ride.
Now Paul's not going to do that.
Yeah,
I can't wait to see
Paul Versey with money.
I cannot fucking wait.
First of all,
his bedroom's going to
look like a footlocker.
He's going to have all fucking
Jordans up on the wall.
He's going to have like 19 different,
just going to have a gold chain
for every fucking day of the month.
Yeah,
kind of car would he likes afford.
I sit down some giant gangster
fucking look at car, you know,
fucking walk in humidors I can't wait to
see it. I really can't wait to see it.
It's going to be, are there certain
people, you know, they get money,
they're fucking boring. Um,
I've been guilty of that.
But uh, there's other people you're
like, Oh God, I can't wait to see this.
This is going to be some
fucking legendary shit if he,
like if I came into Paul's house any
somehow in a split entry house figured out
how to put a war,
the world is mine fountain at the foot
of the landing of the fucking two stairs.
One goes up, one goes down. I,
I wouldn't surprise me in the least and
I can't wait to see it cause I love the
game. All right, that's it.
Here comes some advertising that I'm
going to read some point in the future,
but you're going to hear it
now. Uh, have a great weekend.
You fucking over there and uh,
thank you to everybody by two
tickets out here in port Chester.
I'll see you tonight.
Tomorrow's
say, all right. Here's
the reason the Jackie,
she's black cops.
Everybody.
There's only so many opportunities
in life to wear a Tuxedo. Yeah.
When you're under a mom giving people
this shot, um, it can give you this shot.
So when your big day or special
event rolls around this spring,
look just as great as
you feel, man. For me,
feel better when agree or like black
tops it laptops.com with high quality
rental suits and Tuxedos
delivered to your door.
Set the black tops gives you a new
way to rent with their free home.
Try on you. Get to see the fit
and feel the quality of suit.
Let your eyeballs roll around
in the past months before.
Do your events for your event. And the
best part is it's completely done online.
The Black Tux Dotcom let you create
your look or choose from tons of styles.
That was six elected outfits.
I love you to do this on the Internet.
Someday when you're fucking
robot replacement shows up
dressed like James Bond,
like I recognize that I recognize his
face and then it fucking kills you.
At least it'll be a gentleman robot.
So it's like this usually retail for 1200
bucks today, but as the black trucks,
they started just $95
yeah.
Why would you say 1200 bucks?
Yeah,
just start at nine five
not the $1,200 one. No,
she says if you have any questions
or issues, their expert customer,
Kitty,
there's your back every step of the way.
After ordering your suit will
arrive 14 days before your event.
If anything is less than perfect,
the black Tux will send you a
free replacement right away.
When your event is over,
just drop your rental back in the mail.
Shipping is free both ways.
How easy is that stand out at your event
for the right reasons with laptops to
get $20 off your purchase,
visit the black trucks.com/
[inaudible] that's the black Tux,
dotcom slash birth at
$20 off of your purchase.
All right, lift. Everybody.
Lifts knows that their drivers are what
keep them moving so they do everything
they can to make sure that drivers
are happy on every trip. Man.
Lyft is the ride sharing company that
believes in treating its people better
lifts. This is so much shade
against Uber. It's hilarious.
We actually treat our people like people.
Lift believes that being a ride sharing
drivers should be fun and you're having
a good time if you're out at a good time.
So are your passengers.
While I mean within reason
listless can think of some scenarios.
Well I would fall with was the first
offer in activity when you drive for Lyft.
If you keep 100% of the tips,
drivers have been paid over $200
million in tips since the feature was
introduced. Express. Hey lets
drivers paid almost instantly.
Instead of waiting for Weise
lift as either taking the
guesswork out of pickups,
the new [inaudible] and device use color
coding to help passengers find finding
drivers. You can earn hundreds.
That's actually really cool.
I always wonder why they
will lit up differently. Uh,
you can earn hundreds of dollars a week
plus tips, monitor, earn more money,
drive forward. It's never been
easier to give yourself a raise.
It's a simple formula.
Happy drivers mean happy passengers.
Maybe that's why nine out of 10 with
rides get a perfect five star rating.
Go to lift.com/birth today and you
can get a $500 a new driver bonus.
That's Lynn,
l y f t.com/ [inaudible] dot com slash
Berg limited time only terms apply.
All right.
Then as he adds for this week,
please enjoy the music and a half hour
of a special Thursday afternoon podcast
from a Thursday afternoon. Then went
by or maybe never happens. So yeah,
just
one day.
Gotcha.
This is
[inaudible].
Hey, what's going on? It's bill burn
and this is the Monday morning podcast.
For Monday,
June 29th,
2009 and that was an MP three
by one of my listeners, uh,
kind of an old school one, which
I kind of liked. Uh, you know,
a little old school, a
little new school, you know,
still have had the eighties heavy
metal radio station sound to it.
And then it also had like that, the
newer sort of a, what do they call that,
that cookie monster
singing where people were
red, red, red, red, red, bro.
You know,
I really respect the musicianship
of being able to play that fast,
but I have to admit, I, maybe I'm too
old, but I just can't listen to something
guy go, Rawr, Rawr, Rawr,
Rawr, Rawr, Rawr Rawr.
Without laughing or it just
seems ridiculous to me. But, uh,
but maybe that's me. I don't
know. But uh, thank you for the a,
I know those things take a
long time to put together,
so I appreciate anybody who does one.
And I actually got a,
I got another one this week was, so, uh,
next week there'll be a different intro
and a, if you're new to my podcast,
that's one of the things.
Um,
every once in awhile one of my listeners
will put together an MP three and then
it takes me eight days to figure out how
to fucking sink it up in garage band.
I just wish I knew a way where I,
I could play it and talk over
it like you would on like a, a,
a fucking a I guess a radio show
if anybody knows how to do that.
You know what?
There was a fucking question I was going
to ask you guys some sort of computer
question. God Damn Man, I gotta
I gotta write these things down.
I really going to write these things
down anyways. I'm still in New York City,
everybody. I am down to my, uh,
the final week.
I just have one more scene to shoot.
I got two lines, that's
all I got left. And then I,
then I'm out of the movie and
it's been, uh, it's been great.
It's been a great experience. And, uh,
but I am going a little bit nuts because
I've been away from my life for so
long, which, uh, I dunno,
I think a lot of you guys maybe don't get
to experience that if you have more of
a real life where you get to just go to
work and then come home. Um, you know,
like when you go on vacation, how it's
fun for the first fucking week, you know,
and everything's cool.
Maybe takes a couple of days to relax,
but then they comes to that point where
you get in a vacation where you kind of
ready to go home and you know,
you need to, you need to,
you just need to sleep in your own bed.
Yeah. I just want to go home, you know,
see my dog and fucking, you know,
put them in a fault pauper, you know,
put it in a full Nelson. Maybe give her
a couple of jabs to a little doggie nose.
Uh, yeah. It's another thing.
If you new to my podcast,
I really love kicking the shit
out of my dog. Um, it's uh,
I'm kidding. You know, now, you know
what this really is. This is me,
my inability to say that I miss
people in my life. Okay. This is my,
my fucking Irish Boston,
you know,
inability to hug right now to say
that I actually, uh, you know,
maybe some people in my life,
see I have to have an ambiguous right now.
So anyways, yeah. So I've been
fucking staying here in New York,
you know, going into the same
goddamn diner every morning. And uh,
I know this is a really hacky premise
and I say that every week as I throw out
hacky shit.
But what is the deal with ordering orange,
orange juice and they charge, they charge.
I had a small, they charged me 450.
You know,
I got a couple of eggs.
So I thought it was going to come in
and about like fucking uh, you know,
the $13 range.
And next thing you know,
it's like I owed like 25 bucks is
cause I ordered a fucking orange juice.
Is it? Cause everybody loves it. You know,
there's no shortage of
oranges. It's, I don't know.
Jesus Christ is podcasts socks.
This re this podcast really sucks.
Thank God I had an intro
cause I, I literally just
ran out of steam right there.
You know what is the deal
with oranges bill? Huh?
All right. Let's talk about
some fucking topical Shit.
Jeezy you would think that I would bring
up some other shit. Maybe some other,
let's just backtrack with all the
crazy shit that's happened this week.
All right. Bernie Madoff just
got a 150 fucking years in jail
for being the piece of shit that he
evidently is because the guy got convicted
for a, you know, that whole Ponzi scheme.
I think that's great. I totally back that.
The fact that they gave
him the maximum amount,
I was already getting pissed
when his lawyer was like, well,
he's this age now and so he's probably
only going to live another 13 years,
so we would like if he just
gave him 12 years, what,
why should he get out at all? He's
going to live another 13 years. Well,
let's give him 14 to make sure he
fucking dies in prison. You know,
I'll tell you out of all the fucking
things that you can do short of like
physically assaulting somebody is,
you know,
if you steal old people's money,
okay.
And they worked their asses
off their whole life. You know,
especially some of these
ritual people who, you know,
worked really hard taking advantage of
sweatshop labor and you come in there
and no, I'm just fucking around. But
seriously, you know what I mean? Like,
and then they ended up
having to eat dog food.
You took their whole life's work
away, man. I can't imagine that.
I mean God bless those old people for
not coming down there and just literally
killing the guy. I would actually
contemplate that. You know,
what kind of jail do you think that they
would send to you and send you to if
you like an 85 year old guy
who had worked his whole life,
you're 85 they means you probably
fought in at least one war.
So you're a veteran. So you already got
at the like right there. Everybody's like,
well fuck that. That guy used
to be a marine, you know?
Yeah.
Fought for our freedom.
He did the right thing his whole life.
Then he got burned by this
fucking feathered mullet
jackass and then he shot him
in the head. He actually saved
us some fucking, some tax
payer money. I don't know.
What kind of jail would they send you to?
They couldn't send you the 11 worth.
It's not like you're fucking fought
dogs like Michael Vick. Right?
So anyways, that guy got 150 years.
I think that's a that, that's great.
But I don't understand why those other
bankers who loaned all of our hard earned
money out to fucking homeless people,
you know who then defaulted on loans and
then not only do they not go to jail,
they asked for more fucking money that
they already print and the print and then
they charged us the interest on it.
Is Anybody,
did anybody out there major in economics?
Can anybody out there explain to me how,
how we keep printing money with no gold
behind it and catch up isn't like $72 a
bottle. Can anybody out there?
Can anybody explain that to me?
You know,
and if you listen to this podcast,
you know that's a major pet peeve of
mine is when somebody comes up to me and
they tell me that whatever I'm
talking about, they majored in,
in college as if that's
some sort of fucking, uh,
uh, what is the expression thorn
in your crown? That's not it.
Jewel in your side. I don't know what
the fuck it is. You know what I mean?
It's like, dude, you, you, I hate people
who go to college and major in Shit,
and then they think
that that automatically,
that makes them a fucking expert on
the subject. It's like douchebag.
You went there and you read the
books that they gave you. Okay?
The fucking school is aligned
with a certain like viewpoint.
And then you read 50 fucking books
with the same goddamn viewpoint.
All right? They're fucking viewpoint,
which is encouraging you to, to,
to go out and pay for a fucking education
that's not even worth what they're
charging you. For you to come out of
school and be 80 a hundred grand in debt.
Somewhere along the line,
the banks give you a fucking credit
card with like a $3,000 limit. All only,
even though you're only making 300 bucks
a week at hot topic or whatever the
fuck you doing.
So they get,
you're buried in that debt and then you're
suppose to knock up some broad by 26
28 have a kid and then go buy
a fucking house. She had done,
you're on the wheel to your 90
you're fucking done. All right.
So I dunno what I'm talking about, but
I'm just, you know what I'm sick of.
I just don't like when I make a point,
somebody challenges it. That's what it is.
Especially with the college education.
But anyways,
I don't understand why those guys
aren't fucking jail. So anyways, let's,
let's back up more. Michael Jackson.
I had no idea how big that guy was.
I forgot. I don't know if any of the
rest you will like this, but I literally,
I forgot how famous that guy was.
Why I should say more like how
talented he was. Because the last,
really,
to be honest with you,
from about 91 92 the last 1718 years
was so not even about his music or his
talent.
It was all about his plastic surgery.
Those trials he went through,
um,
the plastic surgery, you know,
just all the weird stuff.
And then another thing about him was I
really felt that he was kind of like a
comedian who stopped writing a
brilliant comedian. You know,
he just kept wearing those penny
loafers and he kept doing that,
kicking his leg up,
you know,
he does that little knee thing and then
the little mine step to the side and he
throws his fucking hand up into the
air, sort of the John Travolta, like,
I'm going to disco dance, but
wait a second, I'm stopping,
you know? But anyway,
so the guy dies and then they started
showing all his videos on MTV,
if you can fucking believe it.
They actually showed videos on MTV.
And I came in from shooting the
movie at like five in the morning.
And I sat there and I watched his
videos for like a fucking hour and I
remembered once again, how
would a giant, that guy was,
I don't know if you guys are old like me,
but for some of you youngsters out
there when that thriller video came out,
I can't even, it was, it was
fucking great. It was ridiculous.
I just wish that you could just
watch all the videos that, that like
had taken place before that video.
Have you ever seen that journey one,
that awful journey video where, I mean,
I'm not really into the music of journey,
but those were all top notch
fucking musicians. All right.
What's his face there?
Uh, the lead singer,
they're unbelievable voice even
though I just didn't like, and uh,
they had dramas. Steve Smith
is like, he continued to hit.
He's like one of the greatest drummers
in the world right now. Considered that.
But for some reason when
they made the video,
you have all these top
notch fucking musicians.
For some reason they decided that they
should rather than have one of the
greatest drummers in the world drum,
they,
that he should air drum and that
all the guitarist should air guitar.
And then the worst thing ever,
they had the keyboardist air keyboard
and then they will all fucking
just hunched in together,
like sort of just stomp on their foot.
It was fucking embarrassing then.
So anyways,
so thriller came out and basically what
MTV would do was they actually had a
debut with the video.
That's how fucking huge it was.
I remember they used to do debuts what
it was just everybody fucking watched it
and it wasn't just like they debuted
it and then it was in the rotation they
like showed it at like whatever,
like three o'clock in the afternoon,
right as the kids came home from school.
And then they will like,
we will be showing it again at six and
then you'd go live your little fucking,
you know,
I'm 12 year old life and then you'd
come back with fucking five 58 you'd sit
there with your jaw on the floor, you'd
it again. And then they'd be like,
we're going to show it again at
nine. And then once, you know,
right before you went to watch it again,
and then the next day everybody go
to school today, Short four times.
I show it five times.
No Way.
You'd have to stay up to three to focus
more on like these stupid arguments.
And they did that fill out for
like a fucking week. It was unreal.
And I actually watched it a what?
That's the first time I,
they actually showed the full length
one and I don't think I've seen the full
length version of that since
the 80s. And uh, I dunno,
it was fucking amazing. And then it's also
sad because you're looking at the guy,
that's what I was doing. I look
at the old videos, I'm like,
he was a good looking guy.
The fuck did he do or like a,
as you're watching them
gradually, you know, have
operations you just right there.
We should have stopped right
there. Right, right there.
Yeah.
Stop. Freeze one, two,
three red light. But he,
he just kept fucking
going. And, uh, I dunno,
one of the thing that pissed me
off as I was reading in the post,
there was a guy writing for the post
saying how he actually was at the second
child molestation trial and was saying
how ridiculous it was and how he couldn't
even believe it went to trial.
That the charges were such bullshit.
And I just remember thinking going,
where the fuck was that story
in the post during that time?
Because I was reading the posts
because I like the sports page.
And all they did was just talk
about what uh, you know, they,
they had him convicted in the paper.
So in my mind he was fucking convicted.
I hate one papers do that.
Like they go all the way to the left
and then when they realize you know that
they can't go to the left anymore than
they present the fucking right. You know,
I dunno what the fuck up saying in there,
but all I know is I actually started
believing that he was just a really
gullible jackass and was kind of wide
open to that stuff. But you know,
then this is how,
this is how I'm going to leave it,
because the guy was acquitted
twice. I'm gonna, I'm gonna
believe that he was innocent,
but this is the deal.
I would believe that the guy was innocent,
but if I had a kid,
I wouldn't leave him alone with them
for like three seconds. How about that?
You know what I mean? That's, that's
not Mike. I hear you. I totally believe
you. Yeah, those charges were fucked up.
Uh, we're going to go now and uh, yeah,
we're going to slowly back
towards the car and a is,
I listened for the Choo Choo train as
it goes around your house to make sure
that I don't get run over by it. Uh, no,
I don't want a glass of wine. Thank you.
Thank you very much. Uh, Farrah
Fawcett died. This is a really sad,
weak Farrah Fawcett.
I believe that was my first,
um, no, it wasn't. You know what?
Kate Jackson was my first fantasy famous
girlfriend and that's when she was on
the rookies. You guys
remember the rookies? Ben and
[inaudible] at it. Ben In and edit
it. Did it, did it, did it, did it
[inaudible]
remember that shit when they
have those great seventies
fucking TV shows in all right. Theme songs
like that anymore, right. Number, swat
ba but ba, ba Ba ba Ba ba
Ba. But I had to delay,
delay, delay, delay, delay.
Back when they had musicians.
That'd be a whole fucking orchestra.
People used to make God damn
livings ready. TV themes.
But anyways, Kate Jackson,
she was like the original to me more,
however you say that fucking cougars name,
Huh?
With their fucking lead pipe titties.
Um,
yeah, she played, she was the
whole shared the sexy voice.
Absolutely beautiful eyes, beautiful
hair. The whole fucking thing.
She was so fucking hot and she was dressed
like a nurse and there was no fucking
Internet. There was no porn.
There was no, I had nothing.
I was a man without a
fucking country back then.
So I would just sit there fucking
Mesmer. It was a, it was a perfect show.
And she's married to the cop.
The cops character's name,
I still remember was Mike Danco.
Right.
That's like a classic seventies macho.
I'm fucking hitting it,
right name Mike Danco.
Okay.
I'm Mike Danco motherfucker. That's
how we should have said it. There's no,
they should have beeped out motherfucker
every week when somebody said his name,
you know,
and I used to watch that show going on,
I can call and that's what I'm going
to do in life. I want to be a cop.
I'm changing my name to Mike Danko and
I'm marrying some hot ass fucking nurse
and I'm banging our in
that fucking nurse outfit.
I didn't even think shit like that.
I was like so innocent.
I'd even have thoughts like that.
I was literally like in love.
Remember that when you
actually had that in his,
before he ever met some girl who just
fucked up your whole view of women and you
actually viewed them as if they were
like these angels because they were so
gorgeous. You know, before you realize
that a three out of four weeks a month,
they're going to be absolutely
fucking maniacs. But I digress.
So, um, yeah, so Farrah Fawcett
dies. Talk about, you know,
out of all the fucking days to die,
you die on a day when a guy, yeah,
do Michael Jackson is so famous.
If you guys seen that thing,
an entire prison yard in the Philippines
work nine hours to reenact the thriller
dance and they did it and
they put it up on Youtube.
These are prisoners in
the fucking Philippines
that the risk of pissing off all you
white trash, ice road truckers out there.
Fuck Elvis Presley. Elvis Presley was,
he just wasn't anywhere near
that. He was, he was huge artists.
A bunch of people right now.
Now why are you know minute?
That's the fucking king man.
You don't say that Shit.
Elvis Presley was the king.
You understand?
They had buddy Michael Jackson was the
king of Pop. Do you understand that?
That means his,
his kingdom is clarified.
He's the king of everything. No,
he's the king of fucking pop.
Elvis Presley was a fucking king period,
which means Michael Jackson
was his fucking subject. Um,
I get that.
And also Elvis Presley didn't have
the advantage of the worldwide web.
You know what I mean?
Where you can have as little talent as
the chocolate rain guy and you can go
national. So I can only
imagine if, you know,
Ed Sullivan could have put that fucking,
you know,
I don't know what the hell
I'm talking about. Whatever.
I had to defend Elvis a
little bit. I, I, you know,
I used to make fun of Elvis and then I
went to his house one time when I was on
the road and I went in there thinking I
was going to get a bit and thinking it
was going to be funny. And you
know what? It was just sad.
I just saw a guy who was basically
the original behind the music guy,
um, and who was like, even in death,
we're all white as I felt
like I was just like,
I'm just intruding on this guy's house.
And then you walk out back and the his
grave and everybody's taking pictures
next to his grave. It just like, uh,
you know, that house should be haunted.
Like Elvis should literally be haunting
that house and scaring the shit out of
those fucking people. But God knows
they still wouldn't even get it.
They would still thinking, you know, he's
singing, he's singing from the grave.
It's a little more vulgar than I remember,
you know.
I mean, I guess he didn't ride his own
lyrics. Haley probably fucking stolen.
If you believe what some of them people
of color are saying about his music.
Um, all right, what are we doing
here? Let's get on with the, Oh,
wait a minute and now we have to go
back. Before that. Who Else fucking died?
There was some Ed Mcmahon died.
Ed Mcmahon.
Ed Mcmahon died and I hated after
fucking, you know, Michael, you know,
ed McMahon dies. Then a Farrah
Fawcett dies and Michael Jackson dies.
And then there's always that Douche
bag who has to be like, Shit. She bad.
Things come in threes. You
know. Bad things come in threes.
Really? What about David? David Carradine.
You know what about him? He died.
That makes for stupid. Some old lady died
of heat stroke. I saw that on the news.
That's five. Well, was it all on
the same week? Well, you know what,
I got two words for you, Billy Mays. Ah,
Billy Mays and I fucking died too.
So there you go.
That's four famous mother fuckers
in one God damn week. You know what?
Somebody told me some,
somebody wrote me a hilarious fucking
email was saying like, how the fuck they,
they couldn't believe that they
didn't see Billy Mays dying.
They couldn't see his death.
Come on when he clearly looks like he
ate four pounds of Bacon every goddamn
morning. He really did. He ever
do. I hate when people do that.
Like you always predict
some shit after it happens.
But I gotta admit once Billy
died, you were kind of like, well,
he really did have that heart attack
face, didn't he? He just had that,
that bluedot beard and
he was always screaming.
And not only that,
he was around all that cleaner.
How many takes do you think they did as
he was sitting there spraying that oxy
washed fucking whatever the hell
it was called, that oxy oxy clean.
Do you guys ever get that shit?
Did you,
did you feel that it made your whites a
whole lot wider? I don't think it did.
That's why I think Billy Mays. Dot.
I think it was from all that line.
He just couldn't do it anymore.
Screaming about fucking alarm clocks.
I can scratch your back or whatever
the hell he had. I don't know.
So whenever, there you go, what a
fucking month. Huh? David Carradine.
God bless them. And I really think it's
bad that people actually give them shit.
I have no problem with,
with the fact that he liked to put on
fish nets and hang himself. You know?
I hope that I'm that much of a freak
at 72 fucking years old. You know?
I just, I just, I got really like a,
I got inspired by the fact that he
was doing that, that at that age,
you know what I mean?
Do you just picture your 72 you know,
you just fucking hobbling around.
I'll tell you that paper boy,
he keeps playing with the paper too
far away from your door. That's what,
that's what I picture 72 as you know,
you're all excited. You got that.
You can't go up the stairs anymore.
You've got to sit in that electronic
fucking thing that brings you all the way
up the stairs.
You know?
Remember that Shit I was talking about
a long time ago where you have that you
have the elevated toilet seat because
anybody can use gravity and get their
fucking old ass down on a toilet seat.
But it still takes the quad strength
to get the fuck back up off of it.
But you can't afford somebody to
help you up off the toilet seat.
So you have to have an
elevated toilet seat.
So you basically for the rest of your
fucking life, you take a fucking shit
standing there like a third basement,
you know at the ready position.
That's how you take a shit,
you know,
hands on your knees standing there like
fucking Brooks Robinson waiting this
squeeze one out.
Little metamucil wouldn't hurt either.
And then you got David Carradine.
See I'm telling you guys that that's
why each stretching is so fucking
unbelievable if you want it.
That's the biggest thing you
can do other than eating well,
I think to try and still
feel young because if you
don't stretch your hamstrings
and everything, if you don't stretch
it out, use it. I guess. Atrophies.
I don't even know what the fuck that
means. All I know is I noticed, you know,
I haven't been that good about it and
I've been running with my dog and I was
like, Holy Shit, I am rapidly approaching
the age where I can't run anymore.
You know?
I mean that happens anyways.
At some point you're not
going to be able to run,
but if you stop stretching
that is the quickest.
I think that is the quickest way.
And I'm saying that having
absolutely no degree in nutrition,
physical therapy or anything whatsoever.
So you can take that to the fucking bank.
All right,
let's get into the podcast stuff
here that you guys send it. Um,
here's one for you. Last week I was
talking about grenades. I don't know why.
I can't remember why, but I had
somehow as I presented the question,
um, what would happen if I, you know, oh,
I remember because we
were talking about that,
that guy sent in that email about that
psycho who lived across the street,
who was in the army and he used to
sneak shit home and try and sell it.
And the guy was in a bar trying
to sell a fucking grenade. And uh,
be honest, you'd buy it when
you get three Budweisers in,
you're going through a breakup or maybe
you're just young and you have hope and
he just got that one fucking,
that,
that industrial area that they're just
developing in your town, in your like,
all right, this is the deal. We'll
pull the pin, we'll throw it,
and then we'll fucking row. Yeah, of
course you're going to do that. So anyway,
so I presented like,
I was wondering like what,
what the level of explosion
that concussive force,
whatever the fuck it is
of a grenade. Like, could,
if I had threw a grenade on the other
side of my bed and I dove on the other
side of my bed, blocked up my
ears and it exploded. Okay.
And I'm talking about one of those
beds, those beds way, you know,
you can't steal it because
they got like the fucking,
the wood frame underneath it.
Um,
would I be able to survive so
far? Somebody from, uh, the, uh,
the Marines told me, he said, Bill,
a hand grenade in your hotel room would
definitely fuck your day up with a 15
mil,
15 meter kill radius inside
of an enclosed space.
Your head and asshole
would be indistinguishable,
indistinguishable from one another. I
hope that answers your question. Yeah,
I would say you were pretty
specific there. So anyways,
so you who suck at math?
Uh,
a meter is a little more than a yard.
And I only remember that from that
commercial back in the 70s when they were
trying to teach us the metric system,
which bombed miserably.
So 15 times three would be 45 feet,
and that is a radius of 45
feet. Jesus Christ. So then I,
I wrote the guy back cause I
really found that interesting.
Uh, and I guess because it's enclosed that
the ceiling kind of keeps the blast in
and the walls and all that. I guess if
you're outside you have a better chance.
I Dunno,
I'd have to talk more about this,
but this immediately as opened up a new
podcast thing for anyone who's in the
military,
I want to learn about these fucking
weapons and a what they can do to you.
And I'm going to tell you right now,
anybody with a fucking gun,
there's nothing they like better than
telling you what the fucking gun would do
to you.
Have you ever noticed that
anytime somebody gets a gun,
what do they say? I, I, you know,
I just got it to go hunting,
right? And then you'd be
like, well, what's, you know,
what's, what's that gun like
in the guys do from here?
If I shot you right from
here and I shot you,
a whole fucking shoulder would come off,
you spinal core would be dangled.
They always do that shit. So,
you know, what's the point?
I have in a weapon if you don't know
what it would do to a human being.
That's what I say. Huh. Anybody
else? Anybody else or Braveheart fan?
Um, all right. You know,
actually set the end of the day watching
the whole history of the machine gun.
It was really fascinating.
Like this guy actually developed the
machine gun cause he thought it was going
to save lives when he
was in the civil war.
He was a Gatlin was the
guy like the Gatlin gun.
He was sitting there talking about how
he just saw the unbelievable level of
carnage in the civil war.
And you've gotta remember that
to Americans shooting Americans.
So even if you're winning, you know,
it's, it's just a brutal thing.
And he was saying that if
you've got a machine gun,
if it could do the work of 15
fucking people or 20 people,
um, then that would be 19 less people
who'd be out on the battlefield,
who could possibly lose their lives. Of
course he didn't do the math of, well,
if they get one too, then you need to
have another guy with a machine gun.
And then it just keeps fucking escalating.
But I did find it interesting or maybe
that was just the bullshit that he said
because he felt bad that he was making
money off of creating a weapon that could
just literally mow down
people. Um, anyways,
so here's the second part of the, uh,
the grenade thing. Um, I forgot what I,
what did I ask him? Um,
oh, I remember this.
So I emailed that guy back and I
said, okay, so what if I had a suite,
a hotel suite, and I threw it
out into the living room area.
I closed the door in the bedroom
and I dealt dove behind the bed.
So then he proceeded to take
a lot of time out of his day,
which I appreciate. Here.
Wrote me a nice long email.
So this ladies and gentlemen is the answer
to what if you had the suite and you
lit up,
you fucking pulled the pin on a grenade,
closed your bedroom door and
dove behind the bed. See,
I asked the questions that America
wants to know. All right, here we go.
This guy said, I did five years
in the marines. Uh, he said,
I got on the Post Nine
11 redneck bandwagon. Uh,
but by the time I got to Iraq in 2006,
we stop using hand grenades indoors.
Normally.
Normally we would just love a few of
those fuckers in a room and not have to
worry about the assholes on
the other side. Uh, he goes,
I know that's cold blooded,
but hey,
he can have his 73 versions
of an unspecified gender.
[inaudible] you know what, that's
a funny ass fucking loophole.
They really just say he gets 73 virgin.
They don't say that they are women.
Do they? That's fuck, that's
a great analogy. Anyways. Um,
he said, and we replaced them
with a flash grenades. Uh,
basically we didn't want to kill innocent
people in wind up on the cover of Time
magazine as the winner of
Asshole of the year. Um, then we,
after we throw in the flash flash, well,
I just literally lost my place there,
the flash grenades. Then we would
charge into the room shooting.
Like I was a in the Goddamn
Matrix. Um, but anyways,
I have seen hand-grenades go
off and there are two wait,
there were two ways of standard
fragmentation. Grenade can kill you. One,
the blast itself,
which generally projects
in a 15 foot radius.
Is anybody out there?
Can anybody explain to me the,
the blast itself,
how that kills you if you're
not getting hit by shrapnel,
just the blast.
Is that basically like the most
psychotic invisible front kick?
Is that what an explosion is
in, in that, that the air,
the force of the blast
just hits you so hard.
It's like getting hit by like an
invisible truck. Is that what it is? Um,
to be honest with you,
I've always kind of thought about that,
but I never really sat down
and tried to figure it out.
And that's basically what I was able
to come up with having not researched
anyways. But anyways, the guy says, ah,
the concussion from the blast turns your
insides into Jello if you're within a
five meter bubble.
So is that what happens?
You know what I mean?
So literally it's like getting
hit by this invisible fucking,
uh, what, what did Bruce Lee
have? The one inch punch?
It's like getting hit by a like that
times fucking 200. I don't know.
Why don't I read the rest of us
and maybe we'll find out. Ah,
the second way you can die a
horrific deaths is, uh, from uh, uh,
frag grenade is the fragmentation
from the shell of the grenade and the
fragmentation of all the other shit like
wood and pieces of other people that
the blast turns into shrapnel.
Wow.
Jesus Christ.
You know what I mean?
As much as you watched the
beginning of saving private Ryan,
like he's still really can't ever capture
how fucking horrific that must be.
Um,
the amount of damage of frag will do to
you in the next room depends on the wall
and your suite,
what it's made out of.
If the walls are made out of
concrete with rebar and shit inside,
you're more than likely just
shit your pants. That's amazing.
So if there isn't like rebar in there,
which I'm imagining is
those little steal things,
it could still fucking kill you.
Um,
if the wall is thin and some
of the fragmentation may
or may go through the wall
and hit you,
but you'll be safe from the blast itself
and probably we'll probably live all
just be screaming on the floor.
Like that guy in platoon is Barnes
crawls over and digs the shit out with a
knife. Good Lord. God bless you guys, man.
I really do not have a difficult
life here. All right, more.
Most stores on hotel
rooms are pretty solid,
so I think they could take a direct hit
and not damage anything on the other
side. Also, it depends
on the type of grenade.
American hand grenades are the
largest and the deadliest USA USA.
That's right. Fucking America baby. Um,
the Russian grenades are a
little bit smaller. I liked
this. I like the whole, uh,
the whole Phallic thing going
on here with less fragmentation,
but I still wouldn't want to be in the
same fucking zip code when one goes off.
Um, and then the second
question I asked him was, um,
hearing loss is a big
thing for me because a,
I play drums without earplugs for awhile.
And I also went and saw AACD seen a
bunch of other heavy metal bands in every
other time I wear earplugs and
I have tinnitus in my right ear,
which is a,
you know,
sometimes it can be a buzzing sound or
it can be just a ringing sound and it
never goes away and it's driven people
to suicide. If it's loud enough,
mind fortunately isn't.
It's just like,
like right now I can barely hear it.
Like if I actually just stopped talking,
if I stopped like late at night, I can
hear it when there's nothing going on.
If there's no background noise, I just
thought of here like this really low,
just soda
e
in my ear. And I know a lot of you just
was like, Holy Shit, that must be crazy.
But you actually,
that's my phone by the way.
If you're wondering what the other sound
is, that's not the sound in my ear.
That's letting me know that I
have some fucking new Texas. Um,
but anyways,
yeah,
I was always wondering like how these
guys are in war and they're shooting these
fucking machine guns and
all this type of stuff.
Like how do you not lose your hearing?
And he said to,
to answer your second question, he said,
I have a condition called Tinnitus, uh,
which I basically explained, but all
I have them explained it to, he said,
which is a permanent permanent ringing
in my ears and my left ear is pretty
fucked up as well.
Some dude opened up with a machine gun
right next to my head and I didn't have
an ear plug in my left year. So I guess
you guys wear ear plugs over there.
But I would think sometimes if you get
ambushed you don't have a men and then
you just got to fucking open up anyways.
I don't really notice the ringing
unless it's really fucking quiet.
And since I live in the
middle of a dense urban area,
it's never really fucking quiet.
So it's not an issue in combat.
We wear ear plugs that work pretty well.
Shooting aside small rooms is
still pretty fucking loud though.
The loudest thing over there are
aircraft in anything that explodes.
I'm talking about the loudest fucking
thing you would ever hear in your life.
Also,
we normally communicate
non verbally through hand
signals and just knowing where
you should be in a certain situation. Oh,
he's addressing the fact that, you know,
you always watched
those cop movies in the,
in the sort of whisper after they
shot a couple of rounds, you know,
and I've shot a gun
without fucking earplugs.
That's another dumb thing I did when my
hearing and I couldn't hear anything.
So there's no fucking way I could then
whisper to somebody next to me going,
you go around back and I'll try to keep
them busy here cause they got to be
going like, hey, I can't fucking hear you.
Um, so anyways, he said they use hand.
Um,
anyways,
besides shouting within earshot of the
enemy is retarded since they counter
attack and the element
of surprise is lost. Uh,
this email was probably longer than that,
ladies.
Oh, that Lady's who've made fun
of your suit on Konan now, dude,
I totally appreciate that man. If
there's anybody else out there that like,
really,
uh,
that's like some time life
books kind of stopped,
you know when they talk about what
it's really like. So if anybody else,
if I have anybody who's a overseas,
God knows you get the Internet over there,
if you're over there in Iraq or if
you're over there in Afghanistan,
and I'm trying to think of a question of
any of the listeners have any questions
of stuff over there. Um, I
got one for you. You know,
you sit there and you train and you go
through bootcamp and you do all that
stuff, you know, and uh,
you get yourself ready for battle and
then you go on over there. You know,
I know my biggest fear would have
been like, what am I going to be?
That guy who freezes up and is crying in
the fetal position spooning his weapon
in a foxhole is someone's screaming at me,
private bar for Christ Sake,
get your shit together.
You best on fuck yourself pile.
I mean what happens is does
it just naturally clicking?
Cause I would think even in my first
battle, even if I didn't push you out,
I would still be a spazz and
woo fucking empty in entirety
clip. I remember talking
to cops about this shit.
We had this cop on my radio show
uninformed and by the way, uh,
I have a new episode coming out.
We taped one a yesterday that
will be out on a July 3rd.
You can listen to that on a
XM two o two and A. Anyways,
this cop was saying how a lot,
yeah,
he worked with guys the first time
they pulled their weapon. This is,
this is an old school guy,
so they still had like the six shooter
and was saying they pulled that gun out
of their holster and by the time they
brought it up level with the suspect,
they were literally out of bullets
because they would be pulling it out.
But I've had my Bambam like
shooting literally into the
ground in front of them.
They've had guys shoot
themselves in the foot. I'm just,
I just can't imagine the
fucking adrenaline that is
going through your, your,
your body when something like
that is happening. So, you know,
if it's not too painful,
obviously I'm not trying to
have a big therapy session here.
This is supposed to be a comedy fuck.
So if you've got some funny stories or
anything like that, uh, listen to me.
If you've got any funny stories about
war and engaging the enemy, I don't know.
Anything that you would think
would be fucking interesting. Uh,
cause I don't think I can, I can
answer any more questions about comedy.
I've pretty much answered them
all. But um, I don't know,
I'm kind of speaking for the group here,
but I find that stuff really interesting
because my only frame of restaurant
references when I watch movies
and you see these guys, you know,
they throw your,
never see that in the movie.
Like there's a grenade
lands near the guys,
then somebody dies on top of it to
save his buddies life. Now from,
I always thought that you could do that,
but having just read that last one,
evidently if I did that, then
just, you know, all the 200,
whatever bones in my body would just
turn into shrapnel. And you know,
I don't know if people
would die around me,
but they would definitely rolling around
on the ground trying to get my femur
out of the side of their fucking neck.
So we all learned something.
All right,
let's
along with the, uh, the podcast
questions then. You know, it's just not,
the question is obviously post to
all veterans cops, anybody rednecks.
If you got,
knows you probably threw a grenade at a
duck and it's bill came back and hit you
in your foot. Now you've gotta limp. Any,
any of those fucking stories? I, I would,
I would love to hear all right.
Podcast questions of the week. Uh,
this was a really interesting
one. Um, this guy says, ah, Bill,
I come from a family where more than
half of the women have gotten pregnant in
their teens and almost all of
the men have ended up in jail,
in jail at various points in their lives.
Um,
so I've seen firsthand how having a
kid when you're not ready and going to
prison at an early age can
really fuck up your life.
And because I'm trying not to,
because I'm trying to end the tradition
of poverty and dysfunction in my family,
I am very hesitant towards trying to
hook up with random women and can be
considered a bit of a nerd also.
Um,
due to the fact that I don't have like
two or three baby mothers and I'm never
bringing girls around the family,
you guessed it.
I've now been accused of being
gay, I guess by his, his, uh,
his family members. Wow. Okay.
Thought I came from a dysfunctional
family. Um, all right.
I hope you see my dilemma here. Uh, if
I go out of my way to prove I'm not gay,
then I'm acting, acting like the classic
homophobe. I'm not cool with that.
I'm also giving them power by trying to
conform to their perception of what a
quote unquote real man is. But if I
ignore it, they continued to talk shit.
It would be different if, um, if,
if it were a collection of Douche bag
jock sang things like this, but it's not,
this is my fucking family.
The people who are supposed to
love me unconditionally. And yes,
as sad as it may seem, my family members
are that stupid and ignorant. Uh,
they think being gay is something
that warrants being made fun of.
Although I can, uh, I can
really see the humor in this.
It really does hurt a little doing the
right thing by staying in school and
trying to make something out of my life
while staying out of trouble has gotten
me where I'm accused of being gay.
I'm so disgusted with my family that
I'm seriously considering cutting each
member out of my family life.
Even my own mother, parentheses,
my, my father's dead. Your thoughts. Uh,
I think you're doing an amazing
thing to be honest with you.
I think one of the hardest things to do
is to grow up in a fucked up and to be
in the environment and be surrounded
by totally immersed in it.
Yet still have the ability
to pull yourself out of it
and analyze it and look at
how other people are living and if they're
living in a smarter way or a way that
appeals to you more,
to actually try to go and try to go in
that direction without doing what most
normal people.
What most people do in that situation
is they just look at other people.
If they're living a smarter life, they
just dismiss them as facts. You know,
well, I want to go to college like
these a bunch of figs, you know?
Um, yeah, that's a,
that's a lesson I learned late in life
that you really have to watch out who
your, uh, who you surround
yourself with because a,
you basically end up,
for the most part,
you end up doing what they do.
You just get sucked into their vortex.
So I don't know if that's the right word.
Whatever the fuck it is,
you get sucked into that.
They're little, uh, their world.
And so if you're hanging out with people
who were doing dumb shit fucking up
their lives, the chances of you fucking
up your life is going to be huge.
And Dude, you don't want two
or three when babies with,
with two or three different women,
you know that everybody knows that.
And even those fucking retards
who are doing it, they know that.
And you know what it really is?
I really think this is a classic example
of misery loves company and they,
when they're laying in bed at night,
they know that they've fucked
their lives up. And you know what?
When people fuck their lives up,
you know what you do,
you lay in bed and you
think about the first day,
that day when you fucked your life up
and you wish you could just go back to it
and make a left instead of making a right.
That's what the fuck they're doing.
And the harsh reality is you can't go
back in time and which leaves you with one
of two things.
You can even eat them,
man up and admit that you're the
reason and you're responsible for,
you know,
for the fact that your life is fucked up
and you try to make the best of it and
try to actually help other people
not make the same mistakes you have.
That's the most noble
thing that you can do.
Or you can take the easy way out like
most people and is try to fucking do that
and misery loves company and
drag everybody down with you.
That's all they're trying to do.
They're trying to drag you down to the
bottom of the swimming pool so you can
drown in their fucking misery too.
So you're doing the right thing.
And if you have to a,
I don't know if you've got to like
totally cut them out because it is your
family that is your mom and at some point,
you know,
you know they're not going
to be around forever.
So it's never good to not go for long
periods without communicating with your
family.
But you just kinda got to give yourself
a halftime speech or a pregame speech
before you talk to them. To
make sure that, uh, you know,
you basically stay on point and uh,
yeah dude,
that those are my thoughts. You're totally
doing the right thing. And I think, uh,
I think you're a really strong person
that you are able to see how fucked up
your family was. That's a hard
thing to do, you know? Um,
and try and correct it, you
know, so it'll be great.
So then you'll end up
with the right woman,
you end up having great kids and
then you'll be, you'll break the, uh,
your break that circle,
but the problem is dead.
You'll then run into is then when you
have kids is then they're going to want,
they're fucked up kids to hang out
with your, uh, enlightened kids.
And that'll be the hard thing because
they are your cousins in, in, in whatever.
I Dunno, it's a fucking mess. But
Dude, you're on the right track.
So what do I think you should keep doing
what you're doing and try to find some
middle ground where you keep
them at an arm's length,
but you don't totally sever ties.
And when they,
and when they give you shit,
you know about being gay,
just give him shit right back.
Oh really?
Really? Really? I'm, I'm, I'm gay. What?
Because I don't have some fucking psycho
coming in here trying to burn down my
fucking clothes cause I knocked up
another fucking broad. Now don't do that.
Don't go for it. That's what I would
do. I'd go for the jugular. Like, dude,
your life sucks.
Okay.
What's it like earning $400
a week and giving it in,
dividing up 380 of it and fucking given
it to three different women and then
he'd go on down to the fucking hot
dog truck in and buying you dinner.
You dumb fuck, you know, put a
shirt on and get your shit together.
I don't know. I would just say
mean shit. Don't listen to me.
That for the first part of my advice
was good, but uh, yeah, try to find a,
I dunno, you know what, talk to somebody
else for the second half. I right.
I'm not Deepak Chopra, but I, I got,
I think the first half of the
advice I gave you was good.
All right. So that's it.
You're doing the right thing. There
you go. Something positive. All right,
next question. Hey Bill. Um,
essentially a pretty big sports fan.
I was wondering what we are opinion.
What was your opinion of soccer?
Um, I'm not much of a fan. I basically
only watched some of the World Cup,
but today at the restaurant I was watching
Brazil versus USA game and a few of
my Brazilian coworkers,
um,
we're watching the game and for
the first task for the first half,
I had a blast watching the game
because basically I got to play out the
stereotypical over the top clues American.
They were just dying inside when the u
s scored a the first two goals and I got
to fuck with them. I was yelling,
Shit like a throw the flag. Uh,
I'll tell you what Brazil needs to do.
They should call a timeout and regroup.
And then my coworkers
were taking me serious,
furiously telling me that there are no
timeouts in soccer. Oh, that's great,
dude. They should call a
fucking time out. I'll tell you,
there's nothing more fun than playing
up the ignorant American, you know,
that's the greatest thing you can do when
you go to Europe and they start giving
you shit that you don't know anything
about their country and brace it and just
be like, yeah, dude, I gotta be honest.
Nobody talks about your country
in my country, we don't have,
we know who the fuck you guys are.
What do,
I can't believe you're not all walking
around a wooden shoes over here.
You guys have cars, you know, just
fucking play it up. All right. Anyways,
he said at,
my coworkers were taking me seriously.
If you're a seat telling me that
they want a time out. And he said,
once the US scored the second
goal, I yelled, what are the odds?
I'd say about a Brazilian to one
dude. I actually wish I was there to
see that you really signed up noxious.
That must've been great. Is there anything
goes? It goes, but then in the long run,
uh, they ended up giving me shit because
a, as I was watching the game, um,
I was thinking, why, why not
have Brazil take a, Oh, this is,
this is a big conspiracy theory. He
goes, but as I was watching the game,
I thought it's something that,
uh, I'm amazed that the F F I f a
didn't arrange this to make it happen.
I was thinking,
why not have Brazil take a dive against
the US, but you know, make it look good.
And then the next year when
the World Cup came around,
the interest in the US would
be through the roof, you know,
let the u s beat Brazil and then you,
uh, you spit out a bunch of t shirts,
you split them 50, 50, with the
Brazilian, you know, the whole,
we kicked Brazilians ass,
uh,
Brazil's acid in 15 years when
everyone has forgot about the game.
That's when you make the movie. What do
you think about the idea of bill? Well,
I think, uh, if I read it a little
bit better when it made more sense,
you think it would have worked? Um,
yeah. I think we beat Brazil in us.
The U s team started, uh,
building up, you know,
something.
Actually,
I don't think it would've worked because
those people down there take soccer way
too seriously. Brazil takes it really
seriously, but they're not like,
like Columbia or was it Columbia?
Like, uh, was it the Venezuelan team?
Somebody accidentally put the ball in
their own net and the guy went home and he
got fucking machine gun, like the
fucking Saint Valentine's Day massacre,
you know?
Yeah.
Um, so no, I don't think it would work.
I think would work in America because
we don't give a fuck about soccer.
Um, all right. I think that's the
end of the questions that I have.
Anything else here? I'm a
little disorganized. Uh,
all right.
How about this?
How about a movie review and then I'm
going to end this podcast because, oh man,
I have to end it for now.
This is too fucking lock.
I'll read one really quickly.
Uh, the punisher movie review based on
the marvel comic character Thomas Jane,
who was in the midst of the dream catcher
in the thin red line stars is Frank
Castle, who is a former Greenbury
that becomes an FBI agent.
Castle has one last bus to
make that involves stolen
weapons. And during the bus,
the son of a mob boss, Howard St,
played by John Travolta, is killed.
St wants vengeance on who got his son
killed and finds out the castle is one the
one who caused saints son's death.
Not to spoil, but shit happens.
And castle gets in his Camaro
to fuck shit some shit up.
I give it two out of four stars. It's a
movie that tries to be a real realistic,
which is great compared to the over the
top cliche Aquins action sequences and
the SQL.
It's definitely worth the
rent or a purchasing as how
it's $5 on DVD and $10 on
Blu Ray at best buy or Walmart.
And there are two versions,
the three theatrical and
the extended edition.
So this guy gives a two out of four
stars basically saying the punisher is a
good rental. All right. And
that's the podcast for this week.
I hope you guys enjoyed it. Uh,
there's going to be one more podcasts.
I'm out here in New York City and then I
will finally be back out in Los Angelis
. Um, for,
or maybe actually I'll be
in San Francisco. Yeah.
Cause July 13th is a Monday and I will
be doing two shows at the punchline in
San Francisco and I've yet to put those
up on my site, so I have to do that. And,
uh,
the next big date I have is I'm going
to be doing the comedy works in Denver,
Colorado. I believe the dates are the
23rd, the 24th and the 25th. So, uh,
please come out and check that out.
And if you're a fan of my radio show with
the uninformed show with Joe de Rosa,
we have a new episode coming
out, uh, this Saturday,
July 4th, I think I said the
third early earlier, but July 4th,
I'm listen to it.
I'm from nine to midnight on Xm two oh
two I will be sending out an email blast
just to give you guys a heads up
when I get the exact time. All right,
so that's it for the podcast.
You guys all have a great week and
don't take any shit from me. Okay,
bye bye.
[inaudible].