Hey,
what's going on is bill burn?
It's time for the Monday
morning podcast from Monday,
February 5th,
2018 what's going on?
How,
how are you doing?
I'm actually doing pretty
good after a super bowl loss.
Congratulations to the Philadelphia
Eagles winning their first super bowl
championship bubble.
The first one,
first one's the best one.
Um,
if my team hadn't lost,
I would have gone online or something
like that just to watch grown men crying
in Philadelphia over sports,
which is one of my favorite things ever.
Um,
I remember when the Patriots won their
first one. I was actually at the game,
haven't gone previously to when we
lost the fucking bread five Bruh.
Let me took off his helmet
and ran down the field.
Yeah,
I bet it's age and cried on that play.
We're going to make so much money.
Look at him. He's so adorable. Um,
have you seen a picture of
his Dick Lately? No. Um, I
just remember when when we,
uh, kicked that field goal and we won
and I've got to say we, by the way,
people go, oh, well you
will know the field. Yeah,
well I get shit when my team loses.
All right.
Whenever your team wins, people
go, um, you weren't playing,
but if your team loses, then they
gon fuck you guys. You guys lost,
so suck a dick. All
right. We lost just today.
Anyways. Um, yeah,
I remember when we kicked a field goal
to win the fucking thing and everybody by
, but he tackled each other. And I got
up, there was this guy just standing.
They was just standing
like tears in his eyes.
Like he was going to fucking start crying.
And my eyes met his and he was looking
at me. It's a weird, to this day,
it's still wear this moment
that I've had with another male.
I could see if we were at a fucking
funeral of Jesus Christ, you know, man,
the fuck up. And I also remember,
um, if I was in Philadelphia,
I would want to hear from that guy.
One of my favorite things this year
and the football season was when, um,
dad,
when Carson Wentz went down and that
eagles fan called in the radio station and
started breaking down crying to the point,
he freaked out the radio host,
he called up,
he was like sort of complaining
that all of a sudden he's just like,
when's it going to help happen?
No
fucking radio is, it's going like
buddy, buddy, you're crying for hours.
It was great.
It was just fucking great.
So I would love to hear that guys follow
up colleagues probably crying even more.
So
I really wish when I finally saw the
eagles win the Superbowl, that they,
they weren't playing my team so I could
have enjoyed it more because is something
as a sports fan that I really
enjoy because there's only two,
two fan bases that I just wish,
wish eternal misery on.
And that's the Yankees because I have
to the same way they do it with red sox
fans and the Montreal Canadians. Other
than that, you know, if you, I, you know,
I wouldn't ever wish that, you know, a
fan base never got to fill a championship.
So congratulations to you guys.
All right. Now having said that,
um,
I've had the dead Don Henley Song in my
head this whole morning just thinking
about the game because there's always
that fucking devastating shock when your
team loses.
And the song I woke up hearing
today for whatever reason,
was don Henley's last worthless evening
and I was walking around the kitchen.
I was just singing.
That was the worst Farc in
defense that I've ever seen do.
That was the, you know, it was an exciting
game, but if you really look at it,
that was arguably the ugliest
fucking Superbowl I've ever seen.
It was like both teams were
in a fucking prevent defense.
The entire game.
That was a fucking Superbowl people.
There was two punts the
entire game and no socks,
unless you call the call
'em count the Brady fumble,
which I don't know how that works if you
slapped a ball out and then you tackle
the quarterback if that's
considered a sac. Um,
I heard them kind of alluding saying
this was the first sack of the game.
I was at a Superbowl party, which I
usually don't do, but I got a kid now. Um,
and I went actually,
you know,
I had a good time as a bunch
of kids running around,
throwing balls and all that stuff and
I was being the lunatic sitting in the
other room by myself trying to watch
the game or whatever. But, uh, anyways,
you know what's great about having a kid,
you don't have to watch the halftime show.
I would put her in the
stroller and go for a walk.
So I don't even know
who played the halftime.
I just kept walking by the front door
and I kept hearing music and one of the
music ended. I came back in and then
somebody goes, hey, great timing.
Great timing is like, Hey, you
know, I've watched a few of these,
watched a good 40 of them. Um, anyways,
I've never seen like the defense
was so fucking bad in that game.
It was literally like, how did either
one of these teams even make it here?
I don't know if it was the
weird match up or what. I mean,
I don't know anything about the fucking
eagles considering I thought that
fucking Sproles guy was still playing.
Uh,
but I did call it with the running game.
I just didn't know was that fucking do
that you got from the dolphins, whatever.
Right. But I knew that that was
going to be a problem. Um, yeah.
I don't know what the fuck
happened to the eagles,
but I will tell you the
New England patriots,
the game this season where I
went like, oh boy, oh Jesus.
We went in at this year was when we
played the Pittsburgh Steelers and we went
down,
we went down and we scored.
The fucking game was over. There wasn't
enough time left even with big Ben.
And then we gave up a 90 yard screen pass.
And the only reason why we won that game
was because of that stupid fucking is
it a catch isn't a catch that when he
catches the ball here and he turns and
starts running with the ball,
we don't know if he has possession
as he possesses the ball.
And reaches over the fucking goal line.
I the,
my number one thing I want
them to fix in football is,
is that fucking rule.
Um,
I don't remember there
really being a huge,
is it a catch isn't an a catch controversy
before they fucked with that rule.
So every once in awhile,
you know,
you try to make the game
less controversial and you
do dumb shit like that.
Or even the Tuck rule, man, it was
fucking stupid. That was a fumble.
It's the stupid as well. He
tucked it in. I don't know,
but I don't know the rule book the
way they do it. It's fucking dumb.
And all you rate a France who are jumping
up and down because of patriots fans
said that that was a fumble.
Go watch the fucking roughing the passer
call that you guys got back with old
Kenny stable and Ray Hamilton jumping in
the fucking air that gave you a goddamn
Superbowl.
Okay,
so why don't you take off your fucking
rocky horror picture show scary rate of
costume and shove it up your
ass. All right. And sorry.
Still a little upset that my team lost
tack and fucking Raiders fans who are
about to become the most
profitable fucking franchise. Um,
in the moderate and NFL era era.
The second they go to Las Vegas,
they're going to do so well in Las Vegas.
This is my prediction that I'm going to
say the rams who will eventually moved
to Reno or Laughlin Nevada or some shit.
Right.
So anyways,
getting to the game,
that was the ugliest fucking
game collectively of team
defense I've ever seen in
my fucking life. I don't remember
seeing a punter the whole game.
I haven't looked at the stats, you
know, cause my team lost. So you know,
you go on fucking radio silence,
I'm not going on social media cause not
one eagle fan talk to any fucking shit.
And I already looked at my feed last
thing, so he was like, good fuck it,
don't all this shit. It's like where was
that before the game when you're green,
knees were fucking shaken.
Um,
I think there was two punts,
no sacks other than I guess that Brady
thing that they count that as a sec.
Okay. If you told me before
the fucking game started,
I'll just say,
cause I don't know what happened.
I'll say the eagles punted once and the
fucking patriots Panto wants you just
told me.
All right,
you're not going to sack nick foals once
and the eagles are only gonna punt once
and you'll have one turnover. I'd be like,
oh boy. Oh, this is going to be ugly.
We're going to get the living
shit kicked out of us. And I bet
if you told Eagle, I mean, what
the fuck? What the fuck happened?
Or the eagles difference.
Hmm.
I thought they were going to kill us.
I was like teaches this fucking
team looks like those giant teams.
So they've got that great front for,
they've got to fucking running game.
They're going to fucking make Brady move
and we're going to Google.
You'd be frustrated at punting and all
of that shit and then they're gonna have
the running game chewing up the fucking
clock. Um, it was still a great game.
Uh, and I know there's a bunch of Patriot
fans whining about that trick play.
Who by the way Chris Collins worth
just couldn't get over that play golf.
They kept going back towards this guy
[inaudible] I caught him clay. So,
well history, it's like you mean the one
the patriots just ran five minutes ago.
You see that at least five times a
fucking year in the NFL regular season.
It wasn't like this unique trick play.
And if you watch college football,
you see it about 40 times a year.
It's just the standard fucking play now
I guess illegal formation is if there's,
you need six guys on the line and the
eagles had five and there was one guy cut
hair back. So I dunno if you want
to say that's illegal formation.
I'll tell you this with the
defense played yesterday and they,
if they actually called that the eagles
would have scored in the next fucking
play. Alright. That'd be one thing.
If we were actually stopping them,
I would actually look at that and be
like, well wait a minute. Blah blah blah,
blah blah. You know, my buddy
said something funny. He goes,
you don't have to Patriots scored on
that and we actually won the game.
They would be calling it a formation
gate for the next three fucking years,
which is hilarious. We probably would've
lost a draft pick because of that play,
but there's no fucking way,
um,
on any level I would ever take that
victory away from the eagles state.
They totally, they won the
fucking Cape. I write that in a B.
This is how bad the difference was.
Even on the last play of the fucking game,
they still had to give the eagles fan
base of fucking heart attack when they
batted the ball all around in me that
there was like three patriots that had a
shot at the balls as it was
like hanging in the air. Um,
just a really a weird,
weird fucking game. But, um,
I can say this, I am really happy for, uh,
for eagles fans and the city of
Philadelphia and I know that I,
I will always be sort of connected to
that city as if I fucking hate them.
I don't, I never did. It
was just, I had a bad show.
I was in Philly and I went after the
shit that you loved. But I, I really,
the only time I ever really hated a
Philadelphia team was when the Celtics and
sixers had that great rivalry. But
other than that, you know what I mean?
We're in the AFC. You're in the
NFC. We were in the Adams Division.
You are in the Patrick's division.
I actually used to like
the flyers back in the 80s,
because I liked fights and
I remember rooting for them.
I think they played Edmonton,
I forget who they played,
but they were going to lose the game.
And out of nowhere,
Ron Hextall had an absolute shit fit
and for, I've never seen a goalie
do this.
Just skated out of the crease and
started fighting somebody just completely
spazzed out, ran out,
skated out, I should say.
Um, but after awhile I
couldn't become a flyer.
I couldn't stay a flyers fan because
they reminded me of how I was living my
life where it's like, well, this worked
fucking 30 years ago. Let me, uh,
let me keep trying it.
Every year. You know,
they kept trying to beat their way to
the cup cause at one and s because at one
I'm a cup at 74,
75 and then they continued to do
it well into the two thousands.
Um, so anyways, what else did,
I made a couple of notes here.
Uh, I think that was it.
I think that was it. Um,
anyways, but this one, it doesn't hurt
the way those giants one's heart. Um,
this one is just a, this one
just kind of sucks, but anyways,
congratulations.
That's fucking great.
So now the Philadelphia
Eagles in the last 10 years,
the Philadelphia team at the city of
Philadelphia has won a world series and
they won a Superbowl. So now they
need the flyers. It's 76 is to win,
which I don't know how the fuck that's
going to happen. So, um, anyways,
there you go. There's my
Superbowl chatter. Once again,
congratulations to the eagles
fans and, uh, you know,
patriots, feds, he has his, here's the
positive that you can take from it.
All right.
The team 100% over achieved this year.
Not Having Edelman the whole year,
haven't Gronk concussed and Brandon
hooks, cooks, I should say hooks.
Brandon cooks essentially
knocking himself out of the game.
I've never seen anybody do something
like that. When he peeled back,
I literally yelled,
what the fuck is he doing?
I've never seen a guy peel back with the
ball and be looking the wrong way and
get himself knocked out of the game.
They should have been like
Benny Hill music playing.
I don't know what the f I think he
was so surprised he was that open.
He didn't know what to do with the,
he is like,
he had his own public park to himself.
Um,
anyways, he, here's, here's your, uh, as
patriots fans, how you can get past this.
Um, just be happy, you know, every, every
time the Patriots win the Super Bowl,
you know, when you really
think about it, you know,
have you ever gotten a ring yourself?
You don't get a ring.
All you have to do is now go out and
buy a championship tee shirt and get a
subscription to sports illustrated.
So it's nice, you know,
to avoid that expense. Um, anyways,
so there you go.
And now the worst feeling ever,
almost as bad as your team
losing the fucking super bowl is,
uh, the football season is
officially over. No College,
no pro, no Canadian, no nothing.
MMM [inaudible].
Whatever you got march madness coming up.
Formula One starts next month or whatever.
But um,
anyways, congratulations on the
Patriots on a great season. And, uh,
once again,
congratulations to the [inaudible],
you're super bowl champion
Philadelphia fucking eagles, man.
Who would have ever thought, um, now wait
a minute, let's go around the league.
So who's left?
We all know that Cleveland browns
and they certainly didn't take a
step towards wanting one this year,
but you never know. Sure. They
got a bunch of draft picks.
Let's go run a league patriots. Obviously
if one giants, obviously if one jets,
one Superbowl, three eagles,
if one Pittsburghers one ravens have one,
Washington is one,
the Carolina Panthers. Oh, in too,
uh,
Tennessee titans
lost to the rams and one of the great
super bowls of all time. All right.
And they never wanted us to Houston
Oilers. They didn't want an AFL title.
I believe the first year
Jacksonville Jag was never one.
So there's, there's three
teams that have never won. MMM.
And the brown sets for,
yeah.
Bengals never one. That's five lions.
Never one. That's six. Dolphins have one.
Tampa Bay's one. Atlanta never
one. That's seven. I'll shut this.
A lot of teams left.
New Orleans is one.
Yeah.
Okay. All right. Moving on up. And
Minnesota Neville one bears have won.
Yeah.
Kansas city chiefs one. So
go for cowboys. Have one.
Houston Texans have never one
has nine Broncos have one.
Arizona cardinals.
Never one.
That's 10 San Diego challenges.
Jesus Christ.
This is really saying about how
many dynasties has been in football.
Yeah.
The rams never won.
Fuck raid is if one 49 is of one Seattle
of one I probably missed a team or two
there. So 12 teams,
seven one 20 teams have,
yeah.
Well I guess you know something.
If when the Patriots,
we say the Steelers have
one six patriots at one five
49 is one five and cowboys have one
five that's 21 of the 52 Superbowls.
Right. They're spread out against
with just four fucking teams.
Giants got four.
So that's 24 packers have four,
that's 28.
So that's one for like six
teams of one 28 of them. Well,
I guess it kind of makes sense then.
So I guess there's really no
shame at this point, you know,
having never won a fucking Superbowl and
considering like a lot of those teams I
mentioned, we're expansion teams like
the panthers, Texans and fucking Jag was,
um, all right, you go and now the
goddamn season out the window.
And I have to be honest with
you, uh, I am really fearful,
you know,
with Tom Brady going to be turning
41 here that it might be a long,
long time before we ever
get back to another one. Uh,
if we don't get back next year
because, uh, I'll never forget,
you know, everybody talks
about Dan Marino who, uh,
undeservingly gets all this shit for
having never won a Superbowl. I mean,
the game had passed his coach by,
he never had a running game.
He never had a defense.
He still did. What he did.
Was he supposed to tackle people too
and come up with the fucking game plan.
The man would literally throw per 6,000
yards a season if the rules of pass
coverage where the way they they are.
All right.
Now that guy went to a super
bowl in his second year,
I believe in 1984 not only did the
dolphins never get back during his career,
they've never been back period since then.
So that was 34 fucking years ago.
Dan Marino was 23 years old.
He's now 57
that's how fucking nuts this is.
So I'm telling you right now
when Brady and Belichick leave,
mmm.
You know,
I'm going to be 50 years old.
If we go through what the dolphins
go through, I will be 84 years old,
still waiting for them to get back.
So I don't take any of this for granted
because there's a lot of patriot people
hate the pages. Go you guys, you must
have thought he would be exciting anymore.
It's like, no dude, it's
fucking unbelievable.
I'm trying to enjoy every second
of it cause I always think, okay,
this is the last time we're getting back.
Thank God we won.
This is the last time we
were getting back off. Fuck,
we lost this is the last
time. Oh, we lost again.
Oh we won. We won again. Now
we've fucking lie. Yeah, I dunno.
I Dunno. It's fucking, uh, you know, and
for all you Patriot haters out there,
I mean you're really supposed
birds. He said it best. He goes,
it's like you're literally watching
something you be probably never going to
fucking see again that level of dominance.
But, um, I do understand, you know,
if you love you fucking team and
I'll let shit, but uh, anyways, I uh,
we had definite,
I don't know where we are on the run.
We're definitely in the final 10% of it.
And I don't know if that was
the last tip that we shall see.
We shall definitely see. But you
know, here's the thing, if they,
if they never get back again in 34 years,
so they do either way,
I'll be sitting there watching
cause I have nothing better.
Um, okay. What is that
20 minutes in? All right,
let's read a little bit of
fucking advertising, shall we?
Shall we all right.
And don't
talk about how every man looks
better in a suit. I'll tell ya,
I don't think I've ever been. So star
struck is when I see Tom Brady in a suit.
You know what I made
here and just all the perfect places are
Indochino is the largest custom apparel
company.
They make suits and shirts made to your
exact measurements for a great fit. Yes.
So after you get measured,
stop fucking eating stupid or try
to remember exactly what you ate.
Guys love the wide selection of high
quality fabrics and the options to
personalize all the details, including
the lapel jacket lining, Eagles fans.
You can get Superbowl
champions, right? You're a,
you're a little lapel monogram in
much more. Here's how it works.
Pick your fabric, choose your
customization, submit your measurements,
place your order, and wait for it
to arrive in three weeks or less.
You can shop online and indochino.com
or visit any of their showrooms across
North America this week.
My listeners can get any premium
premium Indochino suit for just $359 in
Indochina, [inaudible] dot com
that's I n, d o, c h, I, n o,
a indochino.com when
entering burr at checkout,
that's over 50% off the regular price
for premium made to measure suit plus
shipping is free.
That's indochino.com promo
code [inaudible] for any
premium suit for just $359
plus free shipping. Incredible deal for
a perfectly tailored suit. All right,
and is the latest always the
latest advertiser? I got high.
Uh, you'd never turned us the word
you hate the most when you're married.
You'd never turned down the free money,
right? You never turn down free money,
right? That's how you read it. Well,
if you shop online
without the best coupons,
you're already paying too much coupons.
Is this for like old people?
Old People Online? We'll be back
after these messages. Fortunately,
there's a free browser extension called
honey that automatically finds the best
coupons on the web. So you always get
the best prices on everything online.
Please personalize this
to make it your own. Okay?
In two clicks,
oh wait,
let me make this my own in two
fucking clicks ad oh honey,
yes,
honey.
To add height to any
bought browser for free.
Then shop like you normally do,
honey scans and tests.
Millions of coupons in
the background at checkout
will automatically apply the best
coupon to get you the biggest discount.
Over 7 million fucking people use honey.
He every day and together they've
saved millions of dollar when hi
honeys got your back, you'll never
overpay for anything ever again.
Mandatory personal endorsement.
What's the last purchase you made
with honey? How much did you save?
I don't know how to use it.
I'm fucking 49 years old.
I'll have to figure out how to use this.
Uh,
there's no reason to add honey to your
browser today. I'll tell you right now.
If I use honey,
you know what I would use it for to buy
a New England patriots AFC championship
tee shirts. Oh, making a
joke about your own team.
There is no reason to add honey
to your browser today. It's free.
Takes just seconds to install
and will save you tons of money.
Add honey to your browser
for free right now.
To now join@honey.com h o n e
y.com/ [inaudible] that's join
honey.com/burr hey, all
right. Dollar Shave Club.
Everybody.
Dollar Shave Club.
Everyone knows dollar shave club ships.
Amazing race for a few bucks.
What you might not know is that dollar
shave club also has products for pretty
much everything else you need in the
bathroom. Body Wash, shampoo, Hair Gel,
lip balm, everything. If you're
sick of the nonsense at the store,
now is the time to try out dollar
shave club for a limited time.
Dollar Shave Club is basically
giving away their shit. Shower,
shave starter kit started set, sorry. Uh,
to new members for only $5.
This starter set feature features their
executive razor and three trial size
versions of their most popular
products that help you stay fresh,
so fresh and so clean.
In your first box you will
receive their shave butter honey
bodywash and one white
Shoery on Cherry, but wipes.
You will receive their executive razor
which includes their premium weighty
handle and focus set of cha cartridges.
After the first box replacement cartridges
are sent for only a few bucks a month.
This offer is exclusively
available@dollarshaveclub.com
slash [inaudible] that's
dollar shave club.com/burr dollar
shave club's high quality products.
We'll have you covered from
face cheeks to butt cheeks.
There is no better time to try the
club and lastly, but not leastly
stamps.com
okay.
Postage rates have gone up.
Again,
let stamps.com keep your rates down with
postage discounts up to 40% discounts.
You can't even get at the post office.
stamps.com gives you 3 cents
on every letter you send. Pay
202,016 prices for 2018 stamps.
Just use stamps.com to automatically
calculate and print the correct amount of
postage for every letter or package you
sent. Stamps. Sob chrom makes it easy.
They'll send you a digital scale to
automatically calculate the exact postage
stamps.com we'll even help you decide the
best class of mail based on your needs.
Anything you can do
with@theofficeyoucandorightfromyourdeskwithstampsdotcomiusestamps.com
anytime
I'm sending out my posters
when I'm on the road, right?
I'm a moron if I can figure out,
so can you,
and right now you too can
enjoy the stamps.com service
with a special offer that
includes a four week trial plus
postage and a digital scale.
Go to stamps.com cheese. I can't say
I got the Invisalign in. Sorry people,
go to stamps.com click on the
microphone@thetopofthehomepageandtypeinbirdthatstamps.com
enter
Burton.
Look who just came in.
The one thing that can put my smile
on my face after a super bowl loss.
My wife and my beautiful daughter,
she insisted on coming in.
Okay, come on in. You know what?
I don't know what happened last yesterday
and that Superbowl. I can't explain.
They should've been Benny Hill music
playing during that game. Can you give us,
are your breakdown honey bunch?
What happened?
Pushing the microphone away. You don't
even want to talk about you so devastated.
That's cause you're spoiled
because this, hi. Hi.
Hi.
The Patriots won the Superbowl every
year of your life until this year.
That's right. She's one years old.
They've already been there twice. Oh,
it all she knew was winning.
Sorry.
Sorry that you had to learn
this ugly lesson. Oh my God.
If they showed nick foals wife, one
more frigging time. I get it. Isn't it?
Unbelievable.
I guess I have to say as a redhead,
the way blonde people get treated, I
swear to God, if she was a Brunette,
maybe they would've panned past her face
to some fat eagles fan eaten a cheese
steak. Are you going to say anything?
He just thrown your hands up.
Is it weird that I have head phones
on and a microphone here can say hi.
You say Mama? Nothing. Nothing. Nothing.
She speechless after that loss,
right? There you go. There's a Mama.
Can you say hi? Can you
say hi buddy? You can wave.
Hi. Hey, who played the halftime show
yesterday? Justin Timberlake. Oh,
it was Justin Timberlake. Oh
Shit. I should have watched that.
I was pushing her up and
down the driveway, having a
grand old time. All right.
Hi. All right, let's stop. Stop
trying to show off here. Let me,
let me finish my podcast here.
All right. Come on. Say Bye. Bye.
David showed a quarterback's wife
that much since, um, Kurt Warner,
you know,
although she was a Brunette,
so there goes that theory.
All right.
They're stupid. Pompom hat on. You're
in an indoor stadium. All right, Bill,
don't be a better douche. All right, I
want congratulations to Nick Phil's wife.
Um, I was hoping that the Patriots
were gonna kick the shit out of the,
just so I could have seen
the sports headlines, you know, and if,
if nick falls through like
three interceptions, they
would've said Nick folded,
but it didn't happen.
Um, alright. Formula One,
let's get to the questions here to see.
Oh No,
I gotta tell you about
my show in Reno. So, uh,
I wanna thank everybody
that came out in Reno,
even the dose that tried to interrupt
my show and have a youtube moment. Um,
I, I fucking love that city,
man. I had such a great time.
I went up there and I worked my buddy
Rick Dalea, who we started out together,
um,
way back in Boston in 1992.
I think he may be started like a month
before we tried to figure out who started
before, but I always
remembered seeing him and, um,
you know, seeing a friend, you know,
Jesus Christ and we were, were,
I've known him for 26 years.
I've actually known him longer
than the age where you're at,
when we met each other.
So it was, you know,
just all the stories were coming
out and when he brought me up,
the actually made a reference to
this fucking hell Gig that we did.
Nick's comedy stop where I started.
Um,
they,
I remember that was such a big
deal to work at that comedy clubs,
just a legendary place. It
was the house that, you know,
Steve Sweeney and Don Gavin and
all those guys built. And um,
we were both, you know, no name
comics, just pass being open.
Mike hers had started hosting and like,
you know,
outside rooms like Dick Doroty
rooms and all of that and um,
read Rita from,
Nick's called us up to do a private gig
for Nick's comedy stop and I couldn't
believe it. I was like, oh my God,
things are finally starting to happen.
And you know, mean to Leah found out, you
know, we were working with each other,
which should've been a red flag
right there going like you,
they called you to all my God,
they believe in us. Right.
That should have been a fucking red flag
right there because both of us should
have been opening for somebody who
knew what the fuck they were doing.
But instead we show up.
It was the fishermen's faced
in the north end of Boston,
which is the Italian section,
or at least it was back in the day.
I don't know what, what goes on
there now. Everything, the prices,
they just driven every, every, any, any
sort of like culture has been removed,
which is why I like
going to be so-called B,
c and d level cities because there's
still that unique vibe there.
Um, you'll go there and see stuff that
you don't see in every other fucking city.
Um, you know, the same 10 fucking
corporate chains in whatever, um,
everybody walking around with their
Instagram look on their face, you know?
Um, so anyways, we show up
to this cake. It's outside,
literally in the fucking streets.
They tell this story last week,
I can't remember.
And it was like a fucking band on stage
when I'm on hits your eye like at a
pizza pie that so high.
Right.
And all the Italians and sitting there
singing and you're really just see,
feel this great sense of family,
tradition and culture.
And now you've got these two pasty faced,
you know,
at least Rick was half Italian.
You know, I'm fucking German,
Irish just standing there with
my fucking fire engine, red hair.
So dalea goes on,
nobody has any idea what's like,
it's fucking guys I got now we've got a
little comedy Babababa [inaudible] and
people like, what the, what the
fuck is this guy talking about?
And then delete it goes on stage.
Okay.
Trying to smile through probably
the biggest panic of his life.
And I remember wanting to laugh at him,
but I couldn't because I knew I had to
go on next or whatever he was feeling I
was about to feel. But at least
for me it was going to be worse.
Cause we, at least before he went
on stage, he had fucking hope. Like,
well maybe this'll be good.
But when I saw Rick go on stage,
I had confirmation that this
was not going to be good.
And I just remember him just fucking
interrupting this great fucking party,
which is so many of the
early standup gigs, you know,
just interrupting something that everyone
was totally enjoying and they really
don't need you.
And then they don't know that you're
coming up there and then you go up there
and they're like,
what the fuck is this?
MMM.
All I remember was when I went on stage
bombing and just looking up and seeing
all these old Italian ladies
like hanging out the window,
just looking down at us like,
like, what the fuck is this?
And just afterwards, I forget,
we probably walked out of there.
There's no subway stop or
he walked over to our cars.
MMM.
I don't even remember what, anyway, it
was great to work with him. But, um,
I was in the middle of my set having a
great time and I do this bit where I make
fun of the troops a little bit, you know
what I mean? And it's not even, you know,
it's not even fucking remotely,
it's like a fucking hilarious bit.
The first time I did it, I did it at
a VFW to make sure that, you know,
the way I was doing it,
I did in front of the troops,
they were all fucking die in laughing.
I mean those guys say that lost their
legs over there and shit and they was
still laughing. They love the
fucking bit. So I do the bit there,
you know,
and I've moved on from the bit and at
this point I'm making fun of Isis and all
of a sudden this, this guy walks all
the way up from the back of the room.
And fortunately the chairs were like,
where he couldn't get all the way up
to the front. He starts yelling at me,
pointing at the stage, go
hah, show some fucking spat.
It's what he started seeing. I'm trying
to have his fucking youtube moment,
you know what I mean?
And I was like, what?
Show some respect for
what he's going to know.
So in one of those fucking things like,
yeah,
I love the military is just so fucking
off limits now that who support the truth
you,
you just have to constantly be blowing
the military that you can't even make fun
of somebody in the Navy who all he
does is swab the fucking decks and it's
getting a standing ovation walking
through the fucking airport.
I've done that fucking pit
in front of so many troops.
They've all found it funny.
It's fun.
You know this fat fuck.
Oh my God,
I went off on that guy show.
So why don't you show some fucking
respect and lose some weight.
You fat cunt for your fellow Americans
for every time you get the middle seat on
a flight and you fat fucking
man tit spill into the other.
But I'm so fucking sick.
I'm so fucking sick of everybody being
so Goddamn fucking offended at comedy
shows and just making the
whole moment about themselves.
You fucking mouth breathing chimp,
Jesus fucking Christ.
If you can't fucking
see through the fucking whatever that
fucking expressionists see the forest
through the fucking trees with all of
this shit. I just can't fucking help you.
And considering all the shit that
I had said up until that point,
I didn't show any remote respect
for anything. Every fucking subject.
That's what kills me.
I blamed women,
perceptual harassment.
That's how I started my fucking show.
Where was the risk?
Where we're the fuck was he
during that one fat fucking cunt?
Oh my God.
I was so fucking mad at that guy.
I hated that security escorted amount.
I appreciated that they did
that thinking that I wanted to,
I wanted to talk to that guy for
the rest of the fucking show.
Walks all the fuck way up.
You know,
he was waiting for his Oprah round of
applause when I told him to go fuck
himself. Everybody left. I
can't believe that. You know,
that's the classic thing at like a
comedy show that usually ends up on the
fucking Internet. Um,
you know what I mean?
That self righteous fucking Douche bag.
You know what I mean?
Where everything else that I set up to
that point was so fucking ridiculous and
absurd. And then that's the
one that you're going to
take fucking seriously. Like,
what kind of a fucking moron. And
so saints, he's gay guys like,
did you really think I'm anti
my own country? You dumb fuck.
And when you guys come out to my
show, when you see the bit, okay,
it's so fucking pedestrian.
It's ridiculous.
I want to even know when I did
the fucking bit at the Vfw,
the troops came up to me and say,
can't we say that to each other?
But this fucking guy had to fucking, you
know, take his hair out of his ponytail,
tossing it around and come and have as
big fucking head, Roland moment. Ah,
fucking kill yourself.
I hope you fucking have a heart attack.
You fat fucking cunt.
You when it was was,
if he didn't like the bit than heckle me,
the fact that he came up there
and he's like pointing at me,
yelling at me like he's like,
I'm his kidneys fucking dad.
Anyways. Anyways, let me, let me just
fucking plow that, that other than that,
the Gig in Reno was fucking awesome.
And I got to be telling you that that
was actually more upsetting to me than
watching my team fucking
lose the Superbowl.
Um, all right. Anyways, here we go. Let's
get into the questions here for this week.
The Formula One,
oh by the way,
or Billy's getting in is continuing
with his getting in fucking great shape,
man. Um, I've made it,
my goal is, you know,
turning 50 in June,
you know,
two years of doing stand up comedy
and trying to get a positive out of a
negative five people showed up.
What do I do here?
Do I give in to the fact that this five
people or do I make those five people,
which they brought another 50. You know
what I mean? You get when you fucking,
I dunno,
when you're in this fucking business,
the greatest thing about this business,
unless you knew somebody
when you got into it,
most people get into it and they don't
know anybody and they have no idea what
to do. Um, and they're standing out
in the street in broad daylight,
in the Italian section of
Boston eating your Red Dick.
I mean, if you don't figure
out a positive mindset, uh,
you're really not gonna, you're not gonna
fucking, you're not going to survive.
So I'm turning 50, which, uh, I used
to take was going to be devastating.
I'm actually really excited to try to get
myself in the best shape I've been in,
in by about 20 years. So, um,
I'm trying to get down to my,
uh,
basically the way I was at when a,
in the shape I was in when I started.
Now I'm obviously gonna fall
short because no matter what I do,
I'm still fucking about 30 years older.
But, uh, that's not what it's about.
It's about going for it. And
I'll still, you know, so anyways,
I have a weight that I want to
get into my fucking shoulder.
The rotator cuff feels great.
Um,
and I finally have been able to get a
regimen between all the information that
I've gotten over the last year.
Um,
and I've put together a
program that that is, is,
is really fucking working for me.
And I have to tell you,
you know what I did the other day,
other than taking my beautiful
daughter to the park on the swing,
which I think I'm going to do again today,
it's my favorite thing ever is
she was on the swing and um,
I was able, you know, once I
got the swing going, cause I'm,
I can finally lift my right arm over my
head. I been able to take my shirt off,
um, with both, I've had to
take it up with my left hand.
I'm able to take my shirt off with,
with both hands in like
over a year and a half,
which is really fucked up my
closing bit. Everybody, you know,
cause I really tried to get
sexy in the end, you know, um,
I was actually able to reach up and
hold onto like the bar above the,
and I made sure I didn't put any
weight on the arm all the way.
It was obviously my feet were still on
the ground and I just gave it a little
bit of a fucking stretch. And it was
just this tightness but not pain.
Cause what happens,
I found anybody else go into this shit is,
is when you have an injury like that,
you get into this PR protective,
like, um, the way you hold yourself.
And it's fucking crazy man.
Like having that put my hand
above my head for over a year,
like I can't physically do it anymore
because those tendons don't get stretched
than all this fucking Shit just, I dunno,
grows over it or whatever. They just,
it's weird.
It feels like it doesn't feel like pain.
It's like there's a doorstop
and I just see, or a governor,
I just can't go any further. So, um,
after doing all these other exercises,
I end with that and it feels tremendous.
It was funny, I was doing that
while watching the Superbowl.
Then one of these others, patriots
fans was laughing at me like, dude,
you're really getting into this game.
And I was like, no, no, sorry man.
I'm just fucking working
out my, uh, shoulder. Um,
so anyways, uh, I hope that helps anybody
out there that has set that, that issue.
So I'll actually be able to work out.
But the great thing is I've discovered
bands working out with bands,
um, you know, in a door jam and all that,
which is really going
to help me on the road.
And I think I'm done with the
weightlifting for a long time.
That's kind of what got me into this
year's of weightlifting and not doing
enough back exercises.
And the front part of my body was way
stronger than the back and it pulled my
shoulders forward and one of them
came up and then I, you know,
was bench pressing and just the bones,
I don't know that,
that the rotator cuff tendon just rubbed
on it and got inflamed and then I was
just fucked. And it's really
something that if I, if I,
if it ever happens again, I'll be able
to get out of it and like, you know,
six to eight weeks by just didn't
know what to do. I thought, oh,
this will work itself out. And then
they just became all fucking glued up.
So anyways.
Um,
and have you ever gone through anything
just remotely physical like that to
finally just be able to fucking take
your shirt off a brush your teeth,
you know what I mean?
Or put the shaving cream on my
head when I go to shave my head.
I always had to put it in
the left hand, you know? Um,
I'm fucking mess. All right, here
we go. Formula One, everybody a,
they had Billy the red face con.
I've been a longtime listener for about
10 years now and the podcast has always
been a great break from the
drudgery of everyday life,
especially back in my university, the
university days. Okay. I'm done blowing,
you know. Anyways, my grandfather,
father and I are all car lovers.
That's great.
I remember falling Formula One
closely as a kid when shock villa,
new and Michael Back
in 1997.
I'm so pissed.
I miss that because everybody tells me I
miss the great days of Formula One. Uh,
listening to you get into Formula One
had me thinking of getting back into it
myself.
With that in mind.
I decided to buy myself an early birthday
present and bought tickets for the
Spanish Grand Prix in Barcelona for
this upcoming season for my old man.
And I do, that's the shit I'm
trying to go to two races a year,
so I'm trying to figure
out what I'm going to do.
It's either going to be Mexico City in
Brazil or if I do some tour dates over in
Europe, I'll just book
end and with the race, um,
we shall see. Obviously Mexico
City is deceivingly far away from,
uh,
la.
Like I always picture that it's just
south of Los Angeles cause you know,
you just go south and you're in
fucking Tijuana. Let me look that up.
Where the fuck is it? Ah, you know what?
I got to hold the microphone here. Can I,
can I do this? Do I have this ability? Uh,
here we go.
North
America.
I see a map.
Here we go. Come on. Come on.
Slow Internet. All right, clicking on it.
Oh yeah,
it's like south of like fucking Houston
or New Mexico or something like that,
right?
Yeah.
All right. Where do we go? There's
Australia with the fuck am I all right?
Zooming in. I really
should've hit pause. Oh yeah.
Mexico City is like south of San Antonio,
so it's like flying all
the way to San Antonio.
It's like basically flying all the way
across in and all the way south again for
almost the same distance.
It's probably, yeah,
the equivalent of flying to like Tampa
or something like that. But then Brazil,
if I go to Brazil,
I mean that's all the way you always,
I used to think of when New York,
when my buddies used to go to Brazil,
that they were flying due south and the
two south actually would get you into
like Peru on the western
side of South America. Um,
I would love to go down there too.
Um,
yeah,
maybe I'll do that.
And then other would actually be done
with all the races on this side of the
world. Uh, who knows? That's such
a cool thing that you're doing,
doing that with your dad though.
Anyways, uh, plowing ahead. Um,
I know you like the Air India team. I
also liked the uh, Williams Martini team.
I just liked the colors and I don't
want to pick a perennial powerhouse like
Mercedes or Ferrari. So my question is,
which team race or did you enjoy watching?
Most by father and I are going to pick
a team to root for during the upcoming
season to make our father son
weekend a little more fun. Thanks.
And Go fuck yourself.
Um,
yeah,
who did I like? I actually, uh,
Daniel Ricardo is probably, you know,
the closest to a Louis Hamilton.
And I would also say I
really liked, uh, uh,
cheese. I'm so new to the
sport and I haven't thought
of the name of that guy. Uh,
oh, I know in, in his teammate there,
his teammate was a fucking maniac.
Hold on a second. I've got to make sure
nobody switched on a team. Let's see.
Red Bull racing team, that
kid who's like 20 years old.
Yeah.
Uh, drivers. Here we go and
keep my seat. He switched teams.
Max for staffing was really fun to watch.
Um,
I would say out of the youngest of the
young drivers, he's probably the best.
Um,
I don't know if he's still on the team.
These guys seem to jump around like free
agents and then it's all about getting
on the Ferrari and the
Mercedes team, which, you know,
two seasons in is getting a little boring.
So I would like to see somebody else,
uh, when you know, so, uh,
I at Max for staff and I guess that's,
that's what I would say.
I would say that and I'm, I'm,
that's such a great thing to do.
I'd never been to Spain. That's amazing.
I am going to be doing a Gig, I believe,
to celebrate my 50th birthday. I believe
it's coming together over in Europe.
Uh,
I'm going to go,
I think I might be doing a gig
somewhere in England and then,
uh,
um,
be with my lovely wife and beautiful
daughter and maybe we're going to go to
France again. I'll try to polish
up and some of my French, but I'm,
if there's any races over there,
you know what, you've inspired me.
I'm going to talk to my, the guy who
books me today and I'll be like, we gotta,
we gotta figure out, you know what
Formula One race is going on over there.
Cause I gotta add that 50th birthday and
go to a formula one race over in Europe.
Man, that will be sick. Um,
right. More Formula One's shit.
Formula One grid girls.
Hey Billion Wallace and big
fan from Glasgow, Scotland,
uh, Formula One just announced
that they're getting rid
of the grid girls because
they feel this custom does not
resonate with our brand values.
And clearly is it odd with the
modern day social societal norms?
Same things has happened with the darts
and it's looking likely for boxing and
UFC in the future.
Are these probably,
are these probably ugly feminists
doing nice looking girls
out of a job or are they doing
the right thing? All right.
I don't know what the fuck I kind
of know what you're trying to say.
What are your thoughts? Cheers and
go fuck yourself. You can't, um,
yeah, that's just all,
you know, lip service,
no pun intended. It's just
bullshit. You know what I mean?
And you know,
I think it's all bullshit.
Here's the deal to say this custom does
not resonate as to say it's clearly,
is it odd with modern day
social norms? It isn't. It's a,
it's 100% at odds with
with the public horseshit.
Yeah.
Political correctness,
which all political correctness really is,
is being phony.
You know what I mean?
It's just it just denying
what you're really feeling,
denying what you really want to say,
denying what's you're
really fucking thinking.
That's why comedians seem so fucking
outrageous. They always say, Oh,
you're saying the things that people take,
but I'm afraid to say it.
They're not afraid to say it.
They say it in their cars.
They say with their friends, they
say, and at home, you know I'm not,
I'm not talking about being
a racist fucking moron.
All right.
They're basically trying to say that
men do not enjoy looking at beautiful
women.
This is against the societal norm that
people do not gravitate towards beauty,
both male and female.
Like if you're a good looking guy,
you're not going to have your pick of
the litter. When it comes to women. Yeah.
And vice versa.
Like if you're a beautiful woman that's,
you're not going to have to fucking,
you know what I mean? The, I mean, you
could look at it and like a negative way.
I always thought that because it was
outside of this country that I always
thought that they had a better
way of presenting beautiful women.
That it wasn't just like that
Hooters vibe that we have here.
Does it look this tick by tick
between those knockers, you know,
the ugly way that we fucking do
everything over here, you know?
MMM.
I just,
I think what that is is they probably
got enough crap from these women's groups
and they just don't need
the headache. So, um,
and I also feel that a lot of, you
know, when they say the, you know,
you're exploiting women and
blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
I think there's a lot of truth in that.
I don't think it's,
it's that way with this. I
think that's adds, you know,
what are they doing? What exactly are
they doing? Are they fucking, you know,
twerking and all that shit.
It's just a beautiful woman walking around
with a ring card. That's it. You know,
getting attention in a very safe fucking
way. I mean, what is the fucking problem?
You know? And I do know that, you know,
the way a guys can't handle a good looking
guys fucking Jack down at the end of
the bar, you know, a better looking.
The guy was fucked a good food
[inaudible] to go fight him. You know,
women do the same.
The
thing with the better looking woman
that comes walking into the bar,
they fucking hate him. That's, that's it.
So I think it's pretty fucking childish.
However,
Formula One is on ESPN and you know,
ESPN used to be great but now
they kind of ruin everything.
So I'm going to blame them. They are,
they obviously with too fucking stupid
to keep well boxed in who was,
was phenomenal at his job.
Um, I dunno. So yeah,
I think that's all the whole
thing is it's fucking dumb.
And eventually there's
going to be a backlash.
God forbid there's a beautiful
woman walking around on
stage God for fucking bed
and guys are like excited by it,
like you know,
in fucking whistle in a little bit.
Who gives a fucking, who cares?
You know what I mean?
This is my problem with feminism is that
all the corrections are made for them,
which is really kind of putting it out
there as if that women don't need to
adjust their fucking behavior in any
ways when it comes to men, you know,
and feminists get to speak in these
unbelievable like broad, no pun intended,
blanket fucking statements, but
guys cannot. You know what I mean?
I'll speak in some blanket
fucking terms for men. Hey,
how about sharing your own fucking money?
How about you buy around
every once in awhile?
I bet when you go through
a fucking divorce,
you try to do something fair and try and
instead of trying to take every fucking
last dying you possibly can,
you greedy cunts. Oh right,
we're moving on to the next one. No,
they don't need to adjust that at all.
They don't need to adjust any of
their fucking behavior whatsoever.
They don't do anything wrong whatsoever.
I tell you right now,
if women died that much sooner than men,
you don't think that
there would be a study.
You don't think that
there'll be a fucking ribbon.
You don't think some way that they would
blame men on some level that women die
that much earlier than, than, than men.
If it was that fucking way, I don't know.
I think that that's why guys are so funny
is because nobody gives a shit about
us. They really don't. You know
what I mean? They just don't.
Anything that happens to
a guy's [inaudible] songs,
all I have to be a subsidy
him. Right. That's it.
That's the level of support we
have for one another. Um, alright.
Deported father dear Billy Justice.
Uh,
two and a half years ago,
my father was deported to Mexico.
He had been in the US
since 1978 since he was 13.
My family struggled without him
financially and emotionally.
It's been very rough. I must've been
brutal. He's healthy and not dead,
but he can't be with us. Yeah. That's
got to go, man. It's fucking brutal.
It's been very frustrating and
words can't describe it. Uh,
I'm getting married in a few weeks and
he wasn't able to be at the wedding
everyday.
I see people criticized Trump and can
agree with their reasons for doing so.
But my father was deported under Obama.
My family knows three other people
who are also deported under Obama.
My white friends think they're good
people because they liked Obama but never
looked to see what was happening. Um,
they didn't care then, but they care now.
It makes me feel very mad because
it feels insincere and lazy.
As a white man who seems fairly
progressive, can you tell me why this is?
What would you suggest? I say to
them, it's an emotional thing for me.
So it's hard to choose the right words.
Congrats on your child.
I have two nieces and it's really the
greatest thing to watch them grow. Uh,
thank you. Um, what can you say to them?
I, it depends on how open minded they are.
Um,
people who are really into politics,
which means they 100% watch CNN
or Fox News all fucking day,
as if they're getting some sort
of fair and on bias newsfeed.
You really can't say anything to
either one of them. Uh, I mean,
there are a lot like sports
fans where, uh, I try to see,
you know, I try to, the
best I can to see Bo's,
like I could legitimately be happy
for eagles fans. You know what I mean?
I can legitimately look at
fucking Derek Jeter and say,
that guy's fucking great and I can set
aside my hatred of the Yankees are my
wanting for my team to beat
the eagles yesterday. But,
um, you know, it took me
a long time to get there.
Um, so I dunno, I mean, no one,
the way I was wired, I would just
walk right up to him. Bj, you know,
just so you know, you're fucking
angel there. Obama, you know,
who for some reason gets
no shit whatsoever. I mean,
it probably doesn't hurt that he went,
that his presidency was between
two of the fucking, yeah.
Two of the biggest fucking dip
shits I've ever seen is fucking,
did I say dip shy? And so that, cause,
trying to think over the fucking word,
I could sing and not be
too fucking offensive,
but think that I'm a fucking
lefty here. 100%. Which you know,
most of the times I am, but I mean, yeah,
keep full. We Shantay and forgive me,
hey, you're not getting full. We again,
when after that and then this guy
who fucking tweets all the time,
and then before that you had a guy shoving
cigars in his fucking people's twats
I made, I'll tell, you know,
it's been really rough since the first
George Bush who actually had the,
you know, well we, we, we,
we pushed Saddam out of Kuwait,
didn't go into fucking Iraq and was,
was,
was strong enough to push back against
the fucking corporations. Say, hey look,
this is not what we were doing over here.
We accomplished our mission and we're
going home. That's it. You know?
So it's been a long fucking time.
So I think that there's a, uh,
yeah,
does the thing with Obama, at
least he wasn't Bush or Trump, uh,
kind of thing so that people
have a hard time seeing them.
And I think he gets handled with kid's
gloves in the media, you know what I mean?
They, they, you know, every image of him,
he's like kayaking or fucking play
in highly and all of this shit,
like the joke I was doing in my act like
it looks like an erectile dysfunction
ad and they're really
kind of ignoring that,
that guy for all the hope
that he said and everything.
And I know that that job is,
you know, well, I don't know,
like literally no, but I, I understand
that it's an incredibly difficult job.
And they always say, if you can
get one thing done, which he did,
he did get Obamacare through.
So I guess it was,
uh, and achievement.
But I have to tell you,
as someone who does lean left to watch
him go on tour now was $70 million a tour
dates to go talk to a bunch of
fucking bankers and corporations,
you know, and all of that. And,
and just, I dunno, it just,
it's as far as the way I read that,
that's just those corporations
washing their bribe money.
Like we got you in office,
you did what we wanted you to do.
Now come talk to us for an hour and
we'll give you a nice six figure paycheck
and we'll all do it.
And then you can be worth over a hundred
million dollars like the Clintons,
like the bushes and all,
like,
it's so fucked up that none of them get
called out on that. It's like the bushes,
the Clintons,
the Obamas.
It's like you guys dedicated your life
to public service and the presidency is
the highest paying job, which now is
like a half a million dollars a year.
If you do two terms,
you're going to grow stops.
You're going, what does that 500
times fucking eight. What is that?
That's 4 million bucks.
And somehow they, they,
they all,
they're buying giant houses and they
all end up being worth nine figures.
Um, and everybody just looks the
other fucking way. I Dunno. So
I maybe,
maybe there's someone within your group
that is understanding enough and can see
both sides of that.
You know,
like if I said what I just
said about Obama to a Trump
person, they will be like,
they would be going fucking bananas.
But then if I even remotely suggested
that Trump seemed a little emotionally
unstable and that it's really doing the
country a disservice to be tweeting in
arguing with people on social media,
like a seventh grade girl.
I don't even fucking respond to people
on Twitter when it comes to occasionally
I do. But this is supposed to
be the leader of the free world,
trying to get a Trump supporter to admit
to how pathetic and embarrassing that
is. I mean, that's just kind of
the world that we're in right now.
But maybe one of those Obama
supporters. Maybe you could, um,
you know, I dunno. But then also
we live in such a fucked up world.
I'm going to believe that you're actually
Mexican and you wrote this and that.
You're not some white person that wrote
this shit because they hate Obama.
I have no fucking idea. You never
know. There's no way for me to vet. So,
um, if what you just said was
true, uh, that is horrific.
And I understand what you're saying,
uh,
about Obama because, you know, I,
I think the best thing he had was he
could deliver a speech better than Bush or
Trump, but a, at the end of the
day, I even know the, you know,
the needle kind of lean more
left when he was in office.
Did the ship stayed on course,
if you know what I'm saying. Um,
and that what I'm wearing right now,
I want that guy from Reno to come walking
into my fucking Romeo heck shows the
respect. Alright. Boyfriend's best friend,
a dear Billy boy lady here.
Oh,
here comes some red shoe diaries.
Shit,
I been seeing slash dating my best friend
for almost a year now. And we love
listening to your podcast together.
It's almost, it's absolute. It's
going absolutely fucking wonderful.
Except the one thing,
oh,
well this the one and a
completely different direction.
I thought you to say you ended up banging
your fucking boyfriend's best friend.
All right. Okay. Um,
it's going absolutely fucking wonderful
except for one thing is best friends
sent him pictures of naked slash f slash
half naked girls from Instagram to him.
Uh, we recently became long distance,
so I'm not sure of the frequency still,
but before I moved away,
he did it almost daily.
My issue is one,
his best friend girlfriends complain to
me about it instead of taking it up with
him
and I tell her,
I tell her to just talk
to him way, way, way.
I don't think there's too
many fucking pronouns in here.
I don't know who the fuck
you talking about. Oh,
his best friend's girlfriend.
So the girlfriend of the guy sending
the pictures complains to me about it
instead of taking it up with him
and I tell her to just talk to him.
And number two.
It's actually hard to take that advice
because I don't want him to think I'm
trying to control his life.
Some of these pictures are actually girls
that they know and not just pictures
from the chive or the code of man.
I don't even know what that is.
My question is,
do I have the right to be heard
about out about this? Well,
are you heard about this?
Yes. I'm going to say yes.
Are you a free person? Yes. As much as
they'll let you be. So I would say, yes,
you do. If so, how do I
bring this up to them?
I've lost over 30 pounds over the course
of us seeing one another and frankly
thought it, it would stop, but it hasn't.
Yeah,
that's not why I lost the weight,
by the way. Did it for myself.
Okay, well that was weird. The,
I thought Dobbs sent you were stressing
out or thanks for the advice and kindly
go fuck yourself. Ah, well
that's great. First of all,
you got yourself in great shape.
You know,
it was getting a standing ovation
right now you're, you're fucking vital.
Saw your major organs are loving you as
we live in a world now where everybody's
a hero, including overweight
people. You know what I mean?
I'm telling you right now, uh, if your
finals were standing in an airport,
you got off a plane that they would
not be giving you a fucking round of
applause.
I'm staying in shape is the greatest
fucking thing you could ever do for
yourself and you fucking deserve it.
All right?
And fucking stop playing the
victim and do something about it.
And Mit to the fact that you're the
one with the hand shoving that fucking
cupcake down your fucking throat. I'm
sorry, I'm getting off track here. Um,
I would actually, I absolutely bring it
up with them. That's completely fucked up.
If that bothers you, you should
say something and that, um,
that other,
the guys sending the
photos as being completely
disrespectful to you and you and
your boyfriend.
Okay.
You know, he's happy in a relationship.
Why the fuck is he doing this shit?
Maybe he's jealous. Maybe
he's a moron. I have no idea.
I would absolutely bring it up to him
and just say it the way he said it. Like,
you know, this is something that's
bothered me for a long time.
MMM.
I, you know, this is so weird.
I actually think if you
don't get emotional but you
don't like cry and do the
woman thing, which literally freaks most
guys out. Or maybe I'm super imposing.
Most guys with the way I feel
like when a woman starts crying,
I just started thinking like, oh
Jesus Christ, here we go. Is it now?
How do I,
how do I argue my side now?
When you as an adult or actually
crying about this right now?
MMM.
Then I'm a pushover. Okay. Cause anytime
my daughter cries, that's it. I'm done.
And my wife's just rolls, rolls their eyes
at me just like she's not even crying.
She's whining bill. And I'm like, I
night boy, fuck am I supposed to do?
MMM.
I would just matter of factly just say,
you know, that really hurts me. And um,
but I didn't want to bring it up to you
cause I didn't want to seem like a Nag.
But I'm just letting you know that that
really bothers me and I don't think it's
right.
And just imagine
if we turn the tables and
one of my girlfriends was
sending me pictures of guys
with their dicks out every day.
Like how would that make you feel?
Okay.
I'm not saying you have to stop doing it.
I'm just telling you that it bothers me.
Just put it on that and let him make the
fucking decision rather than comment.
Cause I can say it. Tell you as a
typical fucking guy, if you come out
talk to you.
Yeah.
All the guys singing it was like,
oh my God, Oh my God, how to fuck.
I mean I understand that
women are more emotional,
but when you fucking do that and a lot
of ways it's not fair to the guy because
there's no way you can argue with another
adult that is literally breaking down
crying.
Okay.
Okay. I've been in relationships
and I've seen crying,
you know, talking to me about
something to this level crying.
And I'm thinking in my head like,
I haven't seen people crying
like this at a funeral.
So it really takes away your ability
to argue your side if you have a side.
And that causes resentment,
you know,
not to mention the fact that women
can cry on cue. I swear to God,
I feel like some of the time it's
a money manipulation tactics,
but if you are able to just
just say it and just say,
I don't want to be a Nag. And I'm not
saying that he has to stop doing it,
I'm just letting you know
that it really bothers me.
And then if it was going the other way
and I was getting Dick pics sent to me
every day,
I don't think that you'd be too thrilled.
And then just let them deal
with that and they'd be like,
I'm not going to say anything else about
it. I'm just letting you know. All right.
And then let him fucking deal
with it and see what he does.
That would be my advice. All right.
Girlfriend has higher sex drive than me.
Um, all right, dear Billy. Fuck nuts.
That reminds me of that classic Louis Ck
joke to me at a time when he was dating
a Nymphomaniac and she,
and she kept going,
let's do it again. Let's
do it again. And it goes,
and she was really just backing
into me and it really fucking hurt.
And I wanted to say,
Hey,
can you stop banging back into me
before your rip my Dick off you fucking
psycho. But instead I
said, hey, take it easy.
Uh, all right. Girlfriend has higher sex
drive than me. All right, dear Billy.
Fuck nuts.
I started dating an old girlfriend from
high school after 10 years of being
apart. Oh. Like, well, when
Harry met Sally, right?
I'm now 26 and she's 27. We've been
going steady for about seven months.
I love you. You separate. Go and
stay in the skies like an old soul.
And everything has been great up until
around Christmas where the problem began.
To give you some background,
I work from seven in the morning.
Uh, she doesn't go to work until five
in the afternoon and gets out at one.
Oh,
you got to work at seven in the morning.
He didn't tell me when you stopped
though. Um, she doesn't drive,
so I have to pick her up every night.
He only day we have off together
is every other Saturday.
By the time we get back to my place,
I'm completely exhausted and pretty much
falling asleep while she's wide awake
and usually wants to have sex. Recently
my sex drive has plummeted. Yeah,
but you're not getting any sleep.
It's gonna and I can tell
you that having a kid now,
and that's totally true to
sex in your relationship.
It just takes such a backseat. You
kid goes to sleep and it's like, hey,
we could hook up or we could get
like 50 minutes of sleep and sleep.
At that point it's like gold. Um, anyways,
um,
recently my sex drive has plummeted.
Not because I don't find her attractive
or because I don't care about her,
but I'm just drained of energy.
After working 50 hours a week with
maybe four hours of sleep every night,
and after about five months
of sex every other night,
it starts to feel like a chore. Sometimes
I've been turning her down lately. Uh,
this has caused a lot of arguments
and fights in the past two months.
That's probably because
she doesn't know why.
You know,
guys, you know, generally speaking,
our horn dogs in any, you know,
you could be in the middle of
the fucking having chemo in the,
in your girl be hey, you all,
you fucking do it, you know,
banging or where you stand up with
that fucking dripping your arm. Um,
I feel like she doesn't respect my desire
to get some rest and I've suggested
sex in the morning, but at that
point she's already pissed at me.
Okay.
All right.
Well if you communicated it
and
she's still not willing to work with you,
then she's kind of being immature here.
Uh,
she seems to think I don't care about her
and that when I tried to suggest maybe
sex a certain amount a week,
like three of four,
she gets mad at me and that she
always wants tasked to initiate it.
Uh, I've been trying to be more consistent
with being sexually available and more
affectionate lately.
Like visiting her on lunch break and
getting her small glyphs like flowers to
show that I care. But the
problem is still here. Yeah.
Cause this is all you're not communicating
when we do actually have sex.
Sometimes it's just boring for me because
I'm not in the mood or I really don't
have the energy to do anything but
lay there. I really love this girl.
I don't want to lose it
due to something like this.
Do you have any advice for my problem
and when we, when we come back,
you bald ginger ball bag.
Um, I would say this,
you guys need to sit down
and have a talk and just say,
just say everything you just said to me.
This is the problem with
most relationships is people
in it say the things that
they should be saying to each other to
other people and then they expect the
other person to be a mind reader.
She has no idea that you
know how tired you are.
Just tell her and just tell her that
you love her and that you're afraid that
you've, that you're going to lose
her and all of that type of stuff.
Okay.
And just say the reason why I'm doing it
not been in the mood is not because you,
it's because I'm fucking exhausted.
I'm like a Zombie.
I'm getting four hours of sleep and um,
and just tell her that it hurts you,
that you're hurting her.
So I really needed to clear the air and
just sit down and clear the fucking air.
All right. That's what the fuck I
would do. Okay. That's the podcast.
Once again, congratulations
to your super bowl champion,
Philadelphia Eagles.
Um,
yeah,
like I said, you know, I hope you guys
know all the, all these, you know,
I had one bad fucking show in Philly
and everybody thinks I hate the fucking
city.
I actually loved the city other than the
fact you have 58 one ways going to the
left before there's one go into the right
and then another 58 going left and
then 60 going right after that.
It makes no fucking sense.
Other than that, yeah.
I really don't have a beef with you.
Um, and a lot of times, you know,
I wish that show happened in North
Carolina because I would've just stood on
stage making fun of them for
losing the civil war and a,
the fucking Charlotte
bobcat's in a hornets at all.
I would just make fun of all that,
losing their fucking team and all of that.
That's what I would've done.
I just happened to be, I
was actually in New Jersey.
That's the funny thing about all of
that. Um, all right. That's the podcast.
Go fuck yourselves. Um, I
will check in on you on a,
what is it? Thursday. All right. See you.