The,
the heroic path is,
is laid out in like a,
in,
as a metta path by religious systems
basically as the road to redemption and
the redemption is redemption from chaos,
but also from tyranny.
It's redemption from both.
And in,
uh,
in the transcendent space that those
metta stories exist.
That's a divine archetype,
right?
It's the successful hero.
But then that's an archetype mean.
So,
you know,
let's say you're doing everything right
and then your family gets killed in a
car accident and you slip and fall down
the stairs and you know,
you have a concussion and maybe you wake
up in your brain damaged,
you know,
so,
and then while you're recovering,
you get hit by some other illness
because that often a one,
two punch like that will often really
hurt people,
you know,
because they're,
they're just getting up there,
quite fragile and they're pretty hurt.
And then something else comes along and
wax them and you know,
it isn't the case.
That identification with the archetypal
hero will stop those things from
happening because there's an element of
randomness in life.
So.
So you have to be sensible about it.
You have to say it's your best bet,
which is a different thing.
It's no certain path,
but given the range of potential
negative outcomes,
voluntary confrontation with emergent to
normally roughly speaking,
gives you the best poker hand or maybe
makes you the best poker player.
That would be a better way of thinking
about it now so people can be
traumatized by my failure to update
their models because then the moral gets
old like,
oh,
Cyrus,
and it's unable to see the tyranny,
plus it's archaic and can just get wiped
out because it no longer is adapted to
the situation.
It's like you'd be like that if you were
still using dos as an operating system.
Well,
it's a perfectly reasonable operating
system,
but it doesn't.
It usually it used to really work,
but all you had to do was not update and
you'd be extinct.
Right.
One of the things Mercia Eliana pointed
out was that one of the processes that
sort of universally regarded as a sin in
so far as that's a universal conception,
so you might think about it as a data
error,
is speeding along the process of
inevitable decay through willful
blindness,
so things will decay of their own
accord,
so you have to be awake just to keep the
bloody thing alive,
but you can speed the rate at which it
decays by pretending that nothing's
wrong and and refusing to change
anything at all.
And so then you say,
well,
not only does it decay,
but your blindness is contributing to
the decay.
And that's well in one of the stories
we're going to talk about today,
which is the flood story.
That's basically the underlying story of
the flood is like God's pretty irritated
that everybody's blind and stupid,
but he's particularly irritated that
they stay blind and stupid.
And so the consequence of that is
everything gets washed away and that
actually is the consequences of that.
So when the ancient Hebrews,
we're imagining that story,
you know,
when modern people look at that story,
they think,
well,
what kind of God would do that?
It's like,
well,
we talked about New Orleans.
Why did New Orleans get washed away?
Well,
one answer is hurricane.
That's a good answer.
But the other answer is,
um,
maybe they should've made the dike
stronger like they knew for the last 100
years and maybe all the money that was
supposed to be spent on the dikes
shouldn't have got diverted into the
pockets of corrupt politicians.
And so then you say,
well,
why did New Orleans get flooded
hurricane or the sins of man and the
tendency of things to decaying.
Well,
the truth is,
is that they're both equally potent
causal elements.
You know,
when your city collapses because your
engineers have built the concrete with
sand,
which happens all over the world,
right?
Like especially in corrupt countries
where they don't make the concrete
properly because it's cheaper just to
fill it with sand.
The whole bloody city falls over.
It's like,
is that the earthquake?
While.
Yes,
because it wouldn't have happened
without the earthquake,
but it also wouldn't have happened if
people weren't corrupt,
so and there's a constant,
that's the the dynamic between the
terrible mother chaos and the terrible
father like and and the,
the other dynamic there is also the
adversarial element of the individual.
You can't assess the situation without
taking those three causal forces into,
into consideration simultaneously.
Someone just gave me a paper a couple of
weeks ago linking corruption to poverty.
Now I knew that for a long time because
if you look at the list of if you look
at countries and rank the by GDP and
then look at their corruption indexes,
it's like there's a tremendously high
correlation and you might say,
well,
poverty causes corruption,
but really that's what you're going to
say.
You're going to say that poor people are
corrupt.
Really?
No,
I wouldn't do that.
First of all,
there's lots of poor people who weren't
corrupt,
but corrupt people are poor.
You can bloody well be sure of that.
So
d a Dip.
Well,
yeah,
absolutely.
Absolutely.
I mean,
the Robo is falling like mad,
you know,
and there's a variety of causes of that
but is corrupt beyond belief,
you know,
so,
and corruption.
Corruption is like inertia,
you know,
if you and I have a transaction and we
both stick to what we say,
I hardly even have to think about you.
You know,
you're just,
you're a sentence on a page,
what a good deal.
But if you're not that God only knows
you might,
you might wipe me out because I'm
trading with you.
You know,
I mean,
I've had the business dealings with
people.
Some people I don't even have a contract
with.
We just say what's going to happen?
And that happens and for years,
you know,
and then other people,
it's like detailed contracts.
They take really six months of work to
lay out and they're violated continually
and it turns into just an absolute
catastrophe.
And so the cost of that is exceptionally
high.
You can't have a transaction that can be
profitable roughly speaking in the
presence of corruption because the
transaction cost is too high.
And so it just spirals into poverty.
You do spend all your time trying to
figure out what the hell the other
person is up to instead of concentrating
on what you could actually do.
So I think the only real natural
resources,
honesty,
you know,
and you might think,
well that's,
you know,
what's your evidence for that?
It's like that's not a problem in stable
democratic countries.
The best predictor of longterm success
is intelligence and conscientiousness.
It's like,
isn't that an index of.
Isn't that an index of the integrity of
the system?
I mean,
I don't see how you can argue that any
other ways.
Conscientious people are diligent,
beautiful and honest.
They do what they say they're gonna do
and smart people are faster.
So basically what the data reveal is
that if you're fast while you're going
to get there faster than other people
because you're fast and then if you're
fast and honest,
the probability that you're going to
move up your dominance hierarchy is
massively,
massively increased.
You know,
the overall Rahr is probably about point
six,
relationship between Iq and
conscientiousness,
but a lot of that's measurement error,
you know,
because I can't figure out how conscious
you are with a conscientious you are
with a questionnaire.
There's going to be a lot of measurement
error there.
There's less measurement error with Iq,
but then the performance indexes are
also full of measurement error,
right?
Because it isn't easy for me to tell how
well you're doing.
I could use estimates your income,
self reports of how you're doing peer
ratings of how you're doing your
supervisors ratings of how you're doing
your subordinates ratings of how you're
doing,
how much money you make.
If you're a salesman or someone who has
a direct income,
but that only captures a small maybe
that capture 60 percent of your success
or something.
And if that's the case then the are for
the measurement of your success is only
about point seven five.
And so if there,
if the,
if the measurement error for,
for ICU and conscientiousness tops out
at about point seven,
which is probable and the performance
index accuracy tops out at about point
seven,
a correlation of point five is like,
it's not 35 percent of the variance.
It's like 70 percent of the measurable
variance.
So,
you know,
and I can't think of a counter
explanation for that.
Now,
if you look in creative domains,
you have to use openness because,
and you have to use different measures
because creative people,
it's not,
it's not easy to assess the performance
of creative people.
If it was,
they wouldn't be creative because the
problem with creative people is they
keep mucking with the structure that you
would use to assess them,
you know,
so you couldn't assess the castle as an
impressionist,
that just isn't going to work.
So it's very hard for people to think
about what to do with someone like the
castle because he demands that you come
up with a whole new rating scheme.
And that's,
you know,
that's the real problem with creative
people.
So,
but anyways,
um,
I'm going to talk about this summit,
this mind matters thing on Sunday
because I've been thinking about power,
you know,
and we were.
Well we can segue into this.
So we already talked about how the great
mother emergence from chaos and so this
idea,
that's God the father by the way,
I think that's a eastern Orthodox
representation and the eastern Orthodox
church split off from the Western
Christian church in.
It was a long time ago.
I don't remember exactly when.
It was within 200 years of the 10th
century.
So I know that's a fairly big error and
I can't remember exactly the difference,
but it was way before the Protestants
and the Catholics split for example.
So it happened a long time ago.
But the idea here is that there's a
structure that emerges out of chaos and
that structure is symbolized by the
father.
And basically what the father represents
is the,
the model of behavior and perception
that has been constructed by history.
So roughly speaking,
it's what the feminists referred to as
the patriarchy.
Except the problem with the feminist is
they only see the tyrannical element of
the Patriarchy and you know,
a lot of the reason for that is because
they were strongly influenced by the
postmodern philosophers of the late 19
sixties who are almost all without
exception,
radical left wing student
revolutionaries who were working for the
overthrow of the French government in
the late 19 sixties.
So it's like there's a problem with
that.
The problem with this,
assuming that the great father is only
tyrannical,
is,
well,
first of all,
it's ungrateful because know you're in
the university and I know that as a
general rule,
University of Toronto students aren't,
you know,
the happiest creatures in the world and
their reaction generally to the
university.
And I think it's because the workload is
pretty damn high and the place isn't
that social.
You know,
they're stressed and unhappy especially
in their first couple of years.
But
what are you going to say about that?
You're going to say the whole bloody
institution is nothing but a tyrannical
mass.
So like,
if so,
what the hell are you doing here?
You know,
you got to give the devil his due,
so maybe it's 30 percent oppressive and
ridiculous and 70 percent good.
I mean,
what would you say,
what do you guys think?
How would you balance it?
You've been through the university,
you've in your fourth year,
what proportions would you suggest?
Thirty.
70.
Okay.
Well,
one of the things I can tell you that
that's a hell of a lot better than most
institutions.
Right?
So,
you know,
even if it's not the ideal,
which perhaps it isn't,
um,
compared to actual institutions rather
than comparing it to a utopian ideal,
it's like not too bad,
you know,
it didn't crush you completely,
and,
and you guys are all going to graduate
and that's actually going to be of some
benefit and there's even a possibility
that you know more than you did four
years ago.
Right?
And you haven't starved to death and all
those things and everything you taught
wasn't the complete or was taught.
Wasn't a complete lie,
you know,
so all things considered,
alright it's 30 percent mandating tyrant
and 70 percent benevolent farther and
maybe we could push that up to 80 slash
20 or something or maybe 80 5:15,
but leave me,
you're never going to get it past that.
I think at some point your attempts to
make it better than that will actually
make it worse,
you know,
so it's like in the,
in the old Egyptian story of,
of seth and it'll cyrus at horace horace
comes along and chases seth away,
but he's just hovering around there,
out in the border.
You don't get rid of them so you're
never going to get completely rid of the
tyrannical element of your cultural
heritage.
And that's partly because it's made out
of the past and the past is dead and
blind because for obvious reasons,
you know,
all the people who made it are dead.
So it's,
it's static,
dead and blind.
But that doesn't mean it isn't worth
knowing about.
And you know,
your job fundamentally is to revivify
it.
One of the things I often do in this
class,
I'm not doing it this year,
is she'll students Pinocchio Because you
know,
Pinocchio is a dramatic tale about a
marionette whose strings are being
pulled by forces he doesn't understand,
transforming himself into an autonomous
individual.
And a variety of things happen to
Pinocchio.
He has to deal with corruption in the
form of the criminal underworld.
And the devil himself sort of lurks
behind that in the story.
He has to deal with the,
uh,
the temptation of eating,
pulled neuroticism because at one point
that criminals entice him into being
useless and lazy because he's too sick
to stand up for himself.
And then he also has to go deep into
the,
into the,
into the oceanic depths to confront
chaos itself.
And when he does that,
he finds his father who's blind and
dying roughly speaking and brings them
up to the surface.
And now he actually sacrifices himself,
save them.
You know,
even though the story insists that,
you know,
while the father is drowning after the
whales been chasing around,
he basically says,
you know,
I've had it Japan.
I've had it swim to shore and save
yourself.
Pinocchio refuses and drags him to shore
and then he dies in is reborn,
and then poof,
you know,
he's real.
It's like,
yeah,
that's exactly right.
And so,
you know,
part of your obligation as a student is
to come to the university that's 15
percent corpse or 30 percent corpse,
we'll say and make the bloody thing come
back to life without assuming that it's
all tyrannical and just rejecting it,
you know?
And it's very dangerous to do that
because first of all,
if the past is corrupt and tyrannical
sore you,
because you're an embodiment of the past
in so far as you're enculturated,
you know,
so it's not like it's outside of you.
It's inside of you too.
So that's,
that's a hell of a thing.
You're going to write off your.
Are you going to write off your
socialization completely as nothing but
tyranny.
I mean,
that's a big problem.
A,
it's not true.
Although for some of you it's probably
more true than others.
And be,
well,
if that's the case and you're utterly,
utterly corrupt,
what the hell do you think you're going
to do about it?
So that's a big problem,
you know,
plus it's ungrateful and that's a big
mistake because,
you know,
if you're ungrateful you can get
arrogant and then you're really in
trouble and you are trouble.
Sure.
Well that's,
that's exactly why I made reference to
what happened in the sixties,
you know,
because the idea,
then part of that was because people
thought the Vietnam War was staggeringly
unjust and part of that was because
people were pretty tortured
existentially by the underground battle
between communism and,
and,
and the West,
roughly speaking,
which was breaking out all over the
world,
including in Vietnam.
So there was a lot of underground
turmoil but part.
But that doesn't mean you get to throw
the baby out with the bathwater.
You know,
when Timothy leary was a good example of
that,
a turn on.
So that's the LSD tune in,
drop out.
It's like,
no,
turn on,
wake up and adopt some responsibility,
you know?
And so,
but you see,
because as soon as you go to draw out,
you think,
well,
are you running away or leading and
neat,
you would say,
hey,
you're running away.
That's what you're doing.
The probability that you're leading is
vanishingly small.
The probability that you're diluting
yourself about being a leader when you
drop out is exceedingly high.
So the right assumption is if you drop
out,
you're useless and
lazy as well as arrogant and resentful.
And you should start with that
presumption and then go through a
cataclysmic soul searching to see if
maybe it might not be true.
It's true.
You know,
what's the probability,
you know,
saint or loser.
Well that's,
there are so few saints that you just
use a baseline predictions,
you know,
actuarial tables,
you have to assume loser.
So you know,
when,
if you're a loser who thinks they're a
saint,
well then you're going to cause an awful
lot of trouble,
you know,
so and that,
a lot of that happened in the sixties.
So you know,
the sixties generation likes to think
about themselves as admirable rebels.
It's like,
yeah,
let's,
let's check a bit.
For some self serving tendencies there,
you know,
like the refusal to adopt responsibility
and that's always lurking underneath a,
like a revolutionary facade.
So you know,
and I think that's had an absolutely
pernicious influence on the
universities,
especially the humanities which are
dropping in enrollment,
cataclysmically deteriorating in
influence and based far more on,
you know,
the,
uh,
what would you call it,
the,
the idea that you have a moral
imperative to be a radical activist.
It's like,
no,
you have a moral imperative to be useful
and honest.
That's the whole,
that's a whole different thing,
you know,
if you want to change things like,
fair enough,
but don't be thinking that change isn't
dangerous and that you're right,
it's highly unlikely.
So,
so anyways,
it's very,
my point is there's an architectural way
of representing the great father and the
archetypal way is tyrant or,
or benevolent dictator.
It's something like that.
And if you don't get to just say one of
them,
now you know,
here's the way you're thinking about it.
Historically,
you could say that once,
like these are archetipal and religious
representation.
So you could say roughly,
that's God the father and God the father
you see there is ruling over a walled
city and the world acidity is the father
as well because it's an enclosed space
that's keeping chaos out and there's a
hierarchy in there,
a dominance hierarchy and everybody
slotted in the hierarchy and you could
think of the dominance hierarchy and the
value hierarchy as the thing that's
manifests itself as the father
symbolically speaking.
So and that you're protected by the fact
of the hierarchy even though it also
would presses the hell out of you.
Maybe you're like a surf,
you know,
but maybe maybe it's better to be a surf
than to be someone alone in the middle
of a battlefield.
You know,
that's certainly possible.
You can make a case for that anyways.
So then you look at that and you think,
well,
is that tyranny or security?
And the answer is,
well,
it's both.
And what's the ballots and what you hope
is,
well,
let's have a little more security than
tyranny.
And then what's your moral duty?
Well,
to ensure that the great father who you
are not bloody well going to get rid of
and you better not because you'll end up
like the Mesopotamians when they slap
suit,
you remember what happened to them,
right?
Absolutely.
Was Tiamat consort.
He was the masculine element.
Chaos and order.
As soon as the ancient gods were formed,
they made a lot of racket and they were
really careless and they killed Appsu
and then they lived on his corpse.
While that's not a very good idea
because then time,
outcomes,
you know,
swarming back and the probability that
she's going to do you in with all her
monsters,
unless you really pay attention and
speak properly,
is very,
very high.
You know,
the Mesopotamians had that figured out.
Well they and they had it figured out an
image.
It's an absolutely remarkable,
a remarkable story.
So yes,
I can imagine.
Okay.
There's two questions in there.
One of the ones where sometimes it would
provide a lot of both.
Well,
I think that's what happens when you
were subjected to extraordinarily high
standards,
you know,
is that order chaos?
Well,
it's both,
you know,
because there's massive benefits in high
standards.
The problem is,
is they provoke anxiety and they're very
hard to attain.
Does that make them bad?
There's no saying it makes them bad end
good and it's even more complex than
that because whether they're bad or
good,
depends on how you react to their,
their imposition.
If you discipline yourself and
straighten yourself up and learn a
tremendous amount and achieve the high
standards,
it's way better for you than if this
high standards weren't there,
but they're also going to crush people.
You know,
they're going to crush people for all
sorts of reasons.
They're going to be really hard on
people who just aren't that fast.
Even if they work really hard or they're
going to be really hard on people who
are quite fast but really don't work
very hard,
they're going to be hard on people who,
you know,
have impediments to progress in,
in one unfair way or another.
So the tyrannical element is exactly
there.
So,
you know,
I think the whole bloody thing
degenerates into tyranny when the people
inside it are doing nothing but lying.
That's the pathway to tyranny,
you know,
and,
and I would also say that that's the
hallmark of the adversarial personality.
You know,
we've talked about the great mother
creation and destruction and the great
father Tierney and security,
but on top of that is the individual and
there's the part of the individual
that's heroic and I would say that's
exploratory,
attentive,
and capable and willing to articulate
the truth in so far as that can be
conceptualized.
And then his polar opposite,
which is the opposite of that willfully
blind and deceitful at every possible
opportunity.
You know,
there's certainly an interaction between
all three of those levels.
You know,
and I think that's part of the reason,
you know,
one of the things that happened in
Christianity was that the serpent that
was in the garden got associated with
Satan.
That's very weird thing.
You know,
it's very unlikely when that story first
emerged that the serpent had any
association with the idea of the
adversary at all.
But as the story developed through time,
what happened was if you construe the
serpent as chaos itself and maybe the
negative element of chaos,
it was easy to associate that with the
tyrannical father.
So there'd be a botanical element to
that and the adversary himself,
right?
Because it's all negative.
So that's the,
that's the connection between the three
levels.
And it took western culture roughly
speaking thousands of years to delineate
that idea.
You know,
it probably didn't come to its full
poetic flowering until Milton.
And it's very little of it is in the
Bible as it's as it as it currently
stands,
virtually nothing.
That's one translation.
Lucifer's also the bringer of light
though,
weirdly enough.
So you know,
it's a,
it's a very,
it's,
it's wild.
It's again,
it's one of these paradoxical situations
because it's also not always the case
that your adversary is the devil,
so to speak.
It might be an angel in disguise,
you know,
and that's young's notion with regards
to the shadow.
You might think that it's evil,
but it might be the thing you actually
need now lurking underneath that is the
idea that there is absolute good and
absolute evil and I think you can make a
case for that.
In fact,
I think the 20th century made a case for
that and I think that's what was decided
at the Nuremberg trials after World War
Two because the judicial decision was
there are some things you don't get to
do no matter what your culture is like
and no matter what your excuse is,
you know,
and the alternative that too,
that was deciding where we can let you
off the hook because you were following
orders,
you know,
and people really debated that and you
can say,
well the Nuremberg judges were the
allied victors and so they just imposed
their own viewpoint.
But I think that's pretty damn cynical.
There was probably some of that because
things are tyrannical and benevolent at
the same time,
but you know,
accepting that judgment is a very
peculiar metaphysical move.
But rejecting it,
that's also a very peculiar metaphysical
move,
you know,
because basically what you say if you,
if you reject the Nuremberg decision,
is that what happened in Nazi
concentration camps was had to be judged
through the lands of cultural
relativism.
So you can say that if you want,
but you know,
it's not one of those things that you
should do lightly because,
well,
you run into Dostoyevsky's problem.
Dostoevsky's problem fundamentally is if
there's no order,
you know,
hierarchical order.
If there's no god,
then everything is permitted and you can
walk down that road,
but it doesn't lead to very good place.
Okay?
So,
so you know what,
what we're,
what we're trying to sort out is the
idea.
We're trying to propose the idea that
what,
what myths are doing is trying to
represent the fundamental elements of
being as being,
as experienced at every level of being.
So it's not a reduction to chemical or
physical constituent elements.
It's a,
it's a perception of the world as it
manifests itself at every level of
existence simultaneously.
And it's predicated on the proposition
that there's no reason to make any one
of those levels primary from an
ontological perspective.
So what that would mean in part is that
the web of relationships that you find
yourself in is just as real as the
physiological components of yourselves.
Now,
obviously in some sense it can't be
measured or even conceptualized in the
same way,
but that doesn't mean that doesn't mean
that the relationship isn't real,
you know,
so it's,
it's a much more comprehensive way of
looking at things and it tends to take
on this dramatic and imagistic for Mei
think because,
well,
first of all,
it was acted out before it was
understood.
And second images can capture all sorts
of things that words cannot yet express,
which is why we liked,
we liked looking at,
um,
profound artistic images.
They're filling us with information.
You know,
what I found out recently that
Heidegger,
whose ideas actually have a fair number
of similarities with what I've been
teaching you.
Um,
except I'll tell you something
interesting there that I think is true.
So heidegger tended to view modern
civilization.
He tended to view it as the radical
element of the great father stopping us
from being able to interact with pure
being.
So he was very.
His proposition was that we reconnect
ourselves with the positive element of
being and produce our producer culture,
social culture that was much more
benevolent.
But I think if you think about
this from a union perspective,
what the Union's claim,
and this is an Alfred Adler claimed the
same thing and so did need you to some
degree is if you tilt too far in one
direction,
a counter position develops in your
imagination and starts to have an
uncanny influence on you.
So I can give you an example.
So I've had clients for example,
who are way too agreeable,
you know,
so maybe they're pushed around by their
father for decades and you know,
one of the ways they react to the hyper
aggression of their father or the
dominance of their father or maybe their
own weaknesses that they classify
dominance and aggression as evil and
then refuse to engage in it.
Of course that just weakens them
further.
But then they harbor resentment,
you know?
And so one of the things you suggest is
that if you get gripped by an emotion
you need,
you need to let it manifest itself in a
fantasy,
you know,
and I've had my clients tell me
fantasies once they've learned to let
the manifest themselves,
you know,
they'll be irritated,
for example,
by something their father says,
and they'll let the fantasy play out and
it's like,
not only is it murderous like you would
not believe,
but it's viciously and violently
murderous,
you know,
when,
what happens there is that because the
little issues that constitute the
tyrannical element of the relationship
between them are never dealt with.
The part of them that is capable of
standing up and,
and,
and pushing forward has been assaulted
by a million blows.
And it's so.
It's been pushed into such a
pathologically defensive position by
that point that it doesn't fantasize
about,
well,
maybe I should have a chat with my dad
and settled this.
It's like,
oh no,
no,
no.
It's like full fledged murderous
impulse.
And by that time,
the person is also terrified even to let
that fantasy emerge.
Because then they'll think,
oh my God,
you know,
what am I some kind of serial killer or
some kind of homicidal maniac,
and you know,
the answer is,
well,
of course you're partly all I'm a cidal
maniac,
you know,
you got to keep that stuff under
control,
so otherwise you take it out on your
children and the people that love you
and all of that.
But that's not so bad if it's,
you know,
manifest in day to day trivialities and
you kind of keep things sorted out.
But if you don't do anything about it
for 20 years,
you always hear about these guys that
burst forth and do something ultra
violent.
What are the neighbors always say?
Especially if they're the lone killer
types.
Oh,
he was such a nice boy.
You know,
we never saw many.
Never caused any trouble.
It's like,
yeah,
right.
He never caused enough trouble.
That was the problem.
But he sure made up for it in one fell
swoop.
So anyways,
back to heidegger.
Heidegger had this.
Heidegger seemed to have this vision of
the patriarchy,
roughly speaking as hyper dominant and
then valued the opposite,
which was more cooperative and more in
tune with nature and you know,
sort of like an environmentalists dream
of what human society should be like.
And I say that seriously because I
believe a lot of what the modern
environmental movement uses to dry this,
it's utopian visions is actually derived
directly from heidegger's thinking.
I mean,
you can trace the causal pathways.
You got think,
remember what happened to heidegger
though.
He became a Nazi,
you know,
when it was a real shock to everyone who
is a high tech area and follower because
it only seemed like such a good guy.
It's like,
yeah,
well maybe he was too good a guy,
you know.
And so there was the,
he was all sweetness and light,
so to speak,
on the sort of patriarchal end of the
distribution.
And then the counterbalance to that
manifested itself politically and he was
just pulled right in.
So I think one of the differences
between what I'm proposing and what
heidegger proposed is that like I would
never say that,
that there's a utopian solution to the
problem of the great father.
I would say you're stuck with the
positive and the negative.
You're stuck with it.
Now.
I think through diligent effort you can
keep the positive on top of the
negative,
but you don't do that by sacrificing
strength.
You know,
you don't get rid of tyranny by
weakening society.
All you do then is you increase the
probability that when tyranny bursts
forth,
it's going to be far more brutal than it
would otherwise be.
You know,
you increase the benevolent element of,
of society by increasing its competence
and power.
So you make it more powerful,
not less.
Now that doesn't mean more.
That doesn't mean more oppressive,
right?
They don't.
So that's,
that's a solution.
It's problem.
So one of the things Solzhenitsyn wrote
about was he was in prison in the prison
camps in Russia for a long time.
And one of the things that he used to
amuse himself within the darkest
possible way with his compatriots was
teasing communists once they got
arrested,
you know,
and it was pretty brutal because once
you were thrown into the gulag system,
the probability that you were going to
get out,
especially if you were a political
prisoner,
was like,
you're in there for 20 years,
you know,
and you're lucky if you didn't get
worked to death and the thugs and the
murderers and the thieves didn't beat
you senseless constantly.
There was nothing left of you.
So it was no joke to be thrown into
ghoulag if you were a political
prisoner.
And there were lots of people who are
thrown in there purely arbitrarily.
And that's actually because if you
really want to punish someone,
you punish them because they didn't
commit any crime.
That's a way better punishment than
punishing them if they actually
committed the crime,
you know,
because that's just justice.
But random punishment if you want to be
brutal,
that's the one to use.
So the communists would get thrown in
with the prisoners,
had been in there for awhile and they'd
still be like rampant communists.
They'd be writing letters to everyone
and trying to extricate themselves from
the situation assuming that a mistake
had been made,
you know,
and so those units and his compatriots
would just tease the hell out of them
because they had nothing left to lose.
Plus they thought,
well,
you're still part of the God system that
actually imprisoned and brutalized
yourself and us.
So part of Social Lipson's moral problem
with what should I do with you?
Like should I feel sorry for you because
you've fallen into this absolutely
hellish category of that person betrayed
by their own ideals and their own
person,
or should I treat you like,
well you right?
Because you're blind tyrant and look at
what you've produced.
And Solzhenitsyn's answer was you're a
blind tyrant until you repent.
Right?
So as long as you still think you're
right,
there is no possibility of
communication.
So then what he observed was some people
would collapse,
they admit,
and maybe it took a long time that maybe
there was something wrong with the
system and that the other people in
there weren't all the guilty ones in
them,
the only innocent ones.
So some people would accept the facts
even at whatever brutal costs that would
be and what that would be was starting
to decompose the entire value system
they had that was predicated on
axiomatic communists belief.
But the other ones,
and these are the ones that social
instance also writes about,
they just never changed,
you know,
release.
Twenty years later they'd say,
well that just proves the system was
right all along and that I was an error
because you,
you know,
you can always interpret the data.
The data does not speak for itself.
That's a big problem.
So.
So I thought his solution was brilliant.
It's like,
well,
what do you do with someone who still
acting out what has destroyed them?
Well,
until they stopped being part of that,
you can't really forgive them or
communicate with them.
But as soon as they drop it,
it's like,
well then you give them a hand,
which seems to me like a reasonable
balance between justice and forgiveness
and that's a very hard balance to
strike,
right?
It's a very hard balance to so okay.
So then I kind of differentiated this
into the tyrant is the king that eats
his own son roughly speaking.
And that means that like if you have a
tyrannical father say in your actual
family,
what that father is going to do is to
react to everything that makes you
independent or that could make you an
independent being as if it's a challenge
to his own authority and dominance.
And so whenever you stand up,
you know and make your little thrust
forward like you would if you were a
three year old,
you know you're going to get whacked
hard for it.
You're going to get punished for
everything that would allow you to climb
a dominance hurricane to become a
challenger.
And so that's,
that's sort of the paternal element of
the whole situation.
You know,
mother who demands nothing and father
who punishes everything good.
It's a perfect combination.
If you want to raise someone who's
completely demolished and also in in
high probability resentful and
dangerous,
so and you know,
you have societies like that too,
you know,
you see this in corporations,
what especially when they start to
deteriorate as they start to punish the
people inside the corporation for being
hardworking and creative and you know,
the thing is in real trouble at that
point.
It's basically dead.
It might take 10 years to fall over,
but it's basically dead.
So,
and you know,
as corporations,
as hierarchical structures get full of
people who are doing nothing but trying
to climb the dominance hierarchy,
you know,
their power motivated.
They're very annoyed at anyone who's
competent and creative because the
competent and creative people are using
competence and creativity declined the
hierarchy.
Whereas they're just using political
machinations and the desire for power.
So they want nothing.
They don't want to have those people
around because all they are is
competitors and they're not even that.
They don't even actually care if while
they're climbing the ladder on the ship,
the thing is sinking,
you know,
in fact,
they might be facilitating.
It's sinking in trying to pirate
everything they possibly can while the
thing falls apart.
Now it happens all the time.
So when it happens in all sorts of
institutions,
so that sort of the sun eating farther
representation in a political or
corporate institution,
you know when it sorta.
What's interesting about that I think is
that both the Liberals and the
conservatives see that,
hey,
they say the left wingers and the right
wingers,
the left wingers see the tie radical
element of the great father in
corporations and the right wingers see
the tie radical element of the great
father in the government.
So it's projection,
you know,
I mean,
it seems to me like a radical
oversimplification to assume that all
the evil is embodied in the government
or all the evil is embodied in
corporations.
It's like,
you know,
we should be a little more
differentiated than that.
So all corporations are not the same
obviously.
And all governments are clearly not the
same.
And all governmental policies are
clearly not the same,
but people are lazy.
So they don't want to do the
differentiation.
And so what happens is that the
archetypal representations possess them
initially and they failed to
differentiate them,
you know,
and they're pretty happy about that
because their theory explains
everything.
You know,
I,
I asked,
I talked to a guy a while back and he's
a pretty smart guy and I was thinking
about this issue of corruption.
I was trying to think,
I thought,
how the hell did some countries get not
corrupt because I cannot figure that
out.
I cannot understand how that can even be
possible.
And for me that's a massive mystery.
Like I can imagine digging through that
for like 30 years,
trying to sort it out.
And he answered in two seconds.
He said,
well,
it's government.
I thought,
you know,
all that means is,
I don't,
I don't want to think about that.
And so here's my one word,
low resolution answer that covers 50,000
snakes at once.
It's not helpful,
you know,
it,
all it does is convince them that he
possesses knowledge because he's using
low representation representations to
encompass huge swaths of the complex
world,
you know,
it's so,
um,
and then punish them.
Well,
but what that is exactly so,
so the reference there is you know,
people,
people have tried to model optimal
social interactions,
you know,
so should we cooperate or should we
fight and so first of all,
the people who tried to model that,
we're doing it in one offs so it can
make a case that
if I,
if,
if there's $20 at stake and I could get
$20 by like giving you a zero,
I should do that if I'm only going to
interact with you once.
And so the initial experiments basically
showed that if you are a psychopath
you'd win.
But then someone figured out that,
well wait a minute,
you don't ever do anything once you
iterate it and that's a phd an idea,
right?
Because Piaget would say,
well what's the stable solution across
multiple iterations of the same thing.
So it's like,
well what if we always cooperate?
A group of us,
we always cooperate.
Well there's a problem with that because
then psychopath a pop up randomly and
he's like a shark in a tank of guppies.
He just eats all the guppies and that's
the end of this situation.
So if all we do is cooperate,
someone who's noncooperative Canadian,
any immediately get everything we have
and so then the problem becomes,
well,
you don't want to take full of sharks
and you don't want a tank full of
guppies.
What should you do?
And the answer,
because this has been played out on
computer simulations by the way all over
the world,
is well,
how do you ensure stability?
And it's something like,
I trust you.
I start with the presumption that you're
trustworthy if you react in a
trustworthy manner.
Away we go,
we trade and it's transparent.
If you screw me,
I whack you,
and then I offered a trade with you
again.
Cool.
And that seems to be now that's really
worth thinking about because there's a
shadow idea in there,
right?
It's like I trust you,
but if you bother me all bite you and
I'll bite you hard,
but then we can trade again.
So it doesn't that.
What that allows is that you can screw
up,
you know,
and you will.
So it means that we can continue to
play,
even if you're not perfect,
but you're going to get punished and
appropriate amount if you're not
perfect.
And then we'll try to get the game going
again.
And so I would say that's an example of
a pig and celebrated solution,
roughly speaking.
And it could ease,
it could be that that does have
something to do with the way that a
culture learns to become non-corrupt,
but it still doesn't explain how that
gets implemented,
you know?
So.
Okay,
so the,
there's a walled city,
you know,
and that's,
that's uh,
that place exists that's in France.
And fortunately I can't remember the
name of it at the moment.
It's one of the best preserved medieval
cities in the world.
And there's actually quite a few of
those left in Europe.
I've seen a lot of them and they're
staggeringly beautiful,
unbelievably beautiful.
So,
but you see how those things were
constructed a,
because there's a double wall,
right?
And so you think about what's the
psychological message that's embodied in
that city and the messages inside the
walls where there's a civilized
organization,
you're safe from barbarians.
And chaos and the barbarians and chaos
surround that.
And so it's better to be inside the
city.
Now obviously the problem is the city's
walled,
so it's not that easy to get out.
You're trapped in there,
you know,
in some way.
So you could see while you could find,
you imagine if you're a teenager and a
medieval city like that.
You're 12 years old or 13 years old,
you're off with your ratty little
buddies and the first thing you want to
do is go outside the wall and see what's
out there.
But by the same token,
if there weren't any walls,
well then the barbarians would come in
and they'd steal everything you had and
everyone would be dead and that would
not be a good thing.
So,
you know,
it was also a place to store prod,
use our agricultural produce so that it
couldn't,
wouldn't rot and wouldn't get eaten by
bugs and wouldn't be stolen by thieves,
you know?
So,
and that was also extraordinarily
useful.
And so there's a belief system embedded
in that.
That's,
that would be the medieval world order.
But as well as there being a belief
system and a psychological
representation,
it's obviously a physical structure and
it's also a mode of relationship and all
of that together constitutes the great
father.
It's not just the belief and some of
that's going to be tyrannical because
there's a king and some of it's going to
be beneficial because,
well maybe better to have one king than
30 kings.
They're having a war.
So that's been the dilemma in American
foreign policy,
you know,
if,
if you give American football foreign
policy,
some credit,
you know,
which you,
which is a reasonable thing to do
because part of the,
what are the Americans we're always
trying to figure out,
especially since the end of the World
War World War was,
is it better to have a tyrant
or take them out and have 30 of them,
you know,
announcer to that is who knows,
so they took the tire and out of Iraq,
what happened?
You know,
the country basically fractured and it
happens very frequently.
It's,
it's a failed state.
You get little fiefdoms of war lords
basically,
who are certainly no improvement over
the original tyrant and they tear the
place apart.
Now I'm not making a case for the
utility of a tyrant,
but.
But the opposite of order is chaos and
chaos can be just as destructive as
tyranny or maybe it can be more
destructive.
So you know,
the same thing happened to some degree
with the Arab spring.
It was like,
okay,
poof,
chaos.
It's like everybody thinks,
well this is a chance for a new
beginning and you know,
it seems like in places like Tunisia
that actually worked,
and then the things loosened up a bit in
Morocco too.
So there was some indication of some
progress.
But in places like Libya,
it's like,
well,
that looks like it's degenerating into
complete hell.
And you see the same thing in many
places in the Middle East where the Arab
spring occurred.
So
the.
That's also why it's so necessary to
understand what lurks behind tyranny
because what lurks behind tyranny is not
freedom.
It's chaos and Harris has the potential
for freedom,
but then it depends on what people do
with the chaos,
so,
and it's not,
it's not self evident that the chaos is
better than the tyranny.
And part of the reason for that is that
in every society there are agents of
chaos and there are people.
They're often at relatively low strata
on the dominant Turkey.
They're usually young men.
They're usually extremely aggressive.
They're usually incredibly resentful and
displaced and for them as soon as chaos
appears,
it's like it's open season.
You know,
that struck,
the society has been restructured and
they can just go about taking everything
they want.
So you know,
you see that even in countries like
Canada where those are the guys who riot
after a hockey game,
you know,
they need no excuse whatsoever to go out
and chaos and act like absolute
barbarians.
Absolutely.
Security.
Yeah.
But they,
it's a,
it's a causal interrelationship.
You know,
there's a whole chapter on that near in
the last third of maps of meaning
describes the relationship between the
two halves of the adversary.
There's a nihilistic element and a
fascistic element,
you know,
and once the value hierarchy falls
apart,
one response is let's go in there and
get up the golden rebuild,
something,
you know,
I'd say that would be the heroic
element,
but the adversarial element is,
well,
everything's falling apart.
It's every man for himself.
And the fascistic element would be me,
right?
I'm going to exert power not for
competence,
dominance,
pure dominance,
and that's like rape and pillage.
That's what that is.
So,
you know,
in the,
that's what it is and you know,
if you contrast that with utter
powerlessness,
you can see how rape and pillage might
be attractive.
And you know,
that's also why I think it's attractive.
Often too young men at the bottom of the
dominance hierarchy who are
dispossessed.
You know the,
one of the things we know is that if you
have a fairly flat dominance hierarchy,
so that opportunity is distributed and
there's a reasonable probability of
getting from the bottom to the top.
So you have hope,
let's say.
Then the males at the bottom don't get
very aggressive,
but if you get the damn thing pointed up
so that there's almost no possibility of
moving forward.
Even if you use competence,
then the males at the bottom,
especially the ones that are
disagreeable,
so they would be more warrior types.
Man,
they get aggressive right away and there
are there gangs.
They dominate the gangs and they go to
war with each other,
and the reason for that is that the
successful gang members are far more
successful as successful gang members.
Then they would be successful as low
end,
poorly paid conformists.
Now most of the guys in the gang,
or worse off actually,
so some of the best dancer,
biological evidence that's been
collected suggest that most people in a
drug ring.
So there are the people at the bottom
make less than they would if they were
working for minimum wage,
but it's a lottery.
You know,
partly the violence helps because that
top of the dam hierarchies being peeled
off by deaths all the time.
So there's always the possibility that
you're going to pop yourself up three or
four levels and then you'll have a
riotous old time for the next five years
till you die,
which would be a lot better than having
a chaotic existence with nothing for the
next five years until you die.
So,
you know,
part of,
part of what society is always have to
do is to make sure the damn dominance
hierarchy doesn't get so steep and climb
a bowl that all the ordinary men at the
bottom start to get hypervisor is well
documented and the best work on that was
done at mcmaster.
I'm
can,
I can never remember the people who did
the work,
unfortunately,
I can never remember their name.
It'll come to me.
So.
Yep.
So then I guess the best strategy then
decided later to assess the potential
payoff.
The manifest for her as opposed to the
APP.
Right?
Right.
But you know,
people generally don't do that
calculation.
You know,
remember when the Americans went into
Iraq,
what did they think?
What was the theory will be welcomed as
liberator's.
Well,
that was actually true in some cases for
about a week,
but the problem was they wiped out the
power structure.
They dismantled the army and you can see
why,
but then what the hell are all those
soldiers going to do their soldiers.
They know where the weapons are.
They're not just going to sit around,
especially not the hyper aggressive guys
who are already soldiers.
They're going to think to hell with
this.
You know,
it's chaos and I'm going to get what I
want.
It was so interesting when,
when I saw that happening because they
went and wiped out so damn,
and then there was all these people
stealing computers and things from the
government offices and the western media
kept saying looting,
looting,
and I thought,
it's not looting.
You just wiped out the legal system.
There's no legal system anymore.
It's not looting because that would be
against the law.
There's no law.
You just wiped it out.
He was a dictator.
Now you could say,
well,
those people should have followed the
laws.
If it was there.
It's like,
well you wouldn't have gone into that
country if it was true because that
would only be true if the law was just
because if it wasn't just then why the
hell should people are bad and if you'd
been tyrannized by people for 30 years
and you could take a computer.
It's like,
who's to say that isn't exactly what you
should do.
You know the,
the West acted like,
well actually natural law governs this
and Hussein is just a,
what do you call an anomaly,
and so you take him out and then there's
natural law and you should follow it
because I wasn't.
Looting is no looting when there's no
law
like for when of like voluntarily
yourself rather than letting the world
presented your doorstep and it's kind of
like.
I think it's kind of exemplified in this
case,
like you have to do it voluntarily,
volunteer,
that you'll do it in a way that like the
fact that you care about yourself and
you want to have to integrate these
things later.
You just say your own dictator.
You can take the care to reintegrate
with.
That's exactly.
That's exactly right.
So
well they almost,
they also might blow it apart at such a
high level in the hierarchy that there's
no bloody way you're going to be able to
bite off and digest the huge pieces of
that that happened to be laying around,
you know,
so one of the,
one of the,
because part of the reason I was trying
to lay this out over these years is
because I was trying to figure out
citizens or relationship between the
adversarial element of the individual.
So that would be the park.
It's willfully blind and likes to lie
and tyranny and the abolition of the
pause,
development of,
of chaos,
you know,
and the tendency for deep for things to
deteriorate.
Those are all causally link and it
really tight manner.
That's soldier and instance,
observation and Frankel's observation
and handles observation.
It's the whole essence of existentialist
thought,
okay,
what the hell are you supposed to do
about that?
And the answer seems to be don't have it
happen.
And so you say,
well,
when should you stand up against
tyranny?
Well,
you should stand up against tyranny when
it manifests itself at micro levels
right in front of you.
That's what you have to do,
and so that means you have to be awake
all the time for transgressions against
the positive element of the individual
and the pause,
development of culture,
and you have to do it right then and
there and you can say,
and people say this all the time,
well,
I can take my boss on at work.
It's like,
well,
what's going to happen to you?
Well,
I won't get the next raise,
or maybe they won't like me.
It's like,
well,
that's fine.
So that's,
that's.
That's your courage.
What are you going to do when there's a
real tyrant?
Well,
we already know the answer to that.
If you're not even going to stand up
when you're protected beyond belief by
the structure and you have everything
you possibly need and you could probably
even stand up without with and get away
with it,
or you could even stand up and you would
be more respected and the probability
that your career would go properly would
increase.
If you're not going to do it then while
you're certainly not going to do it when
it's Sadam Hussein or Adolf Hitler,
like,
forget it man.
It's wait too late for that.
Now the problem with that is that
there's not a lot of self evident
heroism in it,
so you know,
you don't get to go party in the streets
about how brave you are,
but,
but one of Solzhenitsyn's claims and
Frankl as well was that it was the
accumulation of micro lies that built up
to produce the Nazis and the Stalinists.
So it was bottom up and top down at the
same time.
Lots of causal interconnections in
loops,
but basically put up with the first
imposition.
It was only this big and then they put
up with this acronym position.
Then they put up with the third
imposition and by the time they noticed
that it was really like a major league
imposition pointing it out would get you
arrested while van man.
Then the stakes,
like when does it end?
Well,
it doesn't.
It doesn't end.
It just gets worse and worse and worse
and worse and worse.
You know?
And it almost got so bad in 1962 and in
1984,
it almost got so bad that we had the
third World War,
like it was that close.
So what where it ends is apocalypse.
And so that's why you see very often in
religious writings that the sins of the
individual are linked to the apocalypse.
The reason for that is their link to the
apocalypse.
That's why it's just that you don't see
the causal connections.
So.
Okay.
So any questions about that too?
So there's the representations in a bit
more visible for.
So you know,
this is,
you're trying to get the thing on the
left to be working properly and you're
trying to stop the thing on the right
from taking over completely.
And it's,
it's a real balance because you don't
know,
for example,
even with your own children,
how the hell do you know when you're
tyrannizing them?
And how do you know when you're
socializing them?
One of the things that I noticed with my
kids,
and this was much to my Chagrin,
was lots of times I was confining them
in a tyrannical manner because they were
having too much fun,
you know,
because you always think you're
punishing your kid,
so to speak.
When they're doing something bad,
it's like,
no,
you're not,
you're yelling at them because they're
running about like,
you know,
completely insane,
impulsive,
manic hyenas and they're having a great
time.
And so you say,
calm down,
you know,
what do you treat,
what are you going to turn them into?
Some kid that can sit there and their
desk for eight hours when they're in
grade two and not complaint.
It's like,
is that an improvement?
Well,
yes and no.
So
I also noticed with my kids that when I
was more tyrannical than might be
popular now,
especially with my son,
I cracked down on them now and then
because he's been a little rodent and he
was really,
he was really pushy.
He's a dominant kid,
you know,
and I don't know if you've ever had a
dominant dog,
but you have to flip those things over,
you know,
on their back all the time because
otherwise they just push and push and
push and he was sort of like that and so
he'd get all uppity and then I talked to
my wife and we'd say,
all right,
so we're not going to let him get away
with.
He can't even breathe wrong for the next
two weeks,
you know.
So every time he did a micro mistake we
were on him and I thought,
you know,
this is a bit much.
But what was so bloody weird about that
was every time I did that he liked me
better.
It was so interesting,
you know,
but I think it's very much like the
situation with the dominant dog.
It's like partly what the dog wants to
know is who the hell is in and if it's
you,
he's perfectly happy about that.
But he doesn't want there to be any
ambivalence about it.
So.
Oh,
well,
like if he,
if he,
if he did anything that I thought was a
little crooked or a little dab into a
little too pushy,
what I would usually do with him is make
them sit on the steps,
you know,
I'd say,
okay,
here's the deal.
He could communicate more or less at
this point because he was around two and
a half to three.
The deal was you sit there until you've
got yourself controlled and you're
willing to be a civilized human being
and then you can come back to me and
tell me that and if I like you then I'll
let you come up.
So.
Because you know,
sometimes you'll have a kid do that and
they'll come back and they say what they
think you want to hear,
but they don't mean it.
And so you think,
oh,
I'll give him a chance,
but that you can't do that.
You have to see if you like the kid now
because if they come up properly and say
things so that it's,
it's true all the way down instantly.
If you have any sense,
you're not angry at them anymore,
you think?
Yeah,
I like that kid and then so,
so,
so you know,
if your goal is to produce a kid that
you really like,
which I think is a really good goal,
then you don't let them off the damn
hook until he's that kid.
And so it was really interesting to
watch what that did to him and I think
it was part of cortical integration and
cortical integration of hypothalamic
impulses.
He'd sit on the damn steps like this.
No,
just enraged and I go over to,
I mean,
I'd say,
well,
you know,
are you ready to get off the steps yet?
And he'd go,
no.
And then he'd get himself together and
then he'd come and talk to me and then
I'm like,
my rule was it's,
as soon as he did it right,
it was over,
no grudges,
nothing.
It was done,
you know.
And so that was also very rewarding for
him because he could specify the length
of punishment,
the length of punishment was as long as
it took them,
just start acting like a civilized human
being again.
And the consequence of that was end of
problem.
So that's,
you know,
that seems to,
that's like tit for tat fundamentally
bug me whack.
But as soon as your straight again,
poof,
we'll,
we'll try it again.
So,
and you know,
what I noticed about him in particular,
and he was a dominant kid,
was
you know,
you'd set a rule,
whatever the rule was,
like you had to be,
maybe you had to go to bed at eight or
something.
It was like,
well what happens if I wait until eight,
15,
you know,
or eight,
oh five or eight,
10.
Like he,
he just push until he knew exactly where
the line was very pushy,
but it was also extraordinarily
exploratory,
right?
Because someone says there's a rule,
but you don't know what that means.
So what do you do?
You harass and push and push and
harassed until you find out where the
boundary actually is.
And if it's nice and firm and doesn't
move around,
then you think,
oh,
that's like a table.
And if I stand up underneath it,
I going to whack my head.
So I won't do that.
And then you move onto something else.
But if the boundaries are going like
this all the time,
the kid will just torture you forever.
So which is exactly what he should do.
So
I think whether or not you are going to
tyrannized your child in the final
analysis depends on exactly what acting
ethically in general depends on which is
in the final analysis.
Do you want to make things better or
worse?
What he aimed at and you know you,
there isn't a way of.
There isn't really a way of
managing that unless you get the whole
hierarchy clear in your head.
You know,
do you want to make the world a better
place?
Well part of that is,
do you think it should exist at all?
Are you resentful because it's tragic
and limited?
Are you angry because you're not as
successful as you could be?
Do you have 85 unresolved things with
your wife?
You know,
are you intimidated by your child?
If he happens to be successful,
maybe he's going to be more successful
than you.
You know,
you think you're going to be able to
tolerate that.
No.
Those are all questions you have to
think through.
And you need answers to them,
you know,
and if your goal is I'm trying to
produce a child who's better than me,
first of all,
then you have to admit that there could
possibly be something that would be
better than you,
you know,
and then you have to think that it's
actually your responsibility to
facilitate that and you have to be
committed to it and without that,
well to the degree that you haven't got
that formulated and articulated and
embedded in you and acting it out in
your household,
you're going to be a tyrant,
especially when you're tired and upset
and hungry and you know,
maybe you failed at something and you've
had an argument with your wife or.
So
I don't think there's any general rules
except,
you know,
have a relationship with the kid and
keep your eyes open and made sure that
you're aiming at what's best for that
child.
And you have to love the child to do
that.
And then you have to figure out which
part of the child you actually love.
So,
you know,
in,
in therapy,
I always envisioned myself rogers.
It was unconditional positive regard.
That isn't the way I look at it.
It's like if you come for me to therapy,
I'm on the side of you that wants things
to be good.
I am not on this side of you that does
not want things to be good.
You know,
and we have to sort that out and I'm
assuming that the reason that you're
coming for therapy is because you would
rather than things were going to be good
and so I don't even think it's
appropriate to be on the side of the
client that is aimed at death and
misery.
You know,
the fact that it's there means doesn't
mean you should throw the person back
out on the street,
you know,
because it's there.
So in that sense,
the regard in some sense is
unconditional.
It isn't done conditional.
It's not the right way of thinking about
it.
You make a contract which is okay.
Our purpose is to narrow the influence
of evil and expand the influence of
good,
and we're going to tell the truth each
other and an attempt to figure out how
we do that and we're not going to blow
the relationship apart if horrible
things come up,
as long as we're both convinced that
that's what we're aiming for and the
communication is actually honest and so
it's unconditional in that you won't
break it if things happen that are
pretty unseemly,
but it's conditional in that no,
no.
I'm on the side of you that's going to
tell the truth and that's going to aim
towards the good and that's actually
what you want from me.
You know,
it's sort of impartial.
What time is it?
Okay,
let's,
let's stop for 10 minutes.