So the first thing,
first thing I'm going to do is to tell
you what to do when you start speaking
to an audience,
because some of you will do that in your
life.
So this is a hint,
when you stand up in front of people,
do not talk to.
They're all absolutely silent.
Wait,
because they'll quiet down.
Everybody will quite completely down.
Then you want to wait until just before
it becomes awkward and then you've got
everyone's attention and if you speak
before then you're giving permission to
people to speak while you're speaking
and you shouldn't give them that
permission because the hypothesis is is
that you have something reasonably
important to say because otherwise the
whole setup is ally,
right?
So just so you know,
it's a good thing to know.
And it also.
I can tell you one more thing about
speaking in front of people that's
extremely useful too because it
frightens people.
Right?
To do that,
I never talked to the group,
you know,
because you might think,
well,
I'm speaking in front of all these
people.
You might think that when you're afraid,
that's not really true.
You're speaking to people in the group
and you can move your attention from one
person to another.
If you speak to the group,
you're basically,
you're going to be terrified because the
group doesn't give you any feedback,
but if you look at individuals and talk
to them,
then it's not that much different from
having a conversation.
It is because you have to be prepared
and so on,
but you can judge when you're looking at
someone,
you can tell whether they understand
what's going on,
whether they're hooked in there or
anything like that,
and as long as you're paying attention,
then you're going to utilize your
natural skills as a communicator which
you've been practicing since you were
born.
So anyways,
that's two hints and they're useful
hints.
So,
and I guess the other thing to remember
is that B,
three hints is that it's really a
dialogue,
right?
Even though I think I told you this
before,
most of the response from the people in
the audience is nonverbal.
That doesn't mean it's not a dialogue.
So if you're paying attention to people,
you keep the dialogue going and
generally that'll keep everybody's
interest reasonably high.
Um,
well anyways,
so I want to bring up some mysteries
about words.
Now
the first question might be,
well,
what exactly is a word?
Now I'm talking about words because I'm
really interested in concepts,
but a word is like a unit of,
of,
of conception.
So I'll focus on words and will broaden
out to concepts.
And the reason I want to talk to you
about concepts is because I want to talk
to you about idiot logical and group
identification and such identification
is based in part on shared behavior but
also in part on shared conceptions.
And the reason that I'm interested in
group identity is because I'm interested
in what it is that motivates people to
retain their group identity and also to,
to defend their group identity or
expanded often at the cost of warfare.
And then finally,
because I'm interested in why people
will do horrific things to one another
in order hypothetically to facilitate
that process.
So that's the linkage.
So let's think about words for a minute.
10.
So the first question you might ask as
well,
what is a word and St Augustine,
from what I understand,
formally posited that the word was a
label for a thing and I would say that
that's mostly what people think when
they think about words,
which they don't do very often.
They use them,
but they don't think about them.
So a word to be a label for a thing.
All right.
Now that's a,
that's a funny concept because the thing
is often defined by words and so there's
a bit of circularity in there,
right?
Because for that argument to be exactly
true,
the thing would have to be self evident
sort of independent of any verbal
formalization and then you could just
slap a label on it and it's pretty clear
that our conceptual abilities also
influenced the manner in which we
perceive things.
So there's a reciprocal interplay.
So.
Okay.
So anyways,
that's one definition and you can see
that it has some utility.
So here's another definition.
This is from VIP can Stein that can
Stein said a word is like a player in a
chess game.
One of the pieces.
And what he meant by that in part was
that you're engaged in an activity when
you're using language and the activity
has a vaguely game like structure and
the reason that you're using words is to
move ahead in the game.
You're a player in the game and so then
you can think about,
well,
so that's another analogy that a word is
got a tool like structure and you use it
to,
to attain certain ends into operated in
the world.
And so that's kind of an interesting way
of thinking about it.
And then I was thinking about this is a
more visual analogy.
So imagine that you have a,
a toy train and there's freight cars on
it and you fill the freight cars with
all sorts of different things.
Maybe one is full of screws and Legos
and another one is full of erasers and
coins and so on.
And there's a little tunnel so that the
train track goes underneath it and then
the train is continually running
underneath it and that thing stays in
the same place.
And that's like a word to now.
That's a trickier thing because a word
in compass campuses,
things that are the same and things that
are different,
right?
It has to because everything that you
try to categorize as an entity isn't
homogenous.
It's not homogenous.
It's its internal structure varies.
So.
And that means that in so far as you're
treating it as if it's only one entity,
it might do things that will surprise
you.
You know,
so it's especially true with complex
things.
So you might say,
well this is my wife.
Okay.
And that there's A.
There's a certain set of assumptions
that go along with that label,
but and as long as those assumptions are
met,
which basically means that as long as
the relationship you have with that
person stays within that definitional
box,
then you can use the term and you can
get somewhere with it.
But because people are full of snakes,
you never know when they're going to
jump out of the category that you've put
them in and manifest something that's
completely unlike the word that you've
been using to describe them.
And many things are full of snakes or
you could say to some degree everything
is full of snakes and that's why it's
useful to think of a word as a place
where multiple things move through.
So another example that you might think
about is say a stock because the stock
market's kind of a good model of the
environment as such.
No,
a stark is like a thing.
So you can think of it like a thing and
people do think of it like a thing.
But the problem is is that the stock
itself is absolutely dynamic entity and
what it contains at any given moment is
far beyond your capacity to comprehend
because the.
If you think about how a company is
operating in the economic and then the
biological environment,
I mean it's subject to any number of
factors.
So for example,
you know maybe it's a coffee company
stock and then there's some weird blight
in one of the coffee growing countries
because I don't know,
maybe because people have been using
water improperly and so then the coffee
dies and their crops bad and then the
price goes up.
It's like that,
that the stock as an entity in some
sense contains the whole world and you
can treat it like it's one thing for
certain operations,
but most of the time that's really going
to trip you up.
It's going to trip you up in a serious
way.
So.
Okay.
No,
I thought I had one more.
Well that'll do for now.
There's three different.
So I mentioned three different kinds of
concepts and there is another one but I,
I can't bring it to mind at the moment.
So.
Okay.
So here's another way of looking at it.
The world is extraordinarily complex,
like it's insanely ridiculously complex
and part of the complexity is the fact
that,
and this is a hard thing to grasp,
although it sort of self evident once
you think about it,
everything that you see exists at
multiple levels of analysis
simultaneously,
right?
And this is sort of like the train
metaphor.
So you know,
for you to be you for a person to be a
person,
there's an incredible number of micro
structures that make up that person that
has to be functioning in no
unpredictable manner whatsoever.
You know,
so it exists at a,
at a quantum level,
and we're not going to talk about that
because there isn't anything to say
about it.
That's intelligible.
You exist at an atomic level,
at the molecular level,
and then the molecules make organs and
then the organs interact to make you and
then your nested in a family and then
that family is nested in the city and
the city's nested in estate and the
state is nested in an economy and the
economy is nested in a biosphere and
every single one of those levels of
analysis.
It isn't that it's relevant to you.
It's actually that it is you.
Now.
You only figure that out when something
goes wrong because as long as things
aren't going wrong,
they're invisible and now that's an
important thing to realize.
So one of the things that one of the
determining factors with regards to your
capacity to regulate your own emotions,
including anger and fear,
disgust and a variety of other things
we'll talk about is the fact that a
million invisible things are doing
exactly what they're supposed to be
doing all the time.
Now,
the problem with that is that at any
time any of those things can go wrong,
so and that's uh,
that's the problem of,
of finite mortality in a sense,
know that you're,
you're the sort of being that can be
plagued by unexpected events at multiple
levels of analysis and it's by no means
obvious which of those levels of
analysis is most real.
I think they're all equally real.
It's also no small feat to pick the
level of analysis at which you should be
approaching a given problem that people
argue about that all the time.
You know,
when they might say something like,
what's the greatest problem facing
humanity today?
It was like even conceptualizing where
the problem is in that entire tree of
being is something that you can argue
about for forever and not get anywhere.
So,
so part of what I'm,
what I want to point out to you by all
these examples is that a lot of what
human beings are doing in their
perceptual and cognitive operations is
constraining the complexity of life to
limits that enabled them to stay alive,
but also within limits that enabled them
to bear staying in lie alive.
Both of those at the same time because
you want to keep existing obviously and
hypothetically.
You want to propagate and but also
hypothetically want to do both of those
things while not suffering yourself
absolutely to death and so that that's a
set of constraints and it's necessary to
know how much of the world his invisible
to you because unless you have some
understanding of how much of the world
his invisible,
you can't understand how many things
might be going wrong when something goes
wrong.
And so here's,
here's a.
here's a a hint.
In some sense,
if something interferes with the
integrity of your categories.
All the snakes that are inside those
categories come out and then you have to
deal with all those snakes and that's a
big problem.
And so you don't like having your
categorical systems,
the adequacy of your categorical systems
challenged in any way and it's no
wonder,
and it seems to me that this is
particularly relevant with regards to
social conflict between different ethnic
groups or between groups that have been
historically isolated from one another
to some degree because the groups come
at the world with different conceptual
structures and they're not necessarily
isomorphic.
Some of the more fundamental assumptions
might not be the same from one place to
another,
and that means the validity of the
categories that both of those groups use
to organize their existence in the world
come under assault when they meet.
So it's a big problem.
And you know,
you might say,
well why do people engage in conflict
all the time?
And part of the reason is is because
there is conflict.
I give you believe one thing and I
believe another and we happened to
occupy the same territory and those
beliefs have implications for how we're
going to behave.
We're just going to be conflict.
There's going to be conflict.
And as far as I can tell,
there's a very limited number of ways
that that conflict can be resolved.
One is I can become a tyrant or you can,
which one of us is a tyrant,
one of us is a slave,
and that you know,
the logical end point to that is one of
us is alive and one of us is dead and
the other possibility is that we can
negotiate and see if we can figure out
how to cohabitate in this territory
behaviorally and conceptually
simultaneously for a long time.
But that's extraordinarily difficult
because it means you have to take your
concepts apart where they conflict and
then you have to figure out how to put
them back together in a manner that
actually works.
So when you might say,
well,
you should be tolerant.
It's like,
yeah,
you better be tolerant because you'll
never get along with anybody if you're
not.
But you should be tolerant is no answer
to this question because the question
is,
well,
how tolerant should you be an under what
conditions?
And believe me,
you can be too tolerant.
That's easy.
Sure.
I mean,
I gave you an example last week,
I think it's one that I really like
because you're in a relationship with
someone and they betray you.
Your category is not adequate.
Now which category?
Whoa,
wow.
There's a big problem.
You know?
The answer is you don't know which
category,
right?
Because you don't know where the error
is.
Now obviously there is an error of
assumption,
but at what level and with what
category?
So the problem is is that an anomaly of
any seriousness calls the validity of
the conceptual system as such into
question at some unspecified double
degree,
you actually don't know.
And that's a big problem because what it
means is that it's very difficult not to
react catastrophic Lee to anything
that's unexpected because the unexpected
thing could have virtually instantly
consequences.
Now usually it doesn't,
but what good is usually usually it's
not that helpful.
So okay,
so fine.
So the world is very,
very complex place and it's doing
unpredictable things and it's doing
unpredictable things at multiple levels
of analysis simultaneously.
And your problem is how do you act in
that environment and how do you
constrain it conceptually so that it
doesn't kill you or overwhelm you,
it doesn't cost you a physiological or
psychological damage.
So that's a big problem.
So,
and it's,
it's sort of a reflection of the idea
that you don't have to learn to be
afraid or on guard you start that way
because the world is an incredibly
complicated and unpredictable and
dangerous place.
And then with a tremendous amount of
effort,
both individually on socially,
you can construct up environments that
are physical and conceptual within which
you can have some degree of safety,
security and the hope of some progress
during your life.
So we're going to dispense completely
with the idea that secure,
stable and promising is the normal
condition of a human environment.
It's not.
And to keep an environment like that
requires a tremendous amount of
collective effort and individual effort.
So we're reversing the propositions to
some degree.
Chaos is the underlying reality.
An order emerges from that with
difficulty.
And then it's also maintained with
You know,
I can give you one example.
I think if I remember correctly,
to keep a military helicopter in the air
so that it just doesn't plummet to the
ground,
like the piece of metal,
it actually is,
requires something like 35 hours of
maintenance for one hour of flight and
the reason for that is that thing is
barely a helicopter,
like it's just holding together by
nothing and then you have to work like a
mad dog to stop that thing from falling
prey to instantaneous entropy and just
not functioning.
And a lot of our elements of
civilization are like that,
you know,
they're in place so to speak,
but to keep them doing what they're
doing,
which basically means to keep them
inside the category that we placed them
in.
It takes a,
it takes a tremendous amount and almost
incalculable amount of continued input
of energy and time and while it's
counter in tropic,
be it right.
So.
And things have to be stable at multiple
levels of,
of differentiation for anything complex
to maintain itself for any length of
time.
So it's by no means entropies the
standard,
the standard reality complex things
decay towards their simpler forms.
That's the rule of existence and we're
very complex forms and so we're
chronically trying to stop entropy from
tearing us into our constituent
elements.
So okay,
now some of you have seen this before,
but I'm going to show it again.
Maybe you haven't seen precisely this
version of it,
but this line of research wasn't piloted
by Dan Simon,
although he's done a tremendous amount
to popularize it.
His demonstrations have become some of
the most famous demonstrations that
psychologists have ever put together and
this particular line of investigation,
although it might be old hat to you guys
perhaps was an absolute staggering
shocked everyone when it was first
revealed because the hypothesis was that
first of all that we see the world
pretty well.
You know,
that we,
and when we look at the world,
we're seeing it in a relatively
comprehensive manner and,
and that's wrong.
And then the second hypothesis,
which is,
which was a deeper hypothesis,
is that even if we don't see the world
that well,
if something that's unexpected
conceptually happens,
we will.
Our attention will be automatically
drawn to it.
And that also turns out to be wrong.
So we're going to look at this video and
I'm
so the rule is here because he probably
won't be to hear the sound,
you're going to see two teams,
one white and one black and the teams
are going to move around.
They have a basketball,
each of them,
they're going to move around,
they gonna throw the basketball back and
forth to the other members of their
team.
So the white dress people in the black
dress people.
And your job is to count how many times
the basket ball is thrown back and forth
successfully.
So you're going to be looking out the
white dress,
the players dressed in white and you
just count the basketballs.
And so if you've done this before,
well,
don't spoil it for those who haven't,
but you may not have seen this variation
in any case.
Okay?
So there's the grill of one person
leaves and then the curtain changes
color.
Right,
right,
right.
So it's brilliant,
it's brilliant.
It really is.
It's,
it's amazing.
In fact.
So.
Alright.
So you know,
when you look at that and you think,
what do you think?
If I'm concentrating on one thing,
there's a lot of other things I'm
missing in.
Some of those might be unbelievably
massive and then it's even worse as
Simon just demonstrated,
which is if I'm concentrating on one
thing and I'm paying attention for the
possibility that something strange might
happen,
well I'm watching for the strange thing.
Other strange things that I don't expect
will happen and I won't see them.
All right,
so I like.
I liked that demonstration because it's
such a concrete presentation of the fact
that we're dealing with something
complex with relatively limited
resources.
Now it's kind of obvious if you think
about it because there's you and then
there's the entire rest of reality,
including the reality that's within you
that you don't understand,
but it's.
It's still something completely
different to have that pushed in your
face like that.
Now,
one of the,
as I mentioned before,
one of the propositions basically up
until the time this line of research
started,
was that you operate in the world with a
certain set of assumptions.
You see the world and you interact with
it and the things that you're
interacting and that you see are real
and it's relatively straightforward
matter to perceive them because they're,
they are like things and you can
interact with them in a manner that
produces a predictable outcome and if
something radical happens,
you will automatically attend to it.
So that was the proposition of
psychological theory,
psychophysiological theory for a very
long period of time and it had a huge
influence on fields like artificial
intelligence before they discovered that
it was virtually impossible to perceive
the world.
It's so complex that we can't really
figure out how we do it.
Although,
you know,
in the last five years,
tremendous strides have been made in
having machines that can actually
operate in the real world,
which is something new and absolutely
remarkable and amazing.
So,
but what,
what the bottom line for this turned out
to be that.
No,
no,
you don't see the world.
You see a subset of the world and which
subset you see depends on your intent.
Now,
of course,
that's obvious from this video,
right?
Because your intent when you're watching
the video is to count the number of
balls that are being passed back and
forth and that attend intent occurred
merely because I asked you to do that.
And so one of the things that that
indicates is how easy it is for you to
shift what your goal is.
You know,
when human beings are unbelievably good
at that.
Now for most animals,
goals are driven in some sense by the
operation of underlying fundamental
biological systems.
They're not just goals,
their whole schemes of perception and
action.
They're like little subpersonalities I
would say in that they're embodied,
perceptual,
cognitive and emotional solutions to
classic biological problems.
So they're like.
It's like an animal's head is full of
little robots and it's not like they're
driven by a motivational system.
The motivational system is a sub element
of the animal that participates in the
entire animal's being.
So if an animal is hungry,
then it sees the things that hungry
animals sea and it responds emotionally
to the cues that are associated with
food or it's absence.
And it thinks in so far as an animal
thinks and strategizes.
And some of them do,
like the hunters in particular,
the pack hunters,
then it strategizes from within that
framework,
and so you can't think about it as a
drive.
You have to think about it as an entire
way of looking at the world and then you
kind of have to think of the animal as a
collection of different ways of looking
at the world in accordance with the
different problems that the animal has.
And then you're like that too.
Except as your cortex grew radically
over the last several million years you
underwent,
this seems weird transformation where
you're timespan God extremely broad and
your capacity for abstraction increased.
And one of the consequences of that was
that you learned how to replace what you
might regard as purely biologically
determined,
relatively immediate goals.
Although they're really personalities
with unbelievably abstract goals that
could be manifested in a social
environment and that might work over
very long periods of time.
And that's a whole different thing.
And so what?
What the upshot of that is,
is you can pretty.
You have a system that's that that
allows you to formulate virtually any
frame of reference imaginable and then
to look through the world and act on the
world in accordance with that frame of
reference so that I can just say to you
your task now,
this is going to be something you value.
Your task is to turn yourself into a
personality for whom counting the basket
ball throws for the next five minutes is
the PR is your primary aim in life,
and you do that.
No problem.
You reconfigure your entire perceptual
system so that you you feel inadequate
to some degree.
If you can't perform the task,
you're motivated to do it.
You focus your perceptions.
You're pleased.
If you can track the balls,
you're pleased if you get the right
answer and you do that at the drop of a
hat.
So,
so that's one of the consequences of
human cognitive transformation.
So now
what that also means is that from moment
to moment as a consequence of the varied
goals that you're pursuing,
you also make a determination of what
you have to attend to and what you can
ignore.
And the answer to the question,
what should you attend to and what can
you ignore is you should attend to the
minimal number of entities necessary for
you to produce the outcome that you
desire.
Okay?
Now,
if you read classic cybernetic accounts
of motivation,
the ones that are cognitive,
if you look at the behavioral theories
of motivation,
they're mostly drive motivations.
So there's a deterministic element to
them.
You're in a,
you're in a state of deprivation,
and as a consequence,
you're driven down a certain behavioral
road.
Okay?
So that's the behavioral idea.
And there's some truth in that because
some of your biological subsystems are
fast and ancient enough,
so they do kind of operate as chained
deterministic systems.
And in fact,
before you act in,
in any complex way,
you actually set up a system of chained
deterministic events so that you can
implement the action.
So I can show you an example of that.
So,
all right,
so what you're watching,
what my arm does.
Okay,
so you see that I accelerated it very
rapidly.
And then just before he hit the surface,
I stopped it.
Now it turns out that I can move my hand
so fast that a new signal from my brain
can't get to my hand during the time I'm
going like this,
and so what that means is that I have to
set that entire system of operations up
as a ballistic movement and then release
it and you're doing that all the time.
When you're in,
when you're dealing with the world,
you have systems that are automated and
that run into deterministic manner and
what you're doing in part when you act
on the world is you're disinhibiting
them one after the other,
so you do that.
When you're driving,
for example,
where do you look when you're driving?
You don't look right in front of the
car.
Why?
That's because you're going to run over
what's there.
So what?
What good is looking there?
If it's something's there,
you're going to run over it.
There wasn't a thing you can do,
so what you do is you look far enough
down the road so that you can sequence
automated actions as a consequence of
your perception and then they run in
some sense,
they run ballistically.
You can't control them once they've,
once they've been implemented and you're
doing that all the time,
like you're wandering around on a
platform of semi automated systems and
your choice in some senses,
the choice of which of those semi
automated systems you're going to
implement at any given time.
Okay,
so you throw up a frame of reference.
We're going to talk more about them in a
minute.
He throw up a frame of reference and
then you attend to anything that gets in
the way.
If it interferes with the desired
outcome,
so that's not the same as merely
responding to anything unexpected.
As you can see what the grill it.
Now,
if that gorilla would have jumped in
front of one of the players in white and
grabbed the ball,
there's a high probability that you
would have seen them,
especially if it would have onto it for
some length of time because what
happened there was that the anomalous
event turned out to be a relevant factor
in your pursuit of the goal that you
deemed appropriate.
So you could say that you respond
to the world as if it's a predictable
place.
As long as it's doing what you want it
to do and then you respond to the world
as an unpredictable place when anything
happens that stops you from reaching the
goal that you've determined to be
relevant at this point in time.
And so those are,
in some sense you're two modes of
operation.
Then you could also add that if you're
pursuing a goal or embodying a little
goal directed personality,
then things that facilitate movement
towards that goal are going to be
positive and things that interfere with
movement towards that goal are going to
be negative.
And when you understand that,
then you've got some sense of how the
fundamental emotional systems work.
So.
All right,
so
all right,
so this little diagram is designed to
show you what the relationship between
conception and and actuality might be
and even what the relationship between
conception and a word might be.
So the theory behind this little diagram
is that there's a set of phenomena in
front of you that's too complex to deal
with.
And so what you do is you generate a low
resolution representations of it and
that low resolution representations is
actually what you see.
It's not a concept or you could say it's
a percept,
it's what you see when you look at
something.
So for example,
and then what you do with your words as
you,
you labeled the percept of the thing.
And so it's like,
um,
it's like a double
compression.
That's in some sense what you're doing.
So you have a complex reality,
you perceive it in a,
in a,
in a low resolution form,
and then you labeled the perception and
that gives you a word.
And so what you're doing basically is
taking the world that you can understand
and you're make putting it in smaller
and smaller and tighter boxes until you
have a box that's small enough and tight
enough so that you can actually
manipulate it.
And that's a fine plan except when it
doesn't work.
And so then the question is,
well,
what do you do when it doesn't work?
And that is the question.
Okay?
So you could say,
if you look at the top left hand corner,
I call that the thing in itself,
which is a phrase from Sarah translated
phrase from German philosophy in the old
idea was that well you never really have
contact with the thing in itself,
you because you're not capable of
perceiving it or comprehending it.
So what you see are elements of it.
So we're going to say,
well that's the thing in itself,
it's a schematic representation of it.
It's quite complex.
And then hypothetically you can see that
thing in all the other ways that are
illustrated in the diagram.
Right?
So if I asked you what that was,
you could say,
well it's a rectangle or you could say
it's a with four rectangles as sub
elements.
Or You could say that it's,
I think that's what,
24 rows,
which it also is.
Or You could say it's a bounded
rectangle that's made out of two paths
and for sub rectangles.
Or You could say that it's.
I don't remember how many are in there,
but you know that's the most
differentiated representation.
Object Five.
And then you might say,
well,
which of those is the real object?
And the answer first would be,
well none of them are.
And then the second answer would be it
depends on what you want to do with the
representations and you actually,
it's not really obvious that you can
make things more real than that.
It's like how real is what you're
perceiving it's real enough for certain
operations and not real enough for
others.
And so
it's validity.
It's a pragmatic approach is it's a
validity is determined by its
applicability in the situation in which
you want to apply it.
Okay.
And then at the bottom there are words
and the words are basically labels for
those percept.
So you know,
I'm the first one you could sum up as
432 because I guess there's 432 little
circles there.
And the second one you could on the
bottom,
you could summarize as across or a
rectangle and the one at the top you
could summarize as a flag and you get
the point.
So the word is representing a percept
that's already simplified.
And that's representing something that's
more complex underneath it.
Okay,
so here's another way of looking at it.
So if you're looking at a computer,
your computer crashes,
we'll say,
so,
okay,
you're working on your computer and then
you might think,
well are you actually working on your
computer?
And the question that they answer to
that is,
it depends on exactly what you mean by
computer and exactly what is this thing
that's a computer.
So actually when you're working on a
computer,
what you generally see is only the
screen and you don't even see the
screen.
You see that tiny sub element of the
screen that contains those
representational entities that are
directly relevant to the area of the
world that you're focusing on right now
because you want something to happen.
Okay?
So really when you're interacting with
the computer,
you're just interacting with this tiny
little part of it.
And then the problem is in order for
that tiny little part to maintain its
validity as a representational entity,
all the things that you don't see about
the computer,
half the work,
right?
And then you might think,
well,
what don't you see about the computer?
Well that's what this diagram is
supposed to be showing.
So the first thing is you don't see the
elemental properties of the computer and
that would be its existence at a quantum
level and that actually turns out to be
increasingly irrelevant for computer
designers because you know,
you cannot specify the location and the
momentum of a particle at a quantum
level with 100 percent accuracy.
And what that means is it actually has,
it actually has relevance.
The little wires in computer chips are
getting so small now that there's some
reasonable probability that an electron
you think will be in the wire is outside
the wire.
And that means they'll short out.
So at some level of interaction,
the quantum properties actually matter.
Okay?
So that's part of the computer you don't
see.
And then while the computer itself is
made out of all these little parts that
are as complex as little cities and it's
just packed with that and you what you
don't know about that could fill hole
volumes in any of those things can you
know,
malfunctioned in any moment.
So that's a big problem.
And then those micro parts are arranged
into subcomponents with a desktop.
Maybe you're a sound card is gone or
your video card is gone or something
that you could take out and replace.
If you could only specify the proper
level of analysis or you know,
maybe you bought a lousy brand and
that's the problem he bought.
Bought some cheap computer that's made
in a digital factory.
And the probability that's going to be
reliable as zero.
And then you might ask,
well why is it that that brand is not
reliable?
And you might say,
well,
the economic system within which it was
produced is corrupt.
And so as the political system.
And so as a consequence of that,
people can get away with shawty
manufacturing.
And that manifests itself as the fact
that your computer crashes in the middle
of an essay and then you might say,
well,
what's the right level of resolution to
solve that problem?
And answer to that is,
that's not obvious.
It depends on what you mean by solvent.
Now usually what you mean is do the
minimum necessary to get the system back
online so that you can return to your
activities.
But it's by no means obvious that that's
always the right solution.
And sometimes it isn't because at some
point you're going to say,
well I should just throw the computer
away.
And you know,
if you own computers that when to throw
them away is actually a complicated
problem.
How many of you have like three or four
old laptops lying around the house?
Right?
Right.
So like,
why?
Well,
they still work well do they really?
And then a deeper question is what makes
you think that they're still laptops?
And the answer to that is,
well they look like laptops and that's
also wrong.
They look like laptops.
If you think that a box is a laptop and
it's not and it with computers,
you can really see this way because you
can have an entity that's fully
functional,
a laptop,
and then if you just leave it on your
desk and don't touch it for five years
or let's say 10 years,
what is it then?
Well,
it's become so disconnected from the
ecosystem that it's a part of that it
might not be useful for anything
anymore.
You might not even be able to get it to
work and you know,
most things around us don't change that
fast so we can.
We can perceive them in relatively
simple forms and they don't transform so
quick that that shows us that our
perception is going to stray,
but computers aren't like that.
They transformed so rapidly.
You probably spend one fifth of your
time just trying to just trying to keep
up with the transformations.
Do you think that is to be used,
the anticipation in a person that it
could be used as a laptop if they wanted
to make it?
Sure.
Well,
it does to some degree.
The question is do you actually use it?
That's the first question,
so and that's actually the manner in
which you test the validity of your
perceptual theory because I would say
that a laptop that you don't use is
actually not a laptop.
It's just a hypothetical laptop now
began to see.
I mean I'm being picky,
picky about these sorts of things,
but I'm doing that because we're trying
to understand exactly how categories
work and it is not obvious.
It's not obvious at all.
So the problem is is that the laptop
actually transforms into a brick
relatively slowly and deciding when it's
a laptop and went into brick is not
obvious because it doesn't denounce
that,
you know,
it just doesn't stop working all of a
sudden.
It just works in a manner that's
completely counterproductive.
And one of the things that's quite
interesting is there's not a lot of
evidence that the electronic revolution
has increased productivity and I think
the reason for that is how much time
during the week do you suppose you spend
just keeping your computer updated and
making sure that you understand how it
works.
Like would that be 10 percent of the
time that you used the computer?
Is that,
is that unreasonable estimate?
Like what do you think?
I mean I think for me it's like 20
percent of my time it's horrifying
because I have quite a few computers and
you know,
they're always doing weird things of one
form or another.
Even when I just leave the b they'll
update and then they will work or you
know,
I have a new computer and it's got such
a high resolution screen that you can't
use photoshop on it because he can't see
the menu items anymore.
And Adobe is known about that for a
whole year.
It hasn't fixed it.
And so like there's all these weird
little snakes popping up all over the
place with something as complex as your
computer and battling them off I think
destroys all the potential productivity
that the tool was actually designed to
produce.
So I don't know if that's true or not,
but it certainly seems that way to me.
So.
Okay.
So the laptop,
it's a funny entity too because you can
certainly see that it's connected
directly to a very large network.
Right?
And that's the Internet clearly,
but partly that's an information portal,
but partly the,
the thing stays alive because of its
connection to the Internet,
right?
It's continually updating,
it's continually being modified because
it's plugged into something that's
essentially a living system.
And when you think about it as a laptop,
you're just ignoring all of that and you
really can't because you can't ignore
all that because it's there.
It's even more real than I kind of think
of these things like leaves on a tree,
the trees,
the real thing.
These are just leaves and you know,
they fall off and then you have to then
and then they're dead.
So that's a good indication of the way
that our perceptions deceive us.
And you know,
one of the things you might notice is
what kind of emotional reaction do you
have when your computer ceases to be a
laptop while you're working on something
important?
What's your response?
Frustration and anger mostly.
Yeah.
And there'll be some anxiety in that
too.
And probably some contempt,
you know,
because you might say,
well,
this stupid bloody thing,
or something like that,
which is an expression of contempt,
which is associated with disgust and
then there's the anxiety which is,
oh my God,
what am I gonna do with this now?
And then there's the anger and that as a
consequence of something interfering
with your goal,
directed with your goal directed
pursuit.
And so one of the things that's really
worthwhile to note is to note that
panoply of emotions.
Now there might also be a little excited
possibly because you could say,
oh,
well I wanted to get rid of this piece
of junk anyways and get a new computer.
Right?
Because so when it collapses into its
sub elements,
this mess of sub elements,
there's all sorts of possibilities that
immediately arise that your nervous
system is attuned to and the way your
nervous system responds to that is it
gets frustrated,
angry.
It gets afraid,
it gets disgusted and it gets curious
about what's going to happen next.
And all of that happens at the same
time.
And I would say that that response,
which is an embodied response and an
instinctive response,
although there's cognitive elaborations
on it,
that's the response you have when you
actually see the actual world or as
close as you're going to get to it
because I don't think that you see the
world at all until the things you're
doing don't work,
and as soon as they don't work,
Bang you see the world now see is a
weird way to think about that.
But then we could say,
well,
that's the closest you ever get to
having contact with the thing in itself.
And it's very,
very stressful to have contact with the
thing in itself because God only knows
what it's going to do.
So your conceptual systems protect you
from contact with reality in the same
manner.
One of the things young said,
which I think is extraordinarily funny,
he said,
the purpose of religious systems is to
stop people from having religious
experiences.
It's an extraordinarily remarkable and
intelligent claim because you know,
do you really want to have a religious
experience that'll carry you into bits?
Yup.
Interesting encounter with things that
are not the real world when it stops.
Now let's take a lot of effort.
Well,
think about how we do it.
You know,
like say say something collapses on you,
like your car breaks down.
I mean,
do you actually solve that problem?
Well,
generally you don't write.
What you do is you parse off the problem
to someone else whose knowledge about
the multilevel reality of the automobile
is much more and differentiated than
yours.
And so partly the way we deal with the
complexity of the world is that we set
ourselves up as a distributed
supercomputer and we can,
we can call on elements of that
supercomputing process.
It says at any given time to increase
our level of resolution of the world and
to solve the problem,
and so partly we solve it as
individuals,
but a huge chunk of it is that we solve
it as a consequence of continual
communication.
And that's also becoming increasingly
obvious since the rise of the Internet
because now I don't care what problem
you have.
There's a high probability that someone
somewhere merely as a consequence of the
innate altruism of human beings has put
together an extraordinarily detailed
video on exactly how to solve this
little micro problem that's be said to
you,
which is really a fascinating and an
unexamined phenomenon because I'm sure
you guys are all familiar with that.
I,
I wanted to change the stereo.
I have an old card.
I want to change the stereo.
So the search was how to replace a
stereo in a 2005 Huyandai's Sonata,
you know,
in some guy down in the US for some
reason,
videotaped themselves doing it.
And there it was and it's really quite
cool that that happens because you know,
psychologists,
Sydney evolutionary psychologists and
biologists always argue about whether
there is such a thing as actual altruism
and you know,
it's hard not to see someone taking the
time to post to post an observation of
them undertaking a complex task for no
financial reward whatsoever.
It's hard not to see that as a form of,
you know,
spontaneous,
old truism.
It's very,
very cool.
Yeah.
Happens with people that are really
anxious or something like little things
abstract and it seems like the whole
world.
Yeah.
Well we'll get.
We'll get to the relationship between
your conceptual systems and how things
fall apart here right away.
So.
All right,
so I've run you through a couple of
examples of the complexity that you're
faced with that's invisible.
That's the thing that's really most
worth considering is that your stability
is dependent on the maintenance of a
million conditions.
The maintenance of a million conditions
that could go wrong at any particular
time,
but generally don't,
at least not in a functioning society.
All right,
so
I will look at this.
So I mentioned frames of reference and
so you cannot look at the world without
a frame of reference and the reason you
can't do that is because it's too
complex to see.
So that means that a frame of reference
is actually a pro,
a necessity for perception itself,
which is quite interesting.
So you cannot perceive it all unless you
perceive locally and pragmatically.
That's what it looks like.
And then you might ask yourself,
well what are these frames of reference?
Look like,
and this is where I think neuro
psychology and cognitive science meets
narrative psychology and psychoanalysis
because I think this just as the
smallest units of your semi robotic
subsystems,
the ones you share with animals,
our personality,
like when they manifest themselves,
so the concepts that you use to build
the frame of reference that you orient
yourself with our narrative like because
you can say,
well,
what's a narrative?
And the answer to that is it's a
description of a personality inaction.
That's what a narrative is.
And so if the actual problem solving
subcomponents of your psyche are
subpersonalities,
then the description of those is going
to be basic narratives.
And so the hypothesis here is that
because we're tremendously imitative
creatures,
first of all,
I can poll your personality out of you
at any given time by just watching what
you do and matching it with my body and
we're doing that all the time.
If you're a reasonably social person and
you're talking to someone one on one,
you're going to match your behavior to
theirs and all sorts of ways.
I mean,
one of the experiments we did once was
we brought undergraduates into the lab
and we just put like a,
you know,
a bowl of chips between them and
basically what we found is that each of
the undergraduates,
eight exactly the same amount of chips
as the other.
So sometimes a dyad would settle into no
chips and so neither of them would eat
anything.
And then another dyad would settle
somehow into,
well we'll eat all the chips and so then
each of them would eat half and the
correlation was like point nine.
It was unbelievable and these were
strangers you know.
And so you're mirroring the other
person's embodiment,
like a mad dog all the time and it's a
great thing to be able to do because it
means that you can,
you can unite your being within the
same,
within the same locale.
And that means you don't have to have
conflict.
Plus it also means that you can learn
very rapidly from someone else just by
doing what they're doing.
I don't know if you guys have seen this,
but there's computers now that,
that take advantage of this idea.
And so what happens is like,
let's say you have a computer,
that it's a robot and you want it to do
this task.
So pick something up here,
move it up here,
pull it over here and put it down.
All you do is you take the robot's arm
and you put it down and you close it and
then you lift it up and you move it over
and down.
And then the robot would do it by
itself.
And so that's,
you know,
that's the beginnings of robotic
imitation.
And that's actually real.
Imitation is mind boggling because once
it kicks in,
as soon as one thing learned something,
then all the other things that are
exactly like it can learn something.
And so what I think will happen in the
next five years is we'll finally get
robots that are fairly autonomous and
they're really,
man,
they're really on their way.
And then we'll get ones that are good at
imitating each other and then the thing
will just explode.
Because if there's a.
say there's say there's 10 million of
those robots that are reasonably
complex.
Then as soon as one of them learns
anything,
all the other ones will immediately know
it and while that's not,
that's.
That's exponential growth on a scale
that we can't even imagine and that's
coming very,
very rapidly.
But anyways,
you already do that and that's part of
the reason people are so damn smart.
But then you're also capable of a
different kind of invitation and that
invitation is when I watched myself do
something and then I formulated into a
concept and then I tell you the concept
and you decompose it so that you can use
it in your own body.
And that's basically what we're doing
when we're telling stories.
So now it's kind of low resolution
communication,
but it doesn't matter.
It's unbelievably powerful communication
and as far as I can tell,
the basic unit of that narrative or that
frame of reference,
is this your somewhere because you are
localized in time and space and that
isn't as good as it could be for one
reason or another.
So you're trying to improve it and then
you have some notions about what you
have to do in order to improve it.
And you act them out,
you implement them and I think you're
doing that all the time and I can't see
how you can not do it because you have
to have a technique for simplifying the
world.
And so as far as I can tell,
this is the technique and so a basic
story was while I was here and then I
went there and that was better and
here's how I did it.
And so that's a pretty good story.
It's not great,
but it's good enough.
You might listen to that or you might
watch it as a on a video like I did when
I was trying to figure out how to fix my
car stereo.
Right?
So it's a story about how to fix a car
stereo.
And you might say,
well that's not a very good story.
It's like I didn't say it was a very
good story.
I said it was the basic element of
perception and also of narrative
communication.
And,
and to make that,
those two things,
united is a tremendously exciting
possibility because one of the things
that you may have noted about
psychology,
this is something we talked a lot about
in my personality class,
is that there's a real disjunction
between narrative psychology,
which generally tends to be by
psychoanalytic and,
and neuroscience,
for example,
and psychometrics,
which tend to be,
while they're not narrative anyways,
you know,
they,
that we haven't been able to bridge the
gap.
And so part of the reason I'm telling
you,
the things I'm telling you right now is
so that you can bridge the gap.
So an so an opt out of this.
And that's when we go to this next,
this next diagram here.
Sorry,
I have so many diagrams.
It's hard to keep track of the monsters.
Yeah,
this one.
Okay,
now you've seen this before,
but I want to walk through it again
because it's important and it's,
it,
it allows you to do a
reconceptualization that unites things
that can't otherwise be united.
So the one of the issues might be,
well,
what is an abstraction composed of?
And I would say,
well,
it depends on the domain in which the
abstraction is being implemented.
So an abstraction about the world is
slightly different than an abstraction
about you.
I think what they have in common is that
when you make abstract representations
of the world,
you're making abstract representations
of the world as a place to act.
And that's a critically important thing
to understand because we're scientific
in our explicit cognitive
presuppositions.
We think that world models our world,
our models of the world as a place of
things.
So we're kind of taking a page from St
Augustine.
In some sense the world is made out of
objectively existing independent
material entities.
And when you develop understanding about
the world,
what you're doing is producing a map of
those entities.
And the thing is that's true in a narrow
sense in that that is what you're doing
when you're doing science,
but science itself is nested inside of
narrative structure as we talked about
before.
So then the question is what's the
nature of the more comprehensive
narrative structure?
And I don't think that you can
understand,
you cannot understand profound
narratives unless you understand this,
this,
underlying,
these,
this underlying set of assumptions.
You're not naturally predisposed to view
the world in objective terms.
Now we talked about that from a
Darwinian,
the Newtonian point of view last time.
So when I told you what I thought about
that,
but here's,
here's the idea,
you know,
so let's say we'll talk about the domain
of morality.
And the reason that I put this under the
debate of morality is because it has to
do with how you do act and how you
should act.
So that's a moral domain.
And then I would say most of the time
when we're communicating information
that we find relevant to one another,
what we're communicating is moral
inflammation and the moral information
is how to perceive and act in the world
such that things work.
Now obviously you can have a debate
about what those things are,
but that's still what we're trying to
do.
And you can debate about what work means
and so on and so forth.
And we're doing that all the time
because it's complex.
So if I say,
well,
you're a good person,
then we could unpack that.
I could say,
okay,
well what are the snakes inside being a
good person?
And we can say,
well that's a higher.
It's actually good person is a
representation of a complex hierarchy
and so I've outlined some of the
hierarchy here.
If you're a good person,
one element of being a good person,
although maybe not a necessary element,
but one element is that you're a good
parent and then a sub element of that is
that you can take care of your family
and Isabell.
An element of that might be that you can
play with the baby or that you could
cook a meal.
Now you don't have to hit a home run on
every single one of the constituents,
sub elements of the entire category in
order to qualify as a good person,
but you can see that there's a shared
structure.
You know that people recognize that's
characteristic of a good person that's
actually composed of action patterns and
perceptions has nothing to do in some
sense with the objective world.
It's a completely different way of
looking at it.
So if you're going to play with the baby
while then you think,
well,
what do you have to do to play with the
baby?
And so you know,
we might make a goofy face out the baby
because babies respond to that sort of
thing.
Sometimes by crying,
but often by smiling you can tickle
their feet.
You can kind of poke them,
you can play with their arms,
you know,
you can rock them back and forth.
There's and you watch the baby.
So you find out if it's having fun too.
And now the thing that's interesting
about actually playing with the baby is
that the,
the,
the phenomena that you're manifesting is
no longer abstract and conceptual.
It's embodied play,
decomposes into movement patterns of
movements like a dance.
In fact,
if you take a mother and she's getting
along with her baby and you videotape
them interacting,
what you see is that the mothers who get
along with their baby are doing a dance
with them and the baby is harmonized
with the mother.
So there's this sort of melodic and
fluid dance.
Whereas the baby that's not getting
along with its mother,
it's more like having a conversation
with someone who disagrees with
absolutely everything that you say in
random ways.
No.
So you start off an invitation to the
conversation and they nail you with a
non sequitur,
so that's a nonstarter and then you try
it again and they nail you with
something else that seems completely
irrelevant and and so it's Jerky and
discontinuous and you see that with
people interacting with children all the
time.
I think that's part of the reason why
people use dance as a mating strategy.
It's like,
you know,
is this person capable of mutual,
harmonious imitation?
Now it's not a perfect test,
but
it's not too bad.
It's got.
It's got some utility and it's so the
abstraction,
the abstract narrative representation.
You're a good person.
That is not an objective category.
The,
the abstract representation.
You're a good person,
decomposes at the highest level of
resolution into a sequence of actions,
and piaget,
for example,
would say that while you learn those
basic actions as you're putting your
nervous system together from,
from birth until now,
so you're building yourself up at the
bottom because so when you dance,
you know there's certain movements you
have to make and those are movements
that you could make in other
circumstances that would also be useful.
And so you're for,
for piaget,
you build yourself from the bottom of
this hierarchy towards the top.
Okay?
So then,
you know,
one of the things that you might note is
that as you go up the chain of
abstraction arguments about what those
categories contained become more and
more likely,
you know,
and so you might say for example,
to your,
to your mate,
that being able to
prepare a decent meal is such an
important sub element of being a good
person.
That if you fail to do it or can't,
that actually means you're a bad person
and you can see right away why that
would provoke all sorts of arguments.
And so part of the reason that I'm
bringing this up is because we're
always,
we're engaged in a constant process of
mutual exploration to determine how
these hierarchies are properly arranged
and what are necessary sub categories of
them and how those subcategories shoe
should be hierarchically instantiated
with regards to one another and we have
to have some agreement about that or we
actually can't communicate.
So like if,
if my stance is you burn the vegetables,
you're a bad person and your stances,
I burned the vegetables and who the hell
cares about that?
Then the fact that our hierarchies of
values are structured completely
differently means we're gonna have a
very difficult time communicating and
there's going to be a lot of conflict
about how that conceptual structure
should be reorganized.
And that's actually what you're doing
when you're arguing with someone about
something important.
It's like you're trying to say,
okay,
we need to get our hierarchies are
narrative,
hierarchy succinct so that what you want
and what I want can happen at the same
time.
And so that we understand each other.
And we can partly do that by talking.
Um,
we can also do it by suppressing the
other person,
which we tend to do an awful lot or
suppressing ourselves in favor of the
other person and so forth and so on.
But the thing is there's that,
that,
those,
those places have known agreement are,
are like,
they're like tunnels into a,
the complex underlying reality that we
have to deal with and places where the,
the nature of that,
the nature of the complexity of dealing
with that become apparent.
And part of what happens as a
consequence of that is people just don't
have those discussions.
They don't know how to do it.
They can't decompose the situation.
You know,
and I can give you an example of that
which you're going to face.
Let's say you're in a family,
you're married to someone or whatever
the equivalent happens to be.
You both have a career whose career is
more important,
you think,
well,
it doesn't matter.
It's like it matters because there will
be times when you have to make a choice
between the two career paths.
It's like,
okay,
well how do you do that?
And the answer to that is you don't know
and neither does anyone else,
and worse,
there are no rules for having a
discussion.
You have to come up with all the rules
and everything about the discussion
because you can't even tell when you're
being reasonable,
you know,
because you might say,
well,
the person who makes the most money,
their careers,
the most important,
it's like
you are you going to accept that?
What do you think that's valid?
And if you don't,
okay,
fine,
what are you going to use it as an
alternative criteria?
It's very,
very difficult.
You know when most of the way we solve
this as collectives,
as we have standard hierarchies of
narratives that we just all adopt.
That's the our,
our identity with our history.
That's a role.
If you adopt your role in mine and my
hierarchy is structured to take your
role into account and the reverse is
also true.
We don't have to have a conflict.
Now you might have a conflict as an
individual with your role.
That's a whole different story.
But if you pop out of your role,
and I pop out of mine,
were in no man's land and in no man's
land,
three things happen.
Tyranny,
slavery,
or negotiation.
And most people can't negotiate.
And the reason for that is it's too damn
complicated.
What time is it?
10 after two?
Yes.
Let's take a break.
Okay.
For,
for,
for 15 minutes.