One,
one person who visited me during the
break had a question that was a good
not,
but all the other questions weren't
good.
But this one is a question of good
general relevance.
So do you want to repeat your question?
People having but then dose those
religion,
right?
Yeah.
Well it's a really good question.
So the question is,
Nisha said God is dead and he believed
that things would fall apart as a
consequence of that.
And I'm claiming,
for example,
that people have an implicit religious
structure and they act it out.
Okay.
So there's actually a lot of things
happened as a consequence of the fact
that that's a reasonable issue.
A good question.
So one of the things you might think
about is that,
so nature is claiming Dostoyevsky's
claim were quite straight forward.
They said that once you took the
foundation out of something,
it would fall out.
It might take a long time to fall,
especially if it's a big thing.
So,
you know,
you could make the claim,
for example,
that the Soviet Union basically fell in
like 1970 but it took 19 years to topple
over because it's a big thing,
right?
It's,
it just doesn't crumble all at once.
And so Nietzschean Dostoyevsky's claim
would be once you hack out the basic
assumptions and question them,
that it's only a matter of time until
the entire structure decays.
And you could think that perhaps,
you know,
if you have a habit and then you become
conscious of the habit and you practice
a new habit,
then you can have a new habit.
And so what that means is that you can
use your conscious mind to restructure
your implicit beliefs.
It's hard.
Or you can use your conscious mind to
destroy your belief in the value of
those implicit actions and demolish them
across time.
Okay.
So that could happen.
And I think to some degree that has
happened,
it's certainly happened enough so that
people are very confused about what they
believe or even about what belief means.
Cause there's a contradiction between
what people think and there's a and how
they act.
So,
okay,
that's one.
Okay.
Tangent.
So to speak.
You,
and he actually took that question very
seriously in some sense because the
nature,
here's the floor niches argument.
I think it's like,
I hesitate to ever say that because like
I said,
he was a staggering genius.
So,
but nature believed his proposition was
that once the religious edifice fell
that people would have to create their
own value.
So he believed that the over ma'am,
the superman so to speak would be a new
type of human being,
like an existential type of human being
who would be able to accept the fact
that there was no ultimate meaning,
but create their own values.
Okay.
What the weird thing about that is you
don't actually seem to create values.
That's what,
that's where is flawed.
And I think that's where he implicitly
accepted the presuppositions of the
rationalists.
Because if there's no real source of
value,
then it stands to reason that you create
values,
but you don't,
not easily like,
you know,
think about your own life.
You know?
So let's say you make a new year's
resolution.
You say,
well,
I'm going to study like three hours a
day.
It's like you're trying to create your
own value structure,
right?
But then you find out it's a lot harder
than you think because you don't listen
to yourself.
It's like you wonder off and you know,
play video games or watch something on
youtube,
you know,
and,
and you know,
why are you doing that?
Well,
it's because you're led by values.
You don't create them.
Now maybe there's a cocreation,
you know,
because it's not like you can't change
yourself at all.
But we should be very careful before we
jumped to the conclusion that values are
or even can be something that people
actually create.
Now the phenomenologists like heidegger
and young well would say,
no,
let's,
let's just not get too hasty about
making the presupposition that we can or
should create her own values.
Now,
one reason you might be hesitant to do
that is that Hitler created is value,
so to speak.
And so did the Soviet communists and the
North Koreans.
You know,
they're trying to impose a rationalist
value structure on a society and the
consequences of that,
it'd be,
you know,
people debate about how many people died
in the Soviet Union as a consequence of
internal repression.
And as the Marxist revisionists rally
back to the original beliefs,
the estimate keeps going down.
But you know,
it was tens of millions of people.
So,
and in China,
who knows,
it was maybe it was 100 million people,
it was a lot of people.
And then of course there's the Nazis it,
you know,
so the,
the,
the act of attempting to rationally
constructed value system and then impose
it that it doesn't seem to work out very
well.
So,
you know,
on a sociological level,
we seem to have evidence that that's
dangerous.
And then on a personal level,
it's like,
yeah,
you're so sure you create your values.
I would say to a large degree you
discovered them.
And so,
you know,
here,
here's,
here's an experiment.
You can try one,
I told you last week I think to try to
watch yourself speak for,
I think you should do it for the rest of
your life,
you know,
because words are very,
very,
very powerful and they lead you places.
So you should be careful how you use
them.
But like here's another really
interesting experiment is watch what
you're interested in.
Try,
don't try to control it so much.
Just see where it is.
Because like in the phenomenologists
certainly made much of this is like for
them,
like for Heidegger,
value is something that manifested
itself in the world and attracted your
attention.
You know,
it wasn't something you precisely
created.
Now I believe you have a hand in
creating it.
We'll talk more about that later because
you're not,
you're not a deterministic entity.
Precisely.
So it's like you can participate in the
construction of a value system,
but you know,
you have to take your biological nature
into mind and you have to take your
cultural nature into mind and you'll
have to take other people into mind.
And so you know,
you have,
you can vary the game,
but I don't think you can really change
the rules.
That's a reasonable way of thinking
about it.
Now what you did in many ways was he
said,
well,
maybe we have to go back down into the
deep symbolic substrata of the human
psyche to find the origin place of the
ideas that we used to hold as religious.
It was a hypothesis in some sense,
and so there,
the psychoanalytic hypothesis is
something like,
it's the,
it's the psychic substrata,
the pre linguistic psychic substrata
that is the source of ritual symbol and
religious ideas.
And so that you can go back to the
source in a sense to revitalize those
ideas.
And that strikes me as a wiser approach
than the rational approach,
which says you can just create your
values.
It's like we tried that.
It didn't work.
It really didn't work.
It was murderous.
So,
and then the,
the alternative,
the no value proposition as well,
then you're going to be nihilistic.
And that's not,
I think nihilism is a form of mental
illness.
It's a sociological,
it it,
it's caused by sociological conditions,
but fundamentally it's a mental illness,
right?
You revise what you mean by believe.
That's part of it and that's what we're
going to try to walk through.
You know,
this is a very,
this is a linear argument in some sense,
although there's going to be a lot of
tangents.
I want to,
I want to show you how that might be
done and what it might mean.
I mean,
who knows what it ultimately means,
right?
There's just no going there.
But my experience with these ideas have
been that once you understand them and
it's a different way of categorizing
Shin,
I would say all sorts of things that you
didn't understand all of a sudden light
up for you.
And it's really helpful,
you know,
because for,
let me just give you a couple of
examples.
You know,
I would say that it's a unspoken
proposition of much of today's
sociobiological thinking that there's
something pathological about human
beings.
You know,
like I've heard people say like human
beings are like a cancer on the planet.
It's like I went to a talk at Ted talk
at Queens,
a Tedx talk where one of the professors
who was a radical environmentalist of
sorts,
you know,
he told the whole audience,
they were all people about your age,
that if they had any ounce of ethical,
if they had any ethical standards
whatsoever,
they wouldn't reproduce.
It's like,
you know,
really he said,
well we've only had one child.
And for me I thought that was one child
too many for him.
But you know,
I thought that's bloody pathological.
When you stand up in front of a whole
bunch of young people who have their
whole future in front of them and you
say,
well,
you know,
you're such a horrid creature in your
very core that it would be a moral
violation for you to propagate.
Its like,
you know,
so I mean one of the things that that
happened to me is like I kind of like
people,
you know,
there are peculiar and weird like
hippopotamuses and,
and rhinos and penguins and all that.
But you know,
I certainly don't think that we're some
sort of cancer on the planet.
I really think that's a,
that's a pre genocidal idea as far as
I'm concerned.
It's like the planet would be better off
without any people on it.
It's like,
Hey,
glad you're not near the old thermo
nuclear button.
Yeah,
really,
really.
You know,
it's like that's an archetypal idea.
Fire will cleanse everything.
It's like,
that's what Hitler believed.
That's why all Berlin was burning when
he committed suicide.
It's like that was what he was after
from the beginning,
the cleansing fire.
It's like beware of those ideas,
boy.
You know?
And so I,
I can see the intrinsic dignity of
people and,
and their intrinsic value and how that
can be expressed across time.
And you know,
and I value that.
It's,
it's,
it's something pristine and,
and remarkable,
you know?
And,
and understanding,
I believe that understanding these ideas
property can give you that kind of
orientation,
you know?
I mean,
everybody's flawed and useless and half
crazy.
I mean,
obviously,
but you know,
that's not exactly the point.
There are reasons we are flawed and
useless and half crazy.
You know,
life is hard and we're finite and we
know.
So we have big problems that confront
us.
It's like,
I don't think any sane person cannot be
crazy so to speak.
But having said all that,
the idea that there's something
intrinsically pathological about human
beings like that is an absolutely,
what's the word?
Apocalyptic idea.
It's like beware of people who tell you
such things,
you know?
So,
and it's certainly not something you
should be thinking about yourself.
God.
It's like who knows what you're up to.
You know?
Maybe some of you will be great people,
you know,
good luck with it.
So,
so I want to walk you through what I
think these ideas mean.
And I'm not asking you to believe
anything I tell you.
It's like don't hack away at it,
man.
See if you can see where it's flawed.
I can't,
I've tried.
So cause I don't want to be standing on
sand.
And so what I've tried to do is to look
at human history and prehistory and to
see what it is that we need to move
forward.
And we have to be united with our
history.
Human beings are historical creatures.
And so if there's a divide between us
and our history,
then all sorts of weird ideas are going
to invade us.
You know?
It's like,
it's quite funny because again,
with the rationalists atheists,
you know,
they basically think that if we dispense
with religion,
everybody would turn into Rene
Descartes.
You know?
It's like we'd be all rational.
It's like,
are you out of your bloody mind?
Look at the new age people,
you know?
That's where we'd be going first.
It's like we'd be like,
Shirley,
what's your name?
Mclean who I read once believed that the
reason that there were so many allergies
in San Francisco was because of aliens.
It's like,
oh,
that's a much more likely place for
human belief systems to end up.
Then like,
poof,
we're all rene decartes.
Like,
that's not going to happen.
You know,
one of the things young said,
which I just loved,
he said,
the purpose of religious structures is
to stop people from having religious
experiences.
That's a smart,
that's smart saying.
So anyways,
so we're going to walk through this and,
well,
you know what I,
what I've come to believe is that the
archetypes we're going to talk about,
because I believe they archetypes is
pretty good way of thinking about them
constitute the fundamental presumptions
of human being.
You,
you can't not presume them.
That's why the religious,
you can't escape from them.
Now that doesn't mean they're right,
but it means that there as right as we
are.
And how right are we?
Well we don't know.
You know,
I mean there were people that I read,
somebody's in the 1970s he was a
journalist,
he wrote a book called the ghost in the
machine.
You know,
and,
and this was a fairly common proposition
at the time.
His idea was that,
well,
you know,
we're animals that have become self
conscious and that may be strictly drove
us incurably insane.
And so we're like an evolutionary dead
end and it's only a matter of time
before we extinguish ourselves.
It's like that's possible.
You know,
no other animal has ever become self
conscious.
It's a big burden,
you know,
and it does drive people kind of crazy
and no wonder,
you know,
cause you have to contemplate your
mortality all the time or at least some
of the time.
And also you're completely aware of how
useless and ugly and you know all these
other things you are compared to
whatever the ideal might be.
It's a lot of burden.
But it seems to me to that human beings
are peculiar in that we can actually
choose,
we have some facility for choice.
I think we could decide whether we're an
evolutionary dead end or not.
And I also believe that grounding our
thinking in these ancient ideas makes it
far more likely,
far less likely that we're going to fall
prey to ideological possession,
which is extraordinary dangerous.
And it'll also give us the metta
framework to conceptualize what might
constitute ideal and well.
So you know,
that's cause I wanted to,
I wanted to find out what's an
alternative cause videology and nothing
is the wrong answer because people can't
live on nothing.
Life is too hard.
You have to see that your being is
justifiable in order to thrive.
And given that your being is
characterized by suffering,
that's no easy matter,
suffering and limitation.
That's the basic truths of life.
It's a Buddhist doctrine for that
matter.
Right?
And it's,
it's not,
it's certainly not something that the
Jews would disagree with.
And it's central to Christian thinking
as well.
You know,
most religious structures thing,
you're doomed and there's going to be a
lot of pain along the way.
It's like,
yeah,
that's true.
Okay,
now we've got that out in the open.
What do you do about it?
Well,
that's the question.
So let's see,
what do we have for time?
It's three 45 is that about right?
This old computer?
I'm not sure it's accurate.
Yeah.
Okay,
so question.
Yeah,
I guess now that we've conceptualized it
as a problem,
it is.
Oh yeah.
Well the thing is,
you know,
sometimes conceptualizing a problem
brings it into focus.
There are multiple ways things realize
themselves,
right?
You know,
you know how it is.
If you,
if you learn something complex,
you think you've learned it,
and then a little later you articulated
more.
Or do you think,
oh,
I,
I didn't understand that completely.
And then you know,
you think you've got it.
And in three years later you think,
oh no,
I really didn't quite have that.
I'm going to articulate it more.
So knowledge comes into focus and so,
okay,
so let's move away from,
from the this philosophy,
philosophical,
evolutionary discussion for a moment.
I want it,
I want to start again with a series of
propositions.
So
it's three.
Oh,
okay,
good,
good.
Three 38 all right,
fine.
So now when I first started to construct
this representation,
I'd been reading heavily a book called
the neuropsychology of anxiety that's
written by Jeffrey Gray.
Jeffrey Gray was one of hands ising
students.
And Isaac was one of the other founders
of modern psychometric personality
theory for a long time.
He was the most cited psychologist in
the world.
And Jeffrey Gray was no,
Jeffrey Gray who died recently was a,
he was a literate guy.
Man.
The neuropsychology of anxiety is a
tough read because he was sort of a
master of neuropharmacology neuro
anatomy,
neuro psychology and animal behavior.
So he's a behaviorist and cybernetic
theory,
although I don't really think he knew
exactly that he was a cybernetic
theorist.
He sort of knew it.
It took me a long time to figure out
that he was a cybernetic theorist.
Cybernetics emerged as a consequence of
the work of someone called Norbert
Wiener,
who was an,
who was at mit and he wrote a book
called,
I think he wrote,
I think the book was called cybernetics
actually.
Anyways,
you can look them up.
Um,
and there are cybernetic principles that
I extracted out of gray and it started
to utilize and then I only found out
later that they were actually
consequences of whiners thinking now.
And he infected lots of people.
So luria who was a great Russian nurse,
neuro psychologist was basically a
cybernetic system.
There was a couple of other Russians,
Sokolov and vinegar Dova who discovered
the orienting reflex,
which was like,
that was like discovering a new planet
or a new continent.
It's like an important discovery.
They should've got the Nobel prize for
it.
As far as I'm concerned,
it's a big deal.
And so Norbert Wiener cybernetic thought
really spread everywhere and it like
pops up.
Piaget is cybernetic in many ways.
And there's,
there's modern personality theories that
are fundamentally cybernetic.
So this is basically a cybernetic model
and cybernetics,
cybernetic models hypothesize that
active organisms,
they basically perform according to the
following.
Yeah,
Schema.
They paused at a target and move towards
it and then they regulate themselves so
they don't deviate too much from the
trail.
So that's what this is as far as I'm
concerned.
So,
so here's,
here's the basic framework within which
you live as far as I can tell and I
don't think you can get out of it.
And you carry this frame with you all
the time and you're looking at the world
through it.
And the framework has a couple of
substructures and one is you have some
sense of where you are.
And that's like a theory.
It's a theory of where,
who you are and where you are.
It's a theory of the present.
These are the present conditions.
Now you might think you observe the
present around you and those are factual
observations.
And so your conceptualization of the
present isn't a theory.
It's a fact.
But don't be thinking that,
you know,
it's a theory.
You might be wrong about the present.
The person you're in love with might be
having an affair,
right?
So there can be massive gaps in your
assumptions about the present.
You know,
you think you're healthy,
but maybe you're not,
you know,
you think your boss likes you,
but maybe they don't.
You think your degree is going to be
useful,
but maybe it isn't.
You know?
Well it's just,
it's just,
it's just a straight forward
observation.
But it's an important one.
You could be wrong about now.
Okay.
Cause one of the things we're going to
try to figure out is where is it that
you could be wrong and what does it mean
that you could be wrong?
All of those places.
And what should you do about the fact
that you could be wrong?
All those places.
And then we're also going to try to
figure out what happens if you find out
that you're wrong.
So,
for example,
you're going out with someone you love
them,
perhaps they've made promises to you and
you know,
poof,
you find out that they'd been having an
affair with three people for the last
five years.
It's like,
hey,
you're wrong.
And so now where are you?
What does that mean that you're wrong?
Well,
it means a lot of things.
It means you're means a lot of things
that you,
it might mean a lot more things that it
means,
which is a very strange thing,
might mean that you're so clueless as is
just mind boggling,
you know,
and that you're blind as a bat.
So that's one possibility and that
you're like that and you've always been
like that.
You better do something about it quick.
That's a possibility might be that you
hooked up with a psychopath,
right?
Which is also something that you should
avoid.
And but that would mean you don't
understand people well enough to know
when they're psychopaths or not,
or maybe that your fatally attracted to
them in some bizarre way.
You know?
It also means that whatever future you
were envisioning that was really a
delusion because that's gone.
And it also means that you've blown out
most of your past,
at least in so far as that relationship
was part of your past because nothing
that you thought was happening was what
was happening.
So then you might think one moment
you're somewhere,
then you get the realization and the
next moment you are somewhere else.
And so one of the things I would propose
to you is that those are actually two
important places.
The one place is the place you are,
when what you're doing is working.
And the other place is the place you are
when what you're doing is not working.
And I would also say in some weird
sense,
those are permanent places.
And I'll tell you why I think this,
but I think they're akin in some manner
to explored territory and unexplored
territory.
And that's their sort of biological
basis.
Because we know that animals are
territorial,
right?
Almost every animal has a sketched out
territory.
Um,
if social animals have to organize
themselves within that,
toward territory with other creatures
like them.
So part of their territory is almost
always a dominance hierarchy,
but they have a territory and they don't
like going outside of it.
So I can,
I can give you an example.
So my,
my parents have that dog and a cat and a
that my dad used to take the dog for a
walk all the time,
but the cat really liked the dog.
And so it was kind of irritated that the
dog would leave.
And so the cat started following my dad
around on his walks.
And so it was really interesting because
the first thing the cat did was when it
was following,
it wasn't right behind the dog.
There's no way it was going to do that.
It would slink along all of the
building.
So it would follow about 30 feet behind
and it would keep one side right against
a building.
And then it would sort of zip across the
intervening spaces of the houses.
Right.
And you might think,
well,
why was it doing that?
And the answer is it didn't know where
the bloody predators were.
Didn't know where the big dogs were.
It didn't know anything about the new
places it was going.
So it was going to stick inside against
one hard wall so that the complexity was
cut in half and it was going to go
really slow on the off chance that some
massive hound came out and ate it.
So it was being very careful.
So that was pretty cool.
So it did that for quite a while and
then because nothing massive jumped out
and ate it and because it started to
understand that territory knew where it
could hide.
It got a little braver and over a couple
of months it got to the point where it
actually follow the,
the dog because it had mastered,
it's expanded its territory and mastered
its knowledge of the territory.
But then I was walking with them one day
and they had a route,
Hey,
and my dad had the dog and he wanted to
take the dog a little farther than he
would normally go with the dog.
And so he was taking the dog across the
street,
but the cat just stayed on the corner
and cried because it,
you know,
it was meowing obviously,
but it was very upset because it wasn't
going out into that weird new place that
it had no knowledge about.
And so it was,
you know,
making its fear really known and animals
are like that,
you know?
So here's something to think about.
This blew me away when I first
conceptualized it was one of the things
that made me understand that
psychologists are always asking
questions backwards.
I,
I'll give you an example.
It's like,
why do people take cocaine?
That's a question,
right?
I think it's a good question.
It's a stupid question.
The question is why doesn't everybody
take cocaine all the time?
That's the question.
Because we know what cocaine does,
right?
It,
it activates the primary incentive
reward systems and almost everything you
do is in an attempt to activate the
primary incentive reward system.
So you've got this white powder and it
is,
it's like you should be,
knows deepen that stuff nonstop,
but you're not,
why?
What's wrong with you people,
you know?
So,
so that's one example of where
psychology is got,
it's got it backwards.
We know why people take intoxicating
drugs.
It's dead simple.
Sometimes it reduces their anxiety,
sometimes it reduces their pain.
Sometimes it cranks up their incentive
reward systems.
You know,
it hijacks the system,
it does it biochemically,
perfectly obvious.
So that's one example.
Now another example is this.
How do animals learn fear?
It's a prime behavioral question,
right?
It's the wrong question because it
presumes that the,
the standard animal is calm.
Why would you presume that?
Why wouldn't we presume instead that the
standard animal is terrified and that
the animal only learns how not to be
terrified with difficulty and under very
restricted circumstances?
Well,
that's a much better way of thinking
about it.
And it makes a lot more sense because
the animals in danger,
especially if it doesn't know its
territory.
So,
so here's how you teach an animal to be
afraid.
If you're a behaviorist and I am not
making fun of behaviors,
a lot of what I've learned about
psychology that's actually real has come
from behavior.
It's like they're rigorous scientists
and,
and they learned an awful lot from
analyzing animal behavior that was
incredibly profound.
And they laid the ground for modern
neuroscience,
the real stuff,
not the FMRI stuff.
You know,
the real stuff.
So,
okay,
so basically what you do to train an
animal to be afraid is you take a rack,
let's say,
and the rats in this cage,
and you put,
you put a little electric shock pad in
the rats cage,
so maybe electrifies the bottom a little
bit and you turn on a light and you
electrify the bottom and the rat jumps
into the air and then you shut it off.
And then you wait a while and then you
do the same thing,
turn on the light,
then you turn on the electric electric
shock mechanism and the wrap jumps in
the air and you do that 10 times.
And then when you turn on the light,
the rat goes like,
this freezes because it's learned,
right?
Light equal shark.
Everyone knows that,
you know,
that's basic conditioning.
Um,
so the rats learn to be afraid.
Okay,
that makes sense.
Except,
okay,
here's your experimental box,
right?
You got the electrification going on in
there and you grab your rat and you
dropped me in the cage.
What does he do first?
He freezes because he's afraid.
He's afraid.
As soon as you put them in the new
environment,
that's the normal route.
The normal rat.
It's like this.
And why is that?
Because things like to eat rats.
So you know they don't like light.
They like it dark and they don't like
being exposed and they don't like being
the new damn cage because God only knows
what's in that cage.
And so the a priori rat is this.
So then what is the wrap do?
Well it's like this for quite a while.
It can be really a long time.
I'll tell you a story about that.
He's like this and then maybe he sniffs
cause rats mostly knows.
Most animals are mostly smell oriented,
right?
Human beings are weird because we're
visually oriented,
but almost all animals,
it's all smell.
Their whole brains are organized around
their olfactory system.
So it sniffs and if it can't smell
anything,
rats,
man,
they can smell.
So there's experiments indicating that
if you take a rat and you poison it and
then it gets sick and another rat has
smelled it's breath,
that rat will not eat the poison that
the first route eight.
Now that's why it's hard to get rid of
rats.
They're smart and they have great senses
of smell.
So the rats checking out like is there
anything here that smells like something
that might eat me?
So cats for example,
rat doesn't ever have to meet a cap to
be afraid of it's odor.
Rats,
hate cat odor.
And so you can take rats in it like a
box and blow a fan over a cat so that
the odor wafts into the box and let's
like the rats are all like this because
God only knows what a cat smells like to
Iraq,
but it ain't good.
Whatever it is.
So the rats like this,
then he sniffing and he's looking around
and if nothing happens then he starts to
relax a little bit,
but not that much.
He still crouched down and he's still at
the attended of rat.
And then he starts to look around a bit
and then he starts to loosen up and then
maybe he starts to move.
And his theory is possibly it's safe
enough here.
So Iraq,
that's careful,
can move and nothing painful or damaging
will happen.
And then he starts to move and nothing
happens.
And then he spends a bunch of times
sniffing around every corner of the
cage.
And you know,
sooner or later he thinks
rats aren't going to die here now.
And then he's sort of a relaxed rat.
And then the behavior says,
you are now a normal rat.
We can teach you to be afraid.
It's like you don't have to teach me to
be afraid.
I know how to be afraid.
I have to learn how not to be afraid.
Now that's a good way of thinking about
your brain.
So you could think about the underlying
motivational and emotional systems in
your brain as default on systems.
They're like a nuclear reactor,
like the core of a nuclear reactor.
You're ready,
man.
Except when other parts of your brain
you're telling you just to keep it calm.
So,
but you don't need to learn to be afraid
any more than you need to learn to be
hungry.
You need to learn how to be calm and
secure.
And that's really worth thinking about
because you got to ask yourself,
for example,
why are you calm and secure in this
class?
What are the preconditions for you not
being afraid here?
So we'll think about it.
Why are you not afraid?
Well,
the floor is solid.
That's a good one.
The roof is probably not going to
collapse.
Why?
Well,
it's actually because you could rely on
the structural engineers who built the
building.
That's kind of interesting.
Why?
You know,
in the Soviet Union they used to make
cinder block buildings out of old
radioactive waste.
And then of course they put way too much
sand in them so that if the earth went
like this once,
it'd be like collapse.
And so the typical Soviet couldn't be
reasonably fearless in this room because
the walls were radioactive and if the
earth moved a little bit to this whole
thing would collapse.
And so part of the reason that you can
sit in here without fear is because the
system that regulates our construction
enterprise is actually not very corrupt.
So that's pretty cool.
So you know,
also we can think about that.
That means that one of the preconditions
for your relative fearlessness is your
implicit belief that the builders who
built this building can be trusted.
And that's really unlikely.
You know,
if you look around the world,
how many countries are there that aren't
corrupt?
I mean,
you know,
the West is corrupt too.
There's no doubt about it.
But compared to our really corrupt
place,
you know,
we don't even register as corrupt.
So what else?
Well,
look at the people around you.
You know,
you guys look a lot the same.
All things considered,
you know,
none of you or have painted your face in
rainbow colors and you know,
you're not decorated with ostrich
feathers and you're not wearing some
outlandish victorian costume and none of
you are stark naked.
And most of you aren't foaming at the
mouth than you know,
like fundamentally you're in a uniform
and there's some variation of the
uniform allowed.
But not much.
How many of you are wearing jeans?
Right?
It's like 50% of you.
Why are you wearing jeans?
It's so other primates think you're
insane.
That's why I'm telling you it's a big
part of it.
It's,
it's acceptable.
And so most of you are wearing clean
jeans,
I presume,
or they're cleaned enough anyways so
that if they're not clean,
it's not detectable,
which is another sign that you're not
completely insane.
Right?
And so you're manifesting markers like
mad that you're basically a normal
primate and that you live in accordance
with a set of well understood implicit
rules.
And that for the purposes of this set of
interactions,
you're not going to violate them.
So everybody can come in here like the
terrified primates.
They are the first class and they can
look around.
They see the desks are all in order.
So that means order prevails here.
The desks all facing this way.
So it's a standard lecture theater.
You know what's going to happen here.
People walk in,
they all sit properly in their tables,
most of them don't talk.
There's another rule.
How many of you are sitting in the same
chair that you sat in last week,
right?
And you know pretty soon you're going to
figure out which chairs years.
And then if someone comes in here and
sits in your chair,
you're going to think that person's in
my chair.
And you know the reason for that is is
you're trying to stabilize the
environment.
You've learned that that chair is safe
and so are the people around you.
And so now you feel kind of comfortable
in that chair.
You sort of think it's your chair.
And so we do everything we can to
structure the environment so that
signals that you're safe are radiating
at you like mad.
And that way you can be calm enough
despite the fact that you're a crazy
chimpanzee.
You can be calm enough to sit here and
not be distracted by fundamental
motivational systems that are out of
control and maybe listen and attend.
And like you just think about how much
work.
Just think about it,
how much work went into building this
room for you to sit in?
You know,
it's like they're being universities for
about a thousand years.
So there's a thousand year conceptual
history of the university.
That's one of the preconditions.
And then we had to figure out how to
make all this stuff and then people
actually had to put it together and then
you all had to be socialized for like 19
years so that you could sit here
relatively quietly while you're
listening to a lecture.
And you know,
we had to build the idea of the
university into our culture and you
know,
somebody's got to keep the lights on and
look at this technology that works.
It's like there are people out there
just slaving themselves to death to make
sure that this little box that you're
sitting in is sufficiently predictable
so that you don't have to be terrified.
It's like good for them,
you know?
And it's all happening so invisibly
that,
you know,
you're probably irritated because your
Internet connection doesn't work that
well or something like that,
you know?
So,
so it's really,
really useful to know that it's a,
the idea that your normal state is calm
and well regulated is highly debatable.
It's highly debatable.
I would say there was very limited pre
conditions under which you are going to
feel safe.
And then I would also say you're highly
motivated to maintain those conditions
and you're also highly motivated not to
go somewhere where those conditions
don't apply.
Right?
You're just not going to do it because
that's a different kind of place.
And I would say that place is chaos.
The place where the rules do not apply,
that's chaos.
And it's a real place that's unexplored
territory and peep you have,
you're hardwired at an instinctual level
to deal with unexpected exposure to
unexplored territory.
And you do that by going like this.
It's a startle and fear.
You're frozen.
And the reason for that is you're a prey
animal and you have sub circuits in you
that are millions of years old that are
there to protect you from becoming prey.
And that could be prey of other people,
that's for sure.
But it could be prey of anything that
would like to meet you.
You know,
and part of the reason you might
understand is that it's not,
there aren't that many large predators
around anymore.
You know,
what's part of the human despoil nation
of the planet is that mostly people
don't like having their children eaten
by tigers,
you know?
So,
and it's,
it's not because there's something wrong
with us,
it's because that's actually a rather
unpleasant experience.
And so if you could have a tiger around
or not have one,
you might well choose not to have one,
especially if you have some,
you know,
certain amount of love for your children
who,
although lovable also happened to be
delicious.
Right?
So,
well,
okay,
so it's a proposition I want to
undermine because I want to start with
the presupposition that fundamentally as
a biological creature,
you're like a wild animal and you're
like,
uh,
a prey animal,
things might happen to you and you're
ready for them.
And then what we do with societies,
we construct up an edifice that has
multilevel,
some of it's actually instantiated,
right?
And the rest of it is cultural and
ritual and behavioral so that you don't
have to be a prey animal.
You can be relatively calm and assured
that nothing terrible is going to happen
to you in the next 10 seconds and that's
worth fighting for.
So,
alright,
that's probably good enough.
So now we've got,
we've got some basic presuppositions
lead down,
you know,
and so let me just review them briefly.
One minute.
Stability is not your normal state.
It's an abnormal state and it's very,
very difficult to maintain.
Okay.
You maintain it at least in large part
as a consequence of being inculturated.
And to be enculturated means to adopt a
value system that works for you,
but that also works for everyone else.
It has to fulfill those criteria.
Furthermore should be the kind of value
system that allows you to move up
dominance hierarchies if you can manage
it.
A lot of constraints on your value
system.
If your value system is producing the
kind of behaviors that fulfill those
criteria,
you don't have to be terrified.
Now,
it's not just terror.
Cause I've also learned that a lot of
what culture is controlling is
discussed.
Now it's actually not in the book
because I just learned that.
So,
and I want to talk more about,
I want to talk to you more about disgust
because we've learned for example,
that people who are orderly
temperamentally,
which is an element of
conscientiousness,
are very sensitive to discussed.
And I think part of the issue is that it
isn't only that things can eat us,
it's the things can infect us.
And so we're just as prone a Priori to
repel anything that's disgusting as we
are prepared a priority to keep at bay.
Anything that's frightening.
Um,
one of the things I learned,
which was terrifying to me,
I read Hitler's table talk,
which was a collection of his
spontaneous dinner speeches that were
taken down by a secretary.
It's a very interesting book.
But one of the things I realized once we
kind of made the disgust orderliness
connection in my lab about two years
ago,
after looking for the biological basis
of conscientiousness forever,
Hitler basically used a bodily metaphor
to under pin his entire political
philosophy.
So for Hitler who was hyper orderly
bordering on obsession,
all he bathed four times a day for
example,
and he was a vegetarian,
which actually is relevant,
um,
because he didn't want animals to be
hurt,
you know,
he was sensitive to discussed and that
was part of what underlying is
vegetarianism.
Um,
he construed the area in race as a body.
Like that was his metaphor.
It's a body,
it's a pure body,
has pure blood.
So there's purity ideas that,
that,
you know,
made part of what he was saying
motivationally significant.
And it was under assault from parasites
and the parasites were,
well for him it was anyone who wasn't
part of that body.
So it was discussed,
gone mad.
It was really was,
you know,
and so that forced me to modify my
theories,
the theories I'm going to present to you
because for me a lot of what society did
was control anxiety,
you know,
in hunger and a lot of other things
obviously.
But I didn't realize to what degree
society also controlled,
discussed and how powerful disgust is as
a political motivator.
So there was a paper published in Kloss
one about three months ago,
five months ago,
maybe more than that now.
It showed that the correlation between
totalitarian beliefs in any given
geographical locale and the prevalence
of infectious disease was about 0.7
and that was true not only across
countries but within countries.
If you divided the places up by how
there were to be infectious diseases in
the relevant states,
0.7
so prejudice,
xenophobia,
fear of foreigners,
all of that huge chunk of that is
discussed.
Sensitivity Gone Mad.
So anyway,
so we're going to talk about that too as
a part of a control mechanism.
Yup.
What's that?
Applause.
One P l o s one one.
It's a public journal.
You can find it.
Look up infectious disease.
And a totalitarianism.
Here's a lot of work done on that.
Now.