Okay,
I want to talk to you a little bit about
theories of truth and there's a reason
for that and the reason is that I want
to make a distinction between two kinds
of knowledge and before I do that,
I want to talk about the multiple ways
that you can determine whether or not
something is true and for whether
something is factual.
It's much more difficult task than you
might think because it's easy to think
that there's only one way of defining
true,
but that's not the case as far as I can
tell.
So the first thing I'm going to do is
talk to you about how things might be
true from a Darwinian perspective.
And if you think you can knock any holes
in this argument,
go right ahead.
Because I'd been hacking away at it for
awhile and I haven't been able to.
So you know,
Darwin had had this theory back in the
late 18 hundreds,
which you're nobody I would all aware
of.
And it was basically predicated on two
fundamental axioms.
And the first axiom was that there's
natural variability in a population and
that was later discovered to be
associated with genetic variability and
that that genetic variability could
transform.
That's mutations do that.
And that was in some sense,
a later addition to Darwin's theory.
And then the natural environment select
the most,
the organism that's most suitable to the
current environment,
all things considered so that it can
propagate right?
And then whatever propagates moves to
the next generation and the same process
occurs again.
Okay?
Now there's a variety of complications
about that theory that I'm going to lay
out a little bit.
Um,
when the victorians first got ahold of
this theory that kind of thought that it
meant that there was a natural
hierarchy,
right?
That as evolution progressed,
it progressed and that higher organisms
followed in the trail of lower
organisms.
And so in some sense,
even though it wasn't a natural or
necessary presumption for those who
adopted Darwinian theory,
the idea of a hierarchy of value in some
sense was still part of Darwinian
theory.
So we could say,
well,
human beings are,
you know,
evolution has led to over.
It's billions of years to us and we're
far more complicated than simple
creatures.
So it seems like there's a process at
least of increasing complexification
going on and maybe that has something to
do with increased value.
We're more fit now.
Modern,
dark,
modern evolutionary biologists take
issue with this because they don't
really think that there is any
directionality in evolution.
And after all,
there are still plenty of one celled
organisms around it.
Fact,
there are more one celled organisms in
your body than there are your own cells
by a huge margin.
So,
so the idea that there's a necessary
direction in evolution,
rain going from simple to more complex
is not formally true except that
obviously there are much more complex
organisms then there were around a
couple of billion years ago.
And so there does seem to be some
directionality,
um,
in some cases.
And it's not exactly obvious why that is
so.
So the reason I'm telling you that is
because it's not self evident that
creatures as they evolve,
become more fit,
so to speak.
And so what evolutionary themed seems to
be about evolutionary theory seems to be
about at a deeper level is something
like a dance between the environment and
the organism.
So the Oregon in the environment keeps
transforming and it does that
unpredictably,
I wouldn't say randomly,
but it does it unpredictably or
unpredictable,
unpredictable built,
does it unpredictably to an
unpredictable degree because some things
that are true today are going to be true
tomorrow,
but other things aren't and you don't
know which ones,
which one of those are going to shift.
Now,
I think if you want to get a practical
idea of how the environment moves
around,
one of the best ways to do that is to
try to predict the stock market because
it's pretty easy to predict the stock
market based on past performance.
But it's very,
very difficult to predict the stock
market by deriving formulas that
predicted past performance to predict
the future.
In fact,
there's no evidence that you can do it.
And so most money managers,
for example,
do worse than chance at picking stocks.
So and so,
you know,
I've thought for a long time about why
anybody would ever invest their money
with a money manager in the stock market
and the best answer I've come up with is
that people don't want to take
responsibility for making mistakes with
their money and so they have a lot of
money and it makes them nervous and so
they don't,
they,
they don't know anything about investing
and maybe you can't,
but anyways,
they don't know anything about investing
in.
So they parsed the money off to a money
manager who's an expert.
And then if they lose their money,
they can say to themselves,
well at least I had an expert looking
after it.
But if you look into it deeply,
you find that there's
the bulk of preponderance of the
evidence suggests that you cannot get
enough information to accurately predict
what the stock market is going to do at
all.
And you can kind of see that that's
true.
Because if you could get a consistent
edge of say one 10th of one percent,
which sounds like nothing.
Oh,
you did.
They I'll have to do is repeat your bets
over and over and soon you'd have all
the money in the world because of
compounding,
so and the stock market,
a good model of the environment because
it is in fact a model of the
environment.
It's not a model of the entire
environment obviously,
but all sorts of things affect stock
market prices,
right?
Psychological factors and biological
factors in whether and political events
and so forth.
So as far as models of the environment
go,
it's pretty good one and you can't stay.
You can't keep up with it fundamentally.
So.
So you can think of the environment that
way.
It's this thing that's dancing around
and some elements of it are more stable
than than others.
So for example,
the sun appears to be pretty stable at
least on our timeframe.
So that's a good thing,
but lots of things can't be relied on
from one moment to another and you don't
know what direction it's going to turn.
So the way that life deals with that is
by producing a plethora of variance and
basically letting anything that doesn't
work die.
So evolution requires an awful lot of
death,
you know,
and there's ideas that what we've done
to some degree is we've internalized the
evolutionary process because we can
invent fictional representatives of
ourselves,
right?
Which would be our potential future
selves and we could run simulations of
the environment and kill off all those
potential future selves that don't look
like they would actually survive.
And that's really what we think about as
thinking.
Okay.
So all right,
so then the next thing you might ask
yourself about,
given that is we're going to shift basis
here a little bit,
is what,
how would you define reality if you had
to come up with a definition of what
constituted real,
how would you go about doing it?
And I would say the way the West does
this,
it's,
there's a schizophrenia element to it,
a split element.
There was an incoherence in it and I
haven't heard anyone else make this
argument.
So if you think,
if you can figure out some reason why
it's stupid,
then let me know.
But so think about it this way,
like our basic presumptions about the
world are materialistic right now and I
would say that those materialistic
assumptions were basically laid down at
the beginning of the scientific endeavor
and so that would be about the time of
Bacon and descartes and so because they
sort of laid the foundations for modern
science and there's some,
there's some rules about what things are
in reality and the rules or something
like,
well,
things are made out of littler things
and then if you go all the way down to
the level where the littlest thing
possible is,
well that's where you find the
fundamental constituent elements of
reality.
And so it's,
it's,
it's an matter is detectable by the
senses and it's Inter subjectively
detectable.
So you can,
you can,
you can detect something with your
senses fundamentally or with the
extension of your senses.
You can describe how you went about
detecting it.
Other people can duplicate that and then
they can report what they detect and if
the reports are similar,
then we assume that that thing is real.
So in some sense it's what our senses
already do,
right?
Because our census triangulate in a
sense.
So how do you figure out if something's
real well,
if you can see it,
you know that's pretty good,
but it's better if you can see it and
hear it and it's better yet if you could
see it and hear it and touch it and
maybe it's better if you could see it
and hear it and touch it and taste it
and so forth.
And you know,
we've evolved these sensory systems that
are quite different from a qualitative
perspective and if they all report the
same thing,
then we believe we have a pretty
reasonable chance of actually believing
that that thing is there.
And then with science we've actually
extended that capacity because we don't
just use the senses of one person.
We use our senses in a rigorous and
collective manner.
And that reports to us the nature of
what we've come to call the objective
world.
And then we say,
well,
accurate descriptions of the objective
world are true.
It's like,
you know,
that's a good theory and you can also
certainly see.
You can certainly see it's objective
utility.
Sorry,
I shouldn't say that.
It's pragmatic utility because when you
play by the rules of science,
it appears that your power expands,
right?
So that's another reason why we think
it's true.
You run through these routines and then
all of a sudden you could do things you
couldn't do before and that's,
that's a different criteria of truth,
right?
That's more like a criteria of
usefulness and a practical usefulness
because you would think to that,
and this is why you thought that science
was actually embedded inside a narrative
in a deeper narrative.
You know,
we wouldn't be doing science if we
didn't think it was useful for
something.
Right?
And then you might think,
well useful for what?
And then,
well,
what would you say?
Maybe you suffer less because of
science.
Maybe live longer because of science.
Maybe you find life more interesting.
You could do a more diverse range of
things.
Whatever we have made the decision that
the utility of science justifies the
endeavor,
but that's a different criteria,
right?
That you utility of something and you
could debate the utility of science from
a Darwinian perspective because you
could easily say,
well,
here's an example.
There was a book written awhile ago by
an ex KGB officer and he was talking
about biological warfare labs in the
Soviet Union and he claimed to have work
in a biological warfare lab where the
goal was to cross Ebola was smallpox.
Now Ebola,
which you all know about,
isn't very contagious.
You have to really be in contact with
someone who has ebola to catch it.
But smallpox,
that's contagious.
So if you get the two things working
together,
you would have a disease that's
basically 100 percent fatal and it would
be,
you could distribute it in aerosol
forum,
which is sort of the dream of any
biological weapons maker now.
They never really managed it,
but you know,
it's kind of an interesting idea.
Right?
And it had,
it turned out and there were no people
left and we'd have to say that our
notion about the utility of science
turned out to be colossally wrong from a
Darwinian perspective.
And you know,
you might say the same thing about
hydrogen bonds,
for example,
or maybe you might say the same thing
about computers because,
you know,
it seems to me quite unlikely that human
beings in their present form are going
to be around 200 years in the future,
you know,
with the rate of the growth of computer
intelligence,
the probability that will become
something biological and mechanical
together seems to me to be virtually
certain we're certainly headed in that
direction.
So anyways,
the question
ideas.
No,
no,
that's,
that's a good question.
The question was,
do you ever think,
do you think that people's interest in
science can not be not pragmatically
oriented?
I actually don't think so because I
don't think that you would be interested
in science if it wasn't pragmatically
useful.
You see,
and that's,
that's exactly the point that I want to
pursue in this lecture today.
It's like we are interested in things
generally as a consequence of their
perceived utility,
you know,
and now the ends,
the framework within which you
determined utility is quite malleable.
So for example,
if you're suicidal,
you might regard it how sharp knife is
as the primary object of interest,
but generally speaking,
you know,
we would assume that especially if
you're a Darwinian thinker,
that your primary interests or something
like survival and reproduction and you
know,
I don't think that's an unreasonable
assumption.
I'm the terms are quite elastic,
so you can throw a lot of motivations in
them without,
you know,
without having to think that rigorously
about it.
But as a,
as a heuristic framework,
it's not bad.
So,
and so part of the reason that you
believe that science was embedded in a
dream,
which was the l chemical dream,
fundamentally it was because he believed
that the people who developed the
symbolic precursors to science.
And so those would be the alchemists.
Newton wasn't outcome by the way.
Um,
we're looking for something
approximating the philosopher's stone,
which was a material object which would
grant it's bearers,
eternal life and good health and wealth.
And so the,
the all chemists were the first people
in some sense to posit that if you
systematically investigated the
transformations of the material world,
which was regarded more or less as
damned by the Catholic Church,
that you could extract out information
that would be of substantial benefit to
the things I just described,
health,
wealth and longevity.
And so you might say,
well why are we pursuing science?
Like why are we motivated to do it?
Why would you spend 10,000
hours looking through a microscope?
It's a very weird thing to do.
And the,
the union ideas,
well,
if you go right down to the base of the,
of the,
of the hierarchy of motivation,
you're doing it to make the world a
better place in some manner that's
important to you.
So you can't.
Science has to be nested inside a
motivational structure or no one would
do it.
Now you know,
you can think about that,
what you want,
but,
but it's not an argument that you can
easily dismissed because you have to
account for why people are interested in
science.
You know?
And if you say,
well,
it's because they want to build a
career,
that's fine because it just nests inside
the same argument anyways.
Okay,
so now.
So we kinda have a definition of reality
from a materialist perspective.
Now there's a few problems with that,
right?
One of the problems is is that when you
get down to the fundamental elements of
matter,
they turn out not to be very much like
matter at all.
They turn out to be these weird quantum
processes and entities that appear to be
tangled up with consciousness in some
way that no one can understand and
certainly display all sorts of
properties that aren't evident at the
macro level.
So you know the formal job of
reductionism,
which is you are one element of
reductionism because there's many
elements of reductionism is that you
explain the complex by the simple and
you know,
for a lone time as we went deeper into
the microstructure of things,
it did appear in some sense to be
getting simpler.
But then when we went down to the
quantum level,
it all of a sudden,
God incredibly weird and no one really
knows what to do about that.
Now,
I'm not gonna,
I'm not gonna introduce quantum thinking
into this discussion because you know
every Weirdo with a crockpot theory
immediately immediately does that and
it's a very dangerous thing to do.
I'm just pointing out that we didn't
expect for the nature of reality to
qualitatively transform as we
investigated the microstructure.
But that's what happened.
So all of that aside,
the idea that truth,
that there are facts about material
reality and that those facts are true is
a very,
very powerful idea.
However,
we don't pursue it because the rationale
for pursuing that truth is based on
truths that are different from the
truths that the process itself reveals.
So you know,
and I think you know,
you,
you might well agree,
hypothetically,
that perhaps investigating how to
combine ebola with smallpox is not
really a good idea from a sign perfect
idea from a scientific perspective.
But there,
it seems not unreasonable to assume that
there's a broader perspective from which
that idea probably isn't for the best,
you know,
now a pure scientists,
there isn't such a thing,
but if there was,
might say it doesn't matter because all
facts are equal because facts don't have
value,
you know,
they're,
they're not valence,
so all facts are equal.
But of course you can't live like all
facts are equal because there's a
trillion facts and if you don't have
some mechanism to zero you in on a
subset of relevant facts,
it's like you're immobilized,
you know,
you're just flooded by inflammation.
I think something like that probably
happens to people in the initial stages
of schizophrenia,
so they can't distinguish.
Everything becomes relevant.
That's a bad situation.
So,
so,
you know,
you're stuck with a subset of facts
anyways and there are reasons that you
choose the subset of facts that you
choose and those reasons aren't grounded
in a materialist philosophy and they
can't be,
at least not in any simple way.
Okay.
So maybe,
you know,
hopefully that's a coherent argument.
Now the next part of it is kind of
something interesting that happened in
the late 18 hundreds,
so in the late 18 hundreds,
there were a group of philosophers on
the east coast of the United States,
uh,
that called themselves pragmatists and
William James was one of those people
and William James is of course,
regarded as one of the founders of
modern psychology,
even though he was a,
he wouldn't be allowed on a faculty of
psychology today because he,
like,
he was like,
he was like the first Hippie,
you know,
in some sense because he liked to
experiment with things like a laughing
gas,
nitrous oxide,
nitric oxide,
you know,
and,
uh,
it's actually quite an intense
hallucinogen at the appropriate doses.
And he wrote like sixties acid freak
poetry back in 1880 when he was on
nitrous oxide.
And,
and you know,
he was very curious about phenomena,
like religious experience and so forth.
So he was very philosophically minded,
psychologist and,
and had some very.
Well,
he was brave,
I would say,
you know,
which sometimes being weird and being
braver.
The same thing.
He was also unbelievably intelligent and
he had a group of people around them and
including a guy named Charles purse,
who's one of the on one of the West's
greatest,
relatively unknown philosophers.
Anyways,
they set up a new field of philosophy
which is classically regarded as the
only American philosophy.
And that philosophy was pragmatism.
You know,
and when you call someone pragmatic,
you sort of mean well,
they're willing to do what works,
you know,
they're concerned with what works.
And that's kind of pragmatism in a
nutshell in some sense,
except it's a lot more sophisticated.
The pragmatist would say,
look,
you've got a problem and the problem is
you don't know everything and what that
means in some senses that all of your
knowledge about anything is limited even
about the things that you think you know
about.
It's limited.
And so you can never be sure.
You can never be certain that what
you're dealing with is what you think
you're dealing with or that when you
deal with it,
what you expect to happen will happen.
And so,
you know,
you might think,
well,
I understand my,
um,
you know,
I understand this can of coke
sufficiently,
uh,
I can drink it and so on.
And so my knowledge is as close to
absolute as it needs to be,
but you know,
this has aspartame in it and everybody
thinks aspartame is dangerous,
but it's probably not,
but probably it's not,
you know,
and so who knows,
if I drink 100 of these things,
that might be the end of me.
And wouldn't that be stupid?
So the point is,
is that because you're surrounded by a
cloud of ignorance that you cannot get
rid of none of your judgments about what
constitutes truth can be final.
And so one of the things that the
pragmatists we're trying to figure out
as well,
given that,
how can you even act because you can't
compute well.
And this came up again in the 19 sixties
and is really bothered people since then
in the guise of the frame problem is you
cannot compute all the consequences of
your actions.
So how can you act?
How can you feel that you have enough
knowledge to act so well?
It's a very difficult problem.
It's unbelievably difficult problem.
It's actually one of the problems that
has made developing intelligent machines
much more difficult than anyone thought
it would be because it turns out that
not only are there an infinite number of
things that could happen as a
consequence of a given action.
There's also a virtually infinite number
of ways to look at a situation to
perceive it.
We look at a situation and there it is
and so we just think it's given,
but it turns out that that's just
seriously wrong and the only reason that
when we look at the world that it's
given is because our psyche,
our consciousness,
which we still think of as sort of a
soul,
is actually something that is grounded
deeply in the biological processes of
our body and that all of those
biological processes that were created
over evolutionary time structure our
perceptions before we even know it and
just deliver this world to us.
So it looks obvious,
but you know,
it took a while.
We've been evolving for like 3 billion
years or something like that,
so it took a lot of tinkering around to
get this perceptual system to do what it
does,
so okay,
so they're very interested in and how
you came up with ideas of truth and what
they.
What they settled on.
Roughly speaking is something like
whenever you can,
whenever you conduct an action,
you set up the criteria for determining
whether what you're doing is is
reasonable or factual based on outcome
that you want to attain and so for the
pragmatists was more like things were
true enough and so if my goal in
interacting with his coke can is to have
a drink and when I do what I am going to
do and I get a drink,
then not sufficiently true and I can go
onto the next thing.
So,
but it's still tenuous because it leaves
open other questions like should I be
drinking this or something else or you
know,
whatever.
It leaves open all sorts of questions,
but it doesn't matter as far as the
pragmatists are concerned.
Now,
when Darwin
published his theory,
the pragmatists God on it right away,
they were really interested in Darwinian
theory because they regarded it as a
version of pragmatism,
which is quite cool,
and they did this within,
I think within five years of its
publication.
You know what caused credit,
quite disturbed people were sort of
ready for the theory,
but the pragmatists,
we're really all over it because they
thought of the mechanism that Darwin
described to account for evolution as a
pragmatic mechanism.
Now that's an interesting idea.
So think about it this way.
So how much do you need to know?
Well,
from a Darwinian perspective,
there's an answer to that.
You need to know enough so that you can
last long enough to pass your genes to
the next generation.
That's it.
And the Darwinians would also say,
well,
obviously you're knowledge is faulting
incomplete because you know your to
transmit your genetic material to the
next generation is somewhat limited.
You know,
you have limited number of partners,
plus you die,
and the fact that you die indicates that
you as a solution to the problem of,
um,
of maintaining your own life.
And reproducing,
you're like a partial solution,
you're a good enough solution you'll do
for the 30 years or the 35 years or the
40 years that you're likely to be active
in,
uh,
you know,
in a functionally reproductive sets.
So you're a good enough answer,
but you know,
the Darwinian send,
the pragmatists also said something else
or implied something else which is your
good enough.
And also not only is that as good as it
gets,
it's also as good as it can get.
So they put some really stringent
restrictions on what would,
what you would regard as a sufficient
solution to a given problem.
And the reason for that was that while
that your knowledge is limited and that
things transform unexpectedly,
and so the best thing you could do is
run along and try to keep up.
And you'll never really do much better
than that in some sense because things
are unpredictable and because they
change in an unpredictable way.
So now the final part of the argument is
this.
So then what are we to regard as truth?
Now leave the materialist claims aside.
I'm perfectly willing to say,
and I think it would be ridiculous not
to that that's a form of truth that at
least is very useful,
so fine.
It's a tool and maybe more than that,
it may.
Maybe it is saying something about the
absolute nature of reality.
I don't care about that.
At least it's a useful tool for us.
It's made us more powerful,
but then we have this other problem
which is,
well,
what about the nature of the system that
it's embedded in like how do we
determine its utility or how do we
determine the utility of anything or how
do we determine how to act or how do we
determine what to value and those
questions can be asked using this
answer,
using the same methodology that science
uses to answer his questions.
Now the consequence of that is what
needs you described at the end of the 19
hundreds as the death of God,
right?
There's A.
There's a conflict,
a serious conflict between the claims of
religion,
which as far as I'm concerned,
have to do with value and moral morality
and the claims of science which are
which have to do with material reality.
All right,
so now
the tricky part comes in realizing that
the selection mechanisms that determined
what happens to you in relationship to
the next generation say are selecting
you on the of your action and your
behavior.
I would say they're selecting you on the
basis of your values,
so because you know if you're a.
If you're an idiot saying you go
charging after a lion and the lion eats
you,
then the the nature of reality,
so to speak,
is rendered a judgment on the value
structure that sent you down that
particular path.
Right,
and so you're being selected by natural
forces as a consequence of your behavior
now and then we can extend that
argument,
especially in the human case or in the
case of any organism that's also subject
to sexual selection and human beings are
tremendously subject to sexual
selection.
Now,
Darwin was a great believer in sexual
selection.
You know,
it was,
he thought it was at least as important
as the selection of the organism by the
natural environment,
whatever that is.
But you know,
biologists really had a hard time with
that and they kind of ignored sexual
selection for 100 years,
which is quite a quite interesting.
I think it was partly because sexual
selection implies,
especially when you're dealing with
organisms that are sort of conscious,
like human beings,
that choice itself is a determinant of
evolutionary processes.
But,
and you know,
the district deterministic materialists
didn't really like that and they
couldn't really come up with an argument
against it,
but they sort of shelved the whole topic
for a very long period of time.
But one of the things we know for
example about human beings is that
females are very sexually selective
female humans as opposed to say to
female chimps which aren't.
And so part of the consequence of that
is that you have twice as many female
ancestors as you do mail ancestors.
Now there'll be half of you are going to
have a hell of a time figuring out how
that's possible.
But it is possible.
But it really means is that something
like the average male who's in your
ancestry had two children,
if he had any,
whereas the average woman had one.
And that'll do the trick right there.
Right now.
I'm not saying those were the exact
proportions,
but those are the average proportions
across huge spans of time now.
So,
so anyways,
so part of what's occurred to select
human beings for the way they are is the
choices that each gender has made with
regards to action and belief,
but in many ways more specifically
female choices.
So it's kind of an interesting.
The next time you were irritated at your
boyfriend,
let's say,
then you can just remember that you
know,
untold millions of women have chosen men
so that they're exactly like he is.
And so,
you know,
you can't really blame them for that.
So all right,
so,
but,
but here,
here's the thing that's tricky from a
scientific perspective,
a,
if it is your behavior and your value
structures,
if your value structures determine what
you're interested in,
how you behave and selection pressure
occurs as a consequence of your actions,
then doesn't it mean that the structure
of the value systems that your behavior
have to be regarded as true or real in
some scientific sense because the Darwin
is basically say,
look,
the best solution is the solution that
you embodied.
There is no higher solution than that
and there you are embodying a solution.
So in what way?
I don't understand in what way that
can't be regarded as real,
you know,
because people think of things like
value structures as EPA,
phenomenal.
You know,
they're not real like,
like material is real,
but I don't get that.
I don't see how that works with
Darwinian thinking because you're
interacting with each other all the time
and you're doing that on the basis of
your capacity for action and the value
systems that drive that.
And obviously those have some effect on
whether or not you're selected by women.
Say or by men for that matter,
but also by the natural world,
so it looks like it looks to me at least
you can make a case that the deep value
structures that drive us,
that are deep,
deep parts of our psyche and I'll,
I'll try to also demonstrate to you that
those exist beyond question.
I already think that question is
answered,
but you know,
there's no blank slate theorists left,
right?
Everybody knows that you come into the
world with an a priori structure.
It's like that a prior restructure was
selected.
So in what way is it not true?
I could say,
well,
it's as true as it gets.
Well,
it's not true like a materialist idea,
but that's okay.
You don't have to have.
First of all,
I don't think the materialist ideas of
truth are the most fundamental ideas
because as I said,
in order for that truth to be relevant,
it has to be grounded in the value
system.
And so there's a value system outside of
science that science serves.
Otherwise we'd be completely.
It would be insane for us to pursue it,
you know,
if we knew that science was going to
lead to the demise of everyone on earth,
which it could,
you wouldn't be motivated to pursue it
if you knew that science was just going
to increase your suffering.
If you're a scientist.
It's like,
why don't you stop doing it if you had
any sense.
So,
so then I would say,
well,
we pursue materialists truths for
reasons that are known.
Materialist and those reasons are just
as real as the materialist truth,
but there are different kinds of.
True.
They're a seriously different kinds of
truth
changes over time.
Good question.
You know,
I would say I would say they change at
least to some degree,
you know,
because you know,
I don't know what values you share with
the primate who was your ancestor and
the ancestor of chimpanzees.
But I would say there's a,
there's no shortage of similarities.
You know,
I mean,
first of all,
we can understand chimps,
you know,
more or less.
We can understand dogs,
we can understand cats.
My daughter had lizards and the more
social lizards there are social lizards
by the way,
you can kind of understand the social
lizard,
you know,
so we certainly understand all mammals.
Um,
and then there are other animals that
are,
that we have deviated from at far
greater spans of time.
I liked the example of crustaceans
because I happen to know a little bit
about lobsters for reasons that were in
my reading,
took me in a random direction,
but like lobsters,
lobsters organized themselves into
dominance hierarchies and we understand
dominance hierarchies and even more
strangely,
the biochemical systems that the
lobsters use to track their dominance
hierarchies and to determine how
confident they should be or how
submissive are serotonergic and so are
the systems we use to track dominance
hierarchies.
And the similarity is so great that you
can actually use antidepressants on
lobsters.
So if you inject the lobster with
Serotonin,
I don't know the precise procedure,
but generally if a lobster has lost a
fight and he liked zooms into his little
lobster place and like pouts for at
least 20 minutes,
he won't fight with anyone else during
that period of time.
And when he comes out,
he's like a smaller lobster,
you know,
because he sort of determines how big to
be on the basis of the ratio of
victories.
Two defeats and the mechanism that
adjusts his posture,
the successful lobster gets,
takes up more and more space because he
says,
I'm,
I'm as big as I think I am.
And that's based on my success in battle
that Sarah to energetically mediated as
well.
You know.
And so when you see a human being,
it's like this,
you know,
taking up as little space as possible.
You can think,
well there's a defeated lobster because
it's exactly the same mechanisms and
they're really fundamental in human
beings and you can't really change them.
You know,
like the way your brain computes your
dominance effects,
how much positive emotion you have and
how much negative emotion.
And if you're way the hell down in the
dominance hierarchy or you feel that
way,
then you're going to experience way more
negative emotion because your nervous
system has calculated that the
environment on average is very dangerous
to you,
[inaudible] you're barely clinging to
the edge of reality and you're going to
experience very little positive emotion
because well,
things don't look that good for you.
And so,
you know,
those aren't really systems you can
control their,
their,
their like master operating systems that
sit at the base of your brain,
you know.
And so you say,
well,
do things change across time?
It's like,
yes,
but they change within constraints that
don't change much across time.
So for example,
I think there's probably as much it's
reasonable to assume that there's as
much conservation of value as there is
con as there is a retention of skeletal
structure,
you know,
and I went at least that much.
There's,
I think there's actually more,
but certainly there's at least that
much.
I went to the Smithsonian at one point,
I think it was the Smithsonian in
Washington.
And they have a,
they have a display of a mammalian
skeletons in there that's extremely
extensive.
So it's everything from little batch to
Wales and you know,
it's really interesting to walk through
that because what you see is that
everything's basically a bat,
you know,
the bats look exactly like us skeletally
except their fingers are way longer.
And you know,
there's all that's happened is that
there are transformations of size in the
basic skeletal structure.
The structure itself is virtually
identical across mammals,
you know,
and so in evolution is a conservative
process,
right?
It just doesn't go zipping off and some
completely random direction.
And so I would say also the way to think
about it is that there are levels of
stability in the evolutionary process
and some domains are extremely stable
across time and one of them happens to
be the existence of a dominance
hierarchy.
It's at least 400 million years old.
And that's old.
It's older than trees.
So if you're trying to think about
what's actually real,
you know,
you can't see a dominance hierarchy and
you can't taste it or touch it or
sensitive in any real way,
but dominance hierarchies are more real
than almost anything that you ever come
across there.
They're probably not quite as real as
rocks,
but they're,
they're real enough so that both you and
lobsters organize yourself into them and
understand them.
And so,
so yes,
there's change,
but there's,
it's changed within constraints.
And I think maybe one of the ways to
understand that it's,
it's,
it's something like the variation in
languages,
you know,
our language is the same or different.
Well,
depends on your level of analysis.
There are levels of analysis at which
the commonalities are what's most
manifest and their levels of analysis
where the differences are most manifest.
But I like to think about it as a
hierarchy and there's fundamental
elements at the base of the hierarchy
and they don't change their,
you know,
life made a bet 400 million years ago
and it was one of those bets that's just
not going to change.
The dominance hierarchy is something
that's going to feature a lot in our
conversations because it's such a stable
element of the environment that it's one
of the fund,
its existence and its nature is one of
the fundamental presumptions of our
being and so there it's extremely
important.
So for example,
one of the things that women do with men
and men do it with women as well,
but they use different criteria is men
are very competitive in a certain manner
and the women assume that the guys who
win are the better men and they just
peel them from the top and so the
dominance hierarchy and part female
selection is one of the things that
determines whether male genes have a
particular type go into the future,
but so is the structure of the dominance
hierarchy because if you're at the
bottom of it,
I mean,
good luck finding a partner.
It's very,
very unlikely unless it's random and
impulsive,
so or involuntary.
So yes.
[inaudible].
I don't know what to say about that.
Actually you don't because I think that
they both ground out in true and that
that grounds out in,
in,
in the Darwinian theory that's at the
bottom.
So because the question is,
for example,
I think is,
look,
let,
let me put it this way,
and you can see he see what you think of
this.
So here's a claim.
Our theory about the atomic substructure
of material entities is sufficiently
accurate so that we can make
thermonuclear bombs,
right?
Everybody agrees with that because
they're,
they are thermonuclear bombs.
Here's a counter proposition.
Our theory about the substructure of
reality is so flawed that we will make
thermonuclear bombs.
Now you see now.
So you think,
well yeah,
that's not a bad proposition either.
So how can both of those be true?
Well,
here's what it looks to me is like,
you know that when you parse an entity
out of its context,
you lose something of the entity.
Now this is something that really
plagues psychologist,
right?
Because psychologists,
so you know,
maybe you'll go up to someone and say,
I was angry today and the person says,
well,
why were you angry?
And then you have a little discussion
about why you're angry and you never
really worry about whether the person
understands what you mean by angry
because you assume that they've been
angry before and so have you,
so you share that,
but also you also assume that the
context of the conversation defines the
ambivalence of the word sufficiently in
that time in place so that it has an
actual meaning.
That's the context.
You know the person hypothetically
because they wouldn't be telling you
that otherwise you know other people.
You understand the language so that when
the word angry emerges that someone just
doesn't come up and go angry.
You know they,
they put it in a story and so the
meaning of the word angry is confined by
the story that's constructed around the
word and that's confined by your
relationship and the relationship is
confined by the culture that you're in.
And so there's lots of levels of
analysis that are going on
simultaneously for you to be able to
understand what the person means when
they talk about being angry.
Now a psychologist to come along and
say,
oh,
anger is a thing,
you know,
pull it out of its context and then
treat it like it's a material entity and
actually that doesn't work very well.
I mean,
there's lots of things that people
discuss in the context of multilevel
language that you can't just pull out as
entity.
Now with regards to our understanding of
the subatomic realm,
well the problem is is that we're
parsing out,
we're parsing out from a very complex
reality,
a particular form of perception.
Now it's a very powerful form of
perceptions,
the form of perception that allows us to
mess about with things at the subatomic
level,
but while we're doing that,
there's a lot of things that those
particles are associated with that we're
ignoring.
So we narrow our knowledge in some sense
by decontextualizing the phenomena,
and then we can do things like make atom
bombs.
But the question is,
is that what makes you think that the
process of decontextualization produces
an outcome?
That's true?
Now you could say pragmatically,
well,
it's true enough to make atom bombs
like,
yeah,
okay,
but it's not true enough.
Not to make them,
so it's tricky.
It's tricky.
Yeah.
Well that's the next thing.
That's the next thing I want to know
that I want to get to.
That's actually why I have this little
diagram up there,
so I'm going to do that now.
So now I'm going to offer you a
proposition and it's like a core.
I'll get to you right away.
How is it?
It's a core proposition.
We tend to think that our knowledge
structures are made out of facts and
that factor about the material world and
I would say that's not very true and
it's partly because who the hell cares
about facts?
Most of the time they just lie there and
they're not good for anything so.
But more importantly,
it can't be right.
It can't be right for a variety of
reasons.
First of all,
the scientific endeavor is only about,
let's say 500 years old formally.
Now you could stretch it back.
Maybe you can stretch it back to the
Greeks.
You know,
if you want to look at precursors,
but it's still,
who cares?
It's 2000 years there,
3000 years,
whatever.
It's like compared to 400 million years,
that's it's nothing.
It's like dust on a.
it's like dust on a cliff.
It's nothing.
Now.
We were doing perfectly well without the
theory beforehand and so to animals and
so you know what?
That you can define,
decide for yourself what that indicates,
but it does indicate that you can.
You can exist in a manner that fulfills
the dark Darwinian ricart requirements,
perfectly fine without ever formalizing
a theory about the nature of material
reality,
so fine.
Now the next thing is your nervous
system isn't built
to to view the world through a cognitive
framework that's composed of empirical
facts obviously,
because we've only been doing that for a
few hundred years.
Chimps aren't doing that and you're
mostly chimp,
you know,
I mean,
I don't know what the similarity is.
It's like 90,
99 point nine at the genetic level.
It's really,
really high.
So it's not like the dissimilarities are
unimportant,
but there's a lot of you that's chimp.
There's a lot of you that's mammal.
There's a good chunk of you that's like
a crustacean.
So you know,
obviously none of those entities are
predicating their action in the world or
their knowledge of the world on material
theories.
Okay,
so then the question might be,
well,
what are the nature of your theories of
the world?
And that's where you get into the
distinction between motivational
significance and value and material
reality.
And I would say that you're the the
cognitive structures that use,
they're not just cognitive,
it's actually your personality because
the personality is far more than it than
a cognitive structure.
Your personality is how you act.
So that's how you act out ideas,
right?
Actually how you move your body through
time and space.
It's how you perceive because you don't
perceive everything.
You perceive a very limited subset of
things and there are processes that are
associated with your personality that
determined what that subset is.
It determines how you value things.
It determines how you respond to them
emotionally.
And then it sets the boundaries for the
contents of your cognitive knowledge.
So I would think of that as a
personality.
And what's the personality up to?
Well,
it's trying to orient itself in the
world.
It's trying to figure out how to act in
the world and I would say that's our
fundamental problem.
Our fundamental problem isn't what are
things made of.
Although I'm not saying that's not a
problem,
it's a problem,
but it's not the fundamental problem.
The fundamental problem is what to do
about what things are made of.
It's like where to go now and you know,
that's an existentialist claim in some
sense.
It's like,
well,
what's the meaning of your life?
What's the purpose of your life?
You know?
And we shouldn't be using materialists
theories to address such questions,
but we do and it's cost us a lot.
So.
Yep.
Really
well that,
that's exactly what I want to talk about
next.
Is it a problem?
Okay.
So Yup.
System of values is,
it's somehow hijacked our motivational
system without being connected,
but that sounds really.
Well,
it couldn't be true.
I mean if it turns out that the
scientific endeavor dooms us,
which it might,
then you could certainly make that case.
You'd have to make it post hoc though
when you won't be able to because there
won't be anybody around.
But you know,
what is that like the idea that science
is a valuable enterprise is a,
it's a theory,
you know,
and it's,
it's 50 slash 50 and you know,
if people,
maybe not,
but it's,
there's definitely room for dispute
dispute.
I don't think we would see the massive
emergence of phenomena like the
environmental movement if there wasn't
part of the human psyche that was very
much worried about untrammeled
technological progress.
Now you know,
it's like hey,
we should also be equally worried about
not like no technological process
progress.
We're basically screwed either way.
So,
so,
but that's in some sense beside the
point.
Okay.
So the reason I got into the ideas that
I'm describing to you,
it's quite straightforward now.
It's,
it's,
I can't really use the story that I used
to use to,
to frame why I'm telling you what I'm
telling you because when I develop these
ideas and I'm been working on them for
30 years,
my primary motivation was to understand
what insanity was driving the Cold War
because.
And so I started working on these things
probably in about 1982,
although I'd been thinking about things
like that far longer than that and I
don't know what it's like for you people
as young people I know you're worried
about the environment and,
but when I was young,
younger,
young,
everyone I knew was very,
very obsessed with the idea that there
was likely going to be a thermonuclear
war and we didn't assume that it was
certain,
but we certainly assumed that it was a
high,
it was highly probable,
you know,
when things came pretty damn close.
So I'll tell you a story.
So one time,
about 10 years ago,
I went to Arizona and,
uh,
I went to see a Patriot missile site.
And the Patriot missiles were the early
intercontinental ballistic missiles.
Now a ballistic missile is an
interesting entity because,
you know,
if you think about something like a,
what do they call those cruise missiles?
Cruise missiles,
it's like a robot.
You can tell that thing where to go,
you know,
it's sort of,
it's got enough intelligence.
So if you don't want it to land there
and you've launched it,
then you can have it land somewhere
else.
But an intercontinental ballistic
missile.
It's no,
no,
it's a rifle.
You point and you pull the trigger at 20
minutes later that thing has blown up a
city and there's no calling it back and
there was no diverting it and you know.
So I went to the missile site and those
things were huge.
They were like major rockets.
The launch tube,
because they were underground would have
been much,
much broader in diameter.
Then this room,
like it was a major league thing because
it would zip up into space and land back
on the other side of the world in 20
minutes.
It's like those things are cruising
seven miles a second.
They're moving.
So when some of them had multiple
warheads,
so they'd get over to the Soviet Union,
let's say.
Then they break apart into multiple
nuclear warheads and you know,
they were,
they were nasty.
And the forest in those things,
there's still lots of them around.
Was made Hiroshima,
looked like a pop gun.
I mean,
people built,
you know,
I don't know if you know this about a
hydrogen bomb,
so a hydrogen bomb has the same
mechanisms that the son uses to produce
heat.
Okay.
Whereas if your standard at Tomic bomb,
it's,
it's low grade in terms of evolution,
in terms of energy transformation,
a hydrogen bomb is so powerful that it
uses an atom bomb as it's trigger.
So you'd like.
It's a whole new scale of,
of destructive magnitude.
And there was like at that point we'll
say 1982,
there is tens of thousands of these
things.
Twenty 5,000
on the Russian side,
maybe $50,000
on the American side.
And they're like,
everybody had it pretty itchy trigger
trigger finger,
you know,
Reagan was in power and he was in many
ways,
right about the Soviets,
you know,
they were an evil empire but,
and he scared the hell out of them.
But um,
but it was touch and go and anyway,
so we're back in this old missile base
and so roadside looking at it and
there's a nose cone for one of these
things that sort of lay in there in the,
in the desert.
And so that was kind of an eerie thing.
So it was about this high and probably
about 12 feet in diameter and it was
made out of plastic about that thick.
It was sort of variegated plastic a
little bit clearer.
That was the thing that would melt off
when the missile reentered the
atmosphere.
So it was like,
you know,
it was a,
it was a weird artifact.
You couldn't just stand beside that
thing and you know,
think neutral thoughts.
It was like,
hmm,
that's a,
that's a wicked thing.
So then we went underground and it was
very bizarre.
It was surreal because the first thing
we pass through was like this museum
front because it was a museum and it was
sort of like your grandmother's nuclear
missile site because it was staffed by
volunteers,
seniors and you know,
there was a little guest book that you
could sign.
It was sort of pine panels and it was
like,
you know,
southern Americans are pretty hospitable
so there are sort of happy to see you.
And it was like,
like I said,
it was like your grandmother's nuclear
missiles silos.
So that was bloody weird.
And then all around the outside of the,
on the walls of the museum,
there were pictures of Reagan basically
and you know,
interacting with various people,
including people from the Soviet Union.
So it was quite weird because it was a
time of war because there I was in like
1982 and then in my grandmother's
nuclear missile silo.
And then we went into the silo itself
which was quite deep underground.
And so first of all,
you go through this massive door that
looks like a safe door except the state.
The safe is on steroids.
It's like 12 feet high and this thick
and it's made out of steel and it's
painted that kind of pastel green that
everybody was really excited about 1957.
And so the whole missile site is like
that.
It's like,
Oh,
here I am in like 19,
19,
57 world destroying technology.
So I moved from the say 2005 until the
year 1982 and then I'm in 1957 and it's
like star trek down there,
you know.
So,
so,
uh,
we go into the main control room after
seeing the silo,
which is now empty.
We go into the main control room,
I think it's 35 feet underground or
something like that,
which is basically far enough under
ground.
So it would be protected from a nuclear
blast that wasn't a direct hit know dirt
has a really good shield against
explosions as it turns out.
Um,
anyway,
so we're down there and one of the
control tables is over there and it
looks like the Star Trek,
you know,
control module,
except it's 1957.
So everything switches and so forth.
And you know,
the technology is kind of rough and um,
there's another control,
there's another control desk here and
they say,
well,
would you like to go through a simulated
missile launch?
And you know,
of course that was definitely my idea of
a good time.
So,
so they showed us what their protection
laws.
And so what happened was there's like a
little place on that side and there's a
key and I believe that the people who
had the keys wore them around their
necks,
although that might not be right,
they may have been stored,
but I think they wore them around their
necks.
Makes Sense,
right?
Because that's really high security.
We're in the key around your neck.
And so the deal was if you wanted to
launch a missile,
that person a was over there with their
key and person b was over there with
therapy because you needed two people to
launch the missile and then you both put
your keys in at the same time and then
you turn them and you held them for 10
seconds and then,
and then bang,
right?
God only knows what happens next.
And so then they said,
someone said,
how close did you get?
And they said,
well,
the keys were in the law at one point.
Now they wouldn't tell us when,
but we knew when it was during the Cuban
missile crisis.
So.
And there are other times where that
happened as well.
That wasn't the only time,
but you know,
it was good enough time.
It was.
So,
uh.
Anyways,
so back when I was your age,
roughly speaking,
you know,
this,
the world was locked in this dispute and
it was no joke,
you know,
it was,
it wasn't that long since the Soviets
went into Czechoslovakia and it wasn't
that long since they went into Hungary
and it was only 40 years after the
second world war.
And it was tense.
It was tense.
And lots of people I knew,
maybe they've,
you know,
maybe it was just justification for
their own psychological nihilism,
but they had a hard time being concerned
about their futures because they really
didn't think they were going to have
any.
And so it was always a heavy Paul that
was over everyone's spirits.
And what it really didn't peak again in
about 1982 under Reagan and there was a
whole bunch of movies made at that time
about nuclear destruction,
including one called the day after,
which you may have watched or may not
have,
but more people watched that than any TV
movie ever made at that point.
And you know,
it was pretty dismal man.
It was like there's the city and Poof,
there's a nuclear bomb and everyone's
wandering around ruined.
And that was sort of the movie.
And Reagan actually said weirdly enough
that that movie actually motivated him
to enter into more negotiations with the
Soviet.
So you know,
you,
you might have thought he would have
thought that through before,
but you know,
he was an actor.
And so I guess the movie was enough to
convince him,
but,
but anyway,
so everyone was,
you know,
we were carrying this around on our
backs in some sense.
And I was obsessed by it for one reason
or another.
I had nuclear nightmares on a regular
basis and God only knows why that was.
You know,
who knows why you get obsessed with
something.
But,
you know,
I was,
I'd already always been interested in
belief systems and what they motivated
people to do.
So when I was really young,
I was 13,
we had a dentist in our town way the
hell up in northern Alberta,
and he had a tattoo on his arm,
you know,
and he was,
maybe there were two Jewish people in
our town,
may never really even occurred to me
that he was Jewish.
So it's not a lot of Jewish people in
Alberta.
But anyways,
you know,
that was Kinda,
I was kinda curious about that in a sort
of small town sort of way.
And um,
I also did a project when I was in
junior high about the Holocaust and I
got pretty interested in that,
you know,
and part of I was interested in why,
why in the world would people do such
things,
you know,
protecting their belief systems.
So let's say that's the Nazis,
but then they were committing these
atrocities that were just,
they are the worst things that human
beings could imagine.
That's the right way to conceptualize
them.
So you know,
you sit in a dark basement with spiders
on your head for two or three years,
dreaming up,
miserable things to do and then come up
with a most miserable thing you can
possibly imagine and then multiply that
by 100 and have people do that.
That's sort of what was happening in the
concentration camps and you know,
and there were places on earth during
the Second World War that were worse
than the concentration camps.
And if you want to read about those,
you can read about,
I think it's unit 52,
it was a Japanese medical experimental
unit who,
Oh,
I would recommend that you don't read
that because you'll read things,
you'll never get them out of your mind.
So.
So that was,
I was very curious about that.
It's like what the hell?
Here we are arming ourselves to blow
each other up and maybe the whole
planet.
And it seems somewhat counterproductive.
You know,
even if you're a communist or
capitalist,
it's like being communist king of a
burned out.
Cinders seems to be a bad outcome,
especially when you're suffering from
radiation sickness and everyone,
you know,
his dad and you know,
you could say thing about.
Same thing about the capitalist end of
things and then I also was curious.
He's like,
well,
why is this war of ideas occurring?
And it burst out into real war is a lot,
right?
Why is it occurring?
Some of it's still going on.
We're still.
The Americans are still at war with
North Korea,
right?
They never did sign a peace treaty and
the North Korean state that rather
seriously.
So there was the issue of well what the
hell?
Why are we arming ourselves with these
horrible weapons that are more than
sufficient to blow up our enemies
multiple times and would maybe take the
whole planet with them.
That seems rather insane.
And then the other issue was,
well we do have two belief systems
operating here.
They're,
they're really not the same.
You know,
like the presuppositions of communism
and the presuppositions of the West,
we're not the same.
They were seriously different at the
level of like constitutional assumption
way down deep.
And so,
you know,
another question and emerged from that
was why a system at all and then how do
you determine the validity of one system
compared to another.
It's a big problem even now,
right?
We have culture wars going on and all
sorts of ways,
you know,
radical Islam against the West for
example.
Um,
is there any way of sort of getting a
handle on what these systems are,
what differences in the mean,
why they motivate people to do atrocious
things as well as defending their own
territory,
which,
you know,
is,
is an understandable thing.
And so generally for me it was like,
what the Hell is going on?
What,
what is happening here?
So I don't know,
you know,
I was going to university and I want it
to continue.
And so that was a pretty good problem.
And I studied political science and
English literature for,
for the first part of my university
career.
And then the political scientists kept.
They were basically Marxists as clueless
as you can possibly get.
And they,
you know,
they basically propose that the reason
people engaged in social conflict was
for economic reasons.
It's like,
that's no answer.
okay,
economic reasons that means people fight
about things they value.
It's like,
well,
yeah,
self evident,
but what's not self evident is why
exactly do they value that things they
value,
you know,
because obviously people can live at
very different levels of material.
Plenty,
you know,
I mean there's people who live in the
Amazon jungle and they basically have,
from our perspective,
they have nothing and they're living
away just perfectly fine.
And then there's people you know,
in New York penthouses and it's like
people are capable of adapting to
situations where the variance in
economic wealth is insanely large.
And so the idea that we're fighting over
scarce resources or something like that
just struck me as stupid and I do think
it's stupid.
It's not even easy to define what
constitutes a resource.
And then,
you know,
you might think about Japan,
right?
It's got no resources at all and it's
rich,
you know,
it's a bit stagnant at the moment
because it's aging,
but Japan has nothing.
It has rice that they have to subsidize
and it's rich as can be,
you know.
So none of that made any sense to me at
all.
I thought it was just posturing and I
still think that I think it's a
ridiculous idea.
It's shallow is can be.
So then I thought,
oh,
I'll study psychology instead,
you know,
and I did that partly because I was
interested in problems at a clinical
level.
But I was also,
I started reading some,
I took a psych course that was self
study and I started reading some real
psychologists,
you know,
in this,
in this self guided reading course.
I read original works by Carl Rogers and
Abraham maslow and I read the archetypes
of the collective unconscious by young.
And I read the interpretation of dreams
by Freud.
Like I was trying to pick out core texts
in the history of psychological ideas.
And you know,
that was really helpful.
I mean,
there's nothing like reading original
works by geniuses to provide you with
some useful information,
you know,
is extraordinarily useful.
Reading.
Um,
and I was reading the chat the same
time,
which was also really remarkable.
I think I read,
I read most of what was published at
that point by niche.
And I tried to read it in chronological
order and it really blew me away.
It,
Mandy,
that guy don't know what was up with
him,
but he could sure think.
I mean,
Nisha said at one point I write in a
sentence what it takes other people,
a whole book to say.
It's like,
that's a pretty huge mystic and
narcissistic comment,
right?
It's like.
And then he talks and he said,
ah,
they can't even say it in a whole book.
So,
you know,
that's,
I love that.
And he was right too.
That's the thing.
And he was right,
you know,
and nature was not in very good health.
And so he'd think like mad and then
write something down that summarize the
thinking because he didn't have the
energy to run through the whole
arguments.
And so he said he liked to philosophize
with a hammer and it's like,
yeah,
I have,
I haven't had a client recently who,
who is,
who was raised as a Christian
fundamentalist state.
And uh,
he was kind of cocky intellectually and
he's not a stupid guy.
And he thought that he would,
you know,
take on Nicha intellectually because he
knew about Nisha statement about the
death of God and so he read me each and
that was the end of his Christianity.
It's like,
you know,
it's you to watch who you pick on,
and he's not a good guy to pick on
because he's a lot smarter than you and
you know,
a lot smarter than almost everyone.
He was an amazing person.
But,
and so I was reading Nietzsche and I was
reading Dostoevsky and I was reading
Aleksandr Solzhenitsyn at the same time
and social units and wrote this book
called the Gulag Archipelago,
which is like the second volume of that
book.
It's just.
He memorized the book in Karnes in a,
in a prison camp in Russia.
And the book is,
I believe it's 2,400
pages long and it's written in like
seven point type.
It's a major league book and you know,
he didn't have much pen and paper in
the,
in the gulag camps.
And,
and he spent a lot of time thinking
about why he was in there and why Russia
was basically the whole economy was
basically predicated on slave labor and
it was absolutely murderous.
So,
and the second volume of that series,
he escaped from Russia in 1975.
It was brought over in a bad translation
and circulated in the,
in the west,
long before it was available in Russia.
I tell you,
once that book was published,
1975,
there was no being a Marxist anymore.
Like he just demolished the claims of
the Marxist left to its moral
credibility,
just demolished it.
And rightly so.
And it's a,
it's an amazing book,
the Gulag Archipelago.
But it's,
it's a,
it's a Walkthrough,
a very deep swamp.
And it's a remarkable book because it's
like reading someone who's screaming and
outrage at the top of their lungs for
2,400
pages,
you know.
So I was reading all that,
you know,
and,
and I was having these nightmares and I
was.
So I was trying to figure out what the
hell it was about belief systems and,
and how things had gone.
So as strange,
especially in the 20th century,
so now I was reading the chip at that
point and I read parts of thus spake
Zarathustra and which is not a book by
Nietzsche that anyone should read until
they read everything else he wrote
because it's nothing like anything else
he wrote.
It's this weird sort of old testament
like poetry and it's,
you know,
it's revelatory in some sense.
So it's a very strange book,
but it's in that book were Nietzsche
announces the death of God and he has a
profit.
Sarah Oostra come down from a mountain
into a marketplace and tell everyone
that God is dead,
you know,
and he says,
God is dead and we have killed him and
where will we ever get enough water to
wash away the blood,
which is the part of Nietzsche's quote
that no one ever refers to.
So I mean,
because we,
you know,
people like to think of niches statement
as triumphal,
in some sense God is dead.
It's like,
yeah,
but Nisha knew what was coming because
back in the eighties,
eighties,
because he was a real prophet.
This man like Dostoevsky.
I don't know how they did this knee,
just sad in,
in,
in his notebooks and will to power that
the concept.
There's two things that were going to
happen to the human race because of the
death of religion.
One was that people would become
nihilistic and the other was that they
would become totalitarian and he said
that what would happen in Europe in the
next century,
so this is like 20 years,
15 years before the 20th century
started,
that there would be hundreds of millions
of people dying as a consequence of the
conflict.
Basically between Communist
presuppositions in classic Western
presuppositions.
It's like,
you know,
when the wall fell in 1989,
no one predicted.
It was like everyone was left
dumbfounded by that event.
You know,
so predicting what's going to happen
tomorrow that's impossible.
Predicting what's going to happen in a
whole century,
15 years before it starts.
It's like you,
you got to think someone's tapped into a
very deep,
deep underground vein to be able to do
that.
But he thought about it as a idiation
and necessity.
It's like cars,
furniture.
Once the idea of God was killed,
he believed that the entire moral
structure that was predicated on that
idea,
which was its fundamental assumption,
would be shaken,
shaken to its core because it's like the
foundation piece was knocked out and
everything would be up for grabs.
If that's not true,
then what?
Well,
that's a theme that Dostoevsky explored
to continually was Dostoevsky who needs
you to read and even more than I
thought,
as I found out recently,
I'm Dostoevsky's take on it was that,
well,
if there's no God than anything than you
can do anything you want.
Everything is permitted.
There's no morality whatsoever and all.
There is an issue.
Also pointed this out to some degree
because Nisha said most people's
morality is cowardice.
He didn't say that morality was
cowardice.
He said that people cover up their
cowardice by pretending that they're
moral when they refuse to do things that
they're terrified of.
It's like it's a nasty little comment
and it happens to be true.
So Dostoevsky as well,
at the same time,
was exploring what might happen from a
political perspective.
For example,
if his ideas about the death of God were
true,
that everything would be permitted if
God was dead and he wrote a book called
the Devil's,
which are the possessed,
which I would also highly recommend,
especially if you read it with the Gulag
archipelago because they're like,
Dostoevsky predicts what's going to
happen.
And then Solzhenitsyn describes what
happened in there.
The same thing.
It's,
it's,
it's rather staggering actually.
And especially because you know,
they're having.
There wasn't anything more powerful
written in the 20th century than
Solzhenitsyn's books and there wasn't
anything written in the 19th century
that was more powerful than
Dostoyevsky's books.
So like that's a one two punch.
So.
So anyway,
so nature is prediction was that once
you pull the rug out from underneath the
system,
it might take a long time to fall,
but it's going to fall because there's
no foundation left.
And the system was actually logically
coherent.
Once you accepted the assumptions.
The assumptions were while they were
basically Christian assumptions in our
Judeo Christian assumptions in Europe,
you know,
and they were predicated on the
religious substructure and those
religious ideas.
Though it wasn't as obvious in the late
$1,900
as it is now,
had an unbelievably ancient history.
So you know,
a Christian ideas are derived from
Jewish ideas and Jewish ideas are
predicated on Egyptian ideas and
Egyptian ideas are based in Mesopotamian
ideas and that's about as far as back as
we can go.
But then we know that there are
shamanistic traditions that are
basically religious instruction that go
back maybe 25,000
years and then,
you know,
before that we don't know,
we don't know,
but there wasn't nothing before that
because there were people like us
fundamentally for at least 150,000
years.
And then there were people who were more
or less like us for depends on how you
count.
We diverged from our chimp human
ancestor about 7 million years ago.
So God only knows how deeply rooted
those ideas are.
Now,
you know,
the rationalist critics like and we
still have the like darkens for example,
you know,
they kind of think of,
of a religious system as a,
as a superstitious scientific theory,
you know,
and that's,
it's exactly what people like.
Voltaire thought 300 years ago,
you know,
and it's uh,
I get their point,
but it's stupid.
No,
I'm telling you like,
it's like,
forget about that.
That's like 1750,
you know,
it's not 1750 anymore and we've got
different problems.
And the idea that religion is a
superstitious scientific theory,
it's like,
that's a really stupid idea.
All that means is that you haven't read
anything about the psychology of
religion or about religious
phenomenology in general.
I mean anybody who has any grounding in
neuroscience and who actually reads,
knows,
for example,
that there are all sorts of neural
phenomena that result in religious
experience.
You know.
So for example,
if you get epilepsy,
there's a high probability that your
aura,
which is the sense you have before the,
the,
uh,
epilepsy hits is a high probability that
that's going to be associated with
religious experience.
And it was for Dostoevsky,
for example.
So what happened to Dostoevsky was that
he was kind of a student radical,
you know,
under the czars.
And they arrested him along with the
other student radicals and threw them in
the prison in Moscow.
I think it was in Lubyanka and they kept
them there for a while.
He's kind of an aristocratic guy,
so he wasn't used to a hard living and
then before they let him go,
they woke him up at six in the morning
and took them out in the firing squad
yard and then they lined up all the
people who would do the shooting when a
firing squad and they shot them with
blanks,
but he didn't know they were blanks and
so that was a little hard on his nervous
system and so he developed epilepsy as a
consequence of that.
And one of the consequences of example,
epsy was that just before he had the
actual seizure,
he said that it appeared to him that his
knowledge of the structure of reality
was deepening and deepening and
deepening and deepening until it was
absolutely overwhelming.
He felt like he was on the verge of
discovering the secret of the universe
and then apparently the secret of the
universe was a little too big to fit
inside his head and he'd have an
epileptic seizure.
But it's very interesting because
Dostoevsky was kind of a hack novelist
before,
before he underwent prison,
then he had the firing squad thing
happened and then he was sent to this
like horrible prison full of murderers
and rapists for for a long time.
And so when he came out,
he wasn't the same guy.
It's hard to say exactly how much the
experience has changed them and how much
the epilepsy changed in.
But certainly there are depths of
representation in his writing that I
don't think he could have reached
without the epilepsy.
And so religious experiences,
man,
they're hardwired into your brain and we
can elicit them with some,
with some regularity.
Now you might think,
well that means there are biological
side effect.
It's like,
yeah,
yeah maybe.
And maybe not to,
you know,
so you,
I don't know what the rationalist do
with that sort of thing,
you know,
maybe they say,
well that's an evolutionary spandrel.
It doesn't really mean anything of any
importance.
It's like
the whole span two spandrel is Spandrel,
is something that characterizes an
organism,
but it hadn't really evolved.
It just more or less happened.
So you can't say that it has a function,
it's like a side effect of something
else.
One of the great tricks of rationalist
evolutionary thinkers is that they call
anything that a biological organism
manifests that they can't account for
rationally a spandrel.
And it's a real,
it's a real,
it's a pathological trick.
And you certainly can't do that with
something like religious experience.
I mean you just have to be adult to
think that I can give you an example.
So I'm obviously part of what's
happening and really just phenomenology
is dominance hierarchy perception gone
mad in a sense.
So you know,
so imagine that there's a hierarchy of
people and that you're hardwired to
admire those at the top.
Well obviously right?
I mean how,
What Percentage of magazine Sold
Disposer About Celebrity Culture.
It's like 50 percent.
So like primates,
like us,
we like to gaze at high status primates
and if you take,
I think they're vervets and you figure
out the vervet hierarchy and you show
low status vervets photographs of high
status for bits,
then they'll spend a lot of time looking
at them.
So part of,
part of what I'm trying to suggest here
is that part of what religious
phenomenology is,
is the inbuilt sense of awe that we have
when we gaze up the hierarchy and we see
what's at the top and you know,
it's not that long since we had
monarchies and in many societies you
weren't even allowed to look at the
king.
You know,
that was certainly the case in Japan
where,
you know,
the,
the emperor would be surrounded by
shoguns shoguns I think that's right.
And they,
they were authorized to kill anyone who
got line.
They just chopped them up with their
swords and any bit of being out of line
was enough.
So,
you know,
dominance hierarchy is a very serious
thing.
And so,
you know,
it's hard for modern people to
understand the aw,
that must have accompanied the
experience of being exposed to a monarch
in a society that was fundamentally
monarchical.
But the Japanese believed like right up
to the second end of the Second World
War that their emperor was a Sun God.
And you think,
well that's pretty damn weird.
It's like,
no,
it's not.
It's the fact that we don't have sun
gods that's weird,
like that's a really,
really old idea,
and the Japanese were just doing what
virtually every culture before them had
done that ever got anywhere with
organization,
and so there's one of the things about a
god is that a god is something like
what's at the top of the dominant
Turkey.
Now,
human beings are very,
very peculiar creatures and we're
capable of high levels of abstraction.
So I'm going to offer you a theory.
Okay?
And this is a lot of thinking compressed
into a very tiny sentence.
Okay?
So imagine a dominance hierarchy.
Now imagine that there's a set of
qualities that makes it more probable
that you'll get to the top of a
dominance hierarchy.
Now,
that's not that hard to imagine,
right?
You might think,
well,
intelligence might have something to do
with that attractiveness might have
something to do with that power.
We know from studies of chimps,
and this is mostly done by friends to
all that you know,
because you might think of kind of
prototypical caveman society that it's
like the caveman that looks most like a
bodybuilder who's the most dominant cave
man,
but so to speak,
but what do all found among the chimps
was that the chimp who is at the top of
the male dominance hierarchy,
who remained at the top relatively
stable so that he wasn't brutally
murdered,
say bye to chimps that were below him in
the dominance hierarchy,
was actually kind of a good leader in
some sense.
You know.
So he got along well with females in the
troop and maybe even attended to their
children to some degree.
And it wasn't a completely unpredictable
tyrant.
And if he was like that,
then you know,
a couple of male chimps would form a
coalition and when his back was turned
at any moment,
then they'd rip them to pieces.
And so.
So that's really.
It's phenomenally interesting because
what it suggests is that there's a
stable set of characteristics,
relatively stable that are operative
within a dominance hierarchy that
propels you to the top and that and that
that's characteristic not only of human
dominance hierarchies,
but it's also characteristic in a way
that's analogous to even chimp dominance
hierarchies.
So you can read Frans de Waal if you're
interested in that sort of thing is he's
written a lot of books about the
emergence of morality and in,
in chimpanzees in particular,
it's very nice work.
I mean he's observing chimps that are
basically in a zoo in,
in Holland,
so you know,
you could make the case that,
you know,
there are a little,
not like wild chimps but whatever,
you know,
fine.
They're not exactly like wild chimps,
but I don't think that invalidates his
research at all.
So,
and,
and you know,
you can observe similar things in wild
chimps.
Okay.
So that's kind of an interesting idea,
right?
There's a set of stable traits that
propels you towards the top.
And some of those would be indicators of
biological health,
like symmetry and beauty,
and some of them would be well,
what other characteristics?
The rest of the bloody truth,
thinker,
admirable.
And because admirable is also a very
interesting phenomena,
right?
Because there are people you admire,
you think,
well,
why are there people that you admire and
what does it mean to admire someone?
And what it means in some sense is that
the effect they have on you is one of
wanting to imitate.
And you know,
human beings,
a lot of our knowledge,
a tremendous amount of our knowledge
isn't propagated linguistically.
It's propagated through invitation and
the probability that were imitating each
other before we develop language is
extremely high.
And we're also one of the few animals,
maybe the only animal that are really
capable of true invitation.
And it's a major league advance in terms
of the transformation of information.
Because what it means is you can go out
there and half kill yourself,
learning how to do something and
stumbled back into the tribe and
recover.
And then I can just watch you and embody
what you did.
And poof,
I've got the damn information and you
know,
I didn't have to expose myself to
dragons and,
and all sorts of other horrible things
that were out there in the unknown.
And so,
you know,
we're imitating ourselves all the time.
So if you admire someone,
what that does is hook up,
it hooks into your desire to imitate.
And that's also part of an like an
inbuilt intrinsic biological process.
Okay,
now fine.
So here's what we're going to say,
dominance hierarchy,
reason for getting to the top,
that produces admiration,
partly because people want to be at the
top of a dominance hierarchy.
That's success.
And we're,
we're wired to climb dominance
hierarchies because the top of a dorm,
if you live at the top of the dominance
hierarchy,
you live longer than you do.
If you live at the bottom of a dominance
hierarchy,
even if you factor out the effect of
relative income,
it's more,
it's less stressful at the top,
you have better resources at the top and
the top is a place,
right?
Because it's been around for 400 million
years.
It's a place,
it's like a conceptual place in a sense
or it's a place that's the emergent
property of social organization,
but it's a place and it's a place where
people want to go,
okay,
you got a dominance hierarchy,
someone gets to the top,
you admire them.
All right?
But that's not exactly what human beings
are like.
First of all,
there isn't one dominance hierarchy.
There's hundreds of the bloody things.
Especially as society becomes complex,
there's a radically very a gated realm
of dominance hierarchies.
Right?
And so then you might ask yourself
across the set of dominance hierarchies,
is there a set of properties that makes
people likely to get to the top?
And that's the kind of question that
only a creature capable of abstraction
could ask or pause it.
And I would say that the figure that
represents the properties that produces
the highest probability of climbing to
the top of the set of all dominance
hierarchies is a mess.
Cyanic figure.
That's what a messianic figure is.
So,
and it's a kind of abstraction it says,
because of course obviously a messianic
figure is an ideal write clearly and so
then you might think,
well,
an ideal in relationship to what?
Well the he,
he generally is the perfect person.
Well,
how would we come up with the concept of
what constitutes perfect?
Think about it as a biological category
where all there's hardly anything more
perfect and the ability to climb to the
top of whatever dominance hierarchy you
happened to be put in.
Now.
One of the things I would say is that
women exerted tremendous selection
pressure on men to be exactly that sort
of creature.
So,
and I can tell you a little bit of
experimental evidence that we have in
relationship shipped to that later.
Fortunately it was an unpublished study
because it was an undergraduate thesis,
but,
but what the hell else would women
select men for?
They had any sense?
No.
You want to select a partner because you
know,
you've heard the idea of hyper gummy,
right?
Women made across or up dominance
hierarchies.
And so people think,
well women are after say something like
wealth and success.
So we tested that women aren't that
stupid,
so what we did was this,
so we showed a bunch of women the same
picture of a guy,
but we attached for stories to it.
One story was the basic two by two cross
was useful versus useless and poor
versus rich.
So we had useless,
poor,
useful,
rich,
useless,
rich and useful,
poor.
And so here were the story.
So the useless,
poor guy.
Well you don't need a story for that.
It's like everybody can figure out what
that is,
you know,
he doesn't have anything and he's never
going to get anything so fine,
useless and poor.
Then there's useless and rich.
That's a harder one,
right?
So what we did was the guy had won a
lottery that paid out weekly for the
rest of his life.
So he couldn't squander the money
because it only came in weekly.
So there was always going to be money
around and we made the amount
sufficiently substantial so that,
you know,
he was in the top one percent,
let's say.
So that's useless.
Rich and useful.
Poor was this guy that he worked for an
NGO and like he was a good guy and you
know,
he's helping people out,
but he was never really gonna make any
money doing this.
He was Sorta altruistically committed to
a benevolent cause,
useful,
poor.
And then there was useful rich,
right.
Which,
you know,
that's sort of the useful rich guy.
He's like the hero of every two bit
romance and if you don't believe me,
then you could read a billion wicked
thoughts.
It's quite a cool book.
It's written by Google analytics guys
and they were looking for the
architectural structure of the sort of
literature that women read on in their
spare time,
so to speak,
on the web.
It's sort of like the female equivalent
of pornography.
And so the main guys in these stories or
surgeon,
that's a good one.
Billionaire Pirate Vampire Werewolf.
Yeah.
So it's very funny.
Anyway,
so what we found was we had women raped
the guys for,
you know,
would you date this guy,
go out for coffee.
Would you date him?
Would you consider a long term?
Would you consider a longterm
relationship?
And the result was wealth was
irrelevant,
useful was relevant,
so the useful poor guy was just as good
as the useful rich guy and that,
you know,
that's smart because what you should
select for isn't having stuff now that's
because maybe this stuff will go away.
And that was especially true in
societies where stuff couldn't be
stored,
which was almost every society we ever
had until the modern times.
So what you select for is the capability
of being successful across multiple
environments,
obviously.
Okay.
So that's very much like the capability
of climbing to the dominance hierarchy
across sets of dominance hierarchies.
And then,
you know,
I talked to you about a little bit and I
suggested that it's not so obvious what
would put someone at the top.
So leadership qualities,
you know,
because you can think about it as blunt
power,
sort of like psychopathic leader,
but you know,
that's pretty pessimistic and it could
easily be that a leader who can maintain
power for any amount of time,
so in some sense isn't going to be
thrown over by violent revolution,
has to be a leader of a certain type.
And that,
that stable across,
let's say it's stable across the
islands,
or we could even say maybe it's stable
across millions of years in very complex
social organisms.
It's a possibility because you know,
partly what I've been trying to get it
as the biological basis of religious
belief.
And I would like to tell you,
I'm not trying to reduce religious
belief to anything because it's not,
it's like Daniel Dennett wrote a book
called consciousness explained and the
critics said consciousness explained a
way,
you know,
so and I could say,
well,
I'm trying to explain religious
phenomenology,
but I am not trying to explain it a way.
I'm not trying to reduce it to something
else.
I'm trying to account for its
relationship with evolutionary
structure.
And you know,
this is also why I think the modern
atheist,
it's a damn clueless.
It's like religion is a human universal,
right?
There's lots of human universals.
Decoration is one everywhere.
People decorate themselves.
Clothing seems to be another.
Roughly speaking.
Um,
some form of marriage seems to be
another language seems to be another.
Sharing food seems to be another.
Like,
you know,
we're human and human beings have
characteristics like other animals have
characteristics and religious experience
and belief of some form is also a human
universal.
So,
you know,
it's something you have to contend with
from an evolutionary perspective.
You can't just brush it off and say,
well,
it's like superstitious science.
It's like,
that's not an analysis.
It's like human beings that religious
animals.
So what the hell does that mean?
You know,
we bury our dead with ceremonies and
we'd been doing that for tens of
thousands of years.
So it's in us.
And no one came up with these theories
because that's what the Marxists used to
say it,
right?
They said,
well,
religion is the opiate of the masses.
It's like,
yeah,
add Marxism was the math,
the math is massive,
you know,
so we know where that went.
So you know,
when Marx's idea,
and this is the same idea that the post
structuralists and the postmodernist
bandy about is that,
you know,
religion is some sort of semi calculated
expression of the power elite and the
purpose of it is to subordinate those
who were subordinate and to keep those
who were in power,
in power across time.
It's like it's a conspiracy theory.
Nobody invented Christianity.
You know,
it's like,
it,
it's,
it took 2000 years to reach its current
form and it was based on ideas.
There are tens of thousands of years
older than that.
So nobody was sitting around thinking,
well,
let's whip up a system to oppress the
masses.
And like,
even if you did come up with a theory
like that,
how in the world are you going to get
people to buy into it?
You know,
it's not that easy to start a mass
movement and I think there's a 2 billion
Christians,
something like that.
How do you get all those people to be
thinking that this is a good idea?
It's not easy.
Would I say say again?
That superstition?
Yeah,
it created to control.
Sure,
absolutely.
You know,
I mean superstition is what you have
when you don't know what the hell you're
talking about fundamentally.
Although I wouldn't put it down that
much because you know,
often superstitions are like functional
theories,
you know,
so they're.
And in theories have,
there's a lot of different ways that a
theory can be valid.
You know,
we talked about functional utility as
well and some things that look like
they're superstitious have functional
utility.
They're approximations.
And one thing to think about a theory is
I think of theories as tools and that's
a pragmatic perspective.
So I would think of scientists science
as a tool.
I think religion is a tool as well and
nobody would complain if they had a tool
box full of different tools.
Right?
And,
and you can chop down a tree with a
hammer if you have to,
but it would be better to use an ax,
but a hammer beats the hell out of a
stick.
So,
you know,
my point is,
is that even a bad theory can be a
better tool than the one you had before.
It's like approximations to the perfect
tool in some sense,
so I think your thinking is going to be
a hell of a lot easier,
you know,
all things considered if you start to
think about theories as tools and to
also think about the theory as a tool
that has a limited domain of
applicability and that is a pragmatic
idea and I really think,
I really think the pragmatists were
right.
I think they got it right.
Religion is a universal human
characteristic.
So many people that
no there aren't.
They just think about how many vegans do
you know?
No,
they're clueless.
They're clueless religious because what
they have is ritual without,
without,
without philosophy.
Fundamentally.
So what's happened in,
in many cases is that as the
sophisticated religion so to speak,
have collapsed.
What emerges from their ashes are
rituals and rituals are sort of the
ground out of which are religion
emerges.
Vegans,
vegetarianism,
Vegetarians,
environmentalist's.
Anybody who's in India log,
you know,
and,
and the reason,
the reason that I would consider those
in the religious domain is because their
systems of value and they're predicated
on fundamental assumptions that you have
to take on faith.
See,
that's the thing that's so peculiar
because it really turns out that if
you're going to act and you have to act,
you have to make assumptions.
And the reason for that is what the
hell.
You know,
you got to put your ignorance somewhere
and people put their ignorance.
They box it up inside their assumptions
and those assumptions very so.
And then you know,
the other thing is you got to ask
yourself,
when you're wondering if someone is
religious,
what you use as a marker.
Now the typical marker would be I give
you a questionnaire and I asked you,
are you religious or do you go to church
or you know,
do you follow the precepts and rituals
of something that we would recognize as
a standard religion?
And lots of people will say no to that,
hey,
but then you watch them and you think
this is a Nietzschean observation.
What makes you think that the morality
that you consider moral hasn't been
conditioned to the absolute last degree
by 2000 years or 3000 years of in the
West at least Judeo Christian tradition.
It's like all the ideas of fundamentally
all the ideas that individuals have
value.
It's like we just,
which is very peculiar idea.
You know,
everyone here,
all you people virtually I would suspect
believe that.
It's like,
why do you believe that and what do you
mean you believe it?
What does that mean?
And what it means is you act as if it's
true and I don't care what you say.
Like what the hell do you know about
what you believe?
You know,
you,
you come to university,
you can probably spout off a few
ideologies and rationalize all sorts of
complex behaviors.
But the idea that you actually know what
you're up to or who you are is like,
why would you think that you're the most
complicated thing that exists?
So you don't think you understand the
son,
you know,
in the son's a lot more,
a lot less complicated than you are.
So I don't buy for a moment the idea
that people don't have religious
beliefs,
they just are generally clueless about
what they are.
So and that's,
that's actually part of the problem I
want to address is that one of the
things that has happened is that in some
sense what the evolved religions,
let's call them did was there's a
behavioral substructure that constitutes
cultural practice,
accepted cultural practice.
And I would say it's predicated on
observations.
Like there is an optimal pattern of
behavior that's associated with across
dominance hierarchies.
That's the central value.
It's something like that.
And that happens everywhere.
And there's similarities in those
rituals because there are similarities
among human beings and similarities
among dominance hierarchies.
Okay.
So you get the behavior laid down,
first is which everyone's acting like a
pro social creature and then the next
thing you get is the representation,
the symbolic representation of what the
pro sociality might be like.
And then you get that expressed in
religious symbolism.
And then on top of that you get
something like an articulated system of
religious propositions.
And then on top of that,
maybe you extract out a philosophy.
It's something like that,
so it's relatively coherent across
different levels of analysis.
Now what happened in the 19th century
and partly because of the rise of
science,
is that the conscious element of the
religious belief got flipped on its head
because everybody woke up and said,
what the hell do we believe these things
for and what do we even mean?
They're true,
virgin birth and reincarnated,
God,
and you know,
for God the father and all the peculiar
propositions of Christianity and Judaism
and Islam.
It's like we wake up,
we think,
wow,
look what we're doing.
We don't know what we're doing,
and here we have this whole new body of
knowledge that suggest that none of that
is factually true.
Well,
no one was saying,
well,
maybe there's more than one form of
truth.
You know,
and people weren't thinking about
pragmatic truth,
for example,
or behavioral truth.
They were having this weird conflict
which you all suffer from between,
you know,
a materialist description of reality and
what
religious propositions that didn't seem
to be in concordance with that.
You know,
we've looked far out into heaven through
the Hubble Hubble telescope.
Nobody found God because that means
there is no God in heaven.
It depends on what you mean by God.
Depends on what you mean by heaven.
So it's not obvious at all that the
heaven of the Medieval thinkers is the
same as the space that we know about
from an empirical perspective.
It's not obvious at all.
So.
Okay,
so let's stop for a bit.
For 10 minutes.
Let's say.