Okay.
So we talked a lot about the brain last
time and we're going to talk a little
bit more about that.
And then we're going to talk about
organization of hierarchical systems and
then we're going to talk about their
representation in mythology.
So this is from a paper by Swanson and
Swanson has been studying the
hypothalamus for a very long time and
brain organization in general.
And the way he conceptualized as it is
is in a rather piaget the incense.
And so the,
the essential outputs of the nervous
system are basically patterns of motor
behavior and those are controlled by
patterns of spinal cord activity.
And those are controlled by patterns
that higher brain levels including the
hypothalamus.
And then those are controlled by
emotional systems.
There's patterned responses at the
emotional level.
And then those are controlled by pattern
pattern responses at the level of the
cortex.
And the body sort of builds itself from
the bottom up.
Um,
and as it builds itself from the bottom
up,
it's trying to integrate the function of
all the systems that are necessary for
the maintenance of the biological
maintenance of life in the medium term,
short term,
medium term and long term.
And in a social context that works for
the social context.
And it also works for the individual
context.
So you could imagine that that's a
rather,
it's hypothetically possible that
there's only a certain set of solutions
to a problem that complex.
And if that's the case,
then that would account for the
emergence of something approximating a
universal morality.
And it would also explain why every
possible political system won't work.
So
no,
this is Swanson's map of the
hypothalamus.
Now you'll note that the hypothalamic
structures,
they're the ones with the little circles
and so on,
on the left.
It like every other element of the
brain.
The hypothalamus isn't a homogenous
structure,
right?
And generally when you name something,
if you think about it,
the name presumes a homogenous structure
because otherwise you would
differentiate the name and you would
call it a bunch of names instead of just
one.
And so what happens,
for example,
that as people learn more about the
brain,
you'll,
you'll notice this as you learn more
about the brain,
you start thinking about it necessarily
as the brain,
which is like a homogenous mass of
neurons.
And you start thinking about it in terms
of its functional subsystems.
And then once you learn more about
those,
you think about those functional
subsystems in terms of their functional
subsystems.
And you can keep differentiating all the
way down.
You can differentiate all the way down
to the molecular level.
And so as your knowledge improves,
your level of resolution improves and
you can use more and more precise
terminology.
What you see is that the hypothalamus is
composed of a number of systems.
And one of the things that Swanson has
done with this particular diagram is
indicate which parts of the hypothalamus
this is in a rat's brain are basically
responsible for reproductive behaviors
in which are responsible for defensive
behaviors.
And that's part of the hypothalamus.
Now the other part,
so,
so there's a very archaic system way
down in the bottom of the brain,
older than emotions about his oldest
pain that's responsible for these very
fundamental motivational drive.
So you can think about the hypothalamus
if you want to think about this way as
the part of the biological basis of what
Freud would have called the Ed.
No,
we don't have to think about it as in
terms of relatively vague statements
like the Ed anymore because we know more
about the underlying circuitry and we
know that it's,
that it's,
um,
quite standard across mammalian species
and even farther back in the genetic
chain then just mammals.
So yeah.
System.
Yeah.
Well,
you know,
systems develop in an evolutionary
chain,
right?
And some systems are more primordial
than others and so the hypothalamic
systems are more primordial than the
hippocampus and the Amygdala acts
systems.
And so pain,
you can think of pain as an emotion.
People usually don't,
they usually think about it as an,
as a motivational system.
But the distinction between those terms
is vague.
Anyways,
pain has a emotion like component and a
motivation like component,
like anger does.
All I mean by older is that it was their
first.
So anxiety for example seems to be an
elaboration of pain.
So pain,
pain represents pain indicates damage to
the system that's being stimulated
basically.
Something like that.
Well let me get to that because I will
get to that because that's another
reduction
probably for all of them.
Yeah.
So,
so this governs reproductive behavior
that would be outputs from the
reproductive system to other systems
that mediate positive emotion,
but they're all too,
so part of the hippocampus,
part of the hypothalamus is devoted to
these motivation like processes.
I think their motivation like
personalities and part of it is actually
devoted.
The other part of it,
the other half of it is devoted towards
exploration and the exploration system
is the source.
The roots of the exploration system in
the hypothalamus are the,
are the,
are the bottom part of the structure
that produces the kind of positive
emotion that's associated with approach
and and joy.
So,
and it's also extremely all because it
has its roots in the hypothalamus.
So that's the dopaminergic system.
So half the Hypothalamus,
roughly speaking,
is devoted towards the regulation of um,
fundamentally motivated behaviors like
sexuality and defensive aggression say,
and the other half of it is devoted
towards exploration.
And so that's quite interesting because
one of the things that means is that
exploration,
that tendency,
the proclivity towards exploration is
also unbelievably archaic.
It's really,
really old.
And as I mentioned,
I think I told you this before,
if you studied the behavior of a
decorticate cat,
which is a cap that really has almost no
brain left except the hypothalamus and
the spinal structures,
that cat is hypo exploratory,
hyper exploratory,
sorry.
It explores more than a normal cat,
which is quite strange given that it
doesn't have much of a brain.
But part of the reason it explores more
is because it can't form the memory
structures that would inhibit the
exploration has a consequence of
learning.
So basically what happens is you're
curious about something until you figure
it out.
And then you've built a representation
of it,
which is in some sense a representation
of what to do around that thing.
And once you've built that
representation,
it's not necessary to be curious about
that thing anymore because you've
figured it out and you might as well go
on to some other thing that you don't
understand.
But if you don't have much of a brain,
you can't store the consequences of your
exploratory activity.
And so you can't inhibit it.
So that's why a cat without a brain is
hyper exploratory.
So what I think is really interesting
about the hypothalamic work is that
we're going to talk a lot about the
representation of exploration in
mythology.
And it was very interesting to me to
learn that the proclivity towards
exploration and the positive emotion
that's associated with that is so
ancient that it's grounded in the
hypothalamus.
So it's as all so to speak as hunger and
sex knows are very,
very old things.
So now you might say,
well,
if the hypothalamus can do all this,
why do you need the rest of the brain?
And that's a perfectly good question.
Um,
some animals don't have much more brazen
than that.
It seems to me that the reason that you
need it is because when you have
motivational system a and motivational
system be in motivational system c and
Motivational System d,
there are conflicts.
There are potential conflicts between
their operations across spans of time.
One can interfere with another,
and the optimal arrangement is so that
the operations of each of these systems
is sequenced in such a manner that each
of them get what they need on an ongoing
basis.
And so part of the reason that you need
the rest of your brain is to do the
proper sequencing is to figure out when
you should do what.
And so the rest of the brain and part is
there to take time into account.
But it's not only there to take time
into account,
it's also there to take context into
account because reproductive behavior,
for example,
has to be context sensitive.
Even though it's a fundamental
motivation.
It has to be context sensitive because
every situation is not the same as every
other situation,
especially among animals that become
increasingly complex.
So part of the reason that you need more
brain or that that it might be
worthwhile under some conditions to have
more brain is to solve the problem of
how to organize multiple fundamental
motivational systems working
simultaneously.
And that's a lot of the problems that
you're trying to solve on a day to day
basis are precisely that.
You know,
you have to add emotional regulation to
that and you have to also,
because we're social animals,
you have to add the problem of the fact
that there's all sorts of other people
who are trying to do exactly the same
thing cooperatively and competitively in
the same environment across different
spans of time.
So it's a very complex optimization
problem.
It doesn't seem like it's precisely
computable.
A lot of it seems to have to,
a lot of the way we do it seems to have
to do with ongoing negotiation,
you know,
because you might say,
well,
what's the answer to the proper
hierarchical arrangement of motivational
necessities?
And I think that the past can offer,
um,
hints in that direction and also can
probably inform us about what won't
work.
But those are sort of vague and broad.
And in order to determine how to update
that and bring it into the present,
there has to be continual,
ongoing communication and negotiation.
So,
okay.
So then you can think about the
relationship between what we were
thinking about as the
fundamental unit of personality.
Because I think of this not only as the
fundamental unit of narrative,
but the fundamental unit of personality
is that the,
the basic motivational systems,
which I've sort of outlined here,
um,
in schematic format,
I'm not claiming that these are
precisely,
precisely accurate or scientific
categories,
but you can think of them.
The basic motivational states basically
as associated with self propagation and
self maintenance.
Those are the two big problems that are
a living creature has to solve.
And then those problems are broken down
into the operation of more specialized
subsystems,
like the desire for affiliation,
which is,
seems to be a basic motivation among
people.
Uh,
sexual desire.
Those are all proper itself.
Propagation motivations,
thermal regulation,
thirst,
hunger,
elimination,
all the sorts of things that you think
of as basic biological necessities.
And so each of those has the capacity to
pop up something that's approximating a
personality when it needs to.
And so it's not a drive,
which is an important thing to realize.
There's a drive like element to the
degree that that process has become
habitual or that it's based in instinct.
So,
but so the drive like the more drive
like something is,
the more likely it is that lower levels
in the nervous system are taking care of
it.
And so maybe spinal systems for example.
So you know,
if you put your hand on a hot stove,
you'll jerk it back fast before you feel
the pain.
And that's because there's a reflex loop
between your sensory receptors on your
hand and your spinal cord.
It's very fast.
It just goes like that.
It's a sensory motor loop and it's
basically deterministic.
So things that extremely high resolution
are becoming increasingly deterministic.
So the pain comes in after you've pulled
your hand away and that seems to be
something like it's teaching you in some
sense your body is teaching you.
That's one way of thinking about it,
not to do that stupid thing again.
And are they.
People also think maybe that pain
immobilizes us so that we're more likely
to heal and or less likely to keep
engaging in the behavior that caused the
damage.
So,
all right,
so our motivational systems are popping
up these little personalities all the
time.
And you know,
one of the dictums of psychoanalytic
thought is that those little
motivational personalities can more or
less have a life of their own because
they're there,
there are subsets of you,
and if they're not integrated into the
complete personality,
well then when they emerge,
they're going to be rather primordial
and unsophisticated.
And you see this in people,
for example,
who have outbursts of anger.
You know,
it's that it isn't exactly reasonable to
say that they've become disinhibited.
Although that's one way of thinking
about it.
It's actually more reasonable to assume
that they haven't developed enough
sophistication to integrate that
motivational system.
So that capacity for anger,
for example,
into their personality as a whole.
And one of the dictums of Humean
psychotherapy in particular is that it's
are extraordinarily useful to integrate
those elements of your personality that
might have like a fiery liked nature,
a potentially dangerous nature.
Anger and aggression is a really good
example of that.
But sexual desire is also a really good
If you're sophisticated,
you have that system at hand when you
need it,
but you don't use it in a manner that's
destructive to your operations as a
whole across time.
And you don't use it in a manner that
dis dis disrupts the relationship that
you've established socially with your
family and broader society.
So it's all integrated.
It's like it's integrated into a game.
And one of the things you might think
about is that a lot of the games that
people do play and that people like to
watch our games of aggression,
integration,
you know,
so football is a really good example of
that.
I mean,
those guys are massive and they're
strong and they're aggressive.
But you know,
by,
and by and large,
when they're in the football game,
they use that to further the game.
Now they're trying to win individually
and their treat teams trying to win.
But at the same time,
both teams are competing within a
framework of rules.
And that's in a broader framework that
encompasses the entire audience,
which is also continually giving them
feedback on the quality of their play.
You know?
So if somebody does something
particularly brutal and unnecessary,
the whole audience is going to complain
about that,
you know?
And that's,
that's one of the ways by which the
players determine how much force can be
used and how much force can't be used.
Because as the,
as the game continues,
it's not easy to tell when you're being
too aggressive or not too aggressive.
You know?
So
it's funny,
I was reading a little while ago about
the Canada,
Russia Harkey series in 1972 and if I
remember correctly,
the Canadians played by European rules,
which meant that there was no body
checking.
So that was kind of hard on them because
the Europeans don't check.
But the Canadians claimed that in games
they played where there was no checking,
there was a lot more hitting with the
ends of sticks and a lot more slashing
and like there were,
there were still all sorts of
aggression,
but it was ne never able to get up to
the point where you could give someone a
solid hit.
And the Canadians take on that was that
the game wasn't necessarily less
dangerous or less rough without
checking.
It's just at the aggression got
subordinated.
And so you know,
it's,
it's not an easy thing to figure out
exactly what level of force is necessary
to push any given thing forward.
But none is definitely the wrong answer.
You know,
and if you're ever involved,
which you will be an oh no doubt are now
if you're involved in difficult
negotiations as you move forward,
salary negotiations or negotiations
about a given project or even even
complaints that even attempts on your
part to solve problems at work,
like being subject to,
you know,
to arbitrary tyranny or being bored to
death by a useless project or something
like that.
If you don't have that capacity for
force at hand,
you're not going to win.
You're not going to win,
you're just going to get walked over and
how much force you need.
That's part of the ongoing dialogue.
And so,
and that's really worth thinking about a
lot of what happens in psychotherapy as
well as exposure to things that are,
that people are afraid of and the
development of new micro skills.
So for example,
sorry,
I have a client who isn't very socially
skilled.
You know,
we might practice things like shaky
hands and telling each other who we are
because if you don't have that down as a
routine,
it's difficult to make a foray into a
broader social environment.
So sometimes people are stopped socially
because they lock micro skills and
sometimes it's because they're afraid
and those two things interplay.
But another thing that happens in
therapy and awful lot is that people
come in for assertiveness training.
You know when there are people who've
usually,
they're usually agreeable in
temperament,
but there are also people who have
failed to integrate that capacity for
aggression into their personality for
one reason or another.
Maybe they weren't taught to.
That's certainly possible.
Maybe when they manifested aggression,
they were punished for it.
Maybe they observed other people who
were too aggressive and decided that
they were never going to be like that.
That's a common response,
but it doesn't,
it doesn't really matter because once
you're an adult and you're working in a
competitive world,
which you will definitely be,
you have to have that capacity because
otherwise you get pushed to the bottom
of the dominance hierarchy and exploited
and so,
and it's not necessarily because of
malevolence.
Partly it can be that,
but often it's just,
it's the consequence of the fact that
generally if you're negotiating for
something,
there are forces pulling on that from
all directions and the out the obvious
what outcome is obviously.
Right.
It's not obvious at all.
And so it's a matter of negotiation and
so you have to be able to put your
position forward with some force and not
be timid about it and be articulate
about it and all that is a consequence
of integrating these systems that can be
very dangerous if they're not working
properly into your personality rather
than ignoring them and letting them run
in an underground fashion,
which is what they would do.
Yes.
Yeah.
Well the thing about Freud,
this is what the comment was,
that it's reminiscent of Friday and
sublimation.
Freud more or less had an inhibitory
mortal of socialization,
you know,
because he thought of people as pushed
by the Ed so that the ego has pushed by
the head and inhibited by the superego.
And there's some truth in that to the
degree that that you're subject to quasi
tyrannical pressure by a society that
isn't well integrated.
A lot of what's going to happen to you
is don't do that.
And the capacity to not do something
that you're motivated to do,
like an impulsive thing is obviously
necessary.
But sublimation in a sense is the basis
of Piagetian theory.
And Piaget's alternative to Friday and
thinking is that it's not inhibitory.
Especially not if it's,
if your personality is properly
integrated,
what it is instead is integration into a
game like structure.
We're going to talk more about that.
So the point is is that you're starting
at high levels of resolution with your
body,
you know,
and you're building these structures out
of your capacity to move and at your
capacity to perceive and these
motivational systems that are driving
you.
And as you become socialized and as you
bring more and more people into the
conversation,
the hierarchy gets more and more complex
and sophisticated and then it's the
whole thing that's regulating.
It's not inhibitory,
you know?
So you don't want to inhibit your
aggression.
You want to harness it so it serves the
purposes of the greater the individual
and the greater good.
If you can figure out how to do that,
it's better that way because you have
more power now.
It might be better for you to be
cowardly and,
and retreating if the alternative is to
be impulsively aggressive and
destructive.
But that's not nearly as good as having
the capacity for aggression at your hand
and being able to use it in a
sophisticated manner.
So,
all right,
so this is a way of thinking about how
things,
yes.
Okay.
I don't think it's,
I don't think you can say that it's that
simple.
I mean I think that happens,
but how it happens,
we don't know.
And the thing too is that this
organization does not only take place in
your brain.
That's another thing that the
psychoanalysts I think over estimated
because they tend to think of psychic
regulation as internal,
but it's not.
So for example,
as long as you're acceptable to your
peers,
you seldom have to regulate your own
behavior because they'll regulate it for
you.
Right?
And so when you're out in the world,
I mean you guys are all sitting there in
a particular way,
partly because if you deviated from the
appropriate way to sit there,
whatever that is,
if you deviated from that sufficiently,
the group would turn on you right away.
So as long as you're awake enough to
respond to the subtle cues that people
are giving you,
you don't even have to worry about the
internal inhibitory problem.
Now what you want is you want your
nervous system is organized in a way so
that it fits well into the overall
organization of the society.
And there has to be cross talk between
notes.
But Society exists,
right?
So anything society will do to regulate
you,
you don't have to do.
And that's really useful.
It's an outsourcing problem,
you know,
and there's lots of things you
outsource.
So one of the things is think about
something like self esteem.
Self esteem is a very,
I don't like the word because self
esteem is really something like
extroversion minus neuroticism.
It's,
it's close to that.
But let's,
let's,
so let's look at it in a slightly
different way.
Let's say,
well how valuable should you regard
yourself?
And so then you think,
well that,
so and then we might think,
well maybe that has something to do with
competence.
Okay,
well,
so how competent are you?
Well,
the answer to that is you really don't
know and there's actually no way of
telling.
So your nervous system has to guess.
And the way it does that is that first
you're put on a normal distribution for
negative emotion and that you're just
sort of given that at birth.
That's your temperament.
And then the socialization can pull that
one way or another.
I know it can,
it can make you more stable or less
stable depending on how you interact
with your parents and the immediate
environment and how dangerous the
environment is.
And then the next thing you do is you
observe yourself operating in the world
and you see how good you are at solving
problems and that adjusts it.
And then everyone else is broadcasting
to you all the time what your
comparative value is.
And so that's,
that's really how you establish an
estimate of your competence.
And it's almost always comparative
competence because the question in most
groups isn't,
can you do something?
It is,
but the real question is,
can you do something as well or better
than anyone else in this particular
group?
Because there's no absolute standard for
being,
being able to do things precisely.
You know,
everyone is insufficient when you think
of the,
the ultimate task,
right?
Because people's knowledge have limits.
So the question is,
well,
are you up for the challenge compared to
the people around you?
So it's,
it's a very complex calibration process
and it certainly doesn't all take place
inside.
It can't,
you're not,
you're not complex enough to do that.
And it's foolish anyways,
you know,
partly what the stock market does.
The stock market has a massive
conversation about the relative value of
property.
Roughly speaking and it it,
it,
it moves around a lot because you think
about all the variables that are
beating,
taking into account at the same time,
it's not only every company and every
commodity in relationship to every other
company in every other commodity.
It's also all that in relationship to
the price of all the currencies and that
takes into account political stability
or instability in disease and
catastrophe and hurricanes and so on and
so forth like that has,
there has to be something dynamic and
ongoing that enables those calculations
to be made because there it's
incalculable otherwise,
and the same thing is true in some sense
of your competence.
You can't calculate that on your own.
You have to have help and so that's
partly why the group also decides where
you are in the dominance hierarchy.
Now the group could also under or
overshoot that happens lots of times,
you know,
because maybe the local environment that
you're in isn't a very good
representative of the broader
environment.
This happens to lots of smart people in
high school,
for example,
or junior high where if they're
intelligent,
that is not necessarily socially
valuable for a number of years.
And if the person who's intelligent
doesn't get out of that environment into
an environment where intelligence is
valued.
So hopefully that's a university,
then you know their,
their actual potential isn't going to be
valued by the dominance hierarchy in
proper keeping with its,
with its actual re real world value.
So anyways,
okay.
So the issue is,
and this is the ethical issue is this is
the ethical issue is how do you
hierarchically organize these
subpersonalities because you might
think,
well why do you have to hierarchically
organize them to begin with?
Now there's an element here for the
postmodernists you can think of of this.
So 130 years ago,
Nietzsche announced that God was dead,
right?
And so that was a rep that was a
reflection of the collapse in some sense
of the believability of traditional
religions.
And you can think of traditional
religions as a coherent overarching
narrative.
Now,
you might argue about how coherent
coherent it is,
but they're pretty coherent.
That doesn't necessarily mean that
they're accurate,
but they're pretty coherent.
So the slats were pulled out from
underneath those structures.
Now what happened during the 20th
century was two things and one was some
of those religious narratives were
replaced by ideological narratives and
that turned out to be a really bad idea.
And so that was one stream of thought in
some sense stemming from Nietzsche,
or at least from his observation,
there was another stream of thought
which basically said if religious
structures have collapsed and they had
two,
that means all grand narratives have
collapsed.
And that's really a postmodernist claim.
But the problem with that claim is you
can't act unless you have a hierarchy of
values because you can't figure out what
to do next.
Also,
you can't even figure out if you should
do anything,
but you certainly can't figure out what
to do next because in order to organize
your behavior and move forward,
you have to say that one thing is more
important than many other things,
right?
Every time you act,
you're making that decision.
Now you might say,
well,
you can only make that decision at a
micro level,
like what's best now.
But people who do that are impulsive.
That's how we define them.
And that doesn't work out well across
time.
You know what they're doing is
responding to,
um,
in some sense,
instinctual whims moment by moment,
that doesn't seem very sophisticated.
You don't want someone round like that.
You can't predict what they're going to
do.
You can't cooperate with them,
they can't follow rules.
You can't have a project with them,
you can't trust them.
It's like that isn't going to.
And so the idea that grand narratives
are obsolete is it's based on a
misunderstanding of exactly what the
narratives are.
And it's also based on absence of
realization that a narrative is
primarily something you act out before
you represent.
So a narrative can be latent.
So let me give you an example of that.
So
I thought it puzzled about this for a
long time.
I'd say you go out and watch a
chimpanzee troop.
Now we know of the chimps are organized
in a dominance hierarchy and we know
that the dominance hierarchy among
chimps is male dominated.
The females have a dormant,
it's hierarchy too,
but the fundamental dominant Turkey's
male dominated.
It's not like that so much with barnum
bolts by the way,
which are very much like chips.
But so you can watch the chimps and you
can see that chimp a knows the chimp B
is higher up in the dominance hierarchy
and Chimp d knows the C is higher up in
the dominance hierarchy and you can even
see that the offspring,
like if you have a high dominant female
and she has offspring,
all the other chimps know that you don't
mess around with her offspring because
she's a dominant female.
So that the,
the mapping of the dominance hierarchy,
the mapping is quite sophisticated.
So then you might say,
well the chimps are following rules so,
but then you think,
well no they're not because they don't,
they don't actually know rules because
while it,
cause you got to ask what exactly is a
rule,
right?
Oh well that's a good question.
Like a rule seems to be the articulation
of a principal,
but it seems to be something that you
have to represent.
Like you say,
well,
a rule is chimp be always submits to
chimp.
A,
that's the rule that the is following,
but the chip isn't following rules
because the chimp doesn't have rules,
but there's regularities there and so
what?
Those really are a behavioral patterns.
They're not rules.
Now,
understanding that is extremely useful
because what you can understand is that
regularities in complex social behavior
can emerge in the absence of any
conscious representation,
any consciously articulated
representation of those rules.
Because you might ask,
well,
where do moral presuppositions come
from?
Assuming that,
say religious systems,
for example,
are concerned with moral presuppositions
and that social systems are concerned
with those two,
where do they come from?
Well,
there's lots of theories about that,
right?
The Marxists would say,
well,
it's all about exploitation and an
economic advantage,
and a postmodernist would say it's all
about exclusion and power because
they're sort of quasi Marxist sorted.
They're quasi marxists.
Anyways,
there's always this there and,
and you know what Karl Marx,
for Karl Marx,
religion was the opiate of the people
and he thought about it as a structure
that it emerged because the power elites
wanted to dominate the,
the,
you know,
the people who weren't empowered to
extract out value from them.
And it's like there's no doubt that
there can be an element of exploitation
in any social system.
And there's no doubt that social systems
are hierarchical so that there are
people on the top and people on the
bottom.
But in human society,
there's lots of dominance hierarchies.
There's not just one.
And we value lots of different things
from people.
And it's by no means obvious that the
dominance hierarchies were set up
consciously through conscious thought by
any group of people over any span of
time for any purpose whatsoever.
It's particularly obvious when you also
understand that while we are not the
only things that have dominance
hierarchies,
chimps have them,
wolves have them.
That's why you can have a pet dog.
You understand the dog,
you know it doesn't even want to be the
boss in the house.
That's a nervous and upset dog.
It wants to have its position as a
valued low level entity in the dominance
hierarchy.
And a dog is just absolutely happy when
that happens.
So you know,
cause what is the dog gonna do buy
groceries?
It's like no it's not.
So it has to be low in the,
in the dominance hierarchy because it
doesn't have the competence.
And one of the things that's very,
very bizarre about Marxist and
postmodernist thinking is that there
doesn't seem to be any recognition that
dominance hierarchies are often
structured based on competence.
No one on like arbitrary distribution of
power.
I mean if you want to go have your
appendix out,
what are you going to look for?
Are you going to look for the most
powerful doctor or you can look for the
most competent doctor.
Well you hope that there's a rough
relationship between power and status
and competence,
right?
Because otherwise how are you going to
figure it out?
But if it's a good hierarchy,
it's based on competence,
not on arbitrary power.
So we might say that when a dominance
hierarchy starts to be based on
arbitrary power or purely on economics
on economic terms than it's actually
turned into a tyranny.
It's no longer a functional heart
hierarchy.
It's already stultified and twisted into
a form that can't be sustained.
And then people are going to get upset
about that and start talking about it.
Or or worse,
they're going to start doing things that
are quite disrupted.
But the idea that the hierarchical
structure per se is pathological or that
it's consciously imposed or that it's
not necessary or that it has,
it has nothing to do with competence.
It's like,
no,
that's just that better not be the case
because we would be in serious trouble
if it was the case.
So I would say the more,
the more functional the society,
the more the,
the power hierarchy is based on
competence in relationship to what the
society deems is actually valuable.
Now in not,
obviously no society meets those
criteria perfectly because you can't,
it's,
it's part of a dialogue and a continual
processing of information,
you know,
so you can't hit the target always
moving,
but you can hope that the dialogue
continues.
So here's,
here's a little vision I had of how
things work,
like a democratic society works okay,
because people often think if they're
conservative,
orderly,
low and openness,
then they think the conservatives are
right.
And if they're more on the liberal or on
the left side,
high in openness,
low and orderliness,
than they think that the left is
correct.
But,
but the left and the right aren't
correct.
They represent different systems of
values and the values that they
represent are valid sometimes in some
situations.
And then the question is,
well,
when and in what situations?
And the answer to that is not only did
not know,
you can't tell.
And so it's like this.
So imagine that people are on a cliff.
It's like they're on a flat plateau and
it's a cliff on both sides.
And down at the bottom of the cliff is
fire and rocks.
And so you want to stay on top of that
cliff and it's quite narrow and there's
a line you should walk down right down
the middle,
but you can't tell where it is.
So what do you do?
You put all the left these here and you
put all the right wingers here and you
put a rope between them and you tie the
rope to you and the right pull this way
in the left poles that way.
And if they're pulling properly,
then you can walk right down the middle.
But the only way they can pull property
is if they keep talking to one another,
you know?
And if,
if the left disappears,
then the right pulls everything over the
cliff,
down into the flaming rocks.
And if the left disappears,
then the right pulls everything off the
cliff,
down onto the rocks.
And we know that.
We know that.
And there's been good personality models
developed recently.
They're not public yet precisely.
That show that if you push a virtue to
its extreme,
it turns into a vice and that all the
vices that basically ended up in the
same place.
Yes.
What would you say happens if both sides
are talking a lot but not to one
another?
Like if there's a lot of preaching to
the choir.
Well its dysfunction.
It's dysfunction
because I was thinking about modern
American politics where they can
actually show with data that it's
increasingly polarized,
like just increasingly left and right
and subcultures.
Well what what it means.
What that means is that people can't get
along.
That's what it means.
And you know,
you can say,
well part of getting along is following
a shared set of rules and that's true.
But the rules are kind of low
resolution.
But to get along like you think about
your family,
if your family is structured so that
it's just a bunch of rules and you
better damn follow them or there'll be
punishment,
you know that can be better than just
sheer chaos,
but it's not as good as general
principles encompassing continual
dialogue that works best.
And you know,
you might think,
well what are the general principles and
what we'd hope our,
well we can look at what people have
done in the past and we can look at our
history and our culture and we can
think,
okay,
we're going to try to,
we're going to try not to do the things
that people have done in the past that
are evidently stupid.
Like maybe Nazi-ism isn't the way to go
for example.
So we're going to see not what we're
going to try not to do that.
We can extract out those general
principles,
but then we have to talk continually in
the present because the present keeps
moving around.
There's no way of mapping it using a
structure from the past.
You can only approximate,
you know,
it's like,
if you took up a google map of Toronto
from 10 years ago and you said,
well this is the map,
it's not going to be updated.
It's like you'd have a real rough time
driving around the waterfront cause
you'd keep running into skyscrapers that
you know,
aren't supposed to be there.
And so there's,
the map is obviously useful,
but the update process is also
unbelievably useful.
And you can also say,
if you look at left and right,
you can roughly say that the left is on
the side of update and the right is on
the side of structure.
And you might say,
well how much update and how much
structure?
It's like enough to solve the problem.
That's the answer.
What's the problem?
Keeps changing.
How do we keep up,
we talk.
And part of that also is like if you're
talking,
most of you guys are lefties because
most of you are open and not very
orderly.
Now there is going to be exceptions in
here,
but,
and you're young because youth is often
associated with,
with political beliefs that are more in
the left.
And I think that's because you're in a
more plastic state of,
of development,
right?
There's still a lot of things open to
you.
So,
but the thing about it is that you have
to get along with the right.
And that's partly because the right
represents what's already there.
So how do you do that?
Well,
that's hard.
But the one thing you definitely do is
listen,
you try to figure out what the hell
they're up to,
you know,
and why and what they stand for and the
value of that and where it's too extreme
and it's not easy.
But that's,
that's why a democracy is a dialogue and
not,
that's how it regulates itself is
through the dialogue.
Okay.
So what you're basically trying to do is
or integrate your abilities,
your sub personalities,
which is how I'm going to represented
into a functional hierarchy.
And a functional hierarchy is one where
the subsidiary parts of the hierarchy
don't conflict.
So let me give you an example.
You can tell me what I based this on the
Piagetian notion of the equilla braided
state.
So Piaget had this idea that there's two
ways you might be able to run an
organization.
So say you're moving towards a
collectively defined goal and one would
be to put someone at the top of it and
kind of give them complete control,
tyrannical power.
And so that meant you were going to do
what that person said or else.
Okay.
Now,
the problem with that is that that
person isn't always going to be right
and that you're not always going to be
happy about doing what they say.
And that the fact that you're not happy
means you're not going to be as
productive.
And it also means that the organization
is going to have to expand quite a lot
of energy keeping you in line.
Okay?
So here's an alternative.
Alternative is,
here's the goal.
Okay,
well let's agree on some general
principles in relationship to the goal.
And then let's negotiate.
So one of the things I did with my kids
when they were teenagers was,
you know that there's a certain set of
procedures that have to be undertaken in
a household in order for that household.
The function,
right?
So roughly speaking,
people need to eat.
It should be clean enough so that
contamination isn't a problem.
It shouldn't be.
It shouldn't be so messy that it's
impossible to do anything that you want
to do when house.
You know what Cetera,
there's,
there's guidelines that we all basically
implicitly understand that that
constitute a well regulated familial
environment.
Well.
So then how do you obtain that?
And one of the processes that I put into
place was we would meet and parse up the
jobs and come to a solution.
And the rule was you can't leave the
discussion until the solution is found.
You have to accept the solution unless
you can come up with a better one and
that will implement it over a period of
time and see how it works.
And that work,
I wouldn't say it worked perfectly
because nothing works perfectly,
but it's a good process because it
brings everyone into the game.
They get to define the,
and they get to define the game.
They get to define the rules,
they get to define the processes by
which those rules will be enforced.
They get to run it as a simulation and
see how it works.
And then at some point later they get to
have another discussion about it.
But you don't want to be discussing in
every,
you know,
every time there's dishes to be done,
you won't want to discuss the entire
moral substructure of the whole
household.
You know,
and dishes are a big deal because
they're part of dishes and cooking are a
big deal because they are part of the,
there's a tremendous conflict in that
area because of,
because of the role
rapid roll transformation that
characterized men and women's since the
pill was invented.
So it's a place where,
you know,
massive social transformations manifest
themselves in local landscapes.
And that's also why solving the problems
in your local landscape is also the way
of solving the big problems.
You know,
it's like who does the dishes when and
why and what are the rewards and
punishments associated with that?
Solve that.
And you solve like 30% of the tension
between men and women.
So,
and that means it's really hard to
solve.
It's not obvious how you do that and how
you do that over the long run and what
the reward should be and how valuable it
is.
So et Cetera,
et cetera.
It takes an awful lot of negotiation.
But if you don't get it right,
then you have a continual war in your
household and you pay for that.
Because if you're having a war in your
household,
then you're going to be stressed to
death and will kill you.
So it's no joke to get these things
right and when you're doing it,
it's applied philosophy.
It's sophisticated and applied
philosophy because that's all you have.
If you don't have roles,
right roles,
you don't negotiate and that's good
cause you don't know how to negotiate.
No rules.
It's negotiation,
slavery,
or tyranny.
Those are your options.
So these are very complicated problems.
That's also the why.
When you,
when you work hard to solve them in the
domain that you have in your hands,
you're also doing the best you can
possibly do to figure out how that might
scale up on a broader,
in a broader way.
Right.
I read a great book once called
Systematics,
written by a guy named John Galt.
It's a really fast,
fantastic book.
Yeah,
I know John Galt,
weird enough,
man was actually his name.
John Galt is the name of a fictional
character in an Ayn rand book and he's
one person who stops the world because
for a variety of reasons,
he stops the industrial world because
he's thinking he's getting exploited.
It's had a huge effect on modern
American monetary policy by the way.
So anyways,
this Guy John Galt has written a whole
bunch of axioms about organizational
structure,
which are quite brilliant.
And there's a couple I really remembered
in.
One is the organization does not do what
it's name says it does.
I love that one.
It's so smart.
So,
and the second one was large functional
organizations grow out of small
functional organizations.
So if you want to build something big,
you have to start it small and local and
then figure out how to make it scale.
And in some sense that's what you're
doing,
that's what you're doing and your
relationships with other people and
that's what you're doing in your
familial situation.
That's what you're doing in your
intimate relationships.
You solve those problems.
You,
you develop a template,
like a skilled template of perception
and action that you can then bring out
into the broader world.
It's really important.
So,
so partly,
you know,
you inherit a hierarchical structure and
you might think about that as whatever
principles bind your culture together.
And then some of that's rigid and
pathological and half dead and needs to
be destroyed and re updated and some of
it isn't.
And you have to figure that out by
negotiation.
And that's hard,
but you don't want to blow the whole
damn thing down in one gasp,
like the bad wolf and the straw house.
It's like then you have nothing to live
in.
So you want him,
you want to make modifications in a
culturally determined structure with
caution and care because that is all
that stops you.
That's all that protects you from chaos
apart from your ability to update your
models.
And you blow that over and you find out
what's behind it.
And part of what's behind it is the
dragon of chaos and the terrible mother.
It's not good.
You know,
you saw what happened to Iraq when the
American's knocked over the hierarchy,
right?
It wasn't good.
No,
it wasn't good before cause it was a
tyranny.
But it's clearly,
it's not obvious that it's better now,
you know,
and it,
it's also possible that what's going to
happen is it's going to be replaced by a
way,
worse tyranny.
So northover is structure.
The water comes flooding in.
It's just like a dyke or a or a dam.
So,
all right,
so that's your problem.
Now,
you know,
I set that up as part of a moral
hierarchy.
So at the bottom of any process,
you say,
well,
maybe you're trying to be a good person.
We might,
what might as well assume that.
You might say why,
but my answer to that would be because
it's better than not being a good
person.
You're gonna run into a lot less pain
and misery and you're going to be a lot
less destructive and you're going to
hurt a lot fewer people.
And you might leave everything better
than you found it.
And that's not so bad.
It's certainly better than doing the
reverse of all of those things.
So unless you think there's something
particularly positively valuable about
pain and misery because,
and that seems to be,
you could make that case,
but if I put you in pain and misery,
you do everything you could to get out.
So even if you thought that that was a
reasonable solution,
if I imposed it on you,
you do everything you possibly could to
escape.
So all that means is that you don't know
what the hell you're talking about.
Okay?
So because what you act out is more
representative of who you are than what
you say.
Because what the hell do you know about
yourself?
You have a vague model of who you are
and if vague model of society,
and so you can wrap off some articulated
representations,
but the probability that they're going
to really map the underlying structure
is low.
So,
okay,
so we'll assume you're going to be a
good person.
That's what you're striving for.
And then we can decompose that and you
can decompose it all the way down to
micro behaviors.
And so the issue is you try to build a
hierarchy at the bottom.
It has all your micro behaviors,
you know the things you can do with your
hands and your eyes and your mouth and
your body.
That's the highest resolution level.
And then you're trying to organize those
into higher and higher into more and
more abstract and powerful structures in
some sense that are also homogenous
inside.
They're not full of internal
contradictions.
So that's how you establish peace.
It's how you establish psychological
stability and that's how you establish
peace.
And there has to be negotiations at all
of those levels.
And roughly speaking,
it's better to negotiate at the low
levels and you can do it,
you know?
So I use this example fairly frequently.
It's like,
so you've got a four year old kid in
their room is a mess because they'd been
playing and you think,
well that room can't be a mess.
Why?
Well,
it's hard to play in a messy room that
that might be one answer.
So you have to restructure it so that
you can have so that you can play again,
that's part of why it should be clean.
So then you tell the four year old clean
up this room and then you leave and then
you come back and it's like nothing's
happened.
And the reason for that in part perhaps
is because that's the wrong level of
resolution to solve the problem at with
regards to the four year old,
you could only say clean up your room,
which would be maybe at the same level
as say family care there to someone who
has the underlying structures already in
place.
So you might say to the child,
see your shelf.
And they can do that because they know
how to follow pointing and they know how
to specify an absence and they know how
to link that to language.
So they will do that.
See that hole?
Yes.
Okay.
So you know the person has enough skill
underneath that abstraction to implement
it.
Fine.
Then you say see that bear and you know
they can manage that.
So they look at the bear and you say,
well,
pick up the bear.
You know they can do that.
So they pick up the bear and you'd give
them a pat and then you say,
put the bear in this space.
And they do that and they look at,
you need to give them a pat.
And it's like,
and if you do that with a child for the
whole room three or four times,
then what you're doing is building the
under structures right from the bottom
up.
And then you can say clean up your room.
So,
but if the child,
so exempt for example,
you come back in the room isn't clean,
you might think,
well what do you do about a child who's
being intransigent and won't clean up
their room?
And answer is,
well,
the first thing you do is make sure that
that's the right level of instruction.
And that's the case.
Also,
if you're negotiating with a partner or
an intimate partner,
the first thing you should assume if
they do something stupid,
which they certainly will,
is that they're stupid,
you know,
and that you have to help them out.
Building the micro structures of
whatever it is that you're asking them
to do because people aren't,
people are full of gaping holes and they
lack social skills of all sorts.
It's like,
and it's a huge part of the tension
between friends and between couples.
It's like its absence of ability.
And so you do your person a great favor.
If you say um,
you know,
you forgot my birthday,
okay well what am I supposed to do about
that?
While you might say well that's up to
you to figure it out.
So No,
assume I'm stupid and tell me exactly
what you want.
And then you'll say well that doesn't
really mean anything.
And I'll say yeah but we're going to be
like together for 30 years.
So if you teach me this one time and
it's kind of awkward and stupid then
maybe the next time it'll be 50% better.
You know,
cause well cause you're looking at a
trajectory,
right?
And so you can build,
cause one of the things,
look,
one of the things you could think about
for example,
is let's say you make a meal.
Okay.
Now let's say your,
your,
your goal is to make a really good meal
in an efficient way so that everybody's
really happy about it,
including you,
so that the probability that you'll get
to eat lots of really good meals across
your whole life goes up not to good
solution.
So then you might think,
okay,
I made this meal and it was,
it was a costly expenditure of time,
and I have to be paid for that in some
way in order to be happy about it.
So let's,
let's,
let's think about that for a minute
because it's a concrete product.
So let's say you spent a bunch of time
making a good meal.
Okay?
What do you,
what do you not want people to do?
Yeah.
Okay.
So they're not supposed to say,
Ooh,
what's this?
Hmm.
Okay,
that's a bad response.
What else do you not want them to do?
Not enjoyed.
Right,
right,
right.
Okay,
so there's not going to be a lot of
bickering at the table,
right?
Because then you're going to think what
kind of stupid idiot would make a nice
meal for this lot of like insane
chimpanzees.
Right?
So you're not going to want to replicate
that.
What else would,
would you,
would you want them not to do?
Not Finish it.
Yup.
Okay.
What else?
Not help clean up.
Yeah.
Right.
Not Be grateful.
Not Notice that you put a lot of time
and effort into it.
Not notice that it's above the normal
standards that you sort of went above
and beyond the call of duty.
Right?
Maybe show a little bit of thankfulness.
Yeah.
So then you think,
okay,
well I want to set up my life so that I
get to eat really good meals for the
rest of my life and be happy about
making them.
He's like,
okay,
well what are the preconditions for
that?
Well then you have to fight for the
preconditions because the alternative is
you cook slop miserably and you fight.
Right.
And one of the things that's interesting
about,
one of the things that I don't have to
do with my clients is we do some
arithmetic because people have a weird
idea about what's important in their
life.
So you might think you got 16 hours a
day of awake time,
right?
So,
and you're going to spend four of those
hours,
three of those hours interacting with
food.
Okay?
So that's,
let's say for let's say three.
It's one fifth of your life,
20% of your life.
Okay,
get it right.
Get it right.
It's 20% of your life you got to taking
care of.
Wow,
perfect.
You know,
you think,
well,
who's going to think about think through
those things?
It's like,
well,
do the math.
It's not math,
it's arithmetic.
It's like,
you know,
and so sometimes people will come to me
and they'll say,
I have to fight with my child for an
hour a night to get them to go to bed.
I think,
okay,
let's do the arithmetic.
So how long have you been fighting with
them?
Six months.
How long do you think this will
continue?
Indefinitely?
Two years.
Okay.
So let's say it's two years.
Okay?
So that's,
we're going to say that's 800 days for
the sake of simplicity in math,
let's say.
Yeah,
we'll say 800 and so that's 800 hours.
And so that's 20 work weeks.
So in the next two years you're going to
spend five months of work weeks fighting
with your child.
Okay?
You expect to like them at the end of
that,
do you,
it's like you're going to fight with
someone for like five months and you're
going to like them.
No,
that isn't going to happen.
So you might think,
well,
how important is it to solve that
problem?
Well,
it's five months of work,
weeks worth of importance.
You could put a week into it and you
know,
it might be helpful.
And so it's,
it's very,
okay.
I'm trying to make a case that you have
to look at the hierarchy,
the hierarchical structure of your
values,
you know?
And the best way to do that often is by
paying close attention to things that
people,
normally they're invisible.
Normally they're invisible and that's
not good.
You have to fix them.
And if you fix all those things,
a little tiny things,
if you fix them,
which is hard,
you know,
it takes negotiation but it's not
impossible,
you know,
cause it's the first thing you want to
ask your partner or your family is,
well,
how would we like to have a meal?
You want wretched,
nasty food that someone just threw
together and it's burnt and we're going
to fight about it all the time.
And it's really erratic and it's not
predictable.
And,
and the person who's making it as
unhappy and the kitchen is a disaster
afterwards and everybody's angry about
that.
So that's like one solution.
Do you want that?
And if they all are sensible enough to
say no,
then then you can say to them,
okay,
well what's the alternative?
And then you can think,
well,
we could imagine what the alternative
would be and then we can work on laying
out the microprocessors that would lead
to that outcome.
And we can practice them over time.
And we can assume that if we don't get
it right in three months,
that doesn't mean it's hopeless.
And so
when Freud,
let me give you an example.
I was reading a Gartman study the other
day on marital stability.
Gottman has done some really good
analysis of couples behavior.
He has set up a lab that's basically a
bed and breakfast and he brings couples
in there for a weekend and he wires the
mop physiologically and monitors their
reactivity.
And so what he's,
he can predict whether a couple's going
to divorce with 95 94% accuracy.
It's like impressive.
So what does he found?
He's found two categories of he's,
he's identified two phenomena that are
very much worth knowing.
The first is that the couples who are
going to get divorced and they come into
the bed and breakfast and they speak
with each other quite commonly,
but it's more walking on eggs calm and
well,
they're speaking with each other calmly.
Their physiology is like,
they're very aroused and so,
so they're sort of aroused like someone
who's facing a predator.
So you might think about an unhappy
couple as Predator and prey to each
other.
And so the words are there mostly to
stop predatory activity,
not to actually communicate anything.
It's just to keep the surface comp.
So then you might think,
well what's under the surface?
And one,
it's under the surface.
So Freud would say it's what's under the
surface is unconscious and,
but you can say,
well,
what's under the surface is one of these
hierarchies that's all banged up and
twisted and,
and,
and not in reasonable shape.
And so people don't want to open the
door to that.
So,
but they do.
This is a Freudian slip.
So let's say this,
this goes to the second part of
Gottman's observations.
So the woman goes over to the window and
she says,
oh look,
there's a cardinal outside,
you know,
cardinals,
that bright red bird,
that kind of cool looking,
you know,
it's kind of a trivial thing in some
sense.
But by the same token,
it's like,
it's a little positive thing.
And you know,
20 of them in a day is good thing.
Okay.
So then the,
uh,
the partner,
the husband in this example has a two by
two matrix of choices.
One is,
who the hell cares about your stupid
bird?
Okay,
so that's one.
The second one is then you go over and
look at the bird,
right?
And then the third one is you don't make
the contempt noise but yanked it out.
And the fourth one is you go over there
like a civilized human being and you
know,
and that you're interacting with someone
that you care for and you take a look at
the damn bird and you're happy about it
and it,
and that's as truthful and real as you
can manage.
Okay,
so the option,
that's a Freudian slip,
right?
Because what it says,
there's a whole monster underneath that.
And the monster is all the
disorganization in this entire
structure.
It's like the might be,
we have been tormenting each other about
various things for the last 10 years and
none of them are resolved.
And I'm not very happy about you for so
many reasons.
I can't even remember all of them.
And I'm,
I can't enumerate them right now because
that would take forever.
And it may be,
we would have a huge fight,
but by the same token,
I'm not going to come over there and
make you happy with your stupid bird.
And I'm going to indicate that subtly.
So you can't call me a son of a bitch
because I've just sighing and that's
what I'll say if you do ask me.
But I'm going to load all that up and
I'm going to deliver it to you.
And what's going to happen to you is
because you're smart is your heart
rate's going to go way up,
like you're being attacked.
And the reason for that is you are.
So what the good couples do,
the couples that you know stay together
is they respond to each other's bids,
he calls them bids.
And so if one person wants to share some
little trivial daily positive thing with
the other,
you know,
isn't carrying around a bloody cartload
of resentment and is able to respond to
that in a positive way.
And that way the general interactions
between the couple stay positive,
but that's also because they've worked
this out.
Now,
you know it's gotta be because they work
it out because the couples who are
physiologically reactive to each other,
they're communicating,
but there's all sorts of horror
underneath the surface and we're trying
to figure out,
well,
what is it that's underneath the
surface?
What's the structure of the unconscious?
Well,
that's the structure of the unconscious
and it's either well structured and
functional and mutually agreed to porn
and as explicit as possible,
or it's this constantly and then when
the couples fight about it,
yes,
because they're not very sophisticated
and they're not very awake and they're
not very aware and they don't know how
to do micro analysis and they're tired
and unhappy.
They don't say,
I would rather that you use cloth
napkins when we have a formal dinner.
Then paper Napkins,
they say you do a bad job of
entertaining.
Well,
that's not helpful,
right?
It's like you're wiping out the person.
That bad job of entertaining would be
probably about at the level of family
care in the hierarchy.
And so what you're doing is you're
hitting them in a place that if they
listened to you would knock out maybe
10% of their entire be behavioral and
perceptual structure.
It's like you really want to do that to
some,
you only want to do that to someone
under extreme conditions,
right?
Extreme conditions.
And that would be something like,
okay,
maybe a warning to a child who's gone
astray very badly,
but you know,
has the skills,
you'd say,
well,
the kind of mistakes that you're making
are sufficiently catastrophic so that
your life is going to go off course,
you know?
And then you might have a conversation
with them about,
often for kids,
for guide,
for people that say are between 15 and
25 I know they're not kids really,
but my kids are that age.
Part of that might be,
what the hell are you going to do for a
career?
Right?
And if that's an unspecified,
the person's just all over the place.
So,
okay,
so,
so here's some slides that represent
that.
Great.
So you see the progression of that.
And if,
if things are operating at the top of
the hierarchy that what that means is
you've mastered all the subsidiary
elements and you've built them.
It's not only from the bottom up,
but because the levels crosstalk,
right?
You know,
so you can use,
and that's the next thing we're going to
talk about because you're not just a
behavioral creature.
You're not just an animal like a chimp.
You're capable.
There's,
there's things you can do that animals
can't do.
And what that is,
is that not only can you act things out
in a manner that through action,
we'll organize your hierarchy because
that's what animals do.
But you can also represent that
hierarchy.
You can think about the hierarchy,
you can articulate the hierarchy and you
can play with it abstractly.
And that's what you're doing when you're
engaging in philosophy.
And that's also what you're doing when
you're negotiating.
And that's a really good thing because
it means that you can not only
conceptualize changes and then implement
them.
And,
and you can conceptualize a broad range
of potential potential changes and
improvements and you can implement them
and you can observe what happens.
But you can also communicate that to all
sorts of other people.
So it's a great thing to be able to do.
The problem with it is obviously that
because you can abstractly represent and
question,
you can also knock the hell out of your
belief in the top elements of the
hierarchy.
It's like,
well what does it mean to be a good
person anyways?
You know?
Or why should I be a good person?
Or is there any,
is there any utility or meaning and
being a good person?
Or is there even any,
isn't even reasonable to say that there
is such a thing.
He's a good person.
It's like I think all of those questions
in some sense are ill post.
And the reason I think that is because
they're at the wrong level of
resolution.
You know,
you don't throw the damn baby out with
the bath water so to speak.
So if you're going to critique
something,
don't start.
Don't start at the highest level of
abstraction.
And I think that's a big part of what's
wrong with what people are taught in
universities today because you're often
talked to criticize systems at the
highest level of obstruction.
It's like,
well,
there's something wrong with capitalism.
It's like,
really?
Really?
You're going to do something about that?
Are you,
and it's going to work better in your
lifetime.
That's going to happen.
It's like,
no,
it's not going to happen.
You know,
if you stick a stick in the,
in a functioning machine,
even if you think the machine,
it's all rattling and it's like pulling
people's arms in and it's got all sorts
of catastrophic problems.
You come home and like hit it with a
stick.
It's like it's not going to run better.
It's the wrong level of analysis.
And just because you have a stick and
you can see that the machine doesn't
work very well,
it doesn't mean that you're very bright.
It's like obviously it doesn't work very
well,
you know?
It's like that's not the issue.
The issue is could you improve it
without making it worse?
It's like now that's a big problem.
It's a big problem.
So you know,
you have a wheelchair,
you know,
and the bearings are gone.
So the bloody thing just grinds away,
you know?
And maybe it's wobbly.
It doesn't work very well on ice.
You know,
when you think,
well that's a horrible wheelchair and
you just take it from the person.
It's like then they're lying there on
the ice,
you know?
It's like,
oh,
that's helpful while you're,
you don't have that horrible wheelchair
anymore.
It's like,
yeah,
brilliant.
It's like so like a rattle trap thing
that works is better than nothing.
So if you're going to fix something,
well then you have to be,
I would think about it more like what
you would do if you had to fix a
helicopter.
You know,
like you're not going to critique the
whole helicopter now.
It's not going to be helpful.
It's like,
wow,
that's not a good helicopter.
Right.
We can tell that because it's not
working very well.
Well what are you going to do?
Well then you have to learn a lot about
the helicopter and all of its parts and
how they function.
And then you have to figure out which
part isn't working properly and then you
have to take that part out and then you
have to find a better park and you have
to put it back in.
And then maybe the bloody thing or work,
but like a high level abstract solution
to that.
Like helicopters aren't useful.
It's like not helpful.
And I use the helicopter example because
with a military helicopter,
if I remember correctly,
you have to perform about 30 hours of
maintenance for each hour.
The thing is in the air because like
what's a helicopter?
It's a big lump of metal.
It's really hard to get those things to
stay in the air.
So,
and everything we do is like that,
you know,
it's like the fact that the electricity
is working in this room is a bloody
miracle.
Like it's unbelievable that it works and
there it is working.
We don't even have to pay any attention
to it and it always works.
It's like don't fix that.
Right.
It's a major response.
Denial isn't,
yeah,
cause that's what we're trying to do
here.
We're trying to figure out what the
meaning of life.
Yes.
That's the big talk on Thursday.
Yeah,
right,
right.
Well,
you should.
So that's also part of what people talk
about when they talk about humility.
Because if you look at classic religious
virtues,
and this is true,
I believe it's true of virtually every
religious system that I've been able to
study.
You know,
it's like humility.
Okay,
so what does that mean?
Start at the bottom.
You know,
it's like fix the little things.
But then the other thing is little
things aren't little.
You just,
you know,
they're,
they're not little.
And we already went through that with
the example of mealtime.
It's like,
well,
how much fuss should you make about
meals?
What's 20% of your life?
So how much faster would you make about
that?
Well,
you should expand 20% of your energy
getting that right.
And if you get it right,
it's like an art,
right?
Because,
because meal preparation,
it's,
people are highly social.
They're highly social eaters.
If they're not eating socially,
they're eating goes badly right away.
They can't regulate their intake and
they eat terribly.
You see this with isolated people all
the time,
they don't even eat.
Or if they do eat,
it's like popcorn and,
and you know,
gummy worms or something.
It's really not good.
And so it's very eating behavior among
human beings is very,
very complex.
We're omnivores,
so we have way too much choice.
Plus we're social eaters,
you know,
so it's hard to get that right,
but,
and if you don't get it right,
everyone's sick and miserable and
unhappy and irritable.
So,
and if you get it right,
it's like you bring it right up to the
level of aesthetics and art.
It was like,
that's way better.
So you know when also when you're
thinking about things like the meaning
of life,
life has all sorts of meanings,
many,
many meanings.
And then the meetings are arranged in a
hierarchy.
And so whether there's an meaning or
many meanings depend on where you look
in the hierarchy.
But if you want your life to be better,
which might be some element of
meaningful life,
you know,
one of the things you can start doing is
start doing all the things that you
actually do right?
Oh,
that'll improve things a lot.
And then once once you improve those
things and then the way you're looking
at the problem isn't even going to be
the same pit,
fixed the micro routines and then see
what happens.
It's like you might find that if you get
all the micro routines running properly,
the whole problem of nihilism just
vanishes.
So at least it's worth a shot.
So,
okay,
now here's the next thing we're going to
figure out is like how does that
hierarchy come into being now for a long
time,
this is also a Nietzsche in observation
for a long time,
and this is also,
this is also the basis of conspiracy
theory,
conspiracy sits theory,
sociology.
I would say roughly speaking,
it's like Freud critiqued religion.
He said that it was a defense against
death anxiety.
It's like
there's a,
there's a couple of problems with a
critique like that.
It's like
it's partly a defense against death
anxiety.
So one of the things that you really
want to watch when you're listening to
thinkers and when you're trying to
figure out how to organize your thought
is you really,
really want to be skeptical of people
who boil things down to one prop
principal.
So for example,
marks,
it's economics and class struggle.
It's like,
well,
is that relevant to the study of
societies?
Yes,
we're structured in dominance
hierarchies when we trade,
it's a big deal.
It's not the problem.
It's one of many complex problems.
And so if you take a Marxist view of
history,
what you basically do is you take a look
at history and you interpret it through
an a priori set of axioms,
which is that everything that happened
was determined by economic causes.
Well the ant,
the thing is you can do that because
every single thing that ever happened is
determined in part by economic
consequences.
So all you have to do or causes,
all you have to do is ignore all the
other causes and come up with a really
coherent narrative that you can,
that you can do.
Anybody who is a Marxist can do that.
And like three tenths of a second cause
it's like a machine.
You know,
it's like,
what was,
how,
it's funny,
I was talking to a guy the other day and
he's,
he's one of,
he's an idiot log.
And,
and I asked him a question,
this has been bugging me for a long
time.
It's like I thought,
you know,
in Greece everybody cheats on their
income tax,
right?
And so that's not so good because the
government can't work and then the
economy fails and then everyone starves.
So you might say,
why shouldn't you cheat on your income
tax?
And the answer is,
well then the government won't work and
the economy will collapse and everyone
will starve.
So don't cheat on your income tax.
You know,
and you think,
well I can cheat and that won't really
matter.
It's like,
no,
it matters.
Here's why.
So let's say you're doing your income
tax and you're pissed off about it
because like,
you know,
you're giving away your money and you
don't know which it's being well spent.
And of course,
mostly it's not because mostly nothing
works very well.
And so you think,
well I can cheat because I'm only one
person and you know how,
how does it matter?
But then you think,
imagine we were all supposed to put
money into a pool and then take money
out and I knew that one of you wasn't
putting money in the pool but that you
were going to take it out I'd think,
ah,
well whatever one person,
you know,
crooked psychopath,
we'll just,
we don't have to worry about that
person.
And then it's like three people and then
it's like eight and then it's 10 and
then it's 10% of the room and 10% seems
to be something like a tipping point at
some point.
Certainly if you're the only person
putting money in that pot and everyone
else is taking your,
anybody with any sense is going to think
that there are complete blithering idiot
and they're going to start playing that
game.
Right.
So the question is at what point do you
collect enough cheaters so that the s
the people who are basically honest
start feeling like the game is crooked
and quit playing?
While the answer is probably something
like 10% so art back to the back to the
Floridians.
Now I don't remember why I told you that
story.
It had to do with economic
determination.
Oh,
right.
Thank you.
Okay,
so this is the story.
So I'm thinking,
well,
if that's the case,
if like 10% is a tipping point or 30% I
don't care,
whatever it is,
50 I don't care.
There's a tipping point is at some
point,
if it's a minority of people,
if they're corrupt,
can bring down the whole system.
How in the world do you ever create a
system that isn't corrupt?
Because all everybody almost has to play
it honestly before the thing will work.
And so how do people get from the point
where it's chaotic and corrupt,
which is the case in most of the world,
by the way,
right?
Most places are insanely corrupt.
Some places aren't.
It's like,
how the hell did that happen?
I don't get it.
It doesn't seem possible to me that that
happened.
I understand it because the default is
obviously chaos and corruption.
That's easy.
So anybody can do that.
It's like sometimes systems work and
they're more or less honest.
Like Ebay is a really good example of
that.
It's like,
poof,
I proxy bay,
what's the average level of cheating?
It's like zero,
you know,
it's unbelievably honest and it's a
murder.
It's a miracle.
Nobody thought that would happen.
So how the hell does that happen?
So I was asking a friend of mine and
this guy too,
and I laid this out and like I didn't
even get finished the question and he
said,
government.
And I said,
well,
what do you mean?
He said,
oh,
it's those places that don't have too
much government that are honest.
It's like,
well thank you.
I mean,
I thought that was a complicated
problem.
You know?
And here are you,
you didn't even have to listen to the
whole damn question before you had an
answer.
It's government.
Oh well I'll stop thinking about that
right now.
It's like God really,
really come on,
you know,
one,
a single causal answers to complex
questions and it's like all the tapping
there is that the person is playing an
intellectual game.
That's all that's happening.
They've got this set of axioms.
They've learned how to manipulate them.
It's like chess game basically,
and no matter what the problem is that
you throw at them,
they can run them through the algorithm
and pop out announcer.
It's not helpful.
It's like,
because for me,
for example,
that question only sets,
even if he's right,
it only sets the problem back one step.
It's okay if government is the cause of
corruption,
which it isn't.
It's an because of corruption and it's
also the solution to corruption.
But if it is that because of corruption,
then how come some places have more
government than others?
It's like there's no information in that
statement.
All there is is a rephrasing of the
problem.
It looks like announcer,
it's got nothing to do with announcer.
So,
and what I,
one of the things that really disturbs
me about modern university education is
that,
you know,
a quarter of the people who are in the
humanities and of the distribution are
being taught to think this way.
It's like,
well,
here's,
here's a little rubric power.
That would be the postmodernist
deconstructionist routine courtesy of
Derrida who was a Marxist,
and you take his propositions and you
can apply them to everything.
It's like it's not helpful and it's not
thinking it doesn't do anything.
It just gives you the illusion of of
thinking.
So,
okay,
so
let me just take here now for a minute.
So we were talking about ideological
propositions.
Yes,
yes.
Okay.
So what seemed to happen once the slats
were knocked out of the assumption that
there were fundamental assumptions that
you could rely on.
So let's say like the existence God and
that your relationship to God was an
indication of the greater good.
The greater good was an actual concrete
thing in some sense.
Once the intellectual slacks were
knocked out from underneath that,
then as Nietzsche pointed out,
the power of organized religion started
to decline.
Now it's it,
it hasn't declined as rapidly or as
thoroughly as everyone thought it might
in the 20th century.
Right?
Because the Americans have a pretty
thriving Christianity on the right wing.
And then of course there's all sorts of
fundamentalist movements all over the
world.
But we'll just put that aside for now.
It doesn't really,
it doesn't have anything to do with the
main issue in some sense.
Okay.
So then what is the consequence of not
having the great cultural narratives
anymore?
Well,
there seems to be two.
One is everything's up in the air and no
one knows what to do.
And everybody has a question about every
single level of the hierarchy.
Like why are we doing this and what's
the meaning of life and should we bother
doing anything at all?
And Are we running around destroying the
planet and you know,
so on and so forth.
So it's chaotic.
And the other one is people just
transmute their religious beliefs into
another kind of monotheistic explanation
that's based on some intellectual
proposition.
And so with the Marxists,
for example,
it would be,
um,
economic relationships with people.
For Freud,
Freud was not an unsophisticated thing,
but he did try to boil everything down
to sex and aggression,
mostly sex.
And he had his reasons.
He said,
well,
you know,
without sex you don't propagate.
And Propagation is obviously necessary
for the continuation of life.
And therefore sexuality must be a main,
the main function.
And it's a powerful claim.
But we do know if you look at biological
systems,
we know that your motivational systems
are disparate,
right?
They don't seem to unite themselves into
a single motivational system except
maybe at the level of the reticular
activating system,
which is something like general arousal.
So Freud's wrong about that.
So,
but he was wrong in an interesting way
and I don't think he was an idiot log.
But the point is is that there are,
there are multiple forms of meaning and
motivation and their implicit and they
have to be organized.
And so then the question is how do you
organize them?
Now,
if you have a conspiracy theory of
history,
like the Marxists for example,
or maybe like Freud even because he
thought religion was only a defense
against death anxiety,
then what you basically propose is that
the structures of society,
our rules first and that the rules were
imposed on the society by either someone
or some group of people or something.
So for Marx,
when he's talking about religion,
he says religion is the opiate of the
people.
And the reason that religion,
religion,
allies itself with the capitalist
interests because it allows people to
justify their misery and the hope of an
eternal reward.
And so then they're not rattling up the
whole economic system and the top guys
can keep extracting value from them.
It's like,
yeah,
a bit,
but not all.
Okay.
Because there's a law part of Bar,
a lot of propositions about that that
are wrong.
Like,
and this is goes back to the chimps.
The chimps are out there and their
dominance hierarchy and they understand
the hierarchy and they behave in
accordance with it.
Are they following rules and answer to
that is no,
they are not following rules.
What they are doing is manifesting
patterns of behavior.
Now then you might think,
well did they think up those patterns of
behavior?
And the answer to that is no,
they didn't think up those patterns of
behavior.
So then the next question is,
cause they can't think,
not really.
So.
So the next question is,
well,
if they didn't think the mop,
where the hell did they come from?
You know,
and it's,
it's very interesting question to ask of
a of a book,
like the Bible for example,
which is so well,
which is a bunch of books by the way.
Of course,
you know that it's extraordinarily old
and it's been cobbled together over
thousands of years.
It's like where did that come from?
Well,
it's an extraordinarily complicated
question.
Obviously some people wrote it,
some other people edited,
some other people put it together.
A bunch of different people sequenced
it.
It got modified over time.
It's full of cross references.
It's like it emerged roughly speaking.
So,
and I can show you a very interesting
visual demonstration of that later.
So yes,
religion.
Well,
it's late.
I want to also explain what it's latent
in.
That's because this is the real issue.
It's like if there's a,
there's a claim that was basically
brought forth in the late teenagers,
late 18 hundreds it was formalized,
which is the systems that we use to
govern our morality,
our arbitrary and predicated on belief.
Right.
That was the proposition.
So the question and that's how it all
sorts of consequences and it's a
powerful proposition.
The question is,
is it a correct preposition?
So,
so here's a little diagram here.
So that's from Panksepp.
Jaak,
Panksepp the two top ones,
little rats.
Okay.
So we'll tell a story about rats.
This is quite cool.
So juvenile male rats are wired to play.
Now rats are in general.
Okay.
Because rats have a place circuit.
It's a circuit.
We have it to dogs.
Habit.
Mammals have it.
You know,
I went to the zoo the other day and I
saw a rhinoceros playing.
Watch that for like 10 minutes.
It has this huge ball in its,
its compartment and the bloody thing was
like dancing around walloping this ball
with its huge horn and like it was
dancing,
it was playing.
It's like that was really cool.
Playful Rhinoceros,
you know,
you're out there and play soccer with
it.
Of course you'd get crunched like in two
seconds flat.
Okay,
so play well,
why is that relevant?
So here's,
here's a cool thing.
I think this is like an earth shattering
discovery.
Personally.
Panksepp is a very smart guy.
So you take a juvenile rat and you put
them in a an a player arena.
Hey,
so he throw another juvenile rat in
there and they wrestle around ames.
So then you separate them.
Then the rat has figured out that that's
where he can play.
So the next thing you could do is figure
out whether or not that route we'll work
to get into that arena.
Right?
So like will it pull levers to get in
there because then you can infer that
the route would be happy to go in there
cause otherwise he wouldn't be pulling
the levers.
Right.
Straight behaviorism.
Except they wouldn't say happy.
It's like the rats pulling away.
Pop these out in a little play chambers.
So there's another rat there and let's
say that route is 10% bigger.
Now the rats rough and tumble play,
they wrestle just like kids wrestle.
They wrestle weirdly enough,
they're wrestling around having a fine
time of it.
And it's not aggression.
It's different than aggression and
people can easily see the difference.
Just like you can tell the difference
when you know my dog,
I'll play with him,
like kind of grabbed his paws and he
just goes like,
he just has a short circuit.
He's growing,
his hair is up and he's trying to bite
me.
But the only thing he ever does this hit
me with his teeth,
you know,
and it's a game he knows that I'm
supposed to be able to,
I'm trying to grab these for and he's
trying to bite me and so we do this and
it's like if you didn't know what was
going on,
you'd think the dog was going to tear me
to pieces because it's roaring away and
you know,
and it's having a great time and I let
it nail me now and then and but it's
playing and now it's obvious that it's
playing and that's way different than it
being attacked by an angry dog.
Okay.
So we know there's a difference between
play aggression in real aggression.
So fine,
you get the rats out there.
Now if one wrap is 10% bigger than the
other rat,
then that rat can win all the time.
Cause it's an the weight differences
enough and the size differences enough
so that the big rock can just pin this
small rat over and over and over.
So you might think,
well what does a small rack think about
that?
And the answer is,
okay,
they go out there and they wrestle and
the big rat establishes dominance.
He wins,
right?
So then you take them apart and then you
put them back together.
And what happens is that then the little
rat,
he's charged with inviting the big wrap
to play.
So that's his role now.
So it goes up and does whatever rat does
when it wants to play.
Suspected does something like a dog does
Party puts its head down and sort of
dances around.
You know,
it's like,
are you ready for this?
So then the big rat jumps on him and
they roll around.
And then what happens?
Well let's say you do that over and over
and over because that's the thing is
that something that happens once is not
the same thing as something that
iterates across time.
It's not the same thing.
So how rats play is,
it's a completely different question if
they play once or if they play a long
time with the same partner cause and
there's different rules.
And so here's the emergent rule.
The little rat won't play with the big
rat.
If the big rat doesn't let him win 30%
of the time,
the big rat has to let the little rat
win 30% of the time.
So I thought that's so cool.
It's so cool because what you see there,
that's an emergent morality,
right?
It's,
it's not codafide in rules,
but there's a,
there's a procedural,
there's our social proposition that
emerges there.
And the social proposition is you got to
let the little guy win sometimes and
even rats.
No,
that,
so,
okay,
so that's not a rule.
It's not handed down on high,
so to speak.
It's an emergent consequence of the
interaction of two rats now.
Okay.
So you might think,
well there are some boys doing the same
thing.
Okay,
now Panksepp has always also found other
things.
So he's found,
for example,
that if you don't let rats play rough
and tumble play in particular,
their prefrontal cortex is don't mature
and they get hyperactive.
But you can treat that in routes with
Ritalin,
right?
So you know Panksepp's hypothesis,
which I think is an extraordinarily
credible hypothesis is that the reason
boys in particular hyperactive is
because they're not playing enough.
But you can fix that with Ritalin
instead of letting them play.
And what you do if you're gonna let them
plays you,
you watched the man,
they're going to like play and sometimes
they're going to get a bit too rough and
then you stop them.
You say like,
no,
if you play like that,
the game won't continue.
That's like a first part of moral rule.
You have to play each game in a manner
that lets the repetition of those games
occur.
And so that's why you would have to be a
good sport,
for example.
Right?
Be a good sport.
Why?
What if I can win?
Well,
the question is what does weird mean?
Does win mean you win this game or does
win mean that you play this game in such
a way so that the probability that
you'll get invited to play more and more
games as you mature increases.
So it's two games at the same time,
right?
There's the game and the metagame and
what you're telling a child when you say
be a good sport is you're saying,
but you don't know this because you're
not smart enough and you know what the
hell do you know about Metta Games and
so on and so forth.
You say,
well be a good sport.
Why?
Well,
cause that's how to play properly.
Hollow explanation.
But the answer is something like,
well and maybe a parent will say this
cause other kids won't want to play with
you.
You know that,
that that's a reason.
And that's getting somewhere with an
explanation.
You might have to say why and then you
know,
you decompose it and the kid will
probably know how to ask anyways.
But,
but the point is is that there's a
higher moral principle at stake.
And you might say,
well why is it higher?
Because one of the things he might ask
yourself is,
are some moral propositions higher than
other moral propositions?
Right.
Which is an anti relativist claim.
So it's,
it's,
there's only a binary answer to that.
The answer is yes,
some values are higher than others or
no,
they're not.
No means the hierarchy is flat and it
can't be organized.
Yes means either that the ordering is
arbitrary and tyrannical or that there's
an,
that there's some other process at work
that has a,
that that applies across wide ranges of
contexts and situations.
Now,
Thomas Kuhn,
who studied the structure of scientific
revolutions,
he said his art,
he,
he never really figured out whether he
was a relativist or a phd and he was
Kinda,
okay,
wishy washy on the topic.
Now what Kuhn basically said with
something like
science is a hierarchy and now and then
a revolution takes place at the highest
level of abstraction.
And usually that happens when there's a
theory and it's being applied to explain
the world.
And there's an anomaly that it doesn't
explain.
And for a while you can just ignore
that.
And normally,
but then it gets more and more annoying
and aggravating and takes full stage and
you can't explain it in.
That means there's something wrong with
your damn theory and then poof,
someone comes along with another theory
which explains that a normally now Kuvan
was never sure if the new theory was
better than the old theory or what
better meant or if it was just a
replacement for the old theory,
it was like to Olay didn't work.
Tool b works in this situation.
Now what Piaget said though was that
when he was talking about revolutions of
the same type,
so that'd be the stage transformation.
He said,
no,
no.
There's a rule for better.
The rule is the new paradigm accounts
for everything the other paradigm did.
Plus it accounts for some other things
and so why is it better?
While there's a definition of better
that's implicit in that,
and so imagine that you knew something
and it was only good one place at one
time.
It's like,
great,
that's a good thing.
Let's say you replace that with another
thing you knew and it was good in three
situations.
At three different times.
It's like,
well,
which of those are you going to use?
All other things being equal?
Wow.
Why not use the one that works in more
situations?
And so we could say,
well,
our moral principle is super ordinate to
another moral principle.
If the superordinate principle works to
facilitate the same man's across longer
spans of time with more people.
So then the question is,
well,
how should you play a game?
And the answer is what are you doing
while you're playing a game?
And one answer is you're trying to win
that game in other answers,
you're trying to play that game.
Another answer is you're engaged in
practicing emotive playing that will
enable you to play many games in many
situations successfully.
It's like,
okay,
which of those is most important?
Well,
it's obvious,
which is most important.
If the game is worthwhile,
which is what you propose.
If you play it,
you've agreed to that.
Then obviously playing in a way that
enables you to play more games of that
type better is better end of problem.
So now you can think that through and
see if there's any flaws in the logic.
But,
but people have been thinking about it
for about a hundred years and I think
that's about as far as it's got and I,
I can't see up off whole in that.
So.
All right,
so the boys are playing now you make me
think,
what are they doing when they're playing
rough and tumble play.
Okay.
So now I have played with kids that
haven't had any rough and tumble play
and it's really hard to play with them
partly because they're there,
they're easily frightened,
you know,
they'd like to play.
I know how to play with kids,
they'd liked to play.
They're pretty hepped up on it,
you know,
and they,
they really excited,
especially about physical play,
but they're awkward,
you know,
so you play with them,
they stick their thumb in your eye or
you know,
or they cry really easily when nothing
really happens and like they just don't
have it together.
A kid that has done a lot of physical
interaction,
physical play,
that kid,
it's a different sort of kid because the
first thing the kid knows,
it's not a rule.
The first thing the kid knows is how
forceful can he be with you.
So that it's exciting and interesting
and fun,
but it's not too much.
And that's really an interesting
question name because actually to really
play a good game,
like a physical contact game,
like wrestling with a kid is that you
want to let that kid come right up to
the edge of hurting you.
And the closer the kid gets to the edge,
the more fun it is for both because the
kid will give you a whack and go,
he,
you know,
and,
and that's,
it's good,
you know?
And then maybe he'll give you a harder
whack to see if he can get away with it.
And kids will often,
they'll come up to you,
whack you and then run away and then
they'll look and if you're laughing then
they'll come back and try a harder one.
And then,
you know,
they're doing it incrementally because
it's exploratory behavior.
And part of the exploration is,
okay,
what our bodies like.
And the answer that is,
well what can you get away with doing to
them?
But it's a more sophisticated answer to
which is what can you get away with
doing to them in a way that allows you
to continue to explore without fear or
punishment and without blowing the whole
game to bits.
Okay,
so how do you figure that out?
You do not talk about it cause you
can't.
You have to act it out.
It's like so.
So the kids hitting you in wrestling and
pulling your hair and doing all these
things and you're modifying its behavior
very,
very carefully and,
and,
and in my minuscule detail.
And then you get a kid who can like
wrestle like mad and they're fun to play
with.
They bounced around like a dog that will
bite you.
You know a good well trained dog you can
really play with and you can play with
them rough and it's a blast.
The dog has a good time,
the person has a good time.
It's like excellent.
That's a socialized dog.
So
the other thing that kids learn learns,
which is quite cool,
is what hurts them and what doesn't and
how afraid can they be and still have
fun.
So,
you know,
when you're wrestling with the kid,
you've put them,
you know,
you put them face down,
you put your elbow on Mia,
bend them around,
you throw them in the air and catch
them.
You know,
you've grabbed her by the leg and maybe
you pull them over and you know,
and what you're showing the kid is
here's a bunch of things that your body
can do.
And it's okay that they're,
they're being done,
that it isn't going to hurt you and
you're not talking about you're showing
them.
And so the kid gets kind of confident
about what he or she can withstand
physically.
And the difference between pain and not
pain.
And the difference between fear and not
fear.
And when something's threatening and
when it's not very sophisticated,
it's very sophisticated behave.
And that's partly why kids love to play.
Now,
one of the things that's happened,
which is,
you know,
an indication of a deep sickness in our
society is that I used to work in a
daycare center right when I was about
your age because I really liked kids and
they like to play with me because I know
how to play with them.
And so one of the things I would do with
the little kids was I would draw them
horrible monsters,
right?
Like big teeth things on,
I just sketched them out.
They weren't any works of art,
you know.
But those damn kids,
they would line up to get a picture of a
monster,
draw me a picture of the monster,
draw me a picture of a monster.
It's like they love those little
pictures of monsters.
So then I was pretty funny.
And the other thing I would do is play
with them.
You know,
I'd take him out in the yard and grab an
arm and a leg and spin them around and
bend them over and you know,
twist them around,
let them crawl on me.
And,
um,
there's always one kid in the group who
couldn't do that though.
And he's like,
he hadn't been paid attention to enough,
you know,
so he was,
I think he's like a Taoist uncarved
block,
very vague and ill defined and clunky
and so kid like that,
you know,
you'd sit down,
it's so sad you sit down and you're
interacting with the kids and that kid
comes along sort of lumping along,
you know,
like this and they plop plop on your lap
and they like,
they're about as sophisticated as like a
six month old,
you know,
and they're quite annoying,
which is a horrible thing because
they're so desperate for attention and
it's too late.
Often by the time they're four,
it's like,
good luck fixing that man.
It's not going to happen.
You know?
And those kids are just screwed because
what happens to them is they're so lumpy
and ill formed and,
and uncomfortable in their body and
socially clueless and inattentive and
blind and ignored and resentful that no
other kids would play with them.
And it's no wonder because the other
kids are way the hell up on the play
development trend.
And so their board staffed by them,
it's like playing with a nine month old,
which kids will do,
you know?
But that's not pure play.
And so those kids just drift off.
They get,
they stay on the outside of the peer
group and they never get into it.
They never get into it.
So very,
very ugly.
And so now in daycare centers,
you can't touch the kids.
It's like,
what the hell?
You know?
Well,
why?
because he can't distinguish play for
molesting.
It's like who can't distinguish that?
You know?
And what are you going to do?
You're not going to hear,
you're going to deprive the kids of play
because of your stupid paranoia.
That's the whole,
that's the whole process.
Right.
Brilliant,
brilliant.
You know what you're doing is you're
teaching children that adults are so
dangerous that they can't be trusted to
be near you.
That's a lovely thing to teach children,
especially because they're gonna be
adults.
Yeah.
I don't think it's competent Satori.
I think it's a different level of
abstraction.
So we're going to talk about that next.
Okay.
So the rats even routes need play,
right?
And that's are smart enough to figure
out that the little guy has to win
sometimes.
So,
okay,
here's what happens with chimps.
This is quite cool.
So the little male chimps in particular,
because chimps are very aggressive,
they do a lot of playing and one of the
things they do is tease the older males.
So maybe the older males like having a
snooze under a tree and like the,
uh,
the young chimps have come up and like
poking with a stick or tickle them or
poke them and runaway and so,
and they're trying to see what they can
get away with.
And that's dominance,
hierarchy challenge in its childhood
form.
And it can be a game if it's done
properly.
It's a gate.
If it's not done properly,
it's insubordination and its aggression
and then something's actually gone
wrong.
I'll get,
I'll tell you a story about that.
So one time I was in Montreal and I
lived in a pretty poor area of Montreal.
Um,
and it was like a historically poor,
it wasn't a slum or anything,
but it was a very on the low end of the
working class neighborhoods.
So and uh,
cross the alley about two houses down
there was this house where things
weren't going on that we're good,
you know,
I don't know if it was a crack house or
some damn thing,
but there were people in and out of it
all the time and there was a lot of
drinking beer and which is fine,
but it was like,
it was like antisocial,
you know,
it wasn't,
it wasn't fun party.
It was like,
you know,
corrupt biker Weirdos and all sorts of
things.
And there was a little kid there,
he was about three and I could kind of
kept an eye on that kid and he was an
unhappy kid.
Like he was already,
he had a contempt,
resentment face pretty well developed
already.
And so one day I was out in the back
alley and I was building this fence.
You guys are going to fence in my yard
in.
And so then this little kid came up and
he came up with a bunch of his little
cronies,
you know,
and uh,
I was watching them,
they're watching me with like hatred,
I would say,
basically.
And uh,
you know,
so I was looking at one of the kids and
they were watching me hammer and I
motioned to the kid,
I said,
do you want to,
I couldn't speak to him cause he spoke
cave quad and it was like [inaudible],
which I can't speak French very well at
all.
And jewel,
the real is ul.
It's like,
no,
I can't even hear what the hell that is.
You know.
So,
um,
I,
I motioned to the kid,
you know,
you want a hammer.
And so he comes up and he,
he said in French,
I'm going to steal this and I,
so he was tugging on it and I thought,
well that's pretty weird.
So if he was looking at me mad,
he's going to take this,
he said,
I'm stealing this.
Well,
no,
I'm not going to give it to you if
you're going to steal it.
So,
so that was fine.
So I said no,
and I kept hammering.
They were all watching and then he
stepped about 15 feet back and he ran
right over the fence,
like running on it,
you know?
And I thought,
wow,
that's pretty damn interesting.
It's like,
that's a lot of golf or a three year old
kid,
you know?
It's like,
but it was provocative,
right?
It was dominance provocation and it
wasn't a game because he didn't know how
to play a game.
He didn't know how to play a game.
He just knew like outright aggression.
So he ran over this fence and then he
stood there and looked at me,
you know?
And well,
I don't remember exactly what I did.
Nothing.
I think I was just watching him.
I eventually finished the fence and put
it away,
but I thought that kids headed for
prison just as certainly as as a rock
falls to earth.
It's like,
and I know the antisocial literature,
it's like if you're antisocial at four,
good luck to you.
There isn't much that can be done about
it.
He was so ruined by that point already
that there was,
you know,
it would have taken me if I would have
access to that kid,
I probably would had to fight with him
nonstop for three months to straighten
him out.
And it wouldn't have been pretty,
you know,
because he was already,
he hated adults already and they didn't,
he thought they were contemptible and
useless and that he could prevail over
them and that they were erratic and you
couldn't trust them to punish or reward
or to pay attention.
And there was no such thing as real
social rules and you know,
power dominated everything.
It's like,
and that was all in him,
right?
It was built into them.
They were mostly watching,
you know,
so,
and I don't know what sort of peer
interactions they would have had,
you know,
but as far as I could tell,
because sometimes the more aggressive
guys,
they do form gangs and the gang is
actually there.
It's a functional unit.
There is some social interaction only
within the gang.
Generally it's like a tribe.
So those are the more socialized
antisocial guys,
but some of the kids are so antisocial,
they can't even work with it.
A gang.
So I don't know exactly where he was on
the spectrum,
but um,
like his behavior was,
it was already criminal,
you know,
it was just kid criminal,
same thing.
So,
okay.
So some things I should tell you about
chimps too,
you know,
so you kind of think of the top chimp
like a cave man,
you know,
the tough caveman with a big club.
And so it's the tough chimp that
dominates the hierarchy and it's sort of
like the tyranny theory of male
dominance hierarchies.
It's the strongest,
meanest chimp that wins.
Frans de Waal has been studying chimps
for a long time and he's found it.
That's,
that's just not true.
What he found was what piaget would
suggest,
which is that the chimps that only use
aggression and dominance form
hierarchies that are unstable and prone
to revolution.
So he tells one story,
for example,
of this chimp that climb to the top.
This was,
I believe in the Arnhem Zoo and he was
like brutal champ.
And he was a big tough guy,
you know,
but he wasn't very good at consolidating
his social relationships,
say with other male chimps or with the
females.
So cause he was too brutal for any of
that.
So we didn't engage in a lot of mutual
grooming say with other males because
one of the things you see in the chimps
is the chimp males fight a lot,
but they also groom each other a lot.
So their,
their,
their relationship is more fractious and
aggression,
aggressive and also more cooperative.
So that's quite cool.
But he had forgotten most of that.
He didn't pay much attention to the
females.
So what happened was that the two second
order chimps jumped in one day and torn
to bits.
So that was the end of that.
And it was brutal,
brutal,
brutal.
I think they castrated them with their
teeth,
if I remember correctly.
And torn to shreds.
You know,
the rest of the troop was really
agitated by this and agitated for a long
time afterwards.
But,
and chimps are brutal.
Like they'll catch colobus monkeys and
they eat them alive and the things are
screaming away like,
and they're unbelievably strong.
Like a chimp is about six times as
strong as a grown man.
And so you get near a champ,
boy do not get near a chimp.
Those things can break 300 pound tests,
steel cables with their hands.
They are super strong and they're
vicious.
They're vicious.
So in a lot of what seems to inhibit
chimp aggression is actually the
dominance hierarchy.
It's not clear that they have any limits
on their aggression internally.
So,
and so chimps will,
the male juvenile sometimes in the
company of females will sort of patrol
the edges of their territory.
And if they come across a chimp from a
different troop and they outnumber them,
they'll attack them and tear them to
shreds.
So that was discovered.
I think Jane Goodall discovered that
first.
And she was shocked by it because she
was still kind of operating under Russo
Soliah and assumptions.
And then for a long time she thought,
well maybe these,
maybe I've corrupted these chimps by
feeding them and messing about a bit
with their natural order.
And so maybe that's just a consequence
of pathological human interaction.
But then other chimp researchers
reported the same sort of thing.
And so that's really interesting because
it means that chimps do territorial
rating.
And so that also means that while one
thing it means,
for example,
is religion is not the cause of wars.
You know,
when you might think,
well that's quite a leap.
It's like,
no,
it's not quite elite.
Tribalism might be the cause of wars and
religion might be a form of tribalism.
But chimps basically engage in,
cause I wore like behavior.
And you're not going to lay that at the
hands of any abstract conceptual system.
It's territorial protection.
So,
all right.
So what do all found instead?
Was that the chimps who come to the top,
who managed to stay there?
Our chimps who are,
they're strong for sure,
but they're also,
um,
they also engage in a lot of mutual
social interactions and they pay a lot
of attention to the females.
And so what it appears to be the case is
that,
and this is so cool.
It's so cool.
Yeah.
If you want to be king of the chimps,
you have to be a good king.
And you might say,
well,
what does good mean?
Cause that's an,
you think of that as a moral
abstraction.
What does good mean?
Good,
good king.
Okay,
let's figure it out.
Being torn to bits in a violent
insurrection seems like failure.
Okay.
So,
um,
being constantly hounded from all sides
because you're to Roston not social
enough,
that doesn't seem like an optimal
solution.
Maintaining order in the hierarchy.
So the hierarchy maintains its structure
across time and so that everybody's
attended to properly decreases the
probability of violent insurrection a
lot.
So you might think,
well,
what the chimp is trying to do,
the chimp at the top is trying to
structure the dominance hierarchy in
such a way that it can maintain itself
without violence in a productive manner
with many individuals across large spans
of time.
Now there's nothing abstract about that.
Now you might say,
well,
there may be different ways to do that.
It's like,
fine.
Yeah,
there probably are.
Just like you can be a plumber or you
can be a lawyer.
You know there's men,
there are different ways potentially of
solving that set of problems,
but it's within a bounded universe.
There are things you can't do.
There may be many things you can do,
but there's certainly things that you
can't do.
Okay,
so then that's really useful to know
because what we can surmise from that
potentially is that even higher order
morality is something that emerges.
It emerges as a consequence of social
interactions between motivated beings
across large spans of time.
And that there's actually a pattern to
that.
There's a pattern.
So that would be the pattern that
characterizes the stable hierarch.
So now what is that pattern?
That's where you get to mythology.
So because this is where people differ
from,
from chimps,
so obvious.
So you might say,
well why did the chimps act the way they
did?
D Dupe.
And you might say,
well that's because they're their
parents acted that way.
And then you might say,
well that's because their parents acted
that way.
And you can make that argument going as
far back in time as you want.
And I already made it at one point going
all the way back to lobsters,
right?
400 million years.
That's a dominance hierarchy.
So how do behave in a dominance
hierarchy is something that's been
figured out across 400 million years of
evolution.
At least now you can infer two things
from that.
One is your adapted to a dominance
hierarchy.
Cause that bloody thing is old.
So,
so you have literally the forces of
selection have shaped you such that if
you weren't able to function within a
dominance hierarchy,
you weren't going to survive.
Someone would kill you and you weren't
going to meet.
Okay.
So you're prepared for the damn
dominance hurt.
Now,
the next thing is you can observe and
transmit information across the
hierarchy because it's a living thing
that continues across time.
So it kind of has its own structure that
perpetuates itself across the
generations.
So with the chimps,
for example,
the status of a family is heritable.
Now we don't know if that's a
sociological phenomena or a biological
phenomena or whatever,
but doesn't matter.
It's still the case.
So,
and I think that's because it's probably
easier for high status animals to
produce high status offspring.
Obviously.
Why not?
They have better access to everything
and they're more confident.
So stands to reason.
Okay.
Then there's the constraints of the
dominance hierarchy itself because it's
a particular kind of structure.
It has to operate within particular
kinds of principles.
Okay.
So we were chimps
and then our brains started to grow.
We discovered how to use fire,
we discovered how to use language,
we discovered how to imitate each other.
And we're really good at that.
We discovered how to specify what
someone is interested in by looking at
where their eyes were pointing.
And that's why we have whites around our
iris.
It's so that I can tell where you're
looking,
so I know what you're up to.
Gorillas don't have that.
So what that basically meant was the
precursors to us whose eyes weren't
distinguishable,
the direction of their eyes pointing,
they didn't make or were killed because
no one knew what they were up to.
So we have all these abilities that are
built right into our body.
We built the hierarchies,
they come up automatically,
right?
They emerged from the bottom and then we
watched them and infer the structure and
that's where we start getting into
drama.
So that's imitation,
but complex imitation of longterm
narratives and then representations of
the drama.
And so that would be fiction.
And then extraction of archetipal themes
from the,
from the fiction or the other way
around.
It might be that what we extracted out
first,
where the archetypal themes makes more
sense really.
And that would be the primordial
religions.
What's at the top of the dominance
hierarchy?
God,
What's God?
Well,
it's a kind of ideal.
It's a kind of ideal.
You might think that
this is an oversimplification.
It was frequently the case.
And I'll tell you the stories that
archaic people like the Sumerians
conceptualize their leader as the
incarnation of God on earth,
and he would have the responsibility to
act that way.
It's a very common human cognitive
operations,
right?
Japanese,
we're doing that right up to the second
world war and they still do it to some
degree.
So it's like this is natural thought.
The leader is an Avatar of God.
What's God will leave that question
aside for now.
What's a good avatar or good avatars,
whatever has sovereignty and authority?
Well,
what is sovereignty and authority?
we're trying to figure that out.
Sovereignty and authority is whatever
stabilizes the dominance hierarchy with
multiple members across large spans of
time in a way that won't be overthrown.
We don't know the answer to it because
it's an ongoing investigation and a lot
of it's worked out at the behavioral
level.
But then once we started to observe it
and tell stories about each other and
imitate each other,
we could start encapsulating that in
stories.
And so what time is it?
Three 11 okay.
I'll one more sentence.
So I'll give you a break then.
I'm going to tell you,
uh,
one of the world's great stories.
Okay,
so here,
here's the idea.
We're banging.
So just like when I'm playing with my
son physically,
we're trying to optimize the
interaction.
And the way we do that is by calibrating
each other's strengths and weaknesses
and at each other's emotional reactions
in a way that makes it fun and
interesting and exciting and almost
terrifying.
And that in a way that both players
really want the game to continue.
Okay.
How do you do that?
Well,
you can't say,
you can say,
well,
you have to play fair.
That's a reasonable proposition.
You can't hurt the kid.
You know,
there's arbitrary things you can't do.
You can draw out some general
principles,
but basically you have to figure it out
on the fly.
Okay,
that's how we organize our hierarchies.
We figure it out on the fly,
but then what do we do?
We watch those hierarchies over
thousands of years and communicate about
it.
And so we're trying to figure out what
the hell is it that we're up to.
Exactly.
And then we even take it a bit further,
which is not only what is it that we are
up to,
but what is it that we should be up to?
It's like how do you idealize the
dominance hierarchy structure and what
should be at the top?
And the proposition is something like an
Avatar of the highest value is the thing
that's at the top.
And then the next question is,
what the hell is that?
An answer to that is we're not smart
enough to conceptualize it property,
partly because it's an emergent
property.
It's very complex,
biological,
sociological,
emergent phenomena.
And so we're trying to close in on it
and that's what we're doing when we're
telling stories.
We're trying to close in on it.
What's the ideal human behavior?
So I have a friend visiting right now
and he's,
uh,
he writes thrillers.
He's written like 20 of them.
And he writes comic books like Batman
and Wolverine and so on and so forth.
And so he's interested in,
so the thriller genre,
most of what he writes about are our
vigilante stories.
You know where someone is wrong,
their family is threatened in some
manner.
Maybe it's outside the normal strictures
of the law and they're supposed to do
something about it.
So I asked him what the hell he was up
to because he's a smart guy.
I thought,
well,
why are you writing these thrillers?
Why?
Why is that the genre that captures your
interest very highly verbally
intelligent,
this guy,
and he's very well educated.
I thought,
well,
what are you up to?
And he said,
well,
it seems to be something like this.
I'm trying to figure out.
So usually in a thriller,
the,
the force that is attacking the castle,
the structure,
the family is some male gone mad.
So it's like,
it's like animal man,
you know,
some brutal psychopathic guy or a serial
killer or some like arch criminal or
something like that.
Same thing you see in comic books.
It's like,
okay,
that's like,
that's like the masculine end of the
monster.
Okay.
But then the protagonist and say,
typical protagonist might be a man
trying to protect his family.
He's like,
okay,
what do you do in a monster attack?
Something that you love.
Well,
if,
if you're just like made out of tissue
paper and,
and gelatin,
you know,
you just fall over and die and then
monster comes in and steals everything
you have and kills everyone and that's
the end of the story.
It's like,
okay,
you have to meet force with force.
Now that's a weird thing because if you
go on a monster on the outside and
you're in the inside and you're also
male,
we'll save for this example.
If you don't allow yourself to be the
kind of monster that the monster is,
he's going to win.
So then the question is how do you allow
yourself to be the kind of monster
that's capable of protecting things
without turning into the monster while,
so all his books are explorations of
that.
It's like,
okay,
here's a limit situation where even the
rules aren't working.
Your families on the line,
the law can't protect you.
What do you do?
Well,
we don't know.
You've curl up and die.
Do you hide in the basement?
Do you make a safe room?
Do you move to another state?
You know,
you could just take it,
you fight back,
do you arm yourself?
Like,
who knows,
right?
What's the right thing to do?
Well,
the right thing to do doesn't seem to be
to let that win.
Okay.
So he's trying to,
he's laying out various simulations of
responses,
you know,
and he has all sorts of reasons for
doing so.
So that's partly what we're doing with
stories,
right?
We're not only representing what it is
that we're doing and if we're not,
you'd go and watch the movie and you'd
say that wasn't very realistic.
It has to be a good enough model of the
world as it is so that you find it
credible.
It can twist a principal or two around
and ask you to suspend disbelief for the
purposes of exploration.
You know,
like what would it be like if you had
ex-ray eyes?
You know,
it's,
it's sort of like a superhero thing and
people will put up with that because
it's an exploratory,
it's an exploratory process.
You know,
you can't just break a bunch of rules
arbitrarily.
There'll,
because people get bored of the story,
right?
It's,
it's not a realistic simulation.
You're playing out simulations in a
moral landscape.
So,
and I would say the simulations that
have worked best,
our architect,
so there's deep themes that are kind of,
they're,
they're like templates and there's
somewhat vague,
the details have to be filled in,
in your own life.
But there are broad narrative themes
that are the fundamental framework
within which the specific moral
hierarchy that you need has to be built.
That's the proposition.
Okay,
so now what we're going to do is we're
going to look at those narratives.
And so what we're trying to do,
two things,
we're trying to figure out what's the
proper way to conceptualize the world if
your problem is that you have to act and
live it.
Question Number One,
question number two is if you're in the
world and you have it conceptualized
properly,
how should you act?
All right?
And so that's what these stories are
trying to solve now,
are they correct?
It's like they're low resolution
photographs.
That's what they are.
Or they're low resolution movies and
people have been working on them for a
long time now.
There's a twist here,
which I think is a very cool twist.
The twist is what is it that's necessary
in a story for you to find the story
compelling,
right,
because that's an interesting thing.
It's like obviously you go to a movie,
you say,
man,
I love that are you go there and you
think that stunk.
You know,
I never inflict that on anyone.
It's like,
well,
they're both stories.
They're both expensive.
They're borth,
well produced and sophisticated.
One grabs your interest.
You can't get away from it and the other
doesn't.
It's like why?
What is it about some kinds of stories
that grab you and won't let you go and
now there's the don't.
Well,
that's a complicated thing,
but one of the things I'm going to pause
it is that not only are there,
not only does the dominance hierarchy
have a structure that replicates itself
roughly across time,
but you're adapted to that structure.
And part of that Ab deputation is that
when you're presented with patterns of
behavior that are general,
but that also partake of the quality of
being useful within dominance
hierarchies.
You're a chat,
you're attracted to them.
It's just like when you're a little kid,
look,
think of,
there must be people you admire,
right?
Think of someone you admire.
Okay.
Why?
Why do you admire them?
So give me an answer.
Like if you pick someone you admire,
why do you admire them?
Just pick someone.
Anybody got an answer to that?
Okay,
thank are respectful.
Paved the way for some potential.
Okay.
Okay,
so that seems to be about right Tay.
There's something about that.
But it's interesting because often the
admiration will emerge in the absence of
articulated reasons for it.
You know,
it's more or less something that hits
you rather than,
and maybe you post-hoc think,
well this is why,
but it hits you.
Now there's some being some experiments
down,
I think with vervet monkeys.
So you take vervet monkeys in a
hierarchy and you take photos of the low
ranking individuals and you take photos
of the high ranking individuals and then
you show the vervet monkeys,
the low ranking individuals,
the high ranking individuals,
the verbage will look longer at the high
ranking individuals.
So you might say,
here's a hypothesis for you.
If you see someone manifest elements of
the rough pattern that across dominance
hierarchies enables people to succeed,
you'll be attracted to that,
right?
And that person,
by focusing on that person,
you can flesh out the archetype in some
sense.
You know,
because the one a student asked me once,
they said,
look,
if archetypal stories are real,
why can't we just tell the architectural
story over and over the same story I
called Jesus.
That's really the question.
It's like,
hmm,
why would that be?
And I would say like in primordial
cultures,
that does really happen.
It is repetition of the architectural
story.
But in a sophisticated culture like
ours,
there's like 100,000
fiction works.
Why?
Well,
I think part of it is is that the
archetype in some sense is the template
for good person,
but it doesn't fill in the details
underneath that are relevant for this
place and this time.
And so the fiction,
if it's a good work of fiction,
the archetype shines through it.
But it shines through in a way that you
can extract out information that
actually works here and now in this
situation.
So you need,
you need both the archetypal
representation,
which is how to be a good person.
And then you need information about the
particulars of how to be a good person
so that you can actually do that.
And I think that what happens when you
find someone you admire is they embody
the archetype,
but they've fleshed out the skills.
And so if you watch them and copy them
and apprentice yourself to them,
then you can pull that in.
And it's a great,
magnificent way of developing because it
means that you can benefit from their
experience without having to go through
the same laborious process hopefully of
acquiring that wisdom.
That's why you go to university,
right.
And principle cause it's easier to go to
university and learn the information
that it is to go out there and bang
yourself out against the world and learn
all these things the hard way,
which you don't have time for.
Yes.
Or don't want.
Yeah.
Because a good counter example is also
sometimes a counter example is even
better because,
and this is another way to think about
morality.
I just wrote a chapter,
I'm writing a book.
I wrote a chapter called cal the truth,
and then I thought,
Ooh,
that might not be the right title.
Because then you run into Pontius pilots
problem,
right?
What is truth?
Well,
good question.
It's like,
do I know the truth?
no.
Plus it's dynamic moves around,
you know,
so maybe the re the property is don't
lie,
that's different.
And you might say,
well,
how do I know the difference between
truth and falsehood?
You might say that.
I say,
well,
most of the time you don't ignore that.
Sometimes you do.
So when you do,
no,
don't do it.
So are you.
That doesn't mean that you know the
truth,
but it does mean that you've identified
a useful false hood.
And that's a good thing because partly
what you need to know to go forward is
what not to do and also what to do.
But often what not to do.
It's like the Old Testament 10
Commandments.
It's like,
here's some rough things you shouldn't
do.
Well,
why?
we've kind of,
you know,
ground ground our way through that.
Or they absolutes.
No,
they're like,
they're like a pattern.
It's a pattern.
You can vary it,
but,
but you,
you mess with it at your peril.
That's the,
that's the hypothesis.
So,
okay,
let's take 10 minutes and then I'll tell
you the Mesopotamian creation myth,
which is lovely story.