Things I've been thinking about here
recently,
and I don't know why I hadn't really
realized this before,
but you realize things in stages is that
I think that this model,
this hierarchy,
is actually a model of the unconscious,
so when people talk about the
unconscious,
I think this is what it is because
there's the procedural unconscious
that's at the lowest level,
right?
Because that's movement,
so that would be procedural memory and
then the the,
the hierarchies above that are
representational.
Most of them more or liberty or called
kinetic melodies,
which would be
habitual patterns of behavior that
you've mastered strung together in a
novel way,
but then above that that starts to
become representational and so I think
for example,
when you're digging to the bottom of
things,
when you're having a conversation and
the unconscious opens up in the
conversation,
which almost always happens if you're
having a dispute with someone,
right?
You say,
what do you really mean?
And then they have to decompose what
they're saying into its subsidiary
elements and sometimes that's a search,
but sometimes it's actually,
I'm a meditation.
Where did that idea come from?
What is the underlying structure,
so,
okay,
so keep that in mind.
And then
we were talking about play last time and
we talked about the fact that even
animals have rules for play and that
that's the evidence,
that's evidence that there are modes of
interaction between animals in a social
environment that are acceptable to both
animals,
such that they will voluntarily continue
and,
and such that they aren't so,
so,
and you know,
it's a Piagetian observation that that
constitutes one of the basis of,
of moral behavior.
And that seems to me to be a very,
very powerful insight because it takes,
it takes the idea that there's something
arbitrary about morality.
It takes that out of the picture.
It says,
well it's,
it's malleable,
but it's not arbitrary,
you know,
it can't just be anything.
So that still leaves you with the
problem of how large the boundaries are.
And that's a tough one because obviously
you all know that there are many ways to
play that all function as acceptable
play.
Although one of the rules would be
everybody who's playing the game
actually has to agree to play it,
you know?
And that seems to me to be something
like an absolute rule regarding social
conventions.
So.
So again,
it's a process rule rather than a
content rule to some degree.
But that's okay.
That's still important.
All right,
so now I believe we talked a little bit
about friends.
The walls work with chimps,
right?
And I mentioned that what the wall has
found out is that it isn't just the,
you know,
the caveman chimp with the biggest club
who's the top chimp,
that top champ in a hierarchy that
remains relatively stable and who
doesn't get torn to shreds by his
subordinates,
can't be an absolute tyrant.
There are social conventions that he has
to follow and those seem to involve the
ability to form coalitions with other
males.
So there's a cooperative element and
then also attention to the females and
the infants that are in the chimp troupe
as well.
And in some sense,
what it seems to indicate is that the
more sophisticated the top guy,
because in chimps it's usually a guy,
I think it's always a guy in chimps.
The more sophisticated he is in his
social maneuvering,
the more stable the result and hierarchy
and so what that implies as we've
discussed is that there are,
there are differences that are
qualitative between hierarchies and
that's again,
that's a moral hierarchy.
Some function better than others.
Some you have to define better,
but I think it's reasonable to define
better.
Again from a modified Cooney and Eddie
had perspective.
You say better,
a better system is one that does all the
functions of the previous system plus
more or that it's more stable or
something like that.
You can define better.
So
now
this particular
pictorial representation,
I'm trying to transmute this into into
another dimension of representation.
So you've got here,
you've got your high dominant primate,
and so he,
he represents something if he's
dominant,
what he represents,
his dominance and we're associating
dominance to some degree with competence
in the competence is social competence.
And so you can think that there's a
pattern that constitutes acceptable
dominant side.
I think you could think about that as
authority.
You know what I mean?
People especially rather simple minded.
Social critics like to think that
dominance hierarchies are only based on
power,
right,
but that's except in the most brutal of
societies.
That's just not the case because there's
power,
but there's also competence and lots of
hierarchies in a functional society are
predicated on competence and so what's
at the top isn't dominance precisely.
It's authority and authority is a better
way of thinking about it.
So then the question might be,
well,
how is our authority represented?
And then also what is it?
And so imagine that for app chimp or
maybe for now we'll go with chimp
because we don't know how long ago it
was in history when people started to
abstract out these things.
You know,
if you think of a word like chief,
as soon as there's a word like that
chief isn't or tribal leader or whatever
the term might be.
The fact that that term exists indicates
that there's a category for authority.
Right?
And what that means is that as soon as
you have a category for authority,
you can detached the idea of authority
from the authority holder and you can
start to think about itself right?
In a,
in a troop,
like in a chimp troupe,
there's no authority independent of the
thing that's at the top.
It's completely embodied.
Even though you might be able to say,
if you are an anthropological observer,
you might be able to say,
well,
there is some common,
here's a chimp true here,
and there's a chimp true peer and
another one here,
and you could say,
well,
there's some commonality and behavior
across all of the chimps that are at the
top,
but the chimps don't know that it's just
a natural fact at that point,
but as soon as you can make the category
or the category leader something like
that,
then what you're starting to do is to
conceptualize the principles that make
authority authority.
So and that's because we can abstract
and because we can represent.
We've been doing that for a very long
period of time.
You know,
we do that as modern people all the
time.
There's,
there's a huge body of studies,
studies in management,
science about what makes a leader.
Now.
It turns out that it's very,
very difficult to go into that
literature and extract out anything of
any generality,
you know,
I mean,
my sense,
my sense was in reviewing that
literature that one of the things you
can say about a leader is that a leader
knows where he's going,
but once you go past that,
then the,
what constitutes leadership in complex
human organizations is hard to
articulate,
but it's also rather situation
dependent,
you know.
And I would also say there's different
ways of being a leader that are
dependent on temperament that maybe all
be functional.
So trying to categorize that as quite
difficult,
but people still have been trying to do
that for a very long time and they've
got,
they've gone a very long way.
So here's a way,
here's the symbolic transmutation in
some sense.
So,
um,
at,
at the left top left there,
you've got people playing football and
then in the middle there you've got an
abstract representation of a game.
So computer games are quite interesting
because they've taken the whole
abstraction process one step further
right there.
Representations of representations of
representation so you can play with them
and their simulation,
so then the ones on the,
on the on the far right,
the bottom one,
you see there's a guy standing down
there and he's gazing up at God and
heaven with this cross.
Right?
And to me that essentially a dominance
relationship is that.
Think about it.
Anyway,
so,
so first of all,
you're looking up to see the source of
authority.
So there's the idea that authority is
above you.
Somehow I would say that that
representation is an attempt to capture
an image.
What authority constitutes.
Now when people were capturing this an
image like they are in that particular
drawing,
it isn't that they were trying to put
into images something they understood in
an articulated way.
It's exactly the opposite is that the
phenomena itself of authority as a
concept emerged on the basis of the
processes we've been describing,
which means that it emerged from the
bottom up as as as increasingly complex
social animals organize themselves into
increasingly complex and large social
hierarchies.
There was an emergence and emergence of
morality as a consequence of that
organization.
And then there was an observation of it,
you might think,
well,
what form would that observation take?
And it's a union hypothesis and I think
it's a very good one that part of what
the artistic endeavor does is transmute
what's not understood yet into image,
image and drama.
And that's the source of its further
articulation up into stateable rules.
So for so,
so first of all,
the bottom picture there indicates that
a human being can be struck by the
concept of authority per se.
You know,
so you might think,
well what's even more of an authority
than an authority?
And the answer to that is it's whatever
makes authorities authorities across a
large class if authorities and they
might say,
well what is that?
And the answer to that is,
while we're still figuring that out,
because it's so damn complicated,
it's unbelievably complicated.
Now I can tell you some things about
that image.
I can tell you some things that it
represents.
What it means is that first of all,
it means that authority has this
transpersonal process that's
transpersonal existence,
that's eternal.
So,
and why is that?
Well,
it's because what makes authority
authority is stable across hierarchies.
Hierarchies can come and go,
but the concept itself has an eternal
element to it because it remains
constant across transformations and I
think that's represented in the symbolic
realm by the idea of God in heaven.
It's something like that.
Now I got to tell you to.
I'm not trying to reduce these religious
explanations to the concepts that I'm
describing because I don't think that
what I'm telling you is a complete
representation of what happens,
so there's a transcendent element to
religious thinking that you can't
explain away by by reducing it to its
constituent elements.
But having said that,
we're just going to put that aside.
We're going to try to make it as
concrete as possible.
Now in this representation,
the idea basically is that authority has
something to do with the father,
right?
It has something to do with eternity and
transcendence and it also has something
to do with the cross.
It's Christian representation,
so that's fine.
It's a hypothesis is what that is.
Now it's a weird hypothesis,
right?
If you look at that picture and you
start thinking about it from an
anthropological perspective instead of a
personal perspective,
you might think,
well,
what the hell are these creatures up to
when they're making representation like
that?
It's what are they trying to express,
you know,
and the classical view would be,
well,
this is a belief and the belief is being
imposed on the viewers.
It's like,
well,
let's,
let's not assume that.
Let's,
let's try something different.
Let's assume that it's an explanation
that people have been trying to work out
that nobody really understands and I
think that that's a much better way of
looking at it because otherwise you're
stuck with some bloody conspiracy theory
of history or something like that.
You know,
and I think one of the advantages we
have in the 21st century is because our
culture now is composed of such an
intermingling of cultures.
It enables people,
let's say for the sake of argument in
the dominant culture to step outside of
their own presuppositions and start to
view themselves as anthropologists.
Okay,
so you think,
well,
what are people up to?
Well,
first of all,
that figure,
I'm sorry it's not bigger,
but I'll show you a bigger one later is
being held up in heaven by angels so it
it's,
it's like there's an idea that it's,
it's.
There is some divine entities out of
which a top divine entity emerges and
there's a.
that's a father figure in that
representation.
It's associated with light and it has
this cross and the cross is a very,
very old symbol and so and in
Christianity obviously the cross isn't
representative of the father.
It's representative of the sun and so
that's interesting because what that
means is this representation says that
whatever authority is,
has something of the father and
something of the son,
and the reason I'm telling you that is
because it's going to become very
relevant when I tell you the Egyptian,
that one of the fundamental variance of
the central Egyptian religious story a
little bit later in class.
So it's not just the farther.
There's something else.
And one of the mysteries about
Christianity for example,
and this is one of the things,
the rationalist.
It's always take Christianity to task
four is the idea that God is a,
you know,
is a three part unity.
What's very bizarre idea,
you know,
and obviously it's not an empirical
idea,
it's like it's some bizarre fantasy and
I think that it's expressed quite well
in that drawing,
at least part of it,
which is,
well yeah,
it's a unity because there's something
similar about the father in the son and
there's something that,
that they both need from each other and
it's a dynamic interplay,
but it also has to be something that's
differentiated.
There's utility in differentiating the
concept,
so.
Okay,
so keep that in mind.
Now the top one there on the right,
that's Moses,
and I'll tell you the story of exodus in
detail later in the class,
but one of the things I want to,
to introduce you to is this possibility.
So what happens in exodus basically is
it's a,
it's a tyranny descend into chaos.
Rise story,
right?
So it's like a,
in some sense,
the exodus story is a microcosm of the
entire Christian Bible.
So that's kind of interesting.
It's,
it's a story about transformation nested
inside a broader story about
transformation.
The transformation is everyone's in a
tyranny and they're being exploited and
they need to escape.
Okay,
so you should be able to relate to that
because everybody is in a tyranny and
they're trying to escape.
Now the degree to which the tyranny is
tyrannical varies a lot between
societies,
but the classic adolescent experience
and you see this and coming of age
novel,
it's all at the time,
is the young person against the
establishment,
something like that.
Right,
and that's,
I would say that's an existential,
that's an existential condition.
It's always the young person against,
against the establishment.
Now the establishment is also helping
the young person,
so it's not the only story,
but it's.
It's an architectural component of the
story,
so you have to escape from the tyranny
of the group and what happens when you
escape from that is your cast into chaos
even if it's a tyrannical group,
because even a tyrannical group provides
you with a hierarchy and an identity and
maybe it's a pathological hierarchy and
a pathological identity,
but you could still make the case that
it's better than no identity at all and
I think you play that situation by
situation.
I mean remember what happens to the
Israel lights,
right?
They leave Egypt,
they were all slaves there and they
ended up in a desert and they're
wandering around in the desert for 40
years and lot of them are thinking,
Hey,
it's not so obvious that this chaotic
existence out here in a desert is better
than where I know my three meals a day
are coming from and you know,
you don't want to think about that is
merely something that's an abstraction.
It's like there's plenty of people in
Russia who long for the Soviet Union.
Right?
Because there were,
there was a stability that was
associated with it.
Now we would say,
and I think the Russians themselves said
that was a pathological stability,
but whether it was worse than the
consequent chaos is.
Well,
it's to be,
it's to be seen.
We don't know at the moment for some
societies like Poland,
so like Poland seems to have pulled out
of it quite nicely,
but there are other countries that
haven't.
So the chaos,
and I think this is also the conundrum.
It's very much thing we're thinking
about this because you might think what
stops people from progressing in terms
of the quality of their personality
structure.
And the answer to that is,
well,
every time you want to move forward you
have to let something go and there's a
disintegration associated with that.
And so that's somewhat terrifying.
So like maybe you find,
well the case of the abused spouse is a
good one.
Why go back to someone who abuses you
and people usually do and.
Well,
and that's partly because,
you know,
couples abuse each other all the time,
so it's a matter of degree.
But you know,
if you,
if you go out on the spectrum to the
point where it's pretty damn obvious
that the abuse is criminal,
let's say,
because that's sort of the bordering
line,
people will still return.
Well,
why really hard question why sometimes
it's because the abuser conspires to
make sure that the abused person isn't a
position of such weakness,
that they actually can't leave.
They have no money,
they have no.
And they're terrified.
So you know,
that's that aside.
Well,
what do you give up when you leave while
you give up everything you give up your
past,
you know,
because you have to think,
Jeez,
that was a mistake and that's going to
require a lot of thinking through to
figure out why you made that particular
mistake and how not to make it again,
because you probably will because
whatever got you into that situation to
begin with is undoubtedly still there
unless you fixed it.
And then of course your future is shot,
right?
And so as your present self image and
that's a chaotic collapse,
you know,
it might mean that you have to move
cities.
God only knows you have to change jobs,
you have to change where you live,
you have to change all your friends.
It's like,
is that better?
Well,
not obviously,
and so people won't take the leap off
the burning,
you know,
the burning grasslands on the cliff into
the water below and it's not surprising
because who knows how many sharks are
down there and that it's really useful
to to understand it that way I think
because it tells you why people won't
transcend themselves constantly.
It's like,
well,
you have to make a sacrifice and you
know,
it's not always obvious that the sacrum,
that the gain you will make,
the sacrifice is worth the costs of the
sacrifice and that's even in extreme
conditions.
And that's partly why exit.
This is such an archetypal story.
It's like it's not obvious at all to the
Israel lights when they're out in the
desert wandering about half starving,
that it's only faith that keeps them
going.
Faith that there might be something
better at the other end.
It's like,
well,
so what happens is that they get pretty
damn crabby at Moses for leading them
out there.
You know,
and they start to worship all sorts of
alternative gods,
which is exactly what you do when you're
in chaos by the way,
because when you're in chaos,
you're looking for new moral principles
to Orient Yourself by,
you know,
and those are new hierarchies of value.
And to think about those as alternative
structures of,
you know,
of dominant structures of value that
could be represented by a given daddy,
that's perfectly reasonable thing to do
is especially in the absence of
articulated knowledge of what a moral
structure is,
it's a perfectly reasonable way to
represent it.
So that happened.
So the Israelites are trying to orient
themselves on this trip.
They don't know what the hell you're
doing.
And then another thing happens that's
quite interesting is that,
well,
they're all squabbling among each other.
Now I want to tell you a story about
that.
So among the,
uh,
bushmen,
the Kalahari Bushman,
who by the way look to be the most
genetically similar of all human beings,
to what our earliest relatives would
have been who moved out of Africa.
It's something like that.
So that's kind of interesting.
The Kalahari Bushmen are very
egalitarian society and people like to
think that egalitarian societies,
because they were Galitary Ian are
peaceful,
but that's not true at all.
They're not peaceful at all and neither
is the Bushman society.
And the problem with the bushmen society
is,
is that,
let's say art and whole,
Ah,
you know,
you still my wife,
okay,
well there's no hierarchy.
So what am I going to do about that?
There's no authority to appeal to,
so I'm stuck with it.
So what am I going to do?
Well,
often I'm just going to wait around
until I get my chance and then I'm going
to take out my little bow and Arrow with
a poisoned Arrow and I'm going to nail
you with it because what else is there?
There's no authority.
Now,
this is what the Bushman do,
very interesting is that there's another
tribe located near them and I think it's
the band too,
but I'm not absolutely certain,
but I think it's the band and they have
a hierarchical structure.
So there is an authority and so now the
Bushman,
we'll go to the band to to have their
disputes mediated so they don't just
have to shoot each other when,
when they have an argument.
So it's,
it's quite interesting.
It's we're thinking about because in a
flat egalitarianism society,
nobody has the final word and when
everyone's getting along that's
perfectly fine,
but as soon as two people aren't getting
along,
it's like,
who do we turn to to mediate this?
Okay.
So the Israelites had that problem in
the archetypal story.
And so what happens in relationship to
Moses is that every time to Israelites
have some squawk about who's chicken is,
who's.
They have to come to Moses and they pour
out their tale of woe and he has to sit
there and listen to it.
And then he has to decide who's right
now.
So he's serving as a judge.
Now you've got to think,
what are you doing when you're judging,
which is a word that's all.
You know.
People say,
well,
don't judge me.
It's like,
really?
It's like that's the same as not
thinking.
You know,
judging is actually an extraordinarily
useful ability because it helps you
separate out what isn't good for
anything from what's valuable.
It's like it isn't absence of judgment.
You want.
It's it's judicial judgment,
right?
Principled judgment.
And then you might say,
well what is that?
Well,
that's a good question.
You could say,
well,
it's all arbitrary anyways.
Well then you've just got chaos.
So that's not much of a solution.
Okay.
So the Israelites are coming to Moses
like nonstop bitching about these little
trivial things that are aggravating them
to death and he's sitting there like for
years,
literally for years,
listening to them like 14 hours a day
and finally he does miss it so long that
I think it's his father in law who tells
him he has to stop and distribute the
responsibility because he's just going
to get exhausted.
But you can imagine what happens to you
if you sit there and judge and judge and
judge and judge and judge and judge and
judge is that you're building up a very
articulated and differentiated
representation of the moral structure
that actually constitutes your society.
Because imagine if you're a good judge,
here's what has to happen.
You two are at each other's throats,
like in a really homicidal way,
so things have gone too far and so then
I have to listen to you both and I have
to decide what you're going to do,
but I have to do something even more
spectacular than that.
I have to decided in a way that you both
feel is more acceptable than killing
each other and that means you have to
feel that not only is it is it
reasonable and just it also has to
absolve you of your responsibility to
seek revenge because that's one of the
functions of law that people never think
about.
It's like if someone.
You may not remember this because you're
all young,
but when Michael Dukakis I'm hoping was
running for president,
somebody asked him what he would do.
They were having it Republicans.
He was a democrat.
He had.
He had let some character out of jail
and he went and killed someone and so
the Republicans made a big deal out of
that during the presidential convention
and maybe there isn't a rape involved as
possible.
He was asked on tv what he would do if
his own wife was raped,
you know,
which is pretty good question and do
cactus blue the answer because he w he
kind of wishy washy did way,
you know,
so the right answer is with every fiber
of my being,
I'd like to chop them into bits,
but as a civilized person I'm willing to
defer that to the judicial system
because they'll take appropriate and
measured steps and then my proclivity
won't generate itself through the
community because the danger is if I
take vicious revenge that that'll start
a cycle of revenge and then the whole
thing falls apart and so it's the
judicial system's responsibility to take
that moral burden off my shoulders
because you know what's the right
response when someone you love this
terribly hurt,
we'll it's not,
well,
I'll just forget about that and go home.
It's like that's what you do.
If your contempt to billy week
fundamentally,
so the judicial system has to stand in
for you.
So anyways,
the point is if you make a judgment,
the judgment won't hold unless it suits
the people who are being judged and it's
not going to suit them unless it matches
the implicit moral presuppositions that
they're already bringing to the dispute.
Now you see this in kids,
you know the kids will be arguing over a
toy and then they'll come to the mother
or the father and they'll say,
and then the mother will say,
well,
you do this and you do this,
and if the kids don't like that,
they'll go,
well,
that's not fair.
And kids like,
they're really,
they're really obsessed with fair.
They want exactly fair in an
understandable way.
So the parent not only has to adjudicate
the dispute,
but the parent has to adjudicate the
dispute in a manner that the children
will accept.
Or they'll just go back into the other
room and have the fight all over again.
Right?
Or they'll poke each other.
You know,
there'll be,
there'll be tit for tat revenge going on
nonstop.
So what that means is that the
articulated representation of the
solution has to match the embodied
expectation of the population.
So there's already a morality that's
governing their interactions.
They just don't know what it is.
If there wasn't,
they wouldn't even know when they had
been wronged.
Right?
Because you can't figure out when you're
wrong,
unless you know when you're not wrong.
So to say,
well I've been wronged means to say,
well,
I don't know what's going on here,
but it doesn't seem fair.
And so then Pearl Moses has to look at
that and he has to think about it and he
has to think,
well why is this fair and why is it
unfair and who is right here?
And then what's the solution?
And the story represents him as doing
that for the $10,000,
it would take someone to become an
absolute expert at doing it.
Well then the story,
what the story essentially relates is
the revelation of a moral code.
And that's the Ten Commandments,
right?
Think,
well,
they say the 10 commandments came from
God.
Well that's fine.
We kind of have an idea about God that's
already stemming from the bottom
picture,
so it's the abstract representation of
what constitutes the source of authority
across time.
That's a perfectly reasonable way of
thinking about it.
And Moses,
he has this bright revelation which is
like a moment of insight.
Now what happens in psychotherapy when
you have a moment of insight is that you
figure out what you've already,
that you figure out what you're already
doing.
That's what happens because you come to
the therapist and you say,
look,
I had this relationship and this is how
it went.
Then,
uh,
this relationship and it went the same
way and this relationship and it went
the same way.
What's going on?
And so then you talk about it and you
talk about it and talk about it until
all of a sudden bang,
you think,
ah,
here's the explanation that maps onto
the behavior and it feels like a fit.
Right?
And that's the insight moment.
It's like,
well,
I got it.
And it's interesting because if you,
you know,
I do dream interpretation fairly
regularly and you know,
you think,
well that's kind of like astrology and
you know it,
that's a perfectly reasonable objection
except that it's more like literary
interpretation and you think,
well,
how do you know when you've got it
right?
And the answer is,
well,
it's an insight like you,
you talk about it and all of a sudden it
sort of crystallizes the person goes,
oh yeah,
that fits go.
I've got it.
How you figure that out.
I don't really understand.
I think I don't get it exactly.
I think it's something like when you
get,
when you get the map right,
what happens is that there's an
understanding of how that generalizes
across situations.
And so partly that simplifies the
problem,
you know,
you say,
well here's the rule instead of having
to act it out on stage.
And I think the reason that that would
come with a,
with a burst of insight is because it's
simpler and more efficient and so your
body recognize it,
right?
Recognizes it as an optimal solution.
And I think it also opens up new
possibilities for the future and I think
that gives you a dopamine kick.
And so that's why it's.
That's why that moment of insight is
associated with this really potent and
effective marker.
And that's a revelation when you have a
moment of insight.
It's a revelation.
The people even say that.
Now we might not think anymore that it's
a divine revelation,
but I will tell you if you had a
revelation of sufficient magnitude,
so maybe it was one way up in your
abstraction hierarchy,
if you had a revelation at that level,
you would describe it as a religious
experience.
People do all the time.
It's happens to alcoholics all the time
when their recovery,
you know they have a flash of insight
and that's when a new personality gets
catalyzed and if that happens to them,
sometimes they can stop drinking.
It's the best.
Now,
maybe this is outdated because I knew
the literature 25 years ago,
but I doubt it because we haven't made
really any progress in treating
alcoholics,
revelatory,
personality,
transformation,
cures,
alcoholism.
Now we don't know necessarily know how
to bring in about,
but you know,
the 12 step programs try to bring it
about.
So.
Okay.
So you can think about all that.
There's a,
there's a bigger representation of the
picture.
So that's authority.
What is authority?
Well,
there's a now I'm hoping it's been a
while since I looked at these pictures.
I'm hoping that picture
at that.
I think that picture is a way.
I think it's good step duray and I think
that's Moses receiving the tablets from
God,
but I might be wrong,
but I think that's what it is.
And there's light to associate.
Yep.
What
they just didn't know that they knew it.
They didn't know what to do
or even necessarily why they'd been
wronged.
They just have a sense that this wasn't
right.
And that's.
I think the best way to think about that
is to think about five-year-olds.
They know when somebody breaks a rule,
but they don't know what to do about it.
That bug really bugs them.
That's a phd and observation too.
You're not playing by the rules.
That's enough to make many young kids
cry.
Right,
and when they're crying and you think
what happens when you're crying,
while it's a distress call,
that's it's an.
It's a request for the intervention of
authority.
That's what crying is,
so the kid knows something's gone wrong.
His pattern detection system is not
sophisticated,
but his capacity to represent that and
articulate it well from a Ph,
Eddie and perspective that doesn't come
until multiple stages of development
later,
like the highest level of development
and lots of people according to Piaget
don't even get there.
Right,
and that would be the ability to to play
games with the rules of games and so you
do that when you were having a
constitutional discussion for example,
or maybe when you're talking with your
friends on the playing field about what
the rules are going to be for a pickup
football game.
So you're so you can conceptualize
yourself at that point as not only a
thing that is good because that thing
can follow rules,
which is an earlier stage of,
but that as a thing that's good because
not only can it follow rules that can
abstractly represent the rules,
it can engage in a discussion about the
rules and I can update them and I would
say that's part of what's being
represented by this picture on the left.
So the father is the thing that's the
rules and the son in this representation
is the thing that can update the rules
now it has to die and come back in order
to update the rules.
And so that's partly why the the father
in that figure is holding a cross
because the cross is a symbol of death
and reconstruction.
That's the price you pay for
reformatting the rules because you have
to do that to yourself too.
So Yep.
Value in the extraction is not to play
the game which actually pay attention
to.
Well it's,
it's exactly the advantage of abstract
representation.
You can start to manipulate the
representations before you manipulate
the thing.
So that means you can start to think
about morality.
Now,
is that a good thing?
Well,
I think it was Alfred North Whitehead.
I hate taping these because all these
errors that I'm making in my memory
going to be preserved.
But anyways,
I think it was Alfred North Whitehead
who said something like,
the reason to think the reason that
thought is valuable is because we can
let our thoughts die instead of
ourselves.
Right?
And so,
so then you think,
well,
once you can lay out the rules,
okay,
yeah,
the kids are playing a game.
One kid cheats or,
or another kid suspects the first kid is
cheated and there's,
there's no adults around.
So what,
what's the outcome?
Well,
one outcome is the game stops.
That's a high probability outcome or the
game continues,
but no one's having any fun or one kid
gets resentful and Solomon and the other
kid just oppose,
imposes his will or they fight.
That's it.
Those are the options.
Now when they can abstractly represent
the rules,
first of all,
they can agree on them before they play
the game and kids do that automatically.
So if for example,
if you watch kids play pretend games,
what they do first,
you can probably all remember this from
when you were little kids.
If you're,
you're playing some pretend game in a
blanket fort or something.
Maybe you get together with all the
other kids and you think,
okay,
well this is your role in this is your
role and that's your role and you know,
and here's what we're going to do.
Here's going to be the little drama will
lay out.
Some kids are very good at that.
Once you can get the rules abstracted,
you can talk about the damn things
instead of having to kill each other and
you can also update them in principle,
run simulations of what would happen
with the update,
which is basically what an argument is
or a debate and then you can implement
them.
And so hopefully you can get rid of the
stupid updates before you actually
implement them and die because you
implemented them.
And so the other advantage to
abstraction either in drama or in
articulation is that you can transfer
the rules more or more efficiently.
So you can get the kid to act out the
rule,
but you can also say here's the rule and
you should follow it in multiple
situations and then they don't have to
learn purely through imitation to embody
that rule across all possible
situations.
So whatever advantages abstraction has,
the pulling out of the more rural system
from the underlying behavior has those
advantages and disadvantages.
The disadvantages,
while you can come up with a perfectly
good reason why you shouldn't keep doing
what your forefathers have done for 20
centuries,
you know,
because it doesn't make any sense.
Well it does.
You just don't know why.
And you know,
you can easily.
It's like the Mesopotamians last week we
were talking about,
remember the noisy God's killed app
suit.
I didn't know what the hell he was good
for.
It's like,
you know,
he's there shield against chaos.
He's their tradition.
It's like,
well we'll just kill them and see what
happens.
It's like,
you better be careful because lurking
behind your tradition is chaos.
And you know you might be the master of
chaos,
but you're probably not.
So look out now,
we got some clue from the Mesopotamians
what the master of chaos was like.
The master of chaos was a new kind of
God who had eyes all the way around his
head who could speak magic words.
So there's a.
there's an attention verbalization
communication element to that and the
Mesopotamians figured out that thing
should be at the top.
Now that's it's.
It's.
It's staggering insight to think that
because it also might be right.
It's like,
okay,
what should you follow?
Well,
the first answer is follow the damn
rules.
Why?
Well,
because that's what people expect and
you won't get into too much trouble if
you do that.
But then you might say,
well,
sometimes the rules are wrong,
or sometimes they don't apply.
Okay,
that's definitely true.
Then what?
Well that's a whole different issue.
Well,
in the Mesopotamians would say that's a
really good time to pay attention and to
confront the chaos voluntarily and to
communicate about what you're doing and
to reformat the world,
restructure the world as a consequence
of your confrontation with this chaos.
And that's,
that's a higher daddy.
And I think it's the god of attention,
fundamentally.
It's something like that,
but it's more,
it's attention plus articulation plus
communication.
And that would be the highest.
So the Mesopotamians would say that's
the highest God.
It's a hypothesis.
So to the degree now I wanted to tell
you the rest of the Mesopotamian story.
So cool.
So you remember that Margaret goes off
and conquers tire.
Matt puts it into net,
cuts it into pieces,
makes the world okay.
And then out of Time Matt has organized
this army to go against Marduk and his
and his and and his army.
And what time does,
when she goes out to have a war is she's
at the forefront.
No,
she sort of behind the scenes
maneuvering and manipulating everything.
And she puts,
she creates this like all sorts of
monsters.
The worst monster she can think up and
then have all those monsters.
She picks the worst possible monster and
she puts him at the head of the Phalanx
that goes into battle and his name is
king.
And so martin defeats him too.
So he's like a,
he's a bit of a precursor of Satan.
He's like,
he's a,
he's the agent of chaos,
but he's more embodied,
you know.
Anyways,
Martik makes human beings out of the
blood of king new,
which is also extraordinarily
interesting idea,
but it's very much like the idea in
genesis that was picked up particularly
by the Catholics that human beings are
characterized by original sin,
right?
We're made out of the blood of the worst
monster,
and I took me a long time to think that
through.
I thought,
what the hell?
Why,
why,
why would they think that?
And I think the reason is is that
because human beings are the only things
on the planet that can deceive you,
right?
Like everything else is either the way
it is or you just don't understand it.
It's not like the garbage can.
He isn't trying to deceive you.
There's things about it you don't
understand like at subatomic structure,
but it's not actively fighting against
your comprehension.
Whereas human beings,
there are completely different creatures
and it's definitely the case that along
with our capacity for abstraction and
self consciousness,
we immediately evolved the ability for
high level intrigue and deception and
even see that in kids,
the smarter the kid,
the earlier they learn to lie and you
can see that's,
that's.
You can't separate that from the
capacity to spin off alternative
simulated worlds because that's what a
lie is,
except if you're doing it in a
normalized manner,
you're trying to spin off a world that
actually represents the real world
better instead of trying to spin off a
simulation that allows you to avoid
responsibility for something.
So I think that.
So it's interesting that you know,
the Mesopotamians also,
we're very cognizant of the fact that
there is something in human beings which
was fundamentally the capacity for
deceitful and evil auction.
That was also something that really has
to be contended with,
but they also assumed that Marduk was
the master of that.
So that's pretty cool.
It was very implicit in the story.
So what happens?
So the,
the emperor,
so the emperor lived in a walled city
because cities were world at that time
and the reason for that was if they
weren't Walden,
the marauding barbarians would come in
and kill all the men and take all the
women and burned the place to the ground
and steal everything.
So you know,
people weren't all that happy when that
happens.
So they built big walls to make sure
that that was difficult.
So that was order inside the walls and
chaos outside and chaos was out were the
barbarians are,
which is still what we think.
But what would happen to the emperor,
the New Year's ceremony was that they
would take them outside the city wall.
So they take the emperor who's like king
of order,
they take them outside into chaos to
remind them that even the emperor could,
is,
uh,
is surrounded by chaos.
So then they strip them of all the
clothing and symbols that made him
emperor and they'd make a meal.
And then the priest would make him
recount for the last year.
All the things he did that made him not
a good mark.
So he was supposed to embody Martin,
that was what made him the emperor to
the degree that he could embody the
attentive and communicated forest that
could keep chaos at bay.
He deserved to be emperor.
So that was.
So that's the idea of sovereignty,
right?
Of lawful sovereignty.
It's a brilliant.
It's brilliant.
They take him.
Now the problem is is the emperor might
forget that he's supposed to be Marduk
and he might just be,
you know,
guy with the biggest heroin who's
stealing everything he possibly can,
which is really not what he's supposed
to be doing.
So they take them outside at the New
Year's festival when the world was going
to be renewed,
which we still do,
right?
Because it's out with the old year.
And with the new,
that's when you make your resolutions to
be a better person.
Right?
So this is an ancient ceremony.
Okay,
out you take the emperor,
strip him of his emperor close.
So now he's just some dude.
You have a kneeling there and then
you'll walk them with a glove to just
remind him that he's not boss of
everything.
And then you get them to recount all his
sins basically,
but the sins were okay in the last year,
how did you fail in your task as a
representative of Martech on earth?
And so then the emperor hypothetically
would tell everybody why he was allowed
to and useless in six different ways and
promise to be better.
And then the Mesopotamians would take
statues out of the city that represented
the gods that we've talked about,
and they would reenact the battle of
Marduk against chaos.
They,
they'd act that out.
And then at the end the emperor would
sleep with a ritual prostitute like.
So she'd be like a temple virgin
representing the benevolent element of
femininity.
And then then they'd go back in and have
their year start.
Now it's very much like St George and
the Dragon,
if you think about it,
right?
You know the Saint George and the Dragon
Story.
St George Goes,
a dragon has captured a virgin and St
George is out there.
He's going to slay the dragon and free
the virgin.
And that works at multiple levels of
analysis simultaneously.
One level is the guy who's best at
keeping chaos at bay is going to be the
guy who was most attractive to women
because women are smart,
so that's first.
That's like the architectural level or
that.
That's sorry.
That's the biological level.
The architectural level is even more
abstract.
It's that the dragon tie,
Matt is a representation of chaos itself
and chaos is something that's deeply
informative,
so the dragon has gold or it has a
virgin.
Depends on how the story works out.
When you encountered that,
you free something of value and that's
something that you can.
You can incorporate,
you can have.
That's more like the treasure variant of
the story.
It's also good if you kind of spread it
around a little bit so because otherwise
it's an incomplete story.
Okay,
so what's happening?
What's happening in Mesopotamia at that
time,
his many,
many tribes are being brought together.
They've all got their own mythology and
everyone's trying to figure out,
okay,
how do we benefit from the fact that
we're all going to live together without
having to kill each other?
Which is the standard human problem,
right?
Because it's good to cooperate,
but you don't want the foreigners upset
and you're,
you're,
you're a horse cart and,
and you don't want the whole thing
collapsing into chaos.
So how do you balance that?
So what you could imagine Eliana called
this the war of the Gods in heaven,
which is a very common mythological
motif.
So you can imagine,
if you will,
all these tribes have their own culture
and their own representation of that
culture.
Often in mythological stories,
they're brought together.
Where does the war take place?
Well,
if it doesn't take place between the
people,
which is what will happen if they can't
cooperate,
it's going to take place between the
representations.
So what's happening is,
you know,
culture has got a story and culture be
he's got a story and the story's kind of
are the same and they're kind of not the
same.
And so you think,
well then everybody thinks,
well,
you've got your God,
and I've got mine.
It's like,
who?
Who,
who,
who are we going to pay any attention to
here?
And one answer is,
well,
just kill you.
And that'll be the end of the problem.
My God wins.
Or another issue would be,
well,
we'll just let everything drop into
chaos,
which in some sense I think is what
happened to Rome.
It just ate so many gods can no longer
survive.
Or we're going to figure out how to get
along together.
Well that means your story in my story
have to be brought together.
So they're commensurate.
Now,
one of the things that's quite
interesting is that you can actually see
this happening in,
in the oldest books in the Bible.
So the Bible is a collection of books,
right?
And there's a lot of books that were
sort of Bible like that didn't get into
the final version when people were
arguing about which should be in an inch
in what order.
So the books were written and there's
huge arguments about what should be
included and what shouldn't and what
sequence they should be included in.
And these arguments went over thousands
of years,
is that major legal arguments.
But if you go into the,
into genesis for example,
and you look at the story of Adam and
Eve,
what you find is it's not one story,
it's at least two and maybe three and
that's been identified through
psycholinguistic analysis and also
through anthropological investigation.
And so there's version one and there's
version two and then the guy they call
the redactor,
he was a hypothetical character,
organize these stories,
cut them apart and sequenced them,
tried to keep both in some order that
made sense.
And so what he was basically doing was
taking two traditions whose stories had
some archetipal similarity,
but who's,
who's details deferred and he's trying
to make them logically coherent so they
can fit together.
And you think,
well,
why is he doing that?
Well,
the answer is we either get our stories
together or you're a slave and I'm a
tyrant,
or the reverse,
or we kill each other.
Those are the options.
Well,
apart from pure descend into chaos,
which is,
you know,
not going to do either of us any good
either.
That's kind of a nihilism and it's a
real threat to human societies.
So that's pretty cool.
So the war between the Gods in the
heavens is something like this.
It's like the top left hand
representation is too simple.
We know that because when you're doing
something it isn't.
When you're going from point a to point
B and you act that out because sometimes
you're working at a much more abstract
level,
you might say,
well I'm trying to do well at
university.
Well how do you move your body to
accomplish that will now answer is
that's the wrong level of resolution.
To answer that question,
you'd go trying to do well in
university.
Okay.
How do you subdivide that?
I take five classes.
Okay,
fine.
Now you got subdivided down to five
classes.
I do the readings in each class.
So that's getting closer to behavior,
right?
How do you do the readings?
Well I opened the book and I moved my
eyes.
Right.
So then you get.
Then you're down to a high,
low resolution level of.
Of Representation.
But so when you look at the thing on the
top left,
it's really more like the thing in the
middle.
It's nested,
it's nested value orientations that
ground out in action and how those are
going to be nested.
Exactly.
That's either war discussion that that
determines that war thought or
discussion.
That's it.
That's what you've got,
and if you can't do it with the first
two thought and discussion,
the only recourse you have is war or the
degeneration indicates which will
produce war anyways,
so and then there's a further
transformation is which is well,
if I could do any of these three things
to further my move forward,
which takes priority.
Now you're solving that problem all the
time or you can't act and sometimes
you'll actually see this in yourself.
You know sometimes,
okay,
if you're driving somewhere,
you're not sure whether you're going to
go straight or go left.
You kind of go,
you flip between them.
You know in confusion.
Well,
you're not gonna go anywhere.
If you're doing that,
you have to make one more important the
other than before you can act.
And so whenever you're undertaking any
action,
what you've done is organize the whole
hierarchy of values so that there's no
contradictions at the level you're
operating or you're frozen.
And so you're making value judgments all
the time.
And you know,
this is like,
should you go to the library or should
you read your book at home,
you know,
or maybe you shouldn't you be studying
for that course or this course,
you know,
or when you're really feeling desperate,
should you be in that discipline or
should you be in university or should
you be alive,
right?
That's when you should visit very
seldomly.
No,
you want the local problem to,
to,
to dominate that.
That's.
Well,
if,
if things have got very disorganized,
you're going to go all the way to the
top.
You know,
it's very,
very hard on people to do that.
So societies have to get their
priorities straight,
which is their value hierarchies and
individuals do to.
And then if you're looking at how that
happens over the historical timespan,
you're going to think good.
So battle of gods of the gods and habit,
that's the higher.
And that is what happens.
It's the right way of thinking about it.
If,
if,
if there is a transpersonal space,
that's the imagination in which these
longterm discussions in battles take
place.
You have to represent that somehow.
So human would think about that at least
in part is the collective unconscious
and the collective unconscious is.
Here's one way of thinking about it.
The collective unconscious is all those
behavioral patterns and presuppositions
that we share.
What are those?
Well,
we don't know.
We,
right?
We don't have a full account of that.
We're trying to figure it out.
So.
Okay.
So these are different representations
of this.
So the one on the left,
at the top,
there's another representation of what
constitutes authority.
There's the,
there's God the father,
you see these kind of got a little
pyramid hat on,
which I think is quite cool.
And it also,
I think helps explain why the damn Egypt
shins were so obsessed with pyramids.
You know,
it's a,
it's a hierarchical structure up here at
Mit.
And they thought about that as something
sacred.
And there is something sacred about a
hierarchical structure.
The question is what's the structure and
how should it be structured?
So there's God with his little pyramid
hat and then in front of them he's got
across and I think that's in an orb that
represents the world.
And then in front of that there's a dove
and the dove is the third part of the
Christian Trinity and the dove
represents the Holy Spirit.
And the Holy Spirit hypothetically is
you might think about it as the action
of conscience.
It's something like that.
It's the manifestation of tradition and
the capacity to date tradition in you.
So there's a personal element to it.
So and that's why the dove is a thing
that communicates between the heavenly
realms and the earthly realm.
Fundamentally,
something like that.
Now you see that on the American dollar
bill,
that's pretty cool because what they've
done there,
same kind of idea except the top of the
pyramid is detached from the bottom,
which I really love because what it's.
It's making this claim that the thing
that's at the top of the pyramid isn't
part of the pyramid.
And that's bloody brilliant and I think
that that's an observation.
The Egyptians first,
God right,
and we're going to tell that story here
in a minute.
It's that.
Think about it this way.
We'll go back to the game idea.
Your kids playing hockey and you say,
be a good sport now.
Then the question would be,
if the pyramid at that point,
is the hockey game,
if he's a good sport,
does that mean he's going to win the
hockey game and answer that is no.
It doesn't mean that.
What it means is that he's going to win
the game that goes across multiple sets
of games across very large spans of
time.
And so it's not really part of any
hierarchy.
It's something that's above them all.
And that's the best game to play.
So at least that's the theory.
And you know,
even in that representation,
there's an eye,
it's like pay attention,
pay attention.
You know,
the Washington monument at the top of it
has a pyramid,
you know,
and there's a cap on that pyramid and
the cap is made out of aluminum.
And you might think,
well why would it be made out of
aluminum?
And the answer was when that monument
was made,
aluminum was the most precious metal on
the planet because people had just
figured out how to make it.
So they made this nice cap that was even
more precious than gold.
So what this,
what the symbol is that the thing that's
at the top of the pyramid that isn't
quite connected to it is more precious
than gold.
And that's an l chemical idea too.
And it's right.
It's right.
It's not a metaphor or it is,
but it's a lot of things we think are
metaphors aren't,
they're just descriptions of things at
our level we don't understand.
Yep.
Sacred
cause it keeps chaos in order.
Properly balanced everywhere.
And we'll get into that more deeply as
we get into these stories.
It's a very good question.
You know,
town so that you sort of have to answer
well,
what constitutes sacred and,
and what I would say is the more
unshakable a truth,
the more sacred it is.
Now you might say,
well,
how do you know if one truth is more
unshakable than another?
And the answer is,
well,
you got to figure that out.
And so what I'm presenting as far as I
can tell is how people have figured that
out over God only knows what's what span
of time.
Like it's 100,
it's 150,000
years for sure of actually trying to
figure it out.
And then the dominance hierarchies
themselves,
man,
those things are.
We know there are 400 million years old.
So we've been working at this for a very
long period of time.
So now I would say,
well one of the things that sacred
roughly speaking is how you keep that
thing in tact and transforming because
if it's intact and it just falls apart
because their environment around it
changes,
right?
So what the hell good is that you can't
play the same game forever,
but you have to play a game.
So how do you do that?
Well,
that,
that's the question.
That's why I'm going to tell you the
Egyptian story.
So what time is it?
This is a good time for break and then
I'll come you come back and I'll tell
you this Egyptian story and it's a great
story.