Undoubtedly you've noticed that this is
being taped so the tapes will show up on
some relatively regular schedule.
Um,
I wouldn't expect that precisely because
I don't want to make any promises about,
you know exactly how quickly that'll be
done.
Martin Jang here is doing it on his own
accord so it's like,
you know,
two thumbs up for Martin as far as I'm
concerned.
So because he's done this for a number
of my courses and it's a lot of work and
it's much appreciated.
So anyways,
that's why all of this stuff is set up.
So,
um,
I think I told you pretty much about
what the class entails on your part,
you know,
um,
and if you,
you've heard this lecture and I'm sure
at least a reasonable number of you have
heard me lecture before,
so you sort of know how I'm going to
lecture and that was more or less how
I'm going to do it.
Um,
I'm,
I'm hoping that,
you know,
we can make this class like deadly
successful.
That's the idea.
And that you'll regard it as something
that,
you know,
depending on your participation,
obviously you'll regard it as something
that's really valuable.
I can tell any of the stuff I've learned
that I'm telling you about,
it has been so useful to me that I
can't,
uh,
I can't.
I can't really even communicate how
useful it's been.
It's been unbelievably useful.
And you know,
partly what I'm going to explain to you
if I can,
is why,
you know,
there are tenants of classical morality
and there's a variety of them and one of
them is,
for example,
don't lie.
And you know,
that's a tough one because you might
think,
well,
you know,
why not really?
Why not?
I mean,
if you can,
if,
if you can set up a situation so that
you benefit from a,
from an untruth,
what stops you from doing it,
you know,
and Dostoevsky and one of his most
famous statements,
he said,
if there's no god,
everything is permitted.
And it's a takeoff on Nietzsche and
thinking too,
and it's a problem that he thought would
be the fundamental problem of the 20th
century.
And I think he was absolutely right and
it's a question very much we're thinking
about.
It's like,
why bother with things that are moral?
Why do things right?
Is there even such a thing as doing
things right?
These are great questions.
You know,
and hopefully I'm going to try to do
with you guys is to show you what the
consequences.
I've been thinking about those things
for,
you know,
it's almost 30 years I guess now.
And I've,
you know,
I've got a ways,
certainly a ways that has been
satisfying to me and I want to tell you
what I've concluded and then you can
decide for yourself if you think it's
useful.
And one thing I would really encourage
you to do is like,
you should be skeptical about what I'm
telling you really like you should
question it.
Like,
I don't mean the kind of skepticism
that's like this because like,
you know,
I'm not here to prove myself to you at
all and you're not here to prove
yourself to me either.
So you have to listen,
you have to attend.
But by same token,
I would say like I'm telling you things
that I have tried to hammer to death,
I've tried to see if they were wrong,
you know,
because that's how you're supposed to
test ideas.
You throw out an idea and you have the
hammer,
the hell out of it,
see if you can see if it's wrong,
not whether it's right,
because that's an ideological thinking
and the things I'm telling you are
things I could not disprove.
They seem to stand up.
And I've tried multiple tests,
you know,
so one of them is sort of a consilience
test and the consumer says a word that
was defined by Edward or Wilson and
what,
when an,
when an explanation is consilience,
what that means is that it's coherent
across multiple levels of analysis,
you know.
And so I've tried to test the ideas that
I'm describing to you.
I've tried to determine whether they're
logically coherent and appropriate at
the level of general psychology and
clinical psychology and neuroscience and
narrative theory and religious thinking.
And then also to see if they're actually
applicable as practical as practical
realities in day to day life.
And an end in social life and the,
as far as I'm concerned,
they stand up.
That's been my experience and I've also
watched people over many years now try
to apply them in their own lives and all
I've been able to see so far with my
graduate students and so on is that they
works.
So you know,
ray for that.
And so we're going to try to understand
some basic issues like what the utility
of truth is.
And that's a really important question.
It's maybe the fundamental question is
truth useful?
And if so,
how and why?
And like man,
we're going to go after that.
Especially with regards to verbal truth
because there's something magical about
words.
There really is something magical about
them.
And the way you use words determines the
course of your life.
And maybe more than that maybe the
course of everyone's life.
So I wanted to explain to you how that
can be true and what it means.
So you know,
that should be relatively entertaining.
And hopefully,
what else I can tell you is I'm going to
throw out some key propositions.
There's probably about seven or eight of
them and what I'm hoping is that you'll
be able to use those propositions as
keys that will help you unlock things
that you wouldn't otherwise be able to
consciously understand.
And I gave you some example of that with
this little story,
you know,
because that little story happens to be
an extraordinarily deep little story and
it's,
you know,
it's so old that story like I think that
story stems from when we were still in
trees really.
And that our,
when our prime enemies were snakes,
because it does appear according to
Lynne Isbell anyways,
who's an anthropologist and in
California and that,
um,
our primary predators,
60 million years ago when we were
basically inhabiting trees,
were predatory snakes and that we
evolved with.
And so they're like,
human being versus snake Motif is not
only the oldest story we know from a
consciously articulated perspective,
but it might be the literal story of our
species as a biological entity.
So know that I'm telling you that
because it gives you some idea about how
deep these stories can go.
They can go to the really to the bottom
of things and if you know some of these
key propositions,
when you see archetipal stories
portrayed in front of you with,
and that happens all the time.
I been all the superhero movies that
have come out later,
later lately.
Nursing Home hoards of them,
they are tremendously expensive to make
a hundreds of millions of dollars.
Those things.
It's like they're all predicated and
archetipal themes,
you know,
and I think it's of great interest to
know the most expensive artifacts that
human beings produced or at least among
the most expensive artifacts that we
produce are precisely movies that are
computer generated to tell archetipal
stories,
you know?
And that's also the,
the technological process that in large
part is driving computer innovation
because the most demand that's being
placed on things like computer chips is
actually,
you know,
recreating reality,
CGI reality because it's the most
complicated thing to do.
So it's like,
what the hell?
Why are we doing that?
What's up with that?
Why would you spend $300,
million dollars making iron man,
you know,
there's a profit motive there obviously,
but everybody will go see it.
It's like,
what's up with you people?
You know,
you're going to see some Dingbat and a
metal suit fly around in the air.
You know,
that's not true.
It's like,
what are you doing at those movies?
You think while I'm entertaining myself.
It's like,
yeah,
right.
Except why is it entertaining
and why is it entertaining to all of
you?
Why is it entertaining to everyone?
You know?
There's a reason for that.
So partly what we're going to find out
too is what it is about stories that
attract our interest in why it is why
that is and it's not,
it's not merely entertainment and it's
like the most potent form of learning
that we have.
So well anyways,
so that's the goal.
And during this as well,
you know,
I hope that you can articulate
yourselves further and also come to some
deeper understanding about the absolute
essential nature of proper language use
in spoken language and in written
language because you bake,
you basically think and speak and write
yourself into existence.
And one of the things that means is you
should be very,
very careful with what you say because
you are literally bringing realms of
reality into being through speaking and
you want to make bloody sure that the
realms of reality that you're
participating in bringing into being are
the ones that you would actually like
yourself and those you love to inhabit.
So,
you know,
it's a,
well I don't have much more to say about
the course than that.
So what I'll do now is see if you have
any questions.
So yes,
I felt like I liked them all along.
I felt like he was getting out of
control but that he just wanted some
attention,
but I don't know why from the beginning
of the building and was dragging that
he's bad.
Right.
Well,
okay,
so the question is why is the dragon
portrayed as bad?
It's like,
well,
first of all,
we might notice that culture cross
culturally.
That's not necessarily the case,
right,
so the dragon in the West tends to be
something to conquer and something that
hoards
emergence strangely enough and it's
something to be conquered and the church
are to be taken,
but in east,
particularly among the Chinese,
the dragon is something that's positive
and what I would say is when we'll study
this,
when we get into the symbolism that's
associated with with reptiles,
fundamentally with predatory reptiles,
you'll see that the dragon is actually a
tremendously ambivalent representation
because it represents.
It really represents the unknown or even
more precisely,
it represents the element of the unknown
that you don't even know exists.
You don't because sometimes something
unexpected could happen to you,
but you can understand it when it
happens,
but sometimes something unexpected
happens to you when it's so unexpected
that you can't even conceptualize it.
I would say when the.
When the twin towers fell in New York,
that was an event like that,
it's really outside the domain of your
understanding and then there's a.
there's an ambivalence about that
because you don't know the nature of the
event precisely so the the,
the,
the predatory reptiles,
especially the treasure garden,
predatory reptiles stands for the
potential that exists in the unknown,
and that potential can be positive and
negative,
right?
Because it's the source of all new
things.
It's also the source of that which will
destroy them,
and so it's a very paradoxical entity.
Now,
one more thing,
so,
so the story implies that there's an
optimal size of dragon and I would say
while you're nervous,
systems are actually tuned to detect the
optimal size of dragons.
What we'll talk about this in great
detail as we go through the biology of
anxiety and discussed as it turns out,
which is something I've learned more
about recently.
You know how you can sometimes if you're
engaged in a task,
let's say a cognitive task,
you can find it overwhelming.
It's right something.
You're having a very difficult time
understanding and maybe you even wonder
if you're up to it.
Okay,
so you might say,
well,
your nervous system is indicating to you
that that's a threat,
and then other times you'll be dealing,
say with the cognitive task,
it's beneath your abilities and so it's
easy and you get bored,
so then you'll be dealing with a
cognitive task that it's like goldilocks
and the three bears,
right?
The temperature is just right and what
happens is that you have to grapple with
the task and it pushes you forward into
your development,
but it also really engages you so you're
tied right into it.
It's really easy to remember and
understand it and you make progress and
it's difficult in energy demanding,
but you're completely captivated by that
process.
That's the right size dragon and that's
what your nervous system is telling you.
It's say,
look,
this,
this amount of novel information in this
domain is precisely the amount that you
can incorporate,
well optimally transforming the
knowledge structures that you already
have without exceeding your capacity and
what that does.
The way your nervous system signals that
to you as you get interested in it,
you know,
because you white ask yourself like,
why do you get interested in things and
you bordered by some things and some
things are overwhelming.
It's like you don't have any choice
about that.
It's not a decision you make,
right?
It's something you discover as you act
in the world and so dragons of optimal
size are engaging and they push your
development,
but if they get too big then they're too
much potential.
I see an analogy between us and the
story of the baby in the crib ended up
heading everywhere.
It could be that like the thing about
the thing about that particular symbol
is that it describes the unknown outside
of conceptualization.
It's pure potential.
Now you know,
here's something to think about in
relationship to that.
I did a little Ted talk on potential,
which if you're interested in this sort
of thing,
you might want to look.
Look at it.
Because I,
I,
I got it right in that talk.
I thought,
you know,
there are different ways of thinking
about what the world's made out of and
you know,
we think that it's made of matter.
That's the basic dogmas of the,
of the materialist ground and I would
say,
look,
it's really useful to treat the world as
if it's made out of matter and look at
all the things that treating it that way
has allowed us to do.
But that doesn't mean it's the final
statement about the nature of reality
and whatever matter is,
is pretty damn strange when you get to
the bottom of it.
We don't understand it at all and we
don't understand its relationship to
consciousness.
But putting that aside,
we also act as if things other than
matter are real.
So for example,
we act as if potential is real and
that's a very strange thing because
potential by its very nature is not
really defined because otherwise it
would be potential,
right?
It would be actuality.
But you know,
all of you understand your parents when
they say,
well,
you know,
you should live up to your potential or
there's potential there.
And I would say actually most of the
time when we're dealing with the world,
what we're dealing with is not the
material world per se.
What we're dealing with is potential.
It's like what we're dealing with,
what this could be,
and we're trying to realize the
potential.
And so another thing that you could
think about it think about with regards
to the symbol of the dragon in
particular,
it's the Predator,
the predatory rep pile more and more
basically is that it's a,
it's a representation of potential.
And so,
and I,
I think the reason that it takes
reptilian forum,
and we're going to talk about this in
great detail,
is I think that what happened is we
evolved,
is that the systems that we originally
evolved to detect predators constituted
when,
when we underwent the cognitive
revolution that transformed the world
into abstract representations around us.
That initial print,
predatory detection system was
elaborated opt into the system that we
use to detect the unknown as such.
But you know,
because it's evolution,
the fundamental elements that evolved
over the course of evolution remained in
tact.
We're using the same systems and that
system has a language and so the
language is something like,
well,
the unexpected event is sort of like the
snake in the grass,
which is perfectly reasonable.
You can think about it as a metaphor.
It's.
I think it's deeper than a metaphor,
but you can think about it as a metaphor
and I would say,
well,
there are optimal size.
We have optimal sized adversaries and I
don't think you could live without an
optimal sized adversary.
Which is also an interesting.
It's a very interesting idea because you
know,
one of the things that people always
ask,
this is a very metaphysical discussion
is you know why there has to be evil and
horror in the world.
It's like,
well,
it's not clear to me that the world
could be constituted in the manner that
it's constituted in any acceptable way
if there were no adversaries.
It's like,
well,
maybe the snake in the garden is
necessarily,
you know,
maybe that imperfection and also that
that adversary is necessary.
It's the thing that spurs on development
at it.
What would there be without an
adversary?
Maybe nothing,
you know,
because you like,
I can give you an example.
It's a funny example.
There's this little animal whose name I
cannot remember unfortunately,
but it lives in the ocean and in its
larval stage it has a brain and swims
around.
It's a little tiny thing.
It swims around,
you know,
like little plank and then so on.
And then at some point during it's
development,
it's fastens itself onto a rock and it
grows into something that sort of looks
like a plant,
you know,
but it's stable.
It never moves again.
So as it develops into this stable rock
cleaning entity,
it basically digests its own brain and
then it doesn't need one after that.
And the reason it doesn't need one as
well,
there isn't really anything for it to
do.
It just sits there and filters water.
It takes like a sponge,
sort of.
It takes the nutrients out of the water
and the brain is just like,
it's extra energy using tissue.
And so it does need the brain anymore.
So you know,
so like you don't need to think if you
haven't got an adversary.
So.
So then you think,
well,
are there optimal sized adversaries?
And part of the Little Motif of that
story is if you pay careful attention to
things as they change,
maybe you can keep the damn adversaries
optimize.
And I think that actually it may not be
true,
but it's possible that it's true and
that's something,
you know,
that's something if you really pay.
Because the question might be,
and this is something that I thought
about when I was developing all of these
ideas a long time ago,
it was like,
okay,
well there's obviously some things about
existence that aren't exactly the way
you might lay them out if you had the
choice,
you know,
like the fact that people are
fundamentally vulnerable and that you're
imperfect in 50 different ways and that
life is full of suffering.
Then everybody dies and you know,
all these things that are existential
nightmares.
It's like,
okay,
fine.
It's easy to judge that is unacceptable
and maybe even worse than unacceptable
and intolerable and you know,
I'm deserving of obliteration.
You could even go that far and people do
go that far.
But there's another question that
question begs,
which is,
yeah,
maybe,
but maybe if you brought all of your
resources to bear on the problem without
holding back all of them,
then that would be okay that you could
master it and that's possible.
You know,
so you won't.
The thing is you'll never know unless
you try it.
That's the thing because it's actually a
claim that requires an existential
proof.
You can't listen to someone tell you
that and even if it's true for them,
that doesn't necessarily mean it would
be true for you.
The only way you can test a proposition
like that is existentially.
You have to act it out.
But as I mentioned earlier,
I see very,
very few truly optimistic ideas in
profound thought.
Most profound ideas are pretty damn
pessimistic,
but this is one I think that's an
exception to that,
which is it is possible that your
constituted so that you have enough
resources to deal with reality as it's
actually has.
It actually lays itself out.
And one of the ways,
and people have been thinking about this
for a very long time too,
is that the most effective one of the
most effective weapons you have in that
engagement is the capacity to pay
attention and paying attention.
And it's another thing I've learned over
the years and that's been
extraordinarily useful to me.
We kind of conflate rational thinking
with attention and sort of make
attention like the ugly step sister of
rationality in some sense because we
never really considered it as a separate
entity because we are basically
rationalist suddenly believed that we
can deal with the world and irrational
weights.
And I don't think that's really true
because I think the world has at its
core,
it's existentially irrational.
There's too much of that's observed,
observed and arbitrary,
but it is perfectly reasonable to draw a
clear distinction between paying
attention and thinking.
And you know,
western culture is elevated thinking in
some sense to the,
to the position of the highest dandy.
But I think we've got that wrong.
I think attention is much more powerful
than thinking and that attention that
thinking should be the handmaid of
attention.
Because if you pay attention,
you can pay attention to the things you
don't know and you can become incredibly
powerful if you pay attention to the
things you don't know because you keep
learning and learning and learning and
learning.
And you know,
there was a new testament injunction
junction that goes along the lines of,
you know,
it's necessary to love your enemy.
And I actually think that that's an
existential hint.
You know,
if you listen to people converse,
especially if they're ideologically
minded,
you have a socialist on one side and the
conservative on the other.
All they do is trade platitudes.
There's no discussion.
And the goal of the discussion is to
humiliate the other person and to prove
that you're a priority stance is correct
and that that person is incapable of
conceptualizing the world property.
It's like
one of the most interesting things about
running into people who think
differently than you if you pay
attention instead of thinking is they
will tell you the weirdest bloody
things.
You know,
the things you never possibly have
thought of.
And you know,
it doesn't mean that you have to fall
over and agree with them immediately,
but what the hell difference does it
make if they don't say what you,
you do,
maybe they'll maybe out of 10 statements
the law for you,
one that you wouldn't have
conceptualized.
And that's the difference between paying
attention and thinking and like people
love to be paid attention to.
You know,
it's the current currency.
It's human currency is attention and
attention is unbelievably powerful tool.
You know,
one of the things we'll find out is that
the ancient Egyptians actually
conceptualized attention as a guard and
the guard,
they conceptualized attention as was
horace.
And you all know of horse because you've
all seen representations.
Of course the famous Egyptian I the
single lie,
that's a representation of Horus.
And the Egyptians figured out like for
Mr Damien's avenue for them,
that the highest human dating,
which is like the most powerful set of
human attributes is to be associated
with one,
with language use.
The mesopotamians really nailed that.
But,
but even more importantly with the
capacity to pay attention and watch and
it's sort of suspension of judgment so
you don't have to be right or wrong in
the situation.
All you have to do is pay attention and
listen and watch,
and then potentially a solution will
emerge out of that
and
look,
half our brain is visual cortex
approximately.
You know,
so paying attention were incredible.
Visual animals,
paying attention really matters.
It's harnessing.
That's visual attention in particular,
but that's the harnessing of our most
fundamental cognitive capacities.
So
anyways,
you know,
if you pay attention to things,
you can see what interests you.
And that's also an empirical search in
some sense,
which is quite interesting.
This is part of why I got interested in
psychodynamic ideas.
It's like there are things that rule the
way that you govern yourself that you
have no control over.
You can only discover them and one of
them is what interests you sleep.
So you can't really force it if you're
not interested in something.
It's like,
well,
good luck trying to make yourself
interested.
Sometimes you can do it to some degree,
but more particularly what seems to
happen is that your interest highlights
things for you and then you follow that
around like you're following up,
you know,
a search beam or something like that.
And to me that indicates the action of
very,
very deep underlying psychobiological
systems that in some sense or directing
your consciousness,
you know,
if you pay attention to that process,
you can also learn a tremendous amount
from that.
Like what you're actually like,
you know,
what are you interested in,
where,
where is your being trying to manifest
itself.
That's another way of thinking about it.
So those are all things that we're going
to try to figure out because I would
also say that if you're capable of
allowing your true being to manifest
itself,
so that would be your potential.
That's also the best source you have of
the kind of weaponry that you need to
defend yourself against the inequalities
and tragedies and horrors of life.
Because you can,
you can reveal yourself in a sense by
pursuing what's illuminated for you.
And I can't tell you whether or not
that's true,
but it's a powerful idea and it's a very
old idea and I think there's plenty of
evidence that at least it is a.
You say it's plausible.
Yes,
it's,
it's more than that.
It's but plausible will do because I
can't think of a better word,
intimate,
but it's,
it's,
it's a hypothesis that has enough
potential that it might be worth testing
and I would like you to test that sort
of thing.
Like one of the things that I really
encourage students in this class to do,
and you can start doing this right away,
is pay attention to what you hear
yourself saying.
I just watch.
Pull yourself into to detach yourself
from your ideas and thoughts and watch
what you say and at the same time that
you watch what you say,
watch how you feel when you say what you
say and what I'd like you to try to
detect is you'll notice if you start
noticing that some of the things that
you say make you feel strong and
together and united and other things
that you say make you feel disunited and
week and then I would say quit saying
the ones that make you feel disunited
and weak because they're false and what
and what you're picking up by the loss
of strength associated with that address
is the fact that you're.
You're,
you're.
There's something rotten in the state of
Denmark with regards to that use of
language.
It's manipulative.
You're,
you're trying to appear smarter than you
are.
You're trying to prove a point.
You're trying to avoid something like
there's some game you're playing that's
other than merely stating what you see
to be true at that moment and like
that's a different way to live.
You know,
because you can,
you can calculate and you can plan and
planning is useful.
I have nothing against that,
but you can manipulate reality so that
it manifest what you want or you can
decide that what you're going to do is
pay attention and to call things as you
see them and to see what happens if you
do that.
And they're like,
that's a real risk,
right?
Because you don't know where that's
going to take you.
So that's an act of faith in the
character guardian sense.
So like if you have faith in the truth,
what that means is that you will say the
truth,
and that's a hard thing to do.
Know.
It doesn't mean that you can say
whatever you want you want regardless of
the effect on other people or that you
can use the truth as a baseball bat,
which you can certainly do.
It's sophisticated.
It's,
it requires a tremendous amount of
sophisticated,
um,
it requires a tremendous amount of
sophistication.
But you know,
one thing you might think about is,
well,
if you're,
if you are attempting to make yourself a
mouthpiece of the truth,
you have reality on your side
and then you might say,
well,
could you possibly have anything more
powerful on your side in reality and so
it might not be a reality you want,
or the thing that you would wish for
what you might think,
well you know,
if you,
if you called things as you saw them and
you were very careful about that,
maybe that would lead you through life
properly.
It's a very different way of thinking
and it is tied with this idea that
there's something fundamental about the
truth.
So I would say to start this,
if you want,
just pay attention to what you say.
You know when,
when like you're detached from it.
So don't identify too much with what
you're saying because that's another
thing that people do.
They identify with what they think.
It's like,
what makes you think that you're
thinking?
It's like one of the things you said,
which I really love that he blew me.
It just,
it just slapped me when I first read it.
He said,
people do not have ideas,
ideas have people,
and so,
you know,
I listened to ideologues talk all the
time.
It's like damn talking in some dead,
dead spirit of the past,
you know,
voicing an opinion through them and you
can tell when you're talking to someone
like that because you can predict
everything you're going to say.
So in what sense is that them talking?
It isn't them talking at all,
at some collective.
It's a collective voice that,
that,
that has appropriated them and convinced
them that it's actually part of them.
It's like,
no,
that's the devil.
That's what that is.
So,
so we'll just watch it.
You can try this experimental on your
own,
tried for a month,
detach yourself from what you say and
think and notice when you say something,
if it makes you feel more grounded and
powerful or weaker and stop saying
things that make you weak.
So you know,
that's,
that's sort of like Ed's essential test
number one.
So.
Well it must be just about four x four
or three.
So then I'll see you all next Wednesday,
take a look at the website and I would
say start those exercises or at least
check them out.
Okay.