And I want to tell you the story today
that set the foundation of Western
civilization or one of the stories that
the foundation of Western civilization,
because I think the Egyptian story
qualifies and I think the Mesopotamian
story qualifies.
And so this is the Judeo Christian,
um,
genesis story,
which I think is,
it's a staggering story.
Um,
if you look at the structure of the Old
Testament,
what,
what happens first near the first is
that there's,
there's two things that constitute what
I think are a radical split between
different forms of time.
And so one of them is Noah's flood where
all the chaos comes washing back in the
world is remade.
So there's the,
like the time before the flood now in
more traditional Christian societies,
so say 150 years ago,
that was definitely considered a special
kind of time before the flood compared
to after the flood.
And I think that the old testament is
set up that way.
There's also the tower of Babel.
So this story of the Tower of Babel
where people build a tower that's going
to reach to heaven and God basically
stops them by making it unable to
communicate with each other and then
they dispersed around the world.
That's also a kind of chaos story.
So there's the tower of Babel and the
story of Noah.
And then after that then there's the
story of Abraham.
And what happens is that the stories in
the old testament start to become
historical.
You know,
they're like,
they're like tribal history in a sense.
Like they're mythologized tribal
history.
So they're more than just tribal
But,
but before that,
I think what they are is they're almost,
they're almost pure archetype and we
have no idea how old the stories are.
So we know that the story of creation in
genesis at the,
at the beginning of Genesis,
there's actually two creation stories
there and there are timelines don't
exactly match up.
And the hypothesis basically is,
is that one tribal group or,
or group of tribes had one creation
story and another tribal group or group
of tribes had another tribal creation
story.
And they came together and they didn't
really know how to sort out their damn
creation stories because they both held
them as sacred.
And so what seemed to have happened over
time was that those stories were told
and then when they were written down an
editor,
they called the redactor,
tried to sequence them so they made some
sort of sense and a lot of,
a lot of the Bible is actually the
attempt to take diverse,
Archaic Orchid Temple and Cause I
historical stories and to organize them
in a narrative manner while
simultaneously minimizing internal
contradictions and so very,
very difficult thing to do.
And it's not like only one person did
it.
Thousands of people have participated in
doing it over a huge stretches of time.
So the historical element of the Bible
is probably roughly in the same of the
same age as the Mesopotamian stories.
So,
you know,
you can stretch written history back
about 5,000
years,
something like that.
Maybe a little bit farther than that.
So that's all we're talking about with
regards to written history.
And you know,
people think of 5,000
years ago as a long time,
but it's not a long time,
you know,
that's only 5,100
year old men.
So it's a very interesting way to think
about it.
You know,
that's,
that's not a very long,
long period of time.
The stories before the flood,
I think they're,
they're indeterminately ancient.
I think they have their roots in like
very,
very early shamonic practices and their
associated with ways of thinking that
have characterized people ever since
they became people ever since they
became whatever we are.
There have been human beings like us
anatomically speaking for about 150,000
years and we're also a little bit
neanderthal,
about five percent,
two to five percent,
something like that.
So,
but are anatomically similar ancestors
have been around for about 150,000
years.
Looks like we discovered fire about 2
million years ago.
So we've been cooking for 2 million
years.
So anyways,
it kind of gives you a bit of a
timeframe.
Now,
the first part of the.
There's basically in the genesis story,
there's a story about the creation of
being and then there's two stories
actually,
and then there's the story about the
creation of human beings,
and so the first part of the story I'm
doing,
I'm going to read this to you because I
can't.
It's too complicated for me to just spin
out spontaneously.
There are two structural elements
described in the first chapter in
genesis chaos.
That's one and heavens and the earth.
Okay,
so there's two structural elements,
one,
process creation and one actor God or
the word of God who is engaged in the
process.
The first structural element,
chaos is signified by a word.
This is a Hebrew word,
tail that means chaos by Tau,
who for waste or for matter,
without substance and by the Bohu for
emptiness or confusion.
So the chaos out of which God extracts
order has those elements.
It's chaos,
waste matter without substance and
emptiness and confusion.
So interesting.
There's a psychological element there
too,
right?
So I would say in some sense it's
equivalent to the chaos that you fall
into when everything falls apart around
you.
And that's associated with a shamonic
idea that during the shamonic
transformation,
the Sharman goes back to the beginning
of time,
roughly speaking into the chaos that
proceeds the emergence of order,
and that's part of the shamanic
transformation ritual.
So the chaos that the chaos that's
conceptualized as the ground of being is
partly the potential out of which matter
arises,
but it's also partly the state of
confusion,
that urine when everything,
when order falls apart around you and
that that makes sense if you think about
it,
because the order that's being described
in genesis is the order that makes up
being and so it makes sense when the
order that makes up your being
collapses,
that you're going to fall into something
that's equivalent to the original chaos.
It's a very interesting way of thinking
about it.
I don't think it's metaphorical by the
way.
It's not metaphorical.
It's a different way of describing
reality,
so it's not like a metaphor for matter.
It's different than that.
It's.
It's a analysis of the structural
components of being and basically what
you have is chaos order and the thing
that mediates between them and we've
talked about that already as being the
fundamental tripartite constituents of
of reality itself.
There has to be potential,
there has to be something to interpret
the potential,
and then there has to be something to
mediate between the two things.
So these three words take home tow who
and Vrbo who are very interesting for a
variety of reasons and profitably bear
further investigation.
The Canadian Rabbi Itzhak Marmer Stein,
who has begun to explain the Torah one
word at a time describes tale.
By the way,
take them entire.
Matt are the same word.
Okay,
so that's worth knowing.
And that's.
I got that from Northrop Frye.
So the tail is a is like the first
syllable of the word tire,
Matt.
And so we know that the Mesopotamian,
some people think the Mesopotamian
creation story preceded the creation
story that's in the Judeo Christian
account,
but no one really knows.
There was like a slew of creation
stories with roughly similar
substructures in the Middle East at that
time.
And the Mesopotamian stories of
manifestation of it and so to the Judaeo
Christian story and they,
their temporal order I don't think is
actually even calculable because I think
they both disappear into prehistory
fundamentally.
So.
But it's very interesting to know that
the tail is associated with the idea of
time,
Matt,
because it also gives you some idea of
the because you don't know what the hell
ancient Hebrew words mean,
right?
Well how do you know that you're,
you're not there anymore.
And so it's interesting to see the
association network so you can
understand the concepts.
And so whatever the tail ms,
which is this preexistent chaos is sort
of like tie matt,
who's the terrible thing that raises up
or head when chaos is,
is coming back.
It's also the thing that,
that Marta has to confront with his eyes
open and that figure is very much like
the word of God in the Judeo Christian
story because the word of God is the
thing that's like,
it's exploratory and communicative and
it's the thing that that raises order
out of chaos.
So I don't think that you can understand
that without understanding or I think
that understanding the Mesopotamian
story and the role of Marduk in
relationship to time outs sheds a
substantial amount of light on the
relationship between the word of God and
the initial chaos.
They're parallel ideas.
So one of the things that I should tell
you about Christianity,
which is which is incomprehensible to
me,
I don't understand it,
is that so one of the representations of
the word of God that extracts order out
of chaos is logos.
And that's partly the root word of
logic,
but it's a lot more than that.
Logo's basically means something like,
it means something like heroic
confrontation with the unknown and the
communication of the results thereof.
It's,
it means roughly that.
And one of the things that the
Christians did was assimilate Christ to
the logos that existed at the beginning
of time.
It's a very,
very strange idea and it's a kind of
mystical or artistic insight that's
difficult to,
to.
It's difficult to understand how that
idea could even happen.
And so,
so in some sense,
what the Christians did with the idea of
logos by associating that with Christ
was to make Christ who's at redeemer
figure into the same thing that
generated order out of chaos at the
beginning of time.
And so that part kind of puts them in
the same conceptual class as horace and
in the same conceptual class as Marduk.
And I'll tell you later that it also
puts them in the same conceptual class
as Buddha.
But I'll get to that story later.
So.
So also what that means is that there's
an idea that that lurks latently in
Christianity that the ideal person is
I'm.
And that's partly the person who accepts
the necessity of death and rebirth as
part of the redemptive process is
identical to the thing that at the
beginning of time called order out of
chaos.
It's a phenomenal conception.
And one of the things that I've tried to
argue in a paper that no one's ever read
is that the reason that Western culture
is predicated on the idea that human
beings have an unalterable divinity,
which is basically the source of their
natural rights,
is because it's predicated on the idea
that the individual consciousness
partakes of the process that's capable
of pulling order out of chaos or capable
of mediating between the two.
And if there's something that's
literally divine about that.
And one of the things that I also
promote in this paper is that you all
believe that because you act on it,
like you accept the idea that that there
are natural rights and that people have
individual rights and that they have
intrinsic value.
You don't know why and you don't know
what that idea is predicated on from a
metaphysical perspective,
but you do accept it and you do act it
out.
And so to me,
what that means is you believe it
whether you know it or not.
Now you can argue about that because you
can argue about what it means to believe
something.
But I tend to think that belief exists
in relationship to action rather than
into in relationship to objective
conceptualization.
And so the idea,
and then there's a very interesting
little twist in the genesis story
because what happens when God makes man
and woman,
and this is a very bizarre thing,
is that he basically says that men and
women are made in the image of God.
Now God in that particular story is
plural,
but that's not really relevant to our,
to our concerns.
And I think that's remarkable in a
variety of ways because number one,
while we don't exactly know what the
image of God means,
but we can place that in relationship to
the idea that it was the word of God,
that that extracted order out of chaos.
And so what that seems to intimate is
that it's the capacity of the human
being to extract order from chaos that's
equivalent to divinity,
perhaps in a reduced form.
And I think that that's A.
I think we believe that.
I think that we believe that.
And I think it's right even worse than
that.
And then the other thing that's so damn
bizarre about that is it's not just men,
it's women too.
And that's,
that's something that I have very
difficult time accounting for because I
don't understand why society that was as
deeply patriarchal as say the ancient
Jewish society,
why in the world that,
that would also be attributed to women.
But it is anyway.
So it doesn't matter.
So the,
you know,
the,
the identity with God is equally
distributed between men and women.
So that's quite cool.
So anyways,
back to rabbi,
it's Jack.
More marmer Stein,
he describes tail as the unfathomable,
undifferentiated womb,
out of which existence as we experience
it emerges.
All potential exists in this primordial
energy or state.
So its potential.
So in some sense that's what the chaos
has potential.
And so I've been thinking about that for
a long time too because it seems to me
that what people actually interact with
his potential,
you know,
we think we interact with matter,
but I don't think we do.
I think we interact with all the various
possibilities that matter might
manifest.
And that's not the same thing.
So that when you're interfacing with
your existence,
what you're doing is taking a very large
number of potential futures which are
basically laid out in front of you and
actualizing one or the other as a matter
your choice,
and so I think the thing you're
interacting with isn't matter.
It's the multiple potential states that
matter could manifest itself yet and I
think that's what we call potential and
consciousness seems to collapse that
into an act into into actuality.
So
all potential exists in this primordial
energy or state.
Metaphorically.
It is a confused.
See the mask,
the abyss,
the deep and the surging bellowing of
the waves toe who similarity is a
chaotic condition.
So That's interesting because there's a
psychological element there or a place
without color or form or more
specifically something that seems to for
a moment to have form,
but when looked at again loses that form
total.
Who is this subjective effect of chaos?
The forest that confounds people and
that causes them to have misleading
visions.
So it's very psychological in nature
that that particular concept.
And then Vrbo,
who finally is related to Tau,
who I'm sure I'm pronouncing those
wrong,
but means more specifically the
indistinct entangled,
confused mass that all forms once were
prior to their division into separate
kinds of objects,
so
the heavens and the earth,
so those are the next elements out,
apart from the chaos comprise the vast
and spiritually stunning places that
rise above us as well as the material
domain that makes up our physical being
and the physical being of those things
we experience this material domain is
both a trap in which our consciousnesses
are caught and the a prior precondition
for individual existence and it's
destructive and vulnerable,
but potentially redemptive aspects.
The creation narrative in genesis has
deeply embedded within it the idea that
the materiality of the world clothes,
partial beings,
incomplete avatars of God whose purpose
is the continuation and potential
perfection of the incompletely manifest
being characterizing the original
creation.
This process.
So that's,
that's the process.
Now we've got the order and we've got
the chaos,
and now we've got the process.
The process creation is characterized by
the second word in genesis,
which is Barbara.
According to the cabalist aiden Stein
celts,
the creation represented by Barbra is
not the coming into existence of
something new,
but the transmutation of a divine and
illimitable reality in some into
something defined and delimited
particularized and actualized.
This analysis of Barbara seems very
illuminating first because it attributes
genuinely creative power to
consciousness and cognition,
creative,
the limiting and second because it seems
so closely related to the Christian idea
of the logos,
logos,
one of the most remarkable of all,
the ancient philosophical or theological
conceptions is a word with an
extraordinarily broad range of meaning.
It means our everything.
Our modern word consciousness means
more.
It means mind and the creative actions
of mind.
Exploration,
discovery,
reconceptualization reason and speech.
Logos is further something whose
relationship to the mirror material is
so fundamental that the material does
not really exist at all in its absence.
Finally,
it is something whose workings are
essentially redemptive,
continuing and perfecting the process of
creation.
It is generally transcribed in the
Christian tradition as the word and is
closely identified with the
transcendental being of Christ as well
as with the original creative force of
God.
This is a very peculiar identification
from the perspective of strip tap,
strict temporal logic because it is the
word of God that creates order out of
chaos and that word is a phenomenon that
predates the birth of Christ from the
temporal perspective.
So that's all exceptionally.
It's very.
It's exceptionally incomprehensible,
I would say.
Fundamentally,
it's an unbelievable matrix of
sophisticated ideas and one of the
reasons I started to explore this was
because you know I was very obsessed,
as you all know,
with the dynamic struggle between
essentially between Soviet communism and
the western Worldview,
and if you're a rationalist and a
relativist,
then basically what you have to proclaim
is that both societies predicated
themselves on arbitrary axiom,
so arbitrary descriptions of right and
wrong,
and that basically what was happening
was that there was a war to see which of
those arbitrary systems would dominate.
But I thought,
well,
if it's just a matter of arbitrary ness,
then we're really in trouble.
Because the only way you could pause.
First of all,
neither of those systems are right or
better in any real sense of the word.
And second,
the only way that could be possibly
settled is by brute force.
So then I thought,
well,
what if I look into the origins of the
ideas that are characteristic of the
West?
We know where the bloody communist ideas
came from because they were written down
by marks.
That's pretty obvious,
but the ideas of things like natural
rights in the West,
they're very peculiar ideas.
They're obviously metaphysical ideas and
then you might ask yourself,
well,
are those mirror arbitrary statements or
if there's something deeper underneath
them.
And so that's partly what led me back to
the analysis of these texts,
for example,
because the idea has emerged out of the
text.
It's not like somebody just sat around
and thought the damn things up.
They're very,
very old ideas and it doesn't look to me
like the matrix that they emerged out.
It was actually a matrix ideas.
It was more like a matrix of behavior
and it's over thousands and thousands of
years.
And so that's when I started to
understand that the conception of the
individual in the West is something like
that which mediates between order and
chaos.
And that,
that's not merely a,
that's an ontological statement rather
than a theoretical statement.
It's a statement about the nature of
reality,
not about models,
so to speak.
Um,
you know,
I would add to that the fact that we
don't understand a damn thing about
consciousness except that it clearly
exists and that it also seems to me to
be phenomenally logically accurate.
I mean,
when you guys are,
you're all in this situation right now
and probably possessed by anxiety
because of it,
as soon as you graduate,
what emerges in front of you is a huge
field of an map potential.
And it seems to me that there's no other
way of saying that it's more accurate.
So we could just assume that that is
what confronts you and what you're doing
as you navigate your way through it in
one form or another is actualizing that
potential into some,
into some reality that you inhabit that
is hopefully operating in accordance
with what you both need and want.
But you certainly view yourself as at
least to some degree as a being that is
capable of doing that.
It seems to me,
I mean,
you assume that you can choose what
you're going to do after you go to
university,
like you don't have infinite choice and
it seems perfectly reasonable to presume
that that's anxiety provoking.
Why wouldn't it be?
We also know from the empirical research
that and unstructured future is hard on
people.
They produce stress hormones like mad if
they don't know what they're doing or
why,
if there's a lot of unexpected potential
lying around.
All right.
The fundamental story of the first part
of Genesis is predicated on the
assumption that chaos can be
conceptualized as a matrix,
as something with a metaphorically
female aspect.
A matrix by the way,
that's a matrix is something out of
which matter arises.
It's the same word Matrix matter,
mother.
Those are all the same words and one of
the things that's very interesting about
the word matter is that we use it in two
ways,
right?
And I think it's a reflection of the
Tohu wa Bohu divide.
One thing is things are made out of
matter and then the other thing is that
things matter and part of the Old
Testament conceptualization of matter is
that it's partly matter and partly what
matters and part of the Old Testament
conceptually conceptualization of matter
is that the world is made out of what
matters.
So
and I again,
I don't think that's a metaphor.
I think your.
I think your nervous system is actually
set up in that manner because the way
your brain reacts to the world is if it
matters and since your brain evolved and
since we don't know any other way of
producing an entity that can adapt to
reality without evolution,
then the fact that your brain evolved to
treat the world as if it matters would
indicate that the reason for that is
because it matters and I don't see any
way out of that argument so that because
the normal argument is the physical
substrate is primary and anything that
matters is EPA phenomenal,
right?
That's part of the subjective or
quality,
but I don't see any evidence whatsoever
that that's how your brain is organized.
I think all the evidence suggests the
opposite and that what you're first
attracted to what matters and then you
parse it out into the world so till good
you try on tangling that,
but I haven't been able to untangle it
so.
Right,
right.
Well,
yeah,
but that is hard to Chris' point is that
that meaning manifests itself that
that's why he's a phenomenologist
because the root word of phenomenology
is famous thought,
which means to shine forth and it's the
eight priority state.
Right.
And you know,
I think that you can assimilate those
theories to ideas like the root,
the ground of existence is something
like information rather than something
like matter.
It's actually not like matter because
what's ever at the ground of the world,
we have no idea about.
It doesn't even act like matter.
It's very strange stuff,
but I think it acts at least as much
information as it does matter,
extreme limitation,
the care that you care about,
the things that go on that rebate
rebate.
You mentioned that the only reason tutor
and if your mind is that your mind is
limited and so it has a certain number
of calories and things like that,
and as a result things matter more than
others and so it looks like so.
Right?
Right.
Well that,
that,
that yes,
that's a reflection of the idea.
That limited limitation has utility,
you know,
and so that or that even that limitation
is a precondition for meaning or,
or more.
I think limitation is a precondition for
being.
So one of the things that lead me to
conclude is that there's a,
there's a,
there's a logic in that if there can't
be being without limitation and
limitation producers tragedy,
then how is it possible to have being
that's acceptable?
And I think the answer to that is,
well that's what the redemptive question
is.
The,
the route of morality.
That the essence of morality is to
determine how to live so that you can
have being with,
with tragedy held in a band sufficiently
so that the being is worth having.
And it's a very tricky thing to do
because of the tragedy is built into the
box and I think that what redemptive
system's attempt to manifest portray
there are a form of discovery is how
that human being could what its
structure is and part of it seems to
have to do with truth.
You have to confront the thing that's
tragic because otherwise you can't deal
with it.
That's a big,
that's a huge part of it.
And then you have to communicate the
consequences of that to others.
That's not all of it,
but that's a big part of it.
That's the logo part of it.
You know,
you have to embody the logos
fundamentally.
So.
Okay.
So now I want to move from the initial
part,
which is the,
the creation of something out of
nothing.
The origins of,
of order itself.
I want to concentrate on the story of
Adam and Eve.
And the reason I want to do that is
because I think it's an unbelievably
illuminating story in the same way that
the Mesopotamian story is illuminating.
And I think it's staggering.
The degree to which the information in
it has been compressed.
Now I think what happens,
it's something like this.
People are always telling stories about
one thing or another and they tell
stories down the generations and I think
what happens is that our stories are
handed down across the generations.
All that remains of the stories is those
elements that cannot be forgotten.
And so what that means is that there's
something centrally meaningful about
those elements because that's what you
remember.
You remember what's meaningful.
You get rid of what isn't right.
So if I tell you the story of what I did
today and you go off to someone else and
you retell the story,
you're going to compress it down to just
a few lines and those are the few lines
that in some sense seemed to sum up the
entire story.
And that's the part you didn't forget.
So then you might ask if,
if a thousand people tell a story for a
thousand years,
what's left of the story and the
straightforward answer to that seems to
be,
well,
it's the part of the story that nobody
can forget and that would be the part of
the story that's most richly meaningful.
Now,
why precisely?
It would be richly meaningful.
I think that's a whole different
question and I don't really know how to
answer that.
I think to some degree it echoes in
people you know,
it's like we don't understand that
exactly.
You know,
you go to a movie and the movie will
reach a climax and all of a sudden
little it'll produce an emotional
release in you.
You know,
maybe you'll start to cry.
It doesn't mean you know exactly why
it's something in you is responding to
it.
So it's,
it's,
it's echoing in you in some sense.
So you might even say that the structure
of the story comes to match the
structure of your caring.
It's something like that.
So it's a mirror of your psyche in some
way.
The proverbial Chinese telephone game
where you start with 10 people by the
end,
it's unrecognizable.
I don't know that any meeting carry
through though.
How do we know is is?
Well,
partly we,
we,
we.
There are actual ways we do know that
because there are.
First of all,
what tends to happen in the historical
story is that it isn't change.
That's the rule.
It's its permanence.
So for example,
grizzly bears now in grizzly bears
150,000
years ago,
they are the same and roughly speaking,
the farther you go back in time,
the more people are the same from one
generation to another.
They don't change at all.
So for example,
among the Australian aborigines before
the Europeans came,
there's not a lot of evidence of
cultural transformation over 25,000
year period.
And so I don't think we really
understand the degree to which a static
culture is actually static.
The same thing just happens over and
over and the same stories are told and I
don't think they're told in exactly the
same way as the,
as the story or the game that you're
describing.
Because first of all,
the knowledge is distributed to some
degree in everyone,
so even if you told a part of the story
and you told it wrong,
then someone else is going to correct
you.
So the story's actually distributed
throughout the entire society,
so.
So I don't think it's nearly as fragile
as people assume now,
I don't.
Obviously there are times in history
where those things start to transform
quite rapidly,
but I think that's what happens when the
population starts to grow and diverse,
separated community start to come back
together and then the story starts to
transform.
But other than that,
I think the.
The a prior condition is stability,
not transformation.
Now we do know,
for example,
there's a group of people on in northern
Japan called the Ainu and God only knows
where they came from.
There's all sorts of theories about
that,
but one of the things that's interesting
about the a new is that they have a
ceremony that involves the worship of
bears that seems to have exactly the
same structure as the structures of
their worship that have been found in
Neolithic caves in,
in western Europe.
So the way the bear skull is set up on
the altar and so forth is the same as
the caves that were discovered in
western Europe even though there's a gap
of approximately 25,000
years.
So.
So I don't think that broken telephone
analogy is quite right because that's
the only sentence level first usually.
And the only person who knows the
message to begin with is one person and
there's no context for the message.
So it's an interesting analogy and I
also think some of it's useful because I
do think stories transformed themselves
across time to some degree,
even with the retelling because the
language is going to shift and move and
so forth.
But I don't think we should assume that
the default position is noise.
I think we should assume that it's
signal.
So.
Okay.
Adam and Eve,
the first thing that happens is that
they were both naked,
the man and his wife and were not
ashamed.
So the first thing you might ask is,
well,
what is meant by naked and what is meant
by a shaped.
And so then you think,
well,
there's a number of things about people
that are quite peculiar and one is that
were clothed and although there are some
people who go about naked,
it's not the standard human position in
the world.
In fact,
you can actually trace the the origin of
cloth using the evolutionary structure
of lice because there are some who have
evolved to hold on to cloth,
not hair,
and they've tracked the DNA development,
the genetic development of those lights
back more than 25,000
years.
So people will use cloth and they use it
while they use it,
obviously for production,
but they also use it for all sorts of
symbolic routines.
But the point is is that there it does
seem to be a particular human
relationship with the idea of nakedness.
Now you might ask yourself why and what
does it mean that that the original
people might have be naked and not
ashamed?
And why would that be a surprise to the
readers?
Because obviously one of the things that
sentence presumes is that the reader is
going to assume that the fact that the
men and women who were naked,
we're not ashamed is actually a
deviation from the norm.
So here's what I have made of it,
and you can tell me what you think.
First of all,
they weren't self conscious.
Now you might ask,
well,
what would that have to do with
nakedness?
And I would say,
well,
a huge chunk of white people don't run
around naked is because they're self
conscious and there's a bunch of reasons
for that is that,
well,
human beings are standing up,
first of all,
like unlike other animals,
and so the most vulnerable parts of us
are exposed not only to the world but
directly to the view of other people.
And so most animals running around and
all four,
and that means they basically have
armored backs,
right?
They're most vulnerable.
Parts are not full center in front for
for everyone to see.
So human beings also make face to face,
although they don't have to.
And that also heightened self
consciousness and then in relationship
to shame.
Shame is actually a emotion that seems
to be manifested under conditions of
judgment,
and so you might say,
well,
people are often afraid of public
speaking.
Why you guys are afraid of public
How many of you are afraid of public
speaking?
Okay,
how many of you are completely
comfortable with public speaking?
Oh,
that's good.
That's quite,
that's quite amazing.
So,
okay,
so why might people be afraid of public
speaking?
You Bet.
That's a lot of eyes looking at you.
Right?
And often people who are afraid of
public speaking won't meet the eyes they
look down.
And what that basically means is they're
reacting to the crowd as if it's a
predator.
The best way to overcome that is to
start looking at people and you don't
look at the crowd because there isn't a
crowd.
You look at individuals within the crop
and then that's no problem because you
know how to do that.
So great way to decrease your fear of
public speaking.
Okay.
So,
um,
how about speaking in front of a crowd?
Naked?
That's a common nightmare by the way.
So what do you think about that?
Sounds like fun.
No,
why?
Why more scrutiny,
right?
And so what's the problem with the
scrutiny
it makes you so
why
secure?
Why
that's right.
You have a lot of flaws and you're
bloody well aware of them,
you know,
and it's bad enough to have your
intellectual flaw is revealed,
but to add to that your physical flaws,
you know when you can think about that
as your deviation from an implicit
ideal,
it's something like that,
right?
People don't like that.
That's why you never,
except for the naked news,
you never see that happening or you
virtually never see that happening
except under very specific conditions.
So part of the issue with being naked
and ashamed is that the nakedness has to
do with flaws.
So you might say,
well,
what does it mean to see yourself as
naked?
Well,
I think what it means is to see yourself
with all your vulnerabilities and that's
like your local vulnerabilities,
which just happens to be how hideous you
are as a physical entity,
but then there's even worse,
which is if you're really self conscious
and aware of what it means to be
vulnerable because let's say that's
what's at the core of nakedness is you
also realize you're flawed mortal nature
across time,
so that's partly the burden of the fact
that you're physically imperfect in
degenerating all at the same time and
that's something that human beings
understanding that no other animal
understands.
It's a big deal.
So I think partly the reason that we put
on clothes is so we don't freeze to
death when it's cold,
but part of it also is this to separate
ourselves from continual scrutiny.
A lot of that's going to be sexual
scrutiny to and evaluation.
We shield ourselves from that so that we
can do some other things now and then.
So the original people didn't have that
problem,
so I think they weren't self conscious.
That's the first thing to notice.
So okay.
The next thing that happens is that the
outcome is complaining about the fact
that he doesn't have any company,
right?
So God does this,
the Lord God caused a deep sleep to fall
upon Adam and he slept and he took one
of his ribs and closed up the flesh
instead thereof,
and the rib,
which the Lord God had taken from man,
made he a woman and brought her unto the
man,
and Adam said,
this is now bone of my bones and flesh
of my flesh.
She shall be called woman because she
was taken out of man.
So I want to read you something about
this because one of the interpretations
of that,
especially feminist interpretations of
the story,
is that that makes women subordinate to
men.
And it also inverts the natural order
because obviously men come from women
rather than women coming from men.
And so the idea there is that that's
something like a patriarchal presumption
that overthrew the original matriarchal
order,
which there was none of,
by the way,
that's a faulty.
You are anthropological theory.
There was never a pre patriarchal
matriarchy.
It's a,
it's a,
uh,
it's a misplaced myth that says
historicized because you know,
in the scheme that I showed you,
the feminine is underneath the
masculine,
so to speak,
right?
So in some sense the feminine nature is
out of that,
out of which culture springs,
but that's a psychological truth,
not an anthropological truth.
So the idea that backwards,
the idea of the world,
because if you're making one,
it is,
it is.
Yes,
and I'm going to read you why that is,
but yes,
it is exactly that,
but there's a reason for it and it has
to do,
it has to do with the idea that the
central element of human being is logos
regardless of whether it's man or woman.
Now logo says are also symbolically
masculine because it's associated with
the heroic part of the individual.
So let me read this because again,
it's too complicated for me to conjure
up on the fly.
So it is of course contrary to the
entire scheme of nature,
that woman be derived for Matt and it's
very tempting to read a simple
patriarchal into that derivation.
I think it is more appropriate to give
these ancient and incomprehensible
stories the benefit of the doubt and to
search for something more profound.
Logos is symbolically masculine and that
would be partly because of the idea of
Martech against Matt,
for example.
There are diverse reasons for this that
have little to do with simple
ideological prejudice or with gender per
se.
The profound implicit idea put forth in
this creation sequence woman for man,
is that the individual woman rather than
the mere female is a product of logos
and not simply a daughter of matter,
matter,
mother or nature.
Thus the story does not denigrate the
female as is now commonly postulated,
but elevates human being itself,
man and woman above it,
simply material and symbolically
feminine substrate.
Now there's A.
There's a.
There was some.
There was a whole series of ancient
writings that were uncovered in in the
late 19 fifties that are now called the
gnostic gospels and hypothetically
they're new testament gospels have a
whole variety of sorts that were,
that were defined as non-canonical by
what became the Christian church,
and so they were.
They all emerged in the late 19 fifties.
It's a fascinating story because the
people who discovered them,
if I remember correctly,
it's been a long time since I read this.
Their father had been killed by someone
and so they went out to find the guy who
killed him and killed him,
and then they went to a cave to burry
them and when they dug into cave,
they found all these amphora that had
been buried for thousands of years and
then they took them home and their
mother used a bunch of the papers that
were inside them to light fires with so
the family could cook,
but an interior is dealer came along and
recognize them for what they were and
squirreled them away.
Now,
weirdly enough,
and I don't remember how this happened
either,
is that one of them,
one of these manuscripts called the
gospel of Thomas made its way to Carl
young and he was the only person in the
entire world who had access to any of
the gnostic gospels until probably 25
years ago when they were finally more or
less released to scholars.
So that's also extremely bizarre.
So anyways,
there's a quote from the gauze.
Yeah,
it's very,
very bizarre.
It's a very amazing story.
So anyways,
there's all these gospels and now
they've been translated in various ways
and you can buy them as the gnostic
gospels and the Gnostics were a group of
early Christians who believed that
redemption could be attained through
knowledge as much as redemption can be
attained through faith.
And that was basically crushed by the
developing Christian church.
So anyways,
young is often regarded as a kind of
gnostic,
but it's still.
It's really quite remarkable.
And he ended up with the gospel of
Thomas.
I think that's just like an
incomprehensible fundamentally.
So a similar idea.
This individual woman rather than the
mere female is a product of logos.
And so there's an idea and the gospel of
Thomas and similar ideas put forth in
the gospel of Thomas in more thoroughly
elaborated form.
Simon Peter said to them,
make Mary.
So he's talking about the disciples and
Mary Magdalene is in amongst the
disciples.
And so Simon Peter stands to all the
disciples,
make Mary leave us for females,
do not deserve everlasting life.
Jesus said,
look,
I will guide her to make her mail so
that she too may become a living spirit
resembling you males,
for every female who makes herself male
will enter the Kingdom of heaven.
So the question is,
what exactly does that mean?
Well,
I would say,
you know,
you can think about it.
What do you think's happened since women
discovered the birth control pill?
You know,
it seems to me fundamentally that what's
happened is that many women have taken
on the attributes of masculinity.
That's what they want because that's
associated with freedom and exploration
and,
and the kind of creativity that's
associated with the mind rather than,
I'm not going to say mirror biological
creativity because it's not mere,
it's important,
but it's not.
It's not of the essence of
consciousness,
let's say,
or it's not of the essence of spirit.
And so I don't think that the birth
control pill could have even come about
as a possibility if there wasn't the
lingering idea in western culture that
attributing to women the same spiritual
phenomenology.
That or abilities that characterize men
wasn't the possibility.
Right?
Because you might say women were
emancipated because of the pill,
but then you might say,
well,
what were the preconditions that would
allow a society to do something as
radical as to invent the pill?
Now,
obviously one of the preconditions was
that there was enough of an agreement,
implicit agreement among the scientific
community that the idea of allowing
women voluntary control over their own
reproductive status wasn't the kind of
heresy that should have been punished by
like instant death.
And even even even though that idea was
there,
there was still a huge battle and still
is between Catholicism roughly speaking
in the Western world and the idea of
birth control because it's still part of
Catholic dogma that if you're a good
Catholic,
you don't do that.
And I don't know if you know this or
not,
but you know that I'm generally women.
Women have a menstrual period about once
every 28 days.
Well,
you know,
that's built in.
That was built into almost all
formulations of the birth control pill
even though it wasn't necessary.
So the guy who invented the pale decided
that it would be three weeks on,
one week off so that the menstrual cycle
would stay in tact so that it wouldn't
look as much like a deviation from the
natural order to all those people who
are opposed to birth control.
When the simple matter is is you can
take birth control all the time and
never have a menstrual period and that
isn't a problem or it's,
you know,
maybe it has to happen now and then,
but it certainly doesn't happen.
Have to happen on a weekly basis or a
monthly basis.
So you believed in the 19 fifties he.
There's this phenomena that occurred in
Catholicism,
again,
which I don't understand very well,
but part of the idea was that there was
a shift in Catholic Dogma in the mid
fifties and because there was a
tremendous movement in the Catholic
world to,
to,
to appreciate Mary as a Daddy,
roughly speaking along with Christ and
God and the Holy Ghost.
So it was as if Mary was being added as
the fourth part of the trinity.
And it wasn't a movement.
It wasn't an idea that the aristocracy
of the church imposed on the masses.
It was exactly the other way around.
The idea that Mary was to be uplifted
into heaven,
roughly speaking,
so she would be beside God and Christ
was an idea that was really popular in
the Mediterranean countries and also in
central and South America where we're
married.
Worship is a huge element of
Christianity and what happened was
because of that popular pressure,
the Catholic aristocracy announced
berries,
and this is where I haven't got the
terminology exactly right,
her ascension into heaven in the mid 19
fifties and you believe that that idea
was movement in the collective
unconscious and the movement was that
the.
The imagination of the western world had
progressed to the point where it was
self evident that there was.
That their feminine element of being was
underrepresented in the idea of daddy
and that it needed to be elaborated up
with all of the other mostly masculine
symbols.
And then he would have read that as a
precursor to the possibility that the
pill could have even become a.
An idea like the underlying imagination
had to be arranged to allow that to be a
possibility before any of that research
could have even been conducted much less
the product be sold,
you know,
because you have to,
you got to think how bloody much
preparation does it take for a culture
to allow a birth control device to be
sold for general use.
It's not like that happens just because
it's invented.
I mean,
forget that,
you know,
it's still.
People have by no means yet come to
terms with that.
So
I'll,
I'll tell you the last,
the next part of this story and then
we'll start until next week.
So,
and the Lord God took the man and put
him into the garden of Eden to dress it
and keep it.
Okay?
So that's an interesting idea I think
because.
So what?
It's now.
Now what the story is proposing is that
there's a universal habitation for
mankind and the universal habitation is
the idea of the garden.
Now Eden means well watered place and
Paradise means it's from paradigm means
a walled enclosure so that the original
garden is a walled enclosure.
That's well watered.
Then you think,
well what exactly is a garden?
And it seems to me that a garden is a
productive union of nature and culture,
so it's another order and chaos union,
right?
So a perfect garden is beautiful because
it's natural,
but it's also beautiful because it's
attended to and paid attention to.
And a garden is also something that's
productive,
right?
It's just chaotic wilderness.
It's a place where you can live.
So the idea is that human beings have to
live inside walled gardens and so
there's a physical element to that which
is true,
and then there's a metaphysical element
to it,
which is that the,
the environment of a human being is the
proper ad mixture of chaos and order and
it has to be bounded.
So.
And then there's a,
there's a very interesting corollary to
that,
which I think is tremendously
interesting is that there's a snake in
the garden and that's an interesting
thing because part of that is the
recognition that you can't have a place
of bounded chaos and order that's
productive without having something in
it that's,
it's disruptive.
There's no way of getting the
disruptiveness out and that's because
imagine here's the problem,
and this has been discussed intensely in
Christian theology because there's a
relationship between the snake and
Satan,
which is something we'll talk about
later,
but if you,
if you're surrounded by infinite
potential in some sense,
and that's chaos and you try to wall off
part of it,
you can't keep the chaos out.
You can only keep it out partially in
some sense because it's going to come
sneaking back in because you can't erect
a wall that's going to keep out all the
potential from a designated safe place.
And so if you have to live in a garden,
you're going to encounter snakes and
there's a not even God himself can keep
the damn snakes out of the garden
because it's inevitable consequence of
walling off a small section from the,
from the,
from the whole.
So let me see if I can give you an
example.
Well,
I can think of a metaphysical example,
which is you know you're going to
inhabit one of your conceptual
structures and attempt to keep that
matched with the world.
That's like a walled space.
You're saying these are the relevant
things.
This is the place that I can inhabit,
but the fact of the matter is is that as
your walling off that little enclosure
for you to inhabit,
there's dynamism all around you and the
dynamism is going to affect the
structure of this limited place that
you're attempting to inhabit and at some
point it's going to poke his head
through.
You just can't seal something off from
everything.
The thing is going to come back.
Yet.
Now,
one of the things that happens in the
genesis story is that the snake is
actually something to which Adam and Eve
cannot not attend.
That's the other thing that's so
interesting.
So the snake pops up in what's
essentially paradise and human being's
attention to z immediately drawn to it
and I would also say that's what human
beings are like.
You know,
if we've walled off something and
attempted to make it perfect and secure
and something pops up inside that's
unexpected and predatory and attractive,
the first thing we're gonna do is be
automatically drawn to it and then if we
interact with it,
what it's going to do is to increase our
consciousness and that is what happened.
As human beings evolved because one of
the things we know is that we call
evolve with snakes.
We call involved with predatory snakes
and I'm lynn is bell has demonstrated
that the acuity of primate vision among
very large and diverse range of primates
is correlated quite highly with the
prevalence of predatory snakes in the
environment.
And so the,
the,
the genesis story draws this
tremendously complicated analogy.
And one analogy is snakes give people
vision.
And the other analogy is the snake is
actually representative of the chaos
that surrounds every bounded order.
And so it tells the story of
psychological abstraction.
So that would be consciousness versus
the unknown.
And it overlays that on primate snake.
And it's because it's the same.
It's the same idea at two levels of
abstraction.
So you have the same reaction to
unexpected things that occur in your
pristine environment as you're distant
ancestors would have had to the
appearance of a snake and a place that
they regard it as secure and use the
same damn circuits.
It's the same thing and one of the major
claims in the story of genesis is no
gardens without snakes and so you know,
the story is set up so that God tells
men and women to ignore the damn snake
and not to pay any attention with it
north,
to interact with it,
and also not to eat the fruit of the
tree,
of the knowledge of good and evil,
which we'll talk about later.
But human beings don't do that.
They,
they interact with the snake and they
become self conscious,
which is a catastrophe.
And that's how it shown in the in the
story as well.
So as soon as human beings become self
conscious,
they get thrown out of paradise.
So you can read it this way.
We got so smart by paying attention to
the damn snakes that we figured out we
were mortal.
They drove cortical evolution,
especially the evolution of the visual
system.
Now I'm not trying to reduce it to a
unit dimensional phenomena,
but the point is once you get cortical
elaborated enough,
at some point you're going to discover
time which we have discovered,
and once you discovered time,
you're going to discover one of your
boundaries and what are your boundaries.
This is temporal boundary and that means
that you die and that sort of like the
ultimate manifestation of self
consciousness,
and then as soon as you know that you're
going to die while you're not in
paradise anymore,
that's for sure,
and then you have to start taking.
You have to start preparing for the
future in a self conscious manner,
and one of the things that happens to
add them once God catches them,
after he's become self conscious,
as God says to straightforwardly,
well now you've done it.
You know you've become self conscious.
Now will all you're going to be able to
do for the rest of history is work.
You're going to be condemned to work and
you might say,
well,
what's the definition of work?
That's easy.
It's the sacrifice of the present for
the future and you won't do that unless
you're self conscious because why the
hell would you prepare for the future
unless you knew that it might consist of
nothing but trouble and you know,
genesis portrays that discovery as
something that's absolutely fundamental
to the,
to the ground of human existence and
it's only part of what it portrays.
And so we'll talk about some of the
other details when we get together next
week.
Now what I want to do is I want to tell
you this story.
I want to show you how it relates to the
emergence of self consciousness,
and that's the collapse of paradox.
So it's the same idea as the descent
into the underworld.
So the Bible in some senses a descent
into the underworld and ascension story.
And it's precisely that because it's a
redemptive story.
History starts when people descend into
chaos and the entire historical element
of the Bible is part of the attempt of
human beings to lift themselves out of
the painful selfconsciousness that
they've fallen into as a consequence of
interacted with the snake and the fruit.
So.