So here's what,
here's another proposition.
You can think about what we've been
doing so far in some way.
Okay,
you can think about what we've been
doing so far in some way is trying to
figure out what the world is made of and
to answer that,
we have to think about what do you mean
by the world and what do you mean by
Meda?
Because those,
when you're asking a fundamental
question like that,
the terms in the question have to be
specified with a high degree of accuracy
or you're just chasing.
You're just chasing ghosts around.
So we could say,
well,
at one level of analysis,
one level of resolutions,
pretty obvious that the world,
the objective world,
whatever that is,
is made out of atoms and democracy has
said that a long time ago in Greece,
right?
He was the first guy that came up with
the atomic theory,
but he didn't say that the world was
made out of atoms.
He said that it was made out of atoms
and space and you think,
well that's,
you know,
obvious.
It's like,
no,
no.
It's not that obvious because as soon as
you have fundamental particles and
space,
you can array those particles in space
and you can arrange them in patterned
ways and the patterned ways are real to.
The patterns are real too,
so and without.
Without the space,
you can't do that.
So Adam's plus space gives rise to
something else and really what it gives
rise to as far as I can tell,
it's something very much like
inflammation.
Now,
inflammation is a very complicated idea.
What information is,
but that's okay.
We won't go into that at the moment.
Do you think about music?
Right?
Music is like Adams of sound,
right?
Because they're,
they're discreet.
Quanta of sound,
essentially their raid out in patterns
across time,
and obviously the pattern,
the music is not just the note,
it's the pattern across time.
Okay,
so what are the things we might say is
that,
well,
there's Adams in their space and there's
patterns.
Okay,
so patterns.
Now,
one of the most fundamental patterns.
Okay,
so let's put it this way.
We're going to say,
well,
what's your problem?
How to live in the world?
What's the world?
Well,
roughly speaking,
the problem is how to live as an
individual in society and nature.
It's something like that.
Okay,
so then we're going to say,
okay,
if that's the actual problem,
the first thing you have to do to solve
that is to conceptualize society and
nature and conceptualize the individual.
So you have to represent them somehow.
Okay,
so how should you represent society and
nature and the individual?
And the answer to that is that's
complicated.
It's not obvious.
Now we kinda know,
for example,
that one way of representing society is
the dominance hierarchy.
You know,
that's not only a way of representing
and it's a way of being in this society,
right?
To talk about the dominance hierarchy is
to represent it to be in a dominant
turkeys,
to live it.
So we can take about a dominance
hierarchy.
Society is more than a dominance
hierarchy,
but you know,
that's not a bad first approximation.
And then we can think of the place in
which those dominance hierarchies exist.
We might think,
well that's for lack of a better way of
conceptualizing it's nature.
So it's complicated because he can't
actually some these concepts up in
single words as far as I can tell,
you have to use an array of words and an
array of images because the categories
are so broad that you just can't sum
them up in a single concept.
Okay.
So you can sum them up with words and
you can sum them up with images and you
can sum them up with stories and,
and that's,
that's what we do as people.
So the quest.
No.
So we're going to say,
well,
is that a,
is that the fundamental question?
How to live as an individual in society
and nature?
It's like,
well,
I don't know if it's the fundamental
question,
but it's af fundamental question.
So fine.
We'll go with that.
I'll go back over this a little bit
later,
but I'll,
I'll start with this story.
Yeah.
Okay.
So go back to the birthplace of
civilization.
Then we're going to tell the variant of
this story that was discovered in the
late 18 hundreds.
It's a story about this God called Matt
or Martech.
So here's the basic structure of the
story.
You got to primordial gods.
Now the way that must have been Damien's
conceptualize the world is they kinda
thought about it.
You know how if you're out on the field,
it's flat and he kind of looked at the
world.
The world looks like a dome,
right?
That's the sky on a disk.
So that's the Mesopotamian world.
That's kind of the world as
conceptualized by the people who wrote
genesis as well.
It's a dome on a disk.
Okay?
So the disc is land and underneath the
land is water.
Fresh water.
Why?
Well,
if you dig down in the land,
you hit freshwater.
And then underneath that is salt water.
And how do you know that?
Well,
you know,
if you go out to the edges of the land
and you find an ocean,
it's salt water.
So that's the hypothesis.
Okay,
so now as far as the Mesopotamians were
concerned,
the salt water in the fresh water were
two gods.
Now what did they represent?
Well,
one of them was male and one of them was
female and the female one was the salt
water.
The male one was the,
was the freshwater.
Okay?
So now they kind of conceptualize that
as a kind of a formless chaos,
so you can kinda think of that water
mixture as the chaos from which life
emerged.
It's something like that,
but it's also the case and we should
remember that w that life did merged
from water and that without water you
don't live.
So it's,
it's not,
it's not a stupid idea.
It's kind of low resolution idea.
So is this chaotic intermingling of salt
and freshwater.
So that's sort of the idea.
There's a chaos idea looking at the
bottom of that.
And so that's APP suit and tie.
Matt,
now the Mesopotamians don't say much
about absolute and I kinda think that I
think maybe that's because at that point
society hadn't become so highly
structured that and,
and long lasting that that is a great
representation of it had been formed.
I don't think that happened until the
Egyptians,
but I might be wrong about that.
But in any case,
the Mesopotamians don't say much about
absolute.
So what happens is tire mats down there
in the depths,
Sorta like the whale in Pinocchio fact.
Very much like the whale in Pinocchio
and uh,
her husband and they're locked together
in a sexual embrace.
And so part of the idea here is that
while the Union of opposites is
necessary before something new can arise
and that,
that union of opposites can be
conceptualized in some way sexually,
you know,
using male and female,
because when male and female come
together,
something new emerges out of that and
that sort of ideas like the matrix,
you know,
the matrix of things,
that's the mother matter,
mother.
Things emerge out of a matrix.
So,
so anyways,
absent soon time at are down there in
the depths and they're locked together
in the sexual embrace and they produce
offspring and lots of them.
So that's the initial world of the gods.
Now there's all sorts of gods they give
rise to and we don't know a lot about
them,
but I'm going to make some hypotheses
about the gods because you might think,
well,
what the hell are gods anyways,
you know?
And so I,
I think about them as personalities,
their personalities and their
archetypical personalities.
And so it's like,
well,
Venus for example,
is the god of love and I'll show you
some pictures of Venus.
And so what does that mean exactly?
Well,
it's like a complex of things.
Venus is how you act when you're in
love.
Venus is what people find sexually
attractive in women.
Venus is the,
the possession that occurs when you're
in love or when you're really attracted
to someone.
It's all those things.
And so it's like a forest that can
invade you.
It's a way of perceiving.
It's a superordinate instinct.
It's shared across not only human
beings,
but birds and bees as we all know.
So it's this,
it's a transcendent property and it,
it can take personified forum because it
can inhabit you.
And so it's this thing that's sort of
objective and subjective and it's also
one of the fundamental elements of the
world.
So you might say,
well there's Venus for example,
and there's areas that's Mars.
So that's a god of war and he's usually
masculine and he's very aggressive and
so.
Well,
he's like a,
he's like the personality of,
of a warrior like rage.
So,
so,
so I kind of think about the gods,
especially the more fundamental gods.
There's something like primordial forces
and here's a leap and I don't know about
it,
but I think that it's a recapitulation
in some sense of individual
socialization.
So I think that what happens to begin
with is that,
you know,
you're,
as you emerge as an individual,
you start out in a chaotic and
uninformed manner and then these things
come to life inside of you.
And those things are these fundamental
motivational systems that we were
talking about.
And so they're the first products of
chaos.
And then those things have to get their
act together.
Okay.
So like I said,
that's a leap and I haven't been able to
completely fill in the gaps there,
but in any case,
all these gods and goddesses get created
by time at an absolute right.
So then they're running around causing
trouble.
The first God's,
they'd make a lot of racket.
They're doing a lot of impulsive and
crazy things and they make a lot of
noise and they're not very cautious and
they make a big mistake.
They kill app suit and then they live on
his body.
Now that's a weird one,
a,
and you think,
well,
okay,
what's going on there?
Well,
absolute is masculine and so the
masculine thing seems to be associated
in some way with God,
the father and the dominance hierarchy,
and so what does it mean if he's dead?
It means that all this chaotic activity
that's disintegrated has killed the
structure and so they're all now living
on a corpse,
which is not a good thing,
and maybe they didn't know what they
killed and so,
so imagine they're careless.
They're kind of clueless.
They don't know what the hell's going
on,
and they break a bunch of rules and they
destroy the,
the,
the orderly element of what initially
gave rise to them and then they live on
it's corpse.
In.
Another way of thinking about that is
that that's what you guys do.
You're living on a corpse.
You're living on the corpse of the past,
right?
And it's the consequence of the activity
of the dead and it's dead because it's
the activity of the dead,
right?
I mean the library.
There's no life in a library except for
the people in it.
The rest of it's all ghosts.
So you're living on the dead shell of
the past.
Okay.
Anyways,
these guards are all making all sorts of
racket and running around and spinning
up wind and dust and noise and it's
really chaotic and then they kill Appsu.
It's like,
hmm,
that's not a good idea.
So absolute was also ordered.
And so what happens when you kill order?
When you destroy order,
what happens?
Up comes chaos.
That's what happened in Iraq for
example.
Okay.
So time that comes up and she thinks,
I don't know about these things I
created.
It's like they're really noisy and
annoying and careless.
And uh,
they went and killed up suits.
He's like,
he's my current Saturdays necessary.
It's like,
not for them.
They're gone.
I'm going to wipe them out.
Sort of like God deciding to wipe out
everybody with the flood.
It's the same idea.
These stories all came from the same
area,
right?
So it's another representation of that
idea.
It's also kind of have a vengeful God
Now you might think,
well,
what about this vengeful God idea?
It's like,
well,
do you really want to have a god that's
eventual?
It's like that's a stupid question
because you've got one whether you want
one or not.
So I can give you an example.
So let's think about New Orleans,
right?
So New Orleans got hit by a hurricane
and it was a natural disaster and it
wiped out a big chunk of the city,
right?
Well,
no,
that isn't really right.
So the Dutch live underwater basically,
right?
The whole bloody country is below sea
level.
So the dots make these huge dams and
they maintain them like Matt.
And here's the Dutch rule.
We're going to try to calculate the
worst possible storm that could possibly
happen in 10,000
years,
and then we're going to build those damn
dikes.
So if that storm comes,
we're safe.
Okay.
So what happens?
Holland isn't underwater,
so there's no natural disaster.
So let's go to New Orleans.
It's like,
well,
why did Orleans get wiped out?
Well,
there was a hurricane.
It's like,
did they know that there might be
hurricanes?
Yes.
Did they know that?
The dikes weren't big enough.
Yes.
Have they been complaining about it for
a hundred years?
Yes.
Have there been things put in place to
try to get the dikes better?
Yes.
Did that work?
No.
Why not?
Because it's corrupt.
It's a corrupt state now.
All the money,
they pour it in there too to help the
people after the.
After the flood.
That didn't help them.
It just disappeared.
And so you can't.
If the state is corrupt and the
individuals within it or corrupt,
it means the structure.
The society is dead.
It's a corpse.
And what happens when you make a corpse
out of your society?
A corrupt corpse.
Wow.
That's easy.
Mother Nature comes back and takes what
she has and then you think,
oh,
isn't the world a terrible place?
It's like,
yeah,
try not frittering away the money.
See what happens.
It's part of it.
Yeah.
So there's a whole tangled up idea of
murderers and so forth.
We'll get into that.
So anyways.
Okay,
so ty mass had it.
She said,
wow,
these things aren't worth preserving.
I'm going to go and wipe them out and
then everything will be nice and calm
and peaceful yet.
And so the gods,
they get wind of this,
you know,
and they're thinking,
Hey,
this isn't very good because like,
she's,
that's time out.
We're talking about here she is mother
nature,
like in that inner terrible sense.
And she creates everything and she kills
everything.
And if he decides that we're,
you know,
going back to where we came from,
that's probably what's going to happen.
So they're pretty blurry.
I'm worried about this.
So they get together in a kind of a
council.
So they're trying to organize
themselves,
say they get to get under under council
and they think,
oh well what are we going to do about
this?
And so they elect,
they take one of their gods and they
say,
you,
why don't you go out there and try to,
you know,
keep time at,
at bay and straightened her out.
So one God goes out and has a big fight
with tire Matt and comes back and he's
old,
defeated and wiped out,
not work.
And so then they send another God out
and he's just completely useless.
That doesn't work.
It comes back and it was getting pretty
damn desperate.
They're in the realm of the original
gods and so this is going on for quite a
long time and while this is happening,
the gods are still marrying each other
and producing offspring and so forth.
And one day this new sort of go onto
peers on the scenes and his name is
Martin and Martin is.
He's a new thing.
They're not really sure what to do with
them and he's got.
He can really hear and he can speak
magic words.
And so when he says magic words,
the day appears in the night disappears.
And so he's got the power of speech,
that's a big deal.
And he's got eyes all the way around his
head.
You can see everywhere,
it can really pay attention.
So you know,
and he's big and he's strong and he's
tough and all those things.
But the big things is he can speak and
he can really seek and really pay
attention.
So the gods think,
hmm,
well he's kind of a new character,
we haven't thrown anything like that at
time matt yet,
so let's,
let's do it.
So they all get together in their
counsel and they bring it in and they
say,
well,
you know,
we're kind of thinking to be a good idea
if you went out and fought this terrible
monster,
right?
And he thinks,
well,
you think that's a good idea,
but you know,
it's me on the line here so I need a
price.
And so the price is you make me the
determiner of destiny's.
Now that's an interesting phrase.
Hey,
and we don't know exactly know what they
meant,
but it's something like what I am that's
Marduk is now going to be the thing that
determines how things unfold.
So it's sort of like,
I'm going to be taught God,
you may,
if I'm going off to fight time at,
I'm top God.
In fact,
that's how you can define top God
taught.
God is the God that can go out and fight
tie imac.
So the other,
the other guards,
they're not very happy about having to
subordinate themselves to Martin,
but they think beats the hell out of
being eaten by ty amounts.
So they say,
yeah,
if you,
when you get to be like top God,
you,
you have the tablets of destiny,
you can determine destiny fight fine.
So,
so fine.
Martin goes off and he gets his act
together and it gets big net and he
prepares himself and he rides forward
and encounters time at.
She's this great big dragon like monster
thing that's her there on the,
on the right left.
So you can see she's kind of a dragon
angel monster thing.
She's like,
she is a monster and what she is is
really an amalgam of frightening things
essentially.
So.
And there's Martech on the right and
he's going to go give her a good
whacking.
And so he goes out there and the first
thing he does,
and this is quite cool,
he encapsulate her in a net now.
So think about that because she's
basically natural chaos.
She's the productivity of natural chaos.
And so what mark does is it encapsulates
her in the net and that's like a
conceptual scheme,
right?
He puts,
he puts boundaries around the chaos and
that's what Margaret can do.
That's,
that's his ability with his ability to
speak in his eyes and his capacity to
pay attention.
So he,
he encloses her,
right?
And so that's kind of hard on her.
She can't get out of the net.
And then he cuts her into pieces and
then he makes the world out of the
pieces.
And in fact one of Martin's names is he
who fashioned ingenious things out of
the carcass of format,
which is so cool because it's a tool use
metaphor.
It's right.
How do you conquer nature while you go
in there and you,
you know,
will decompose it in many ways and you
make weapons out of it and you make cool
things and that keeps it at bay.
And how do you do that by speaking and
paying attention.
So that's what the Mesopotamians figured
out.
Now they didn't know that that's what
they figured out because like the idea
was already there,
it was implicit in the dominance
hierarchy in some sense,
but and they were observing the
dominance hierarchy and well,
they got their kingdom together.
They were bringing tribes in from all
over,
right?
And all the tribes had their stories and
then I'll know all those stories had to
fight and so that's like the battle of
gods in the battle of the gardens and
having all those stories had to fight
just like Islam and Christianity and
Catholicism and protestantism or all
scrapping for dominance.
Now they're fighting.
How do we make sense out of this mess?
Maybe take several thousand years,
Mesopotamia gathered together all of
these tribes and their stories and then
the stories fought and out of that fight
emerged this story and that was a good
enough story.
So everyone was happy with it.
And the story was.
Sorry,
I know we have to start.
The story was whatever Martin
represents,
that's top God.
And so what did he represent?
Vision,
attention and speech,
and so the Mesopotamians already figured
out everything else should be
subordinate to vision,
attention and speech.
It's like good work.
Mesopotamians.
Sorry.
It's my daughter and she wants to pick
me up.
Hello?
Hi there.
Where are you?
Okay,
but bye.
All right,
so one final thing.
The Mesopotamian emperor emperor was
charged with the imitation of Martin.
That's what made him sovereign so,
so it's not arbitrary.
It's like if he was going to be
sovereign and he was going to be a good
sovereign,
that meant he had to be a good Marduk
and we'll talk about that when we meet
again.