Well,
good evening,
London,
two weeks ago,
Sam Harris and Jordan Peterson met in
person for the first time on stage in
Vancouver two nights ago.
The three of us got together for the
first time in Dublin and it's a huge
thrill for all of us to now be here with
you in the o two,
as I said to travis when these events
were planned,
I'm not moderate enough to be a
moderator,
but I'm going to do a little bit of
fielding to begin with,
so let me start by saying a little of
some of the ground we are going to be
trying to cover here tonight.
We're going to be dealing with the
conflict between science and reason.
We're going to be addressing the
legitimacy.
Did I say science and reason science and
reason?
Yes.
Occasionally there is.
We're not addressing that.
We're going to be looking at the
legitimacy of holding onto religion in
any form and we are also going to be
addressing the fact that we need to hide
in a sports stadium to address serious
issues.
But I think to begin with,
I'm going to hand over to Sam and he's
going to kick us off.
Well,
thank you.
First,
thank you all for coming out.
I really can't imagine how humble
to be here with you.
You really should just take a moment to
appreciate this from our side because
Justin Bieber is not coming out to sing
in the middle of this as a museum is
that would be a.
and you know,
though we put the date like this on the
calendar with apparent confidence,
there's really no guarantee that you
guys are going to show up and we will
never take this for granted.
So it is really an immense privilege to
be here with you.
So
I thought I could start by first how fun
this has been to,
to have this,
these series of dialogues,
uh,
with Jordan.
Now this is the fourth event we've done.
And the second with Douglas and we
clearly share a common project mean we
are,
we are trying to figure out how to live
the best lives possible both
individually and collectively and we're
trying to figure out how to build
societies that safeguard that
opportunity for as many people as
possible.
And I think we each have a sense that
ideas are really the prime movers here,
that it's not that the world is filled
with bad people doing bad things because
that's what bad people do though there,
there is some of that.
It is mostly that so much of humanity is
living under the sway of bad ideas and
it's bad ideas that can cause good
people or at least totally normal people
like ourselves to do bad things all the
while trying to,
to live the best possible lives.
And that really is the tragedy of our
circumstance that we can be that
confused.
Uh,
so this is where the difference between
Jordan and and me in particular opens
up,
which is how do you view religion in
this,
in this contest between good ideas and
bad ideas.
And for me,
religion emphatically gets placed on the
side of bad and old and a worth retiring
ideas or ideas worth retiring.
And I guess by analogy I would,
I would,
uh,
ask you to consider astrology and I had.
Maybe I can just get a sense of what I'm
talking to.
What percentage of you I want to know,
believe in astrology,
which is to say who among you.
And you can signal this by,
by applause or a house of enthusiasm.
What,
what percentage of your let,
let me just spell it out.
So you know what you're committing to a
and a new neural,
how crazy your neighbor is.
In fact,
what percentage of you believe that
human personalities and human events and
the difference between good and bad luck
in a human life is the result of what
the planets are doing against the
background of stars or it somebody out
there.
Okay.
So now you should know that something
like 25 percent of your neighbors
believe that.
Uh,
oh,
there you go.
So I'm,
I'm,
I'm here.
Wait,
wait,
wait.
I'm hearing,
I'm hearing a heckler among the
astrologers.
Is that for the first astrological
heckler?
I've heard you must be an areas or
so it,
it
won't surprise you.
I have a related question,
which is what?
What percentage of you I want to know
are religious,
which is say,
well,
who among you believe in God,
a personal God,
a God that can hear prayers,
a god that can take an interest in the
lives of human beings and occasionally
law enforce good outcomes versus bad
outcomes.
What?
Who among you?
And now again,
I want to hear applause or,
or silence believing that sort of God.
Okay.
So this is my concern is my concern with
what Jordan has been saying and writing
Lo these many months.
I feel that you are in danger of
misleading these,
the second group of people that,
that the way you talk about God has
convinced and will continue to convince
some percentage of humanity that it's
fine to hold on to this old sort of God,
this God that can hear prayers and they
can intervene or not in the lives of
human beings.
Uh,
and you know,
as we've begun to explore that,
I think there are a lot of problems with
that kind of belief.
Uh,
if nothing else,
there are many such God's on offer and
their devotion to them becomes
irreconcilable among the true believers.
And my concern is that you could do
exactly what you do with religion,
with astrology,
right?
It would be,
it would be no more legitimate to,
to,
uh,
obfuscate the boundary between clear
thinking and superstition there because
the,
this traditional God and the and the
doctrines that support him are,
are no firmer ground than astrology is
now today.
And astrology,
almost everything you say about
religion.
It's the fact that his organized human
thinking for thousands of years,
that it's a cultural universal that
every,
every group of people has,
has given rise to some form of it.
That it has archetypal significance that
has powerful stories.
All of that can be said about astrology
and,
and in fact,
some additional things can be said about
astrology that or are would argue in its
favor.
For instance,
astrology is profoundly egalitarian.
You know,
there's,
there's no bad Zodiac sign every whoever
you are.
Everyone's got a great Zodiac sign and
uh,
you know,
it's,
it's just a inconvenient fact of the
discipline that if I read you Charles
Manson's Horoscope,
you'd have 95 percent of the audience
would find it relevant and,
and that's just,
that's how easily falsifiable astrology
is.
But that my concern is that we could
live in a world where societies are
shattered over things like,
you know,
different Zodiac interpretations and we
don't live in that world for good reason
because we have beaten astrology into
submission.
And I would say that religion in terms
of revealed religion and belief in a
personal God is over the centuries
getting the same treatment by science
and rationality and should be.
And it is a,
a perverse circumstance that we live in
a world that is that a shattered by
religion.
So I think what I'll do first is adopt
the exceptionally difficult and likely
counterproductive position of saying
something not so much in defensive
religion,
but in defense of astrology,
knowing,
knowing full well that that's
fundamentally a fool's errand.
But there's something I want to point
out is that first of all,
astrology was astronomy in it's nascent
form and astrology was also science in
its nascent form,
just like alchemy was chemistry and it's
nascent form,
and so sometimes you have to dream a
crazy dream with all of the error that
that crazy dream entails because you
have an intuition that there's something
there to motivate you to develop the
intuition to the point where it actually
becomes a genuine practical utility.
Now,
when we look back on the astrologers and
we value their contributions to the
history of the world with contempt,
we should also remember that the people
who built Stonehenge,
for example,
and the first people who decided
determined that our fates were in part
written in the stars,
were people whose astrological beliefs
were indistinguishable from their
astronomical beliefs.
And you might think,
well,
in what sense is your fate written in
the stars?
And I would say it's certainly the case
in so far as there are such things as
cosmic regularities.
So it was the dream of astrology that
there was some relationship between the
movement of the planetary bodies.
And the fixed stars and human destiny,
and that's what drove us to build the
first astronomical observatories and to
also determine that there was a proper
time for planting and a proper time for
harvesting and a way of orienting
yourself in the world.
For example,
by using the north star,
it's also the poetic grounded enabled us
to identify the notion that you could
look up and Orient Yourself towards the
heavens and that there was a
metaphorical relationship between that
and positioning yourself properly in
life and at a deeper level.
The,
the,
the cosmos was the place that the human,
that the drama was externalized and
draped itself out into the world as
something that was essentially
observable so that we could derive great
orienting fictions from the observation
of our imagination.
And so,
and part of the problem that that Sam is
pointing to is the difficulty of
distinguishing valid poetic impulse from
invalid political impulse.
And that really is a tremendous problem.
You,
you see that arise also in people who
have religious delusions attendant upon
manic depressive disorder or
schizophrenia.
But so much of what eventually manifests
itself as hardcore pragmatic,
scientific belief has its origin in wild
flights of poetic fantasy,
and it's also the case by the way,
that that's actually how your brain is
organized as far as I can tell that when
you,
and it isn't just me,
I actually,
it's,
it's there.
There's a very large,
what would you call it?
Research Literature,
outlining the relative functions of the
right and left hemisphere,
and it certainly appears to be the case
that when we encounter something
absolutely unknowable or unknown,
what we do is drape that unknown thing
in fantasy as a first pass approximation
to the truth and then refine that
fantasy as a consequence of,
of iterative,
critical analysis.
And so sam believes that what should
happen is that the poetic and fictional
domain should be planted by the rational
domain.
Let me just close the loop.
They're not quite.
I think we need poetry and fiction and
then there's more to engage in with
reality than than being a scientist in a
white lab coat.
But we need to be able to clearly
distinguish back from fantasy or fact
from mirror.
Merely fertile flights of imagination
and we want to be rigorous there and
rational there,
and it's not that.
It's not that there's no place for mere
creativity that's not well,
I guess in the rails of rationality.
Fair enough then,
but then then partly what we are
disputing is the,
the,
the what,
the relative import and have those two
domains,
let's say the poetic and the fictional
and
status of religion.
Now in that.
Well,
I have a hard time reconciling that to
some degree.
With your,
with your more,
what would you say?
Formal statements about the problem
because your mechanism,
the mechanism that you put forth above
all outside of truth is rationality and
it isn't clear to me if you're willing
to allow the utility of spiritual
experience,
which you do and if you're willing to
make,
what would you say?
Allowances for the necessity of the
poetic imagination.
Exactly how it is that that is also
encapsulated under the rubric of pure
rationality.
See,
let's see.
Here's something you can tell me what
you think about this and I've been
thinking a lot about what salmon I've
been talking about.
By the way,
you know,
so I'm making the case in my writing
that democratic institutions not only
grew out of the Judeo Christian
substrate,
but that they're,
that they're properly ensconced within
that substrate,
but I'm also perfectly aware that not
every religious or political system
gives rise to democratic institutions
first and also that there are Christian
substructures,
maybe the most obviously in the case of
the Russian Orthodox Church were the
same metaphysical principles apply,
but out of which a democracy did not
emerge.
And so it does seem to me that what we
have in the West is the consequence of
the interplay between the fantasy
predicated poetic,
Judeo Christian tradition and the
rational critique that was aimed at that
by the enlightenment figures.
And that seems to me to mirror something
like the proper balance between the
right hemisphere and it's poetic
imagination and the left hemisphere and
it's critical capacity.
And then I would say that part of the
way.
So one of the questions you brought up
was how do we decide which,
let's say religious intuitions are
valid.
And I think we do that in part through
negotiated agreement.
You know,
because people have look,
even even among the Catholics,
say in the medieval time there was an
absolute horror of heresy,
so if you were some mendicant monks and
you had a profound religious vision,
the probability that you were going to
be tried as a heretic and burnt at the
stake was extremely high because even
the gatekeepers of the religious
tradition realized that religious
revelation untrammeled by something like
community dialogue,
something like that was something
extraordinary,
extraordinary danger,
and so I would agree with you that the
poetic imagination and the grounds of
religious revelation is something that
can lead people dangerously astray,
but I would say at the same time that it
constitutes the grounds of our initial
exploration and that it's actually
ineradicable necessary.
Okay.
We'll briefly address that and I don't
want to ask a question that brings
Douglas directly in here.
I think this is an instance that have
what's called the genetic fallacy.
The idea that because something emerged
the way it did historically as a matter
of historical contingency,
it is the,
the,
the origin is in fact good and worth
maintaining a or that it was in fact
necessary that we couldn't get these
good things like democracy any other way
or unlikely to.
And I would say that,
that there's no abrahamic religion that
is the best conceivable womb of
democracy or anything else.
We like science.
That's a great place to get done.
Yeah.
So,
but,
but I,
I would just add one other category of,
of uh,
thinking here we have what we think is
factual methods by which we derived
facts.
I would put a rationality there and an
empirical engagement with,
with reality.
Then we have other good things in life
like fiction and flights of fancy that
are pleasing for one reason or another
and could be generative toward the first
category.
But then we also have A.
I would acknowledge we've spoken about
this before,
useful fictions and cases.
I would,
you know,
hope rare cases where were fiction is
more adaptive or more useful than the
truth.
Right?
That there,
there's sometimes the truth can,
can be not worth knowing and I would
argue that they,
you know,
there are those cases where they're not,
but they're few and far between,
but we should focus on that.
But to some degree.
So I want to just point to Douglas here
and focus on that because I think your
fear,
Douglas,
is that my style or you know,
Richard Dawkins or Christopher Hitchens,
his style of antitheism,
you know,
just,
let's,
let's just throw the vickers from the
rooftops now because it is time to end
this thing literally get off twitter
now.
That's a Hashtag
your concern has been that,
uh,
and I think Jordan shares this,
that,
that so much of what is good in our
Western developed societies is at the
very least maintained by maintain,
maintaining so-called Judeo Christian
values or the or the remnants of our
past religiosity.
And that either there is a baby in the
bathwater that can be difficult to
discern.
And we can't empty the tub all at once.
Because,
and this is very much a because there's
a zero sum contest with the religious
enthusiasm we see coming from the Muslim
world,
and of course the Muslim world is all
over the world at the moment.
So in that contest between a very,
an older style of religiosity and be a
theocracy really,
and maternity,
you are not as eager as I have been to,
to pull up western religiosity by the
roots.
Well,
chuck [inaudible] the vickers.
Yes.
I think that's fair.
I mean,
I think I sit metaphorically as well as
literally between the two of you.
Um,
I realized from our conversation in
Dublin,
some of your concerns are about what
Jordan has been saying and what he's
saying.
And I share some of the concern I said
to you then that I use the analogy of
what our friend Eric Weinstein recently
described to me as Jesus smuggling,
that it was a consequence of a
discussion about biologists.
What do you do if you're discussing
design intelligent design?
You can be okay as as your own bandwidth
on the of the issue,
as long as your in depth of knowledge on
the issue is very considerable.
You can be okay discussing that biology
with somebody,
even a fundamentalist Christian,
so long as you can follow every step of
the way.
The fear will always be that the moment
you're not looking,
they're going to smuggle Jesus in.
Oh,
they'll wait until the moment that
you're not comfortable anymore with the
argument,
the bit when you're at the very end of
your cognitive ability and then they'll
trust me.
There's Jesus.
Yes,
Jesus.
Right,
and one of the things I realized from
Dublin was,
although I think you may not think that
Jordan himself is going to try Jesus
smuggling on you,
you fear that somewhere down the line
from what he's saying,
somebody else will do that trick.
Yeah.
It's worse than that.
I actually know the people,
the people who were clapping are doing
that.
I hear from those people on a daily
basis.
Right?
So that the segment of Jordan's
audience,
that is.
That is very happy to be told they can
stay on the riverbank of their
traditional Christianity for the most
part,
and they don't have to get into the
stream of totally modern,
rigorous,
rational thinking about everything from
first principles,
right?
That there's something that,
that the Iron Age scribes got right and
it's right for all time.
Those are the.
Those are the applause.
I'm hearing.
And,
and,
and I,
I,
however,
consciously or not,
Jordan is telling them it's okay to
stay.
Stick right there with a,
with a Shard of the cross.
Okay,
well,
I actually tried a little conscious
Jesus smuggling on Sam to see how that
would go into discussion we had about
the central archetype of superheroes.
But I'm going to try something a little
different tonight.
I'm going to try a little direct God
smuggling.
We won't bother with Jesus.
Let's go right to God.
Why not?
So,
I'm.
One of the things I've really tried to
do when I've been analyzing religious
texts is to take them as to take them
seriously in the sense that I don't
presume that I understand them and I
presume that they're a mystery of sorts
and at least the Bible,
for example,
is a mystery because we don't really
understand the processes by which it was
constructed and we don't understand the
processes by which we all agreed
collectively over several thousand years
to organize the book the way it is
organized or to edit it the way that
it's edited or end to keep what's in it
and to end to discard what's not in it
and why it's lasted and why it's had
such a huge impact.
I don't want to derail you,
but we do understand that the first part
of the process all too well.
We know that the.
There was a political and all too human
process of voting certain texts in for
and some were in for centuries and then
got jettisoned and revelation came in
far later than.
I mean the whole generations of
Christians who lived and died under the
banner of the Bible and it was a
different Bible at the time.
I had the wrong Bible.
So,
but it's the same.
It's the same issue that,
that we really don't.
We really don't understand.
Fair enough.
Salmon,
I'm not saying that political etc.
Considerations didn't enter into it.
I'm sure all human Considerations
entered into it,
but there was some collective process of
winnowing and you can attempt to reduce
that to economic or political causes,
which is generally what secular
assessors like freud and marx both did
and with a fair degree of success side,
my dad.
But there's still some mysterious,
uh,
assessment of what it is that will be
remembered that entered into it.
But It's a separate point to some
degree.
But I'm just saying that my point,
my,
my point of departure when looking at
these texts,
who's one of an essential radical
ignorance,
I don't assume that I understand the
mechanisms by which they were generated
or edited or collected or kept or
remembered or why they had the impact
they had.
now I've been thinking a lot about the
idea of let's say god the father,
because that's a very common
architectural representation of god,
god the father.
So I'm going to tell you an experience
that I had that I've never really told
any audience about.
I had a vision at one point that and the
vision had to do with a dialogue that I
was having with my father.
And you know you have a father,
right?
And when you're a little kid,
you act out your father.
When you pretend to be a father and what
you're doing when you're acting out,
your father isn't imitating your father
because you don't duplicate precisely
the actions that your father ever took
in his life.
what you do is you watch your father
across multiple contexts and you
abstract out something like a spirit of
the father and then when you're a child,
you implement that spirit of the father
in your pretend play and you come to
embody that deeply.
So the notion is that people can
abstract out something like a spirit of
the father and that that's part of our
[inaudible] mimetic tendency,
which is a very powerful human cognitive
tendency.
And in this vision I first started to
talk with my father and I would say more
with the spirit of my father because he
wasn't actually there and I would say it
was the wisest part of him.
And then that sort of transformed into a
discussion that I had with a series of
ancestral spirits.
And then that transformed itself into a
vision of god himself with whom I have a
conversation and this was a visionary
experience.
And then that all went away and I spent
months and months thinking about it and
I thought so you guys can tell me what
you think about this.
And this sort of stretches my cognitive
ability to,
to its utmost limit to contemplate such
things.
But here's a biological argument.
I already made the that a child
can extract out the spirit of the father
and embody it.
Didn't that's necessary in so far as
you're going to be a father and a wise
one.
But we can also extract out the spirit
of the father over much longer periods
of time because my father was a father
because he imitated his father who
imitated his father,
who imitated his father as far back in
time as you can go,
and there's a cumulative development of
the spirit of the farther across time.
Now then the question might be,
does this spirit of the father have any
reality other than the metaphorical?
And I would say,
damn right,
it has a reality and I can describe a
biological reality.
And and,
and I don't know what this says about
any background metaphysics,
but here's a hypothesis.
We know that human beings separated from
chimpanzees over the course of the last
7 million years,
at least in large part because of human
female sexual activity.
So it was the spirit of femininity
collectively that helped elevate us to
the degree that we have been elevated
above our chimpanzee co ancestor.
But here's something interesting to
contemplate.
What is it precisely that makes men what
makes men desirable to women?
And so I have a bit of a hypothesis
about that.
So here's what men do.
They get together in productive groups
and the orient themselves toward a
certain task and they produce a
hierarchy around that task because
whenever you implement a task,
you produce a hierarchy and they vote up
the most competent men to the top of the
hierarchy and then the women's select
the competent men from the top of the
hierarchy,
but the vote that determines who the
competent men are that are more likely
to reproduce as a consequence of male
evaluation of men.
And that's occurred over millennia.
And so there's a spirit of the father
that's embedded in the patriarchal
hierarchy that acts as the primary
selection mechanism that offers men up
to women and plays us.
Our cardinal role in human evolution.
And it looks like we've.
We've personiFied that spirit of the
father in our religious imagery and and
that's,
that's how it looks to Me.
But then there's something that's even
more mysterious and deep about that
that's worth considering,
is that apparently the entire course of
evolutionary history has conspired to
produce human beings.
And we could argue that it could have
been different,
but it certainly hasn't been different.
And that means that that selective
spirit of the father has been part of
the process that's generated our very
being,
and it's certainly possible that that
collective spirit of the father reflects
something metaphysically fundamental
about the structure of reality itself a
way
yes
into insofar as I agree with,
with virtually all of that,
I should say that none of that should
give comfort to people who want to hold
onto this notion that certain of our
books might've been revealed by the
creator of the universe.
Well,
it depends what you by the creator.
Yeah.
Like I'm just saying that,
that,
that the world we're living in now is
one in which we have whole societies
shattered over this notion that some
books weren't written by human beings.
Right?
There's a different class of book,
right?
There's a different shelf in the library
where the products of almost certainly
merely human brains are venerated for
all time and,
and considered uneditable and
uninsurable five by the majority of
human beings.
Yep.
Well,
it's clear,
clear that revelation can devolve into
fundamentalism,
but I'm real,
but any.
But there is a risk,
and alyssa whizzes isn't often made
critique,
but when you're talking about religion,
you're talking about the inquisition,
you're talking about the jihadists.
You're not talking about somebody who
wants to go to their local anglican
church once a year,
maybe get the children to school and
maybe when they at some desolate moment
of their lives returns to this as a
place that stores meaning.
I mean the thing that I think Jordan and
I are in agreement on them this is,
is that thing,
a quote from shop in the heart and the
dialogue on religion when he says,
you know,
the truth may be like water.
It needs vessels to carry it.
And we,
when we were talking about this the
other night,
you know,
you admitted that one of the
consequences perhaps of the,
you know,
the parents sort of going through the
belief structures,
they may not believe in any more,
but they keep doing it as a
demonstration of what you said was the,
the,
the non embarrassing options that
atheists have come up with.
But it may also be that the,
since we don't have very many vessels
that cracked and damaged and sometimes
transparent as they are,
what vessels you have might be worth
holding onto?
Well,
no,
I think.
I think the challenge here is mean it
feels that.
Well,
first of all we should first notice that
these comments very often take the form
of you and I don't need this stuff,
but most other people do.
Right.
And that is,
it can do that.
Yeah.
I mean that's inevitably.
And if it's sort of took that form at
one moment the other night,
whereas where you acknowledged that,
that people have low intelligence are
our best placed in a conservative
paradigm,
a traditionally conservative paradigm
paradigm.
Because there's less to think through
right now.
Obviously you don't want your,
your view on religion summarized by it's
good for stupid people.
Well I do.
I do want to summarize to some degree
that way because one of the things that
we do have the opportunity again to put
his foot in your mouth.
But I would say not,
not only.
I mean,
the thing is is that we're all stupid
and some of us are far stupider than
others,
but we're not,
but we're not that stupid.
I mean,
there is another problem,
sam.
I think,
and this is obviously contentious one,
one of the things I don't go to church,
but there is one thing I admire about
the church and that is that it's managed
to serve as a repository for these
fundamental underlying fictions for two
millennia and that's really something
bloody unbelievable.
I mean the great,
what would you say?
Bloody unbelievable.
Well,
look sam there.
Everything's,
everything's.
Everything's soaked in blood.
We have no disagreement about that,
but the second or alternatives that we
produced in the 20th century were
certainly no less blood sodom and they'd
produced nothing of any productivity.
We did not do it now,
but we have to put to bed that secular
canard.
It's just not so that stalin ism was the
product of secularism or atheism and
norwood.
It wasn't an inevitable product or
products.
It wasn't bay.
And please anyone who has this meme in
your head,
please just allow.
The next sentence is I speak to just
push it out because I'm so sick of
hearing this,
uh,
this,
this idea that the greatest crimes of
the 20th century where somehow the
product of atheism,
right?
When you look at what actually
engineered these atrocities,
it was something that looked very much
like a religion.
It was a religion in every way apart
from an explicit commitment to other
worldliness.
It was based on different dogmatism
through and through.
It was based on a personality cults
that,
that grew up around figures like stalin
and hitler and mao.
It's,
these were the,
it was not the ideas of bertrand russell
and david hume that brought us to the
gulag or to auschwitz.
But then you say it's the thought of
jesus christ.
either we know it's true.
No,
I can say that I,
I can say it
thought of st augustine and I can say it
was the thought of st thomas aquinas
explicitly that gave us the inquisition.
The fact.
Can I make a suggestion?
Yeah.
I mean this is a general one as well as
one for tonight,
but the whole discussion.
I mean,
I said the other night in dublin that to
a great extent,
when the history books are written about
the period we're living in,
they'll probably be described as the
post holocaust period in history,
the post world war two era in europe.
It'll.
It's still going on,
so we're still.
We're still going through this,
trying to work out what happened,
and I have to say one thing that I at
any rate and equally tired of is the
claim that this has got to Be a tennis
game between the religious and
nonreligious,
but people say that the 20th century's
crimes were committed by atheists,
sometimes true,
often wrong,
or that the 20th century,
his crimes were committed by people who
were religious,
sometimes true,
often wrong.
Nobody.
You're not observing a crucial
distinction here because I would never
be tempted to hold religion accountable
for the band.
Things that religious people do that
have no connection to religion.
Right?
So if a muslim robs the liquor store,
I'm not going to blame islam for that.
Or there's no dogs.
There's no doctrine that there's no
doctrine that makes sense of that
behavior.
What I blame religion for and,
and likewise,
there is no doctrine in the mirror loss
of religion.
They,
I atheism that gets you the gulag of
there is that there's not,
there's not,
but,
but let me just,
let me just flush out this point for one
more second.
The only thing I blame religion for are
the things that it becomes rational to
do by the light of these beliefs.
If you accept these doctrines,
a rational and good person can be
tempted to join isis.
That's my concern.
A rational and good person can be
tempted to support the inquisition,
but of the many things they had in
common.
Um,
this is the point that david berlinski
made in his book.
What did the end kvd having common with
everyone who oversaw the gulag bss,
people who guarded the camps,
that people who put people on trains.
What did they all have in common?
What do they have in common with mao,
among other things they had in common?
The fact that none of them thought that
god was watching them,
none of them thought that they were
being observed.
And what
held accountable?
it doesn't help when you think god is on
your side,
but we have just as many examples where
people do it because I think,
god,
god is on their side.
Right?
Watching and clapping.
I'm not denying that.
I'm saying that the attempt to make this
at a tennis match over the 20th century
was a mistake.
We were still trying to work out what
caused it.
Religion had a role.
Atheism had a role,
but the perpetual tennis match of it,
I think,
well,
there is something to be said at a more
sophisticated level,
I would say for the idea that you have
an obligation to a transcendent ethic.
Now you make that claim in the moral
landscape.
You you lay out a transcendent ethic in
my estimation.
That's one that puts the onus of
responsibility on the individual to act
in a way that at at minimum minimizes
suffering and so and you think of that
as a statement of fact that that's the
proper way of being.
And I think aBout it as an axiomatic
statement of faith and that's one of our
differences,
but I have been very careful in my
analysis of the relationship between the
idea of sovereignty and the idea of
religious belief,
and one of the things that I have worked
out,
I think partly from reading such people
as eliana and young,
was that the.
There is an emergent idea of sovereignty
that does involve being accountable to a
god and neighbor here,
here's how I would justify that and I,
I would think about this essentially
from a practical and biological
perspective,
independent of any metaphysical reality
that it might have.
So the ancient mesopotamians,
for example,
believed that their emperor was the
incarnation or the representative of a
god named martin,
and that actually bestowed certain
ethical responsibilities on the ruler.
And so the ruler had to Be a good marduk
in order to be a sovereIgn,
to be regarded as sovereign.
He had to be the embodiment of these
divine principles.
And it took the mesopotamians a very,
very long period of time,
perhaps several tens of thousands of
years.
They weren't mesopotamian during that
whole time.
Obviously to work out what those
principles of sovereignty should be and
the mesopotamians encoded this in their
fictions and their religious fictions,
making essentially the proposition that
the proper ruler had to have eyes all
the way around his head because that was
one of the attributes of martech.
So he was someone who was genuinely
paying attention,
who is capable of coming into voluntary
contact with,
with the great chaotic substructure of
being and cutting it into pieces and
making the habitable world and also
speaking words that were truthful,
that had the power,
the magic power of truth,
and the the ruler had to act that out.
If he was going to be the sort of ruler
that his people weren't entitled to slay
and sacrifice.
And then once a year at the new year's
festival,
he would go outside the city,
the walled city,
and he would act out his role of marduk
and the priest would humiliate them and
ask him to confess all the ways that he
hadn't been a good martech so that he
could remember that he had a
responsibility to undertake this.
This to embody this relationship with
these divine principles,
and the thing that's so important about
this so absolutely crucially important
is that it established the principle
that even if you were at the top of a
hierarchy,
you weren't absolute.
There was something above you that you
were subordinate to,
and one of the extraordinarily useful
ideas about the abstraction of,
of even god as a personified spirit,
let's say,
is that it allows every leader to be
subordinate to something that's beyond
him.
Now,
that doesn't mean it can't be misused,
but it's a very,
very,
very important idea.
Yeah,
except
you can also.
You can get there.
The other way around.
You can realize that you,
even if you're at the top of the
hierarchy,
you are radically dependent on everyone
else.
That the tip of the pyramid at the tip
of a hierarchy doesn't believe that
sometimes they believe they can do
whatever the hell they want.
But I'm saying if,
if you're going to believe something
that's compatible with,
with rationality globally and has the
least conceivable downside,
I would put in that place,
not a superstitious attachment to a
notion of an invisible friend,
uh,
or punisher who's,
who's above you.
I would put in its place they totally
defensible and palpably true fact that
we,
that you can be the king of the,
of the,
of the world,
and you are dependent on everyone around
you to eat,
to not be murdered by them.
I mean like you are,
you are,
you are.
I mean,
it's amazing.
It's amazing how precarious even a
totalitarian regime is.
I mean,
the amazing thing is that,
that these,
the last at all,
because in many cases it would just take
a 50 people to act in unison to kill the
tyrant,
right?
But it never happens because we either
have a first mover problem.
Everyone is afraid to be the first
person shot.
But it is,
it is a genuine mystery that these
systems even perpetuate themselves.
And when they unravel,
when you see,
you know,
kadafi being murdered in a crowd,
you realize,
wow,
it really is just a matter of the
restraint and fear of human beings
keeping any of these things together.
A benign,
if you,
if you wanted a hierarchy where you had
a kind of benign philosopher king
pulling the reigns of a society,
I'm not saying we do,
but even there you could have an ethical
one.
You could have one where and,
and a non superstitious one was the one
where someone recognize,
hey,
this is,
this is how we're doing it,
but we are radically.
I at the top of this hierarchy,
am radically dependent on having,
being surrounded by as many happy people
as possible.
Well
look,
I mean I don't,
I don't in some profound sense
we're actually,
you know,
we're living in this sounds like a
fiction,
but we're living with this problem and
we encounter this more and more when you
talk,
you know,
in,
in silicon valley as,
as you and I occasionally do and I'm
sure you do as well,
where you meet people who are
fantastically wealthy,
who seem uncannily detached at the,
by the detached,
at the fact that the,
there's this growing chasm between them
and those they know and the rest of
humanity and one begins to wonder what
level of wealth inequality will everyone
find alarming.
And some people are acting as though
there is no level that is alarming that
the,
that there's kind of a law of nature
that this thing can grow.
Just impossibly to the point where we
have trillionaires walking around.
Uh,
and you know,
you drive into their motorcades and it's
kind of a,
I mean it's sort of the libertarian
religion one occasionally runs into a
and clearly there's some level of
inequality that's untenable or at least
would be undesirable.
It's a funny thing because that's a
place where our thought loops and then
agrees to some degree again,
because I do believe that you can in
some sense,
rationally derive an an ethic.
So,
so let's,
let's,
let's take the argument that you put
forward.
Say that,
well,
you're,
and this is an extension of your
wellbeing argument to some degree,
which with which I've thought about a
fair bit.
It's like,
well,
okay,
what's the optimal solution for you?
Well,
okay,
well first of all,
there isn't just you now there's you now
and you tomorrow and you next week and
you and a year you in five years.
So there's you and the you that
propagates across time.
So one of the implications of that is
that you can't do anything that's really
good for the eu now that isn't very good
for you a week from now.
Right?
So that means you have to imagine
yourself as multiple individuals across
multiple timeframes,
and then you have to figure out what's
good for all those individuals across
all those timeframes.
Although you discount the future to some
degree because of its unpredictability.
But then so,
so that's a very tIght set of
constraints and you might say,
well,
a rational person would calculate the
optimal across all those,
all those multiple timeframes.
Then you do the same thing with other
people,
which is the point you just made.
Well it isn't just you because who's
you.
There's you and your family.
Most people are in a situation where
they would regard damage to theIr family
as perhaps even worse than damage to
them.
So whatever they are obviously
encapsulates their family and then to
some degree that flows off into the
community and so there is no isolated
you and that sort of point with regards
to the ethic.
But then so,
so I agree with all that.
But then one of the things that I would
suggest is that because that's an
incredibly difficult rational
calculation and perhaps an impossible
one technically speaking,
but certainly very difficult.
That's what that what has happened in
part as our,
as our great narratives have heavy
merged across time,
is that we have observed ourself
attempting to solve that multiple
identity,
multiple timeframe problem.
And we've told stories about people who
do that exceptionally well,
and then we've winnowed out those
stories and we've produced these
powerful narratives that encapsulate the
ethic,
that does in fact reflect that wisdom
and so,
so,
and I think you actually accept some of
that in your,
in your moral propositions,
which is something that we've talked
about before.
So for example,
they'll never really agreed on.
You certainly believe,
for example,
that the embodiment of truth is one of
the means whereby you solve the problem
of ethics.
And I would say that that's a deeply
rooted,
judeo christian concept that that well
rooted that it proceeds any notion of
religious provincialism.
I mean it's,
it's,
it's deeper than judeo christian.
It's deeper than our humanity on some
level.
At one point we talked about the golden
rule and I said that,
that the,
the precursor to the golden rule can be
found even among monkeys.
right?
It's the golden rule is the rule for
monkeys.
Yes,
exactly,
exactly.
Let me just add to the picture you
sketched out.
I,
I agree with.
We have a,
we have an ethical obligation even to
our future selves,
right?
I mean we are in relationship to who we
will,
who's going to be the person who is
drinking his fourth scotch tonight will
be had some ethical relationship to the
person who's going to wake up with a
hangover tomorrow morning and and one
thing we know for sure in which we have
begun to deeply understand that
described scientifically as w we are bad
at all of these calculations,
right?
Like the,
the hyperbolic discounting,
a future rewards.
That's also why I think we have these
stringent limitations on rationality.
Sap,
is that we can't solve the problem
through calculation.
Well,
I don't know,
but we we increasingly can and and even
where it's best summarized not by
capital.
ONe thing I'll grant you is that it's
not always best conveyed or rendered
Indelible and actionable by being being
given a nature paper or an abstract
from,
from a paper in the literature and being
told,
this is the way you want to behave,
to maximize your wellbeing.
It may best be conveyed by certain
stories or certain books that are that
are in the philosophy section of the
bookstore,
not the science section and but you
aren't.
You and I were at the book signing the
other night and someone came up with
with a copy of the meditations of marcus
aurelius.
Write a fantastic book.
There's so much wisdom in that book,
right?
And there's nothing about stoning a girl
to death if she's not a virgin on her
wedding day.
Now we all recognize that marcus
aurelius was a human being who wrote
this book and that that provenance is no
barrier to take in the book deadly
seriously.
It's an incredibly useful book.
And stoicism,
stoicism could be the quote religion or
the guiding philosophy of the west.
It could,
it would be a much better one than
judaism or christianity and and as have
none,
virtually none of the downside.
and so that's my point,
that we're,
we're in this perverse circumstance of
being held hostage by certain products
of,
of literature,
and we need to break the spell and if,
if,
if we're finding it this hard to break,
what do we think is gonna happen in the
middle east or in subsaharan africa?
I mean we,
we,
the,
the moral progress we need to engineer
is a common humanity coming together.
Okay.
Shared values are.
Those are perfectly credible arguments.
But the weakness in the argument I think
is the one that we started to talk about
earlier,
which is that when you talked with dave
rubin and while back and michael shermer
said the same thing recently,
he,
he basically said that atheism is a,
is a doctrine of negation.
That's what you said with ruben is that
there isn't that positive ethos in
atheism.
All it says is that there's no,
there's nothinG persona,
there's nothing transcendent.
It's something like that.
There is no god.
And so and so the problem with the
atheist,
it's not even the assertion that there
is no god,
it's just that it's a failure to be
convinced by any of the gods on offer.
It's just like not believing in zoos,
fine.
And it's not like it's a week.
It's not like it's a weak argument.
I mean I'm perfectly aware of that
making a day istick case or a case for
religion in the face of the claims of
the rationalist atheist is perhaps while
it's a very,
very difficult thing to manage.
but it is also the case that.
And this is where I think we differ with
regards to what happened say in the
soviet union and perhaps to to also in
nazi Germany,
is that when,
when,
when your doctrine demolishes the,
that's called it the literary or
fictional substructure and leaves,
nothing behind an esco.
An ethos needs to be provided because
something will rush in to fill the void.
And it certainly the case,
and this is what niche you warned about,
even though he was a strident
antichristian and it's also what
dostoevsky first saw.
He said,
if we knock out the logos from the
substructure of western society and we
need you to believe that it was
christianity's emphasis on truth that
destroyed christianity,
which was an extremely interesting
criticism.
You know,
christianity had been elevated to truth
to such a degree that it would.
It actually resulted in the demolition
of its own dogmatic substructure,
but be that as it made niches
prognostication was that if we allowed
god to die and perhaps there are reasons
for that,
that the consequence would be that would
be we would be awash in both nihilism
and totalitarian bloodshed and that is
what happened in the 20th century and
so and there's another.
There's another aspect to that which is
what you made you made trying to knock
out the whole thing.
Take out some of the substructure but
not the whole thinG.
That's what nature also showed that his
prediction,
and I think it's blindinGly obviously
true that you might end this post
christian era,
have a reminisce of christianity such as
guilt,
overbearing,
guilt and no means of alleviation or
redemption,
which is actually part of the problem of
protestantism by the way because it's,
you know,
and,
and there are other things too that it
seemed to be,
seemed to be fundamental religious
issues that,
that secular,
I think have a difficult time accounting
for it.
It'S like,
so you actually have to grapple
serIously with the problem that a
doctrine that's essentially one of
negation doesn't offer a positive ethos
and now,
and you are doing now to be perfectly
fair,
you said that reading a nature paper
about the necessity of calculating your
ethic across multiple,
multiple timeframes and multiple persons
doesn't have the motive force that's
going to drive you to act ethically and
life.
And I do believe that's true,
but I think the fact that the ethos
doesn't have motivational push is
actually a fatal flaw.
They don't meet every week to read
marcus aurelius music.
There's no music that goes along with
it,
there's no art that goes along with it.
There's no architecture that goes along
with it like,
but to be fair to the present,
most music and mozart and most
architecture is no longer religious that
is flown the perch provided by religion
traditionally and most of what we care
about in increasingly cosmopolitan and
secular societies is not tied to
religion in any direct way and there's
even whole religions like judaism where
you have to look long and hard to find
anyone who believes much of anything
that is religious,
right?
I have literally sat on stage debating
what I thought was a religious rabbi who
was a conservative rabbi and when I,
when I said something that assume that
he believed in a god who could hear our
prayers,
he threw up his hands and he said,
what makes you think?
I believe in a god who can hear prayers
and I was just,
you know,
I practically lost the debate.
Just be in,
in my astonishment,
you know,
what does it mean to be a conservative
rabbi in this case?
There are religions that have made that
transition to a,
an increasingly attenuated commitment to
the truth of the doctrine and there are
religions who haven't moved an inch
right?
And,
and,
but I think we have to acknowledge that,
that this,
this movement in this direction is
progress because what it,
what it actually is at bottom is
increasing sensitivity to the difference
between having good reasons and bad
reasons for what you believe.
Right?
And,
and the fact that the,
that this book has been around forever
is not a good reason.
The fact that mommy told me so
well it is.
It's actually,
it's not a terrible reason though
because the fact that something has
lasted for that length of time at least
makes the fact that it's lasted a
mystery and you can't just attribute
that to casual politicking or economic
circumstances.
There's,
there's something at look you can say
about many of the biblical stories is
that they're incredibly memorable and
that means that in some sense they're
adapted to the memory structures.
So is the,
the mythology of ancient Greece.
It's incredibly memorable,
but,
but I don't.
I don't all those gods or did the
stories still can be useful,
but the god fear bibs on,
let's say it lives on in a way that is
benign.
It lives on in a way where you learn
about them in mythology class,
in school,
right?
You don't have it.
You don't have a fear of hades drummed
into you as a child by your parents.
The other thing that is,
as far as I can
tell in the rationalist doctrine,
and this is something that I've observed
in my clinical practice,
and so one of the things that's happened
over the last years that I've had many
people,
especially ex soldiers,
come to my lecturers who have
posttraumatic stress disorder and they
say that listening to my lectures,
especially the ones on good evil and
tragedy.
There's a partIcular lecture that I
suppose you might be.
You might think about as devoted to
people who have posttraumatIc stress
disorder and that the language of good
and evil that I lay out in those
lectures is actually what allows them to
recover from the posttraumatic stress
disorder and dealing with people like
that in my clinical practice.
The same thing as being the case.
If we can't transcend the language of
the merely rational and move into an
intense conversation about good and evil
in some senses,
metaphysical realities.
We can't enter a realm of seriousness,
conceptual seriousness,
that's of sufficient depth to help heal
someone who's been touched by
malevolence because that actually is
what happens to people with
posttraumatic stress disorder,
is that inevitably the reason that there
are so shattered isn't because something
tragic has happened to them.
Although that does happen upon occasion.
It's because someone malevolent has made
contact with them and sometimes that
malevolent being let's say,
or blunt force or spirit,
for lack of a better word,
is something that resides within them.
And so there we have these lImits on
rational did.
And the reason I'm making this cases
because we've already identified another
limit of rational discourse.
It's like it doesn't have the motivating
power of great fiction and great
literature and great poetry,
but it also doesn't have the healing
power of language that that takes the
ethical realm to it's extreme in some
sense and and then the next problem
without,
and this is something that douglass has
been,
has been contemplating,
I would say,
is that what?
What evidence do we have that a merely
secular representation,
irrational representation of our ethic
is going to provide us with a motive
force that would be sufficient for us to
do such things as identify what's
valuable about our culture and be
motivated to sufficiently protected
assuming that there's something worthy
of protection,
but we know what a few of those things
are and they have.
They have nothing to do with what's on
the inside of a church or a synagogue or
a mosque.
They have to do with things like free
speech,
right?
Like the trench we are all fighting in
is at least one of them is defense of
the free exchange of ideas and that has
put in peril by many kinds of
orthodoxies.
But some are the old orthodoxy Is the
blasphemy laws and the people who want
states to be killed relieving in this
case islam.
So it's,
it's a that,
it,
those are some of the sacred.
I would,
if were going to list the,
the sacred artifacts of that that keeps,
that keeps our society worth living in
there.
I think the list is going to be very
long before we start getting to the
actual sacred objects.
So anyone faith,
but we,
it will be things like freedom of speech
and freedom of assembly and,
and the,
uh,
the free exchange of ideas across
boundaries.
the fact that we are no longer,
uh,
religiously,
or,
or linguistically or geographically
partitioned in the ideas.
We cAn entertain it.
Well,
it seems to me though,
and this may be my own,
my own idiosyncratic reading of the,
of the,
of the domain.
But when I look at something like,
like I've often considered the cathedral
dome,
let's say,
and there are very old cathedral domes
that have an image of christ put up
against the dome,
right?
So as,
as creator of the cosmos,
okay,
Canada,
I'm trying to look at that from a
psychological and even a biological
perspective and what I see is the
elevation of a particular image that
represents an ideal and so the,
the,
the christ that's represented on the,
on the,
on the dome of the cathedral is
something that's projected up into
celestial space.
So it's an ideal to which you were
supposed to be subordinate or that
you're supposed to embody.
And now ideal is the ideal of the logos.
Technically speaking,
the logos,
the word made flesh,
which is not only the word free speech
for lack of a better term,
but also the embodiment of that elevated
to the highest principle.
and that is given status as the creator
of the universe.
and the reason for that in part,
and this is written into the judeo
christian doctrine right from line one,
is the idea that it's through the
discourse that you value so much that we
actually engender the world as such,
and that is a divine principle and it's
also in my reading,
the divine image of god that men and
women are made in.
And so what I see in the underlying
metaphysic were where you see
superstition and,
and fundamentalism and look fair enough.
And it's not like.
I would never argue that that's not a
danger.
I see the images stick and,
and,
and dramatized representation of exactly
the idea that you hold to be paramount
above all else.
Which is your commitment to truth
expressed in speech.
Okay.
What's my concern,
and this is where I started with you,
is that you could give the same
charitable reading of astrology and
you'd even be tempted to do it a,
as we,
as we talk about astrology as you showed
at the outset now,
but I don't.
Why is it a charitable reading,
sam?
Like how else would you explAin the
existence of something like a cathedral?
I don't.
what the hell are people doing when they
built them saying we could.
It's by dent of mirror historical
contingency and questionable look that
we're not living in a world where the
cathedrals have stained glass windows
with signs of the zodiac on them.
Right?
We could be in that world.
Well,
we are.
We are.
We were very close to being in that
world to some degree because the
astrological endeavor in the judaeo
christian landscape expanded to
incorporate christianity and there's an
entire astrology of christianity
including representation.
Christ
fruit.
Yeah.
Yes.
So,
but my point is that we recognize that
the literal claims of astrology,
the mechanism by which astrologers think
it works is intellectually bankrupt.
Right?
And if any significant mayhem were being
caused by people's commitment to
astrology,
if we had presidents of the United
States who couldn't get elected unless,
unless they paid lip service to a
literal believer in astrology,
if we had presidents who were consulting
there,
astrologers to figure out when to meet
with other world leaders,
right?
This,
this will be a problem that that
rational people would recognize me.
Astrology can be disproven in a single
hour.
You just simply have to go to one
hospital in one city sometime and find,
find two unrelated children born in the
save within 20 feet of each other and
follow their lives and if they have
different lives than than than then the
signs of the zodiac mean nothing.
Part of your argument is an invalidly,
so is hoW in the world do we determine
which revelatory axioms are worthy of
respect and of maintenance and fair
enough,
maybe none,
maybe not,
but maybe it is just a matter of
conscious agents like ourselves having
better and better conversation.
Well that while it is certainly partly
that,
it is certainly partly that,
but let me,
because again,
revelation in my book is nothing other
than a record of past conversations.
So you've either got iron age
conversations shaping your worldview or
you have conversations like these
when you're worried you have both.
You can have both.
You have a dialogue with the past which
brings
made a marcus aurelius.
I read him with great pleasure and great
and,
and astonishment,
frankly,
I mean it is such a modern and edifying
take on ethics and,
and one's own personal wellbeing and
just not getting,
just not being encumbered by the,
by thoughts and,
and,
and vanities that,
that are,
that are so easy to cut through once you
notice them,
but so captivating and deranging of your
life when you don't.
And he,
I mean the wisdom in that book than,
than,
than almost any book I can name.
And you don't have to believe any
bullshit to
let me offer you a continued explication
here.
So,
and you didn't answer my question about
what all these crazy medieval people
were doing,
spending almost all of their excess
capital,
building a representation of the sky and
putting an image on that.
So just hang on a sec.
So,
so let's talk about what it would mean
to embody the truth.
So there's a deep idea and christianity
that this is what it would mean.
It would mean to confront the suffering
of life voluntarily to its fullest,
which would mean to accept the necessity
of death and betrayal of the hands of
your fellow men without undue bitterness
to accept that voluntarily and
antisocial.
Understand that your fundamental ethical
task is to work towards the redemption
of the world and that's associated with
that image that's cast upon the heavenly
dome and I and that isn't a charitable
reading,
sam.
That's a.
That's an essential analysis of the
fundamental doctrines of christianity.
Yes,
but I could do the same thing with
buddhism and give you a slightly
different story,
but nonetheless inspiring and edifying
and I could do the same thing with you,
but you can't do it with rationality,
but I can do it.
I can do it with green.
No,
no,
no.
That's not true.
I can do it with greek mythology.
I can do it with any of these domains,
but the crucial bit for me is that in
order to make use of those stories,
I don't have to believe in revelation.
I don't have to,
but I don't have to believe that you get
everything you want to after you die,
suggesting that you know no,
but I'm talking about the applause of
conventionally religious people who
think that their conventional religion
is in some way cashed out or redeemed or
supported by the reading your given now
of the of christ in the starry heavens.
It's not unless you're adding this other
piece,
which is some probabilistic claim that
yes,
this book probably was dictated by an
omniscient being unlike any other book
or maybe the muslims are right there.
Archangel gabriel did show up to
muhammad and his cave and give him the
one final revelation never to be
superseded and just on the merits of the
text.
We know that's not true.
We know for all it gets wrong and all it
fails to get right about the nature of
our circumstance.
We know that book is not the best book
ever written on any topic,
and here I'm speaking of the koran,
but it's true.
The bible is true.
It's true of the meditations of marcus
aurelius,
but the book,
but no one's claiming that about the
meditations and that's a crucial
difference.
It's a difference that that explained so
much unnecessary suffering in our world
and again,
what I fear about the way you talk about
religion is that it'd be a at the end of
all of these conversations,
I'm still not sure what you believe on
that point,
frankly,
and if I'm not sure no one out there as
well,
why don't know why.
I don't know why.
Expect to be sure about what someone
believes.
How do you think that any one of you are
capable of fully articulating what you
believe you sir,
you aren't completely ridiculous.
You're not transparent to yourself by
any stretch of the imagination.
you act out all sorts of things that you
can't articulate what but how you.
How about at best gets.
Yeah,
no.
If you look,
let's go on cognitive neuroscience on
this,
shall we?
Ninety nine percent of your processing
is unconscious.
You're not capable of articulating
yourselves.
If you were,
you'd be omniscient.
Give me any nonsense about that,
but that is a.
I've never heard so many people applaud
and of a of a simple question.
It was a good one,
honestly.
Yes.
Everything you just said about not being
fully transparent to yourself is true
and you are ruled by committee in there
all the time.
No doubt,
but I'm at.
I'm asking what you actually believe.
I mean,
there's several things I can ask a
asset.
I mean almost any one of these threads
can,
can pull the whole tapestry,
but to take christianity as an example,
what do you believe about this,
the origin of this sacred book,
the bible,
old and new testament.
Do you believe that just maybe it has a
status unlike any other book or is it
simply old Writing of human beings just
like ourselves?
I think it's both.
Okay.
So,
but,
but.
So what does that mean?
That you're.
So you're saying you're saying that
there's somebody who's taking dictation
that is unlike any other dictation.
So,
so homer
though creative or shakespeare they'll
create.
It was sources of inspiration.
Okay.
But everyone's been inspired.
If you talk to creative people basically
often described themselves as something
approximating a conduit through which
higher wisdom is pouring.
Again,
you're dodging shakes that shakespeare
could say that and any writer can say
that really ultimately,
and it's also the case that we would or
we would rank organize.
We would rank order those writers,
which is why you pointed to shakespeare
in terms of the generalizable validity
of the revelations.
Sure.
So well look,
so,
so you run into the same issue.
You know you criticize the bible and
look fair enough.
You know the man,
but you're,
you're also evading a very important
issue which is how do you,
how do you quantitatively rank the
contributions of literature without
assuming that there's a hierarchy of
revelation?
Well though,
there's a hierarchy of wisdom.
Sure,
there's a hierarchy of human wisdom.
I will grant you that everyday of the
week,
but this is what we're talking about.
primates like ourselves having
conversations and this is the most
important game.
We can play this.
This is the best game in town and it has
always been so.
But people are imagining and,
and it includes,
as you said at the outset,
what I would call spiritual experience
and spiritual experience,
is it mit's have a fact based discussion
about the nature of human consciousness
and
why do you allow that as an exception?
Like it because
is part of the dataset.
So it's
possible.
So this is spiritual experience without
the possible of possibility of
concretized revelation.
So it's a formless spirituality that
you're advocating.
No,
no,
it,
you,
you can have.
I'm not even,
I'm not even discounting the possibility
that there are invisible entities out
there in the universe far smarter than
ourselves who we could possibly be in
dialogue with.
I mean there are many strange ideas that
we could defend to one or another degree
that there are people walking around
speculating that we might be living in a
computer simulation,
that all of this is being run on some
hard drive of the future or,
or some,
you know,
alien supercomputer now that you can
actually.
I mean,
nick bostrom and oxford gives a very
cogent argument in defense of that
thesis right now.
You can,
you can deal with that on its merits.
I'm not saying the university isn't
stranger than we suppose or even kenzo
pose,
but one thing we know is that when you
read the bible,
you can turn every page of that book and
you will not find evidence of
omniscience.
You.
You will not find anything in there that
someone as smart as shakespeare or
actually a little bit dumber could have
written.
No,
I don't think that's true.
Sam.
There are incredibly.
There's whatever else they might say
about the biblical writings are
incredibly potent nearby,
but so it's impossible to write
something.
It's virtually impossible to write
something like cain and abel was a
paragraph saying shit.
You understand?
That
spirit of the shakespeare of of two,
3000 years ago couldn't have written
genesis.
He couldn't have written to cain and
abel not in 10 sentences,
so then enable is 10 sentences long.
So then it contains more wisdom than you
can.
Then you can dig out.
Okay,
but now we're getting to the nub of it.
Then you think that it was not the
product of a human mind.
I think it was the product of a vast
collection of human minds working over
millennia.
Okay,
so one of shakespeare's so,
but still we still,
we've just got people,
and this is,
but this concession,
if indeed you're making it,
and I'm still not sure,
is the eradication of traditional
christianity.
If something is deeply wise,
it's reflective of a deeper reality.
otherwise it wouldn't be wise.
I'm in love with deeper reality,
deeper reality that something is wise is
the story of cain and abel reflect
reality.
The landscape of mind that we are that
either takes great training,
great luck or pharmacological
bombardment of the human brain to
explore right there.
There is a way,
there are ways to get there.
There are ways to have the vision right
and and if we will,
we understand this to some degree,
but experientially and we can understand
it to some degree by,
by third per person,
methods of science and it's not.
It's not like I don't,
I mean I've had many experiences that if
I had them in a religious context would
have counted for me as evidence of the
truth of my religion.
Right?
But because I was not brought up in a
religious context and because I spend a
lot of time seeing the downside of that
form of credulity,
I have never been tempted to interpret
these experiences that
try a higher dose.
I prepped,
believe me,
I'll,
I'll go.
I'll play that game of poker with you
all day long.
Be surprised as well.
Maybe.
Maybe there's our next podcast.
Did you see a car that.
Okay,
a question now.
So we're an hour and 15 minutes into
this discussion and hypothetically what
we will do is stop and,
and go to q and a.
But our experience So far has been when
we asked the audience,
because we have done that each time,
whether we asked the audience whether we
should continue or whether we should go
to q and a.
So the first thing I'm going to do,
and you can vote on this by making a
certain amount of noise if you're
inclined to do so,
how many of you would like us to stop
talking and go to q and a?
How many of you would like us to
continue this discussion for 45 more
minutes?
No,
it seems to me that it's an objective
fact is the ladder people have the
floor.
It really is going to be a rude
awakening when those applause or
reversed,
however.
Yeah,
we know.
Yeah.
So let,
let,
let me yet what douglas say something.
What was that last summer?
I was going to ask something.
Yeah.
Um,
I forgot what I was going to ask you
something.
Let's go back.
Let's go back
to v two.
One of the core problems that we've been
trying to address,
which is the,
the apparent failure perhaps of the
rationalist atheist types to develop a,
an active ethos that has sufficient
beauty and motivational power to serve
as a credible replacement for the
religious rituals.
So there seems to,
there must be a reason why that's that
failure has occurred.
Yeah.
Right.
So,
or
list of reasons.
One is that traditionally the impulse to
do that in a religious context has been
fatal.
Right?
So to declare your apostasy has been
almost as reliable way of committing
suicide as jumping off a building in
most cultures and most societies for the
longest time and still is in many places
as you know,
in the muslim world.
So there has been a barrier to entry to
thinking creatively about alternatives
to religion and so much of atheism and
secularism is just a,
a,
a pitched battle against the,
the eroding power of religion.
And when religion really has its power,
right?
We know what it's like.
I mean,
again,
I think what we spoke about this at one
point,
you know,
just that the moment that it makes this
most salient is,
you know,
galileo being shown the instruments of
torture by men who wouldn't look through
his telescope.
Right?
I mean,
that's,
that was the point of contact between
untrammeled human rationality and the,
the womb that bore it,
right?
Your real religious are at,
at the beauty of the heavens.
Right?
So the moment a person like galileo
stepped a little too far and to connect
us to astrology again,
galileo was a court astrologer,
right?
and they were,
there was a car,
there was a point of contact between
astronomy and astrology at that point.
So we're still under the shadow of that
kind of dogmatism and oppression in much
of the world.
I mean,
for the longest time,
I mean it's still in the United States.
You cannot run for the presidency
without pretending to believe in god.
It's amazing.
It's amazing fact,
right?
When will that change it?
Some day it will,
but we have.
We have just had almost no time to
experiment in this space and innovation
sometimes have been some decades.
I suppose the thing that unites unites
Jordan and me on this is if,
if we face some of the problems,
some of the enemies you might even say
that you identify as well,
and the question is whether you should
face them in the midst of an experiment
that may or may not work.
I leap into pure rationality or whether
you might decide it's worth among other
things.
Taking some of the versions of things
that you've had that have been worth in
your past and using them where they're
useful.
Well,
but what are you picturing there because
there really is no leap.
There's no global leap too pure
rationality.
There's just.
There's this incremental or erosion of
religious answers to terrestrial
questions.
So there's again,
the moment you,
you have a science of neurology,
you begin to look at epilepsy not as
demonic possession,
but as a neurological problem before
there's a science of neurology.
You don't know what the hell's
happening.
Right?
So,
so into that safe.
Something obviously drove douglas.
I would say in some sense,
I'm surprisingly to make the assumption
that one of the things that we need to
do to defend whatever it is that we have
a value in the west,
assuming that we have anything of value,
was something like the reincorporation
of this religious substructure
structure.
So it's not something that I would have
expected you to conclude,
but what did you conclude it?
Well,
partly for the reason I just suggested
the leap into pure rationality.
There's no evidence yet that it's going
to work or there's going to be enough or
enough people are going to be able to
partake in it.
Give me the place where you're worried
that it's going to fail and what can
you.
What are you imagining now?
Yeah.
Let me give you one example,
and we may be in the midst of the
discovery that the only thing worse than
religion is its absence
and where.
Where are we discovering that?
Look at the religions that people are
making up as we speak.
I mean everyday there's a new dogma and
you and I and Jordan have repeatedly
trips over those documents.
Some usually survived.
It has to be said,
but there the stampeding create new
religion all the time.
At the moment,
every,
every new heresy that's invented and
they're not as well thought through as
past heresies.
They don't always have the bloody
repercussions yet,
but you can easily foresee a situation
in which they do represent a new
religion is being created as we speak,
by a new generation of people who think
they are non ideological,
who think they are very rational,
who think they're past the myth.
You think that past story,
who think they're better than any of
their ancestors and have never bothered
to even study their ancestors,
right?
Can't you say that dogmatism is the
problem,
but the generic problem here is
dogmatism.
A firm believer in the absence of good
argument and good evidence,
absolutely we can agree that dogmatism
of any kind has that danger or we'll
always have that danger,
but the void also has a danger.
The void that you can create if you
throw out all the stories that helped
get you to where you are also has this
danger because people come up with these
new stories and every day's news now is
about this.
Every our politics is now basically
I mean,
well,
yeah,
and what and what's flowing in to fill
the gap seems to be something like a new
tribalism,
which is exactly what you'd expect in
some sense,
right?
If you,
if you demolish the superordinate
system,
you know religion divides people no
doubt,
but it also unites people and so one of
the things that arguably unites people
above their mirror tribalism is there a
union and an abstract religious
superstructure,
and then if you demolish that,
well then one of the things that does
seem to happen is the of a reflexive
tribalism because people need,
they need a group identity of sorts and
the easiest thing to do seems to be to
revert to ethnicity and race and gender
and sex,
et cetera,
et cetera.
And then we do end up and have ended up
in this situation that douglas outlines.
And you know,
one of the things I think that
distinguishes us temperamentally,
possibly maybe because you're a little
more on the liberal side and I'm a
little more on the conservative side.
Even temperamentally speaking,
is that your fundamental terror is that
a fundamentalism.
Although you also state in the moral
landscape that you understand the perils
of nihilism.
And I would say my fundamental terror is
that of nihilism.
Even though I'm susceptible sensitive to
the catastrophes of fundamentalism.
But I don't think you do address the
problem of the void sufficiently because
I don't think that you have anything to
offer except an and I'm not trying to
minimize your offering.
You make a case that people should work
to alleviate suffering and that we
should live in truth.
But jesus,
sam,
you can summarize that in two sentences.
It doesn't have the potency of,
of the,
of the fictional literary,
artistic substructure that seems
necessary to make that into something
that's,
that's a compelling story.
So this is where we might disagree with.
This could be a fundamental disagreement
because I actually don't see the problem
of nihilism the way you do or the way
it's advertised.
Like once you rip out the fall
certainties and the bad evidence in the
bad arguments and they and they,
the mere dog was imposed on us by prior
generations.
That whole never closes safely with
anything else.
You have to put something in its place
that's shaped just like that.
Some other false certainty or some other
story.
I simply don't think that's the case.
I think there's so many things we
outgrow both individually.
A,
you know,
in our own childhoods and culturally
that where there is no,
there is no void left.
There's no santa claus shaped void that
we have to fill with the
exact same thing,
but people certainly experience.
Some people are good people.
I'm not discounting the fact that it is
hard to be happy in this world.
I mean we are living in a world that
seems designed perfectly designed to
frustrate our efforts to find permanent
happiness.
So you asked me,
you put me on the spot.
Let,
let me just add to my answer to this.
I just think that there's the recipe for
a good life or at least a minimal recipe
for a good life.
It's not that this is all that's
entailed,
but this is,
this is,
this is certainly necessary if not
sufficient,
is to live alive.
That is increasingly motivated by love
and guided by reason,
right?
You can't go very far wrong if you are
motivated by love and guided by reason.
Right?
And,
and the problem is,
is that
the first thing I would say about that
is,
to me that's
a recapitulation of the judeo christian
ethic,
which is
guided by love and use logos to serve
that.
Then you to read the fine print on
reason,
say reason.
I said logos because that's the.
That's something that's deeper there.
Is jesus smuggling?
Well,
yes,
definitely.
It would have.
Okay.
So,
but so I've been,
I've been trying to.
Part of the reason that I'm doing what
I'm doing is to try to address the void.
Let's say,
and I suspect that many of you are
actually here because you would like to
have the void addressed.
And so the way it looks to me as
something like this,
and this is what I've derived in part
from my studies of religious tradition.
So I could say that at the beginning of
genesis for example,
there's a proposition that it's truthful
speech that generates habitable order
from chaotic potential.
That seems to me to be the fundamental
narrative.
And I do believe there's something dead,
accurate and real about that because we
do generate the world as a consequence
of our communicative effort.
And then there's a second proposition
which is that the world that we generate
from the chaos of potential is habitable
to the degree that the communication
that we engage in is truthful and that's
why god who uses the logo set at the
beginning of time to generate the world
is able to say that his creation is
good.
The proposition is the world you bring
into being through truthful speech is
good,
and that's the image of god that's
implanted in man and woman and there's a
grandeur about that idea and you think,
well,
you don't need the grand jury because
it's just a fiction.
It's like,
just wait a second here.
It's not just a fiction unless you don't
believe that in some manner you partake
in the creation of the world and that
you have an ultimate responsibility that
might well be described as divine to
participate in that process properly,
truthfully and with love.
And there's every reason to think that
that's an elevated ideal.
So high that it's worthy of
conceptualizing as divine and also to
presume that it represents some
fundamental metaphysical reality and
that's a lot more powerful than you need
to be.
Good.
Yes.
Problem here.
Jordan,
is it I,
I could do exactly
plea what you just did with buddhism or
hinduism and it is just as grand and
just as deep and just as anchored to the
the first person experience of
contemplative who have taken that as far
as they could take it,
you know?
Well sam,
you should do that and see how people
respond to it.
Well,
no,
because I don't know.
No,
because I
at the end of the end of the game,
that doesn't arrive where I want to get
to where we need to get to because it
is.
It's.
It would be two different effect.
It's there.
There are different claims ultimately
about the status of truth and good and
evil and if at the beginning of the
world and the fate of human
consciousness after death,
it is completely,
completely irreconcilable worldviews.
Yeah.
There are hindus in the audience.
They believe something that is totally
irreconcilable to what christians,
I believe,
I don't think that you can offer,
pardon me,
a watered down version of buddhism as a
consequence of psychedelic experience as
a,
as a,
as a acceptable and credible alternative
to the power of the fundamental founding
myths of the western culture.
And if you think you can try it.
Well,
no,
I'm trying.
I'm not trying that,
but that's,
that's not,
uh,
that's not what I.
Well,
first of all,
just to,
just to get my biography straight,
it's not just the psychedelic
experience.
I'm not making light of the psychedelic
Listen,
to take this.
We were having most of this conversation
on the side of where,
wherein it seems reasonable to worry
about the fate of civilization,
right?
We could have started at a very
different point with just the nature of
consciousness,
right?
Just the,
just the for our first person encounter
with being itself,
right.
You wake,
we,
all of us wake up each morning.
We,
we,
we are thrust from a condition of deep
sleep,
which we seem to know nothing about and
we're just to push through a veil of
dreams into this apparently solid
reality that we call the world and we're
engaging one another in this space of,
of just consciousness and its contents
and we're trying to make sense of it and
science is the best language game we
play.
I would argue in trying to make truly
rigorous sense of it,
but it's not.
It doesn't exhaust all the language
games we play,
we play others that are,
are also fact based.
We talk about what happened historically
before we arrived here.
We talk about a facts as we can
understand them that we just didn't
witness but others did and we call that
journalism,
right?
So we were trying to have a.
It's hard,
it's getting harder and harder.
Discern what's actually going on now,
but we are,
we are thrust into this condition of
being our apparent selves moment by
moment.
And we notice the difference between
happiness and suffering.
Right?
And this is not merely sensory is not
merely that you know,
I don't,
I don't like the feeling of a hot stove
and I do like a a warm bath.
It's ideas,
ways of thinking about ourselves and the
world can can open the door or close the
door to various states of happiness and
suffering and religion comes into
religion.
Leverage is people that the difference
between believing that your dead child
is in heaven with jesus and not being
able to believe that is enormous.
Right.
I wanted to ask you some specific
though.
You've expended it's seven amount of
reputational energy and much more on the
jihadists in your battles.
So we say that.
How much allyship to use a term have you
found from fellow secular,
rational people who want to love and
reason like you?
Well that is a leading question,
isn't it?
I've got fingers if you need more.
Yeah.
I know you.
Your,
your fingers are safe.
No,
unfortunately,
but it's.
But this is a problem of.
I wouldn't describe this to.
Well,
the allies you can easily find among
deeply religious christians say,
are there for the wrong reasons,
right?
I mean,
I.
So I can find,
you know,
I,
I know that the reason they're there for
the wrong the world,
they see the problem clearly for the
wrong reasons.
So for instance,
so I meet secular scientists types,
you know,
anthropologists say who are so far from
knowing what it's like to believe in
revelation that they don't believe
anyone else does,
right?
So when you tell them that members of
isis really believe that if you die in
the right circumstances,
you get 72 virgins and you're surrounded
by rivers of milk and honey and all the
rest.
If you go into the ivory tower,
you meet people who,
who don't believe that anyone believes
that stuff,
but if you go into a mega church,
they know people believe that stuff
because they believe their own dogmas,
right?
That's,
that's what it's like to be,
to be effortlessly right for not
especially good reasons.
The fact that you believe a book,
the fact that you believe a book was
written by god and therefore it's
trivially easy for you to understand
that someone else believes that,
but they just have the wrong book.
That's not the rational basis for
understanding our circumstance that
we're looking at.
I'm not saying whether one is advice and
one is wrong,
but one seems to have more commitment in
that and in one battle you're fighting
commitment and may be important,
and indeed it may be many reasons why
the people who deeply wants to love and
be rational,
I absolutely no damn use in that fight
because they want to preserve their
happiness a bit longer,
preserve their comfort a bit longer,
cannot understand people who genuinely
come from a fundamental standpoint.
Yeah,
and then there's also other steel man
their case for a moment.
It is understandable to be sensitive to
and guilty about the history of
colonialism and the reality of racism
and to be so committed to tolerance as
your master virtue.
That's your attempted.
To tolerate intolerance and not
recognize it to be cowardice,
which in fact,
yeah,
making tolerance.
Your core value is much different than
making truth,
your core value,
which is an interesting thing because,
and perhaps this is one of the places
where you and the fundamentalist radical
leftists sled say differ,
is that the core value that's emerging
there is definitely one of tolerance.
Whereas the core value that you espouse
is one of truth and truth and tolerance
are not the same thing.
No.
Is the pursuit of truth and the belief
that as a result,
truth can be found,
that he's not a single thing on its own.
You just pursue it as a hobby.
It's just something you do,
but that you believe that at the end of
it there is a truth to be found.
Yeah.
So,
but doug was what?
What do you fear is the case here?
If,
if there were more people like me in the
west,
right?
Well,
maybe I'm.
Maybe I'm the,
I'm the outlier here.
I'm somehow infected by this
overwhelming commitment to truth and
rationality and science,
and yet I'm still motivated to worry
about jihad.
Uh,
you're,
you're worried that there are many
people like me who are,
are oblivious to the problem.
Are you worried about it when so many
other people who are.
Hypothetically,
this is the question you asked,
why are you so worried about when
there's so many people who are
hypothetically like you that don't seem
to be worried about it?
I mean,
maybe you shouldn't be worried about it,
is obviously worried
my worry at any rate that we may be
living in an era when we are discovering
that the enlightenment and the
enlightenment values never went very
wide and didn't go terribly deep and
this is a very painful realization to
make.
Not only do we go all around the world
and discover that we find that at home
it turned out not to have gone very deep
in this society and that's the problem.
It is a problem,
but,
but hence my,
my commitment to making them deeper
and to reiterate the point I'm,
I'd be very happy if it was entirely.
Sam harris is all the way down.
I'd have no problem with that.
It's just the underneath sam harris.
It's hell.
I'm also curious to know me too well,
I'm curious about something that has to
be very carefully edited
physically.
You outlined rationality in the service
of love,
like this is an interesting like I'm not
sure you get to get away with that
because like is it rationality or is it
love because I don't understand the
place in your conceptual system for love
given your emphasis on rationality as
the ethic of as the,
as the mechanism of ethics.
So I would say to the degree that I
smuggled in jesus,
which by the way isn't accidental in
some sense and I am fully conscious when
I'm doing it.
You smuggled in love and it essentially
plays the same role.
Well,
no,
the love,
but love is a,
an experienced reality.
I mean love is a state of consciousness.
It's a state of and I wouldn't
ultimately.
It's a fact that one can experience it
or not.
Yeah,
but that's not the same thing.
No,
it is.
There are artifacts that you can
experience something,
but their favorite you're experiencing
is there's also the thing that you're
experiencing as a fat.
What do that,
there are facts about the,
the,
the range of human experiences,
I,
I think,
and not even just human,
just conscious experiences.
If we can build computers,
they can feel love and that's not
inconceivable and will either succeed in
doing that or not,
but consciousness admits of a range of
experiences and love is one of the best
on offer.
It's not the only one we care about,
but it's the one that anchors us to a
positive commitment to the wellbeing of
other conscious systems and,
but the,
but the crucial thing I agree with it is
it is a fact that,
okay,
loving someone entails a really their,
their love and his counterfeits right
there.
People can confuse,
you know,
romantic attachment or lust with love.
Right?
So I've been,
and the buddhists are especially good at
differentiating these various states of
consciousness and,
and uh,
it's a,
a,
this is true pleasure,
mental pleasure in the company of
another that is colored by a commitment
to their wellbeing.
I wanted them to be happy and wanting
them,
wanting to have their hopes realize a
non zero sum commitment,
a or sense of,
of,
of your entanglement with them.
And you can see your failures to love
me.
You can be with people who you think you
love,
you know I'm,
I'm with my best friend say and I just
find out something fantastic has
happened for him and let's say in his
career and I feel a moment of envy.
Say,
well then you see,
well,
okay,
well how much do you love this person?
If your first reaction to something good
happening to them is you feel poorer for
it,
right?
That's the cain and abel story.
Exactly.
So,
so this is,
these are all kinds of different facts
you can witness in your own mind and
yes,
you pay enough attention to the nature
to what it's like to be you.
The full horror show of,
of yeah.
And almost biblical unwinding of all
possibility is available,
you know,
and it's.
And you add psychedelics to that
cocktail and it,
it gets even more vivid.
So,
so are you saying,
but the frame that that's like these are
about the human
mind and it is also factual to say that
it is possible to navigate in this
space.
It is possible to design institutions
and s and social systems and ethical
commitments that help us navigate in
this space.
It's not that we all have to get up
every morning naked and try to rebuild
civilization and all of human wisdom for
ourselves.
Each day you we inherit.
We inherit the most useful tool,
the tools.
You don't have to figure this all out
for yourself and my my appeal to you is
that what we should want to use all the
best tools available without
hamstringing ourselves by this notion
that certain tools are must be the best
for all time or certain books must be
read it on every page with equals
diligence because it.
This book came from the creator of the
universe.
When we're reading marcus aurelius,
if he gets something catastrophic,
lee wrong on page 17,
we say,
well,
what the hell?
He he lived 2000 years ago.
There's no way he knew everything right?
And we turn the page
so we can't do that with the bible and
the mythological representation of that.
So there's an ancient idea,
a very ancient,
okay
idea that when you face the void,
what you do is confronted and leap into
it,
and what you discover at the bottom is a
beast.
And inside that beast you discover your
father die,
lying dead,
and then you re animate your father and
you bring them back to the surface.
And that's the means of dealing with the
void,
right?
And so in,
in essence,
in some sense,
that's just what you said.
You said that
if we accept that,
again,
this is something confabulatory about
that because you can do.
I could change the valence of virtually
every word you use there and it would
also sound profound and true.
I could,
I could swap father for mother and I got
swapped void from mountain top and I and
I could.
It could be the same seemingly
archetypal journey
and it makes sense of.
It's not that easy,
sam.
Like that's the same fast,
easy.
I've done it with a cookbook,
but look,
if it's that easy,
then you can write great novels,
no story there other either it's not the
ability to write a great story so these
things can be swapped out with these and
there is a reason that it's your father
that you rescue from the belly of the
beast and not your mother in those sorts
of situations it,
but
give you a buddhism and hinduism that ha
that have completely different
iconography is and mythologies.
Well,
they're different levels,
but not at all.
It's like languages levels or not.
They're
crucially opposite in many of these
cases.
I'm just saying that this kind of of of
reading meaning into story is there's a
reason why it's not science because it's
because it is in some basic sense
unfalsifiable there's nothing you and I
can do for the rest of our lives to be
sure that the mother isn't at the bottom
of that void and it's really the problem
to develop a factual approach to the
analysis of literature.
Well,
yes,
on its own terms you can say,
well,
but that that extends to things like it
is a fact that hamlet was the prince of
Denmark
and not for me in terms of the meaning
of literature.
Well,
yeah,
you can make true and false claims or
more and less plausible claims about
literature trying to do more defects on
you,
but again,
but this is a very different game than
what most religious people think is on
offer.
Well,
look,
if you look at the domain of science,
most scientists aren't very good at what
they do and if you look at the domain of
religious thinking,
most religious thinking people aren't
very good at what they do,
but that doesn't mean that the whole
damn thing should be thrown out.
There's tons of religious revelation and
and,
and wisdom,
but there's that word revelation.
Revelation is something that we can all
do.
You,
me and marcus aurelius,
right?
That is a very different world than the
world that muslims think they're living
in.
But you just said,
sam,
that we have to go,
and this is why I used the going down
into the void to rescue your father
metaphor.
You just said that we have to and you've
said this before and I know you believe
it as well,
that we have to go back into the past
and find the wisdom that can help guide
us because we don't have to do this as
if we're encountering everything for the
first time and that's exactly the idea
of going into the void to rescue your
father.
That's how that in that is the eternal
age.
Old medication for the confrontation of
the void and you said it yourself and so
I don't know which it is.
It's like,
do we have to go into the past to rescue
what's best given the understanding that
there is something there worth rescuing
or not?
Is it pure rationality and nothing else
moving forward?
They are unconstrained by convention.
It is.
It's just again,
it's,
it's I want our certainties and I think
we all in every other area of our lives,
we agree about this effortlessly,
right?
If I,
if I'm pretending to be certain of
something that you can sense,
I have no good reason to be certain
about you begin to miss,
trust me in every area if it's in
business or if it's in sports or if I
told you I knew that France was going to
win the world cup and I was absolutely
sure.
And,
and,
and yet I magically didn't bet any money
on it.
Uh,
the,
these are,
these are conversations we can have that
everything else.
And yet on this topic of religion,
people change the rules,
right?
And I'm,
I'm just arguing that the rules should
never.
The rules of by which we dole out our,
our credence shouldn't change.
And,
and if they don't change,
and again,
it's,
it's we,
we couldn't be misled by the,
the duration of the past.
Maybe this is what's,
this is the,
the,
the comparison of something like
scientology to christianity is so
invidious because we can practically
meet l ron hubbard,
right?
We've got film of him.
It confabulating about galaxies that
rule ruled by,
by overlords,
whose names he magically knew,
right?
We,
we see,
we see the man behind the curtain,
we don't see that with the apostle paul
or,
or anyone else who brought us the,
the,
the quote real religions,
and yet it's always just been human
beings doing this.
Right,
and,
and if you go back far enough,
they were doing it in a,
in a situation that was completely
uncontaminated by the kinds of concerns
we have as scientists and secular
rational people for evidence and
consistency and a knowledge of the past.
I mean they had nothing.
They had no mechanism by which to record
their observations.
No,
and I'm going to interrupt you.
Yes,
because festival.
I was signed saying five minutes and I'm
very conscious of a number of things
apart from my own silence and we had a
long a session on love just then and I
refuse to finish this evening on such a
positive note and I'd like to turn that
around.
We're all in agreement on certain
aspects if we speech civilized discourse
on the most important matters and much
more,
but there's also,
I'm sure a lot we have in common of what
we just can't bear and I just wanted to
hand over to both of you at some point
to give an idea not of your loves of
your present hates.
Hmm.
That's Jordan.
Hate.
Well,
I would say did.
I spent a lot of time over the last 30
years trying to understand the part of
me that can be deeply satisfied as an
auschwitz prison guard and I would say
that that part is something that's
worthy of hate and I think the best way
to overcome it is to recognize it in
yourself and to do everything possible
to constrain it.
And that's what's given me an
overwhelming horror.
Both of the nihilistic void and the
catastrophes of totalitarianism and the
reason that I've turned to the degree
that I have to the analysis of religious
traditions,
not losing my scientific perspective in
the meantime is because I've done
everything I could to,
to extract out the wisdom necessary to
understand how to deal with that bit of
unredeemed evil that every bit of us
possess
you.
Well,
I would say that I hate unnecessary
suffering,
especially my capacity for it.
And I see so much of my time conscious
time,
moment to moment devoted to this
experience that should be familiar to
all of you,
which has to be captured by thoughts of
the past or the future,
which are,
uh,
which almost by definition have a
mediocrity so transcendent that it's
just a,
it,
it is what makes human life just a,
just pure monotony and pettiness and,
and everything that religion advertises
itself as a corrective to.
Right.
So what I'm sensitive to is that someone
like,
so you could tube when he came to.
This is osama bin laden's favorite
philosopher,
uh,
when he came to America in the,
in the fifties,
he saw his hosts and their neighbors
spending all their time,
you know,
bragging about how well mowed their
lawns were and what just what new
chevrolets they had purchased,
and he looked at all of this as just,
it's just the quintessence of,
of desecration and lost opportunity and
the lack of profundity and for which for
him,
the,
the corrective obviously was islam and
half of that is right.
How it's possible to be totally
captivated by the wrong things in this
life and to make yourself not.
So obviously being a guard at auschwitz
with a clear conscience is the extreme
of the extreme states of happiness.
What was that?
Or being a guard at auschwitz with
happiness.
Yes.
Okay.
Yeah,
we have a worth still.
Right?
So that's the extreme case.
Enter.
And to realize that is that,
that that job was not only filled by
psychopaths,
right?
That it's psychologically normal.
People could,
could be brought to that point.
That's.
Yeah.
I recognize that.
That's the situation we're in,
but most of us live our lives in a
different place where it's just
mediocrity and pettiness and an egg and
needless anxiety and very dimly.
We recognize the possibility of
overcoming that on a day to day basis.
And um,
you know,
honestly,
I think the atheism,
the lack of belief,
the lack of faith in an afterlife,
for instance,
the lack of the lack of belief in the
notion that you get everything you want
or make it everything you want to after
you die and helps leads,
leads to greater depth rather than to
superficiality.
Here,
it's like,
wait,
when I kiss my daughter's good night,
right?
It is with the understanding that I may
never see them again.
Right?
It's not with the assumption that if the
roof caves in will all be reunited and
heaven will along with our pets.
Right?
Which is what many people find consoling
about faith.
But that,
and,
and so what I would say,
what I hate in myself and what I hate in
our culture is everything conspires to
make the preciousness and,
and sacredness of the present moment.
Difficult to realize.
And that's,
that's what I,
that's the tide against which I
keep looking.
I'm,
I'm not gonna answer my own question
primarily because of the length of the
list and the knowledge of the time.
But I would say that if there's one
thing I hated the fact that a
conversations like this civil discussion
on the most important matters between
people who have enormous amounts in
common and have important disagreements
which engaged with the past and which
are going to be facilitated for a long
time by a knowledge of all the
extraordinary progress we're about to
hit.
That can take place in an arena like
this with an audience like you who have
all come out and now set sat here for
two hours.
Um,
and I think it's at any rate,
for my point of view,
one of the most positive things I can
imagine in the world at the moment
that an evening like this is happening
with an audience like you.
Unless either of you want to say
anything.
I think on behalf of them,
all of us,
I just to say what a thrill this is for
us.
And thank you to you and I hope that
this is an example of a constructive
discussion of a kind that might even at
some point catch on.
So thank you.
You
put your hands together for sam harris,
Jordan Peterson,
and Douglas Murray.
All right.